<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1981.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Jan. 2009</title>
    <volume>1981</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of three new species of &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius &lt;/i&gt;from Australia and New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present paper describes two new species of the gobiid fish genus &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt; from southern New Guinea and a third related species from northeastern Australia. All three species are restricted to a small number of river systems. &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellendenensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinctive in having reduced predorsal scales and fin-ray counts and mental frenum shape. It is restricted to relatively clear water rivers of northeastern Queensland. The closely related, &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muscorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is also distinctive in reduced predorsal scales and fin-ray count and is found only in the Fly River system of New Guinea. &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robertsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinctive in fin-ray and scale counts and is found in the Fly River in Papua New Guinea and possibly in a river in Papua close to the Fly River. That species has been confused with &lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giuris,&lt;/i&gt; which generally occurs in lower reaches of the river.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt;; Gobiidae; new species; Australia; New Guinea; freshwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Glossogobius&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Douglass</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoese</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gerald</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Allen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barbus niluferensis,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of barbel (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from Nilüfer River, Turkey, with re-description of &lt;i&gt;B. oligolepis&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niluferensis,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the Nilüfer River, Marmara Sea drainage, Turkey. It is distinguished by a weaker last simple dorsal-fin ray, serrated along the proximal half of its posterior margin, a maximum known size of 146 mm SL, a slender body, a short head, a short caudal fin, and larger irregular black blotches on the back and the flanks, and small black spots on the head, extending downwards to the cheeks. &lt;i&gt;Barbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligolepis&lt;/i&gt; Battalgil, 1941, is a valid species known from the rivers draining to the southern shore of the Marmara Sea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Turkey; Cyprinidae; &lt;i&gt;Barbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligolepis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niluferensis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Turkey</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Davut</firstname>
          <lastname>Turan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maurice</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>Güler</middlename>
          <lastname>Ekmekçi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the freshwater crabs of Mt Kenya and the Aberdare Mountains, Kenya, East Africa (Brachyura: Potamoidea: Potamonautidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of the freshwater crabs of Mt Kenya and the Aberdare Mountains in central Kenya, East Africa is revised based on a large collection of previously unreported material. Three species belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Potamonautes&lt;/i&gt; MacLeay, 1838 (Potamonautidae Bott, 1970) are recognized from the region and redescribed. &lt;i&gt;Potamonautes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeanneli&lt;/i&gt; (Bouvier, 1921) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;odhneri&lt;/i&gt; (Colosi, 1924) are both resurrected from synonymy and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alluaudi&lt;/i&gt; (Bouvier, 1921) is recognized as a valid species rather than as a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suprasulcatus&lt;/i&gt; (Hilgendorf, 1898). All three species are endemic to the Central Province, Kenya.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Potamoidea; Potamonautidae; &lt;i&gt;Potamonautes&lt;/i&gt;; freshwater crab; taxonomy; Mt Kenya; Aberdare Mountains; Kenya; East Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Neil</firstname>
          <lastname>Cumberlidge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-42</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some southern African species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhampsinitus&lt;/i&gt; Simon (Opiliones: Phalangiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhampsinitus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1879 from southern Africa are described or redescribed, among them &lt;i&gt;Rhampsinitus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavobrunneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Some general remarks on the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhampsinitus&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Republic of South Africa; Zimbabwe; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Rhampsinitus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavobrunneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Republic of South Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wojciech</firstname>
          <lastname>Starêga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of montane web-footed salamanders (Plethodontidae: &lt;i&gt;Bolitoglossa&lt;/i&gt;) from the Costa Rica-Panamá border region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of lungless salamanders (Plethodontidae) are described from high montane habitats of the border region between Costa Rica and Panamá. &lt;i&gt;Bolitoglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robinsoni&lt;/i&gt; are distinguished from each other and from other salamander species in this remote area by differences in adult body size, external proportions, foot webbing, tooth counts and/or external coloration. Both new species are assigned to the &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subpalmata&lt;/i&gt; species group, subgenus &lt;i&gt;Eladinea.&lt;/i&gt; The miniaturized &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; is remarkable in being extensively depigmented, yet having the peritoneum and stomach area heavily pigmented and visible through the body wall.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bolitoglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robinsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Cordillera de Talamanca; taxonomy; Central America; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bolitoglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robinsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Cordillera de Talamanca</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Federico</firstname>
          <lastname>Bolaños</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wake</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
