<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1978.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jan. 2009</title>
    <volume>1978</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-01-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tenerva &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Pentatomidae: Pentatominae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Afrotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt; Berg, 1899 (Heteroptera: Pentatomidae: Pentatominae: Cappaeini), is diagnosed and revised based on the study of primary types. The endemic Madagascar genus &lt;i&gt;Tenerva&lt;/i&gt; Cachan, 1952, syn. et stat nov., is recognized as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Tripanda,&lt;/i&gt; but retained as a valid subgenus due to the distinct differences in the structure of the female genitalia. &lt;i&gt;Veterna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorata&lt;/i&gt; Jensen-Haarup, 1937, is redescribed and transferred to &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt; (subgenus &lt;i&gt;Tenerva).&lt;/i&gt; We currently recognize seven species within the genus: &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt; (Tenerva) &lt;i&gt;collaris&lt;/i&gt; (Cachan, 1952) comb. nov. (Madagascar); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tenerva) &lt;i&gt;decorata&lt;/i&gt; (Jensen-Haarup, 1937) comb. nov. (Namibia, South Africa, Zambia, Zimbabwe; Yemen); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripanda) &lt;i&gt;dispar&lt;/i&gt; Schouteden, 1964 (Democratic Republic of the Congo, Ivory Coast, Nigeria, Republic of the Congo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripanda) &lt;i&gt;horacekorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Central African Republic, Gabon, Ghana, Ivory Coast, Nigeria, Republic of the Congo, Senegal); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripanda) &lt;i&gt;jurickorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Guinea); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripanda) &lt;i&gt;longiceps&lt;/i&gt; (Villiers, 1967) (Central African Republic, Ghana, Guinea, Ivory Coast, Republic of the Congo); and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripanda) &lt;i&gt;signitenens&lt;/i&gt; (Distant, 1898) (Angola, South Africa, Tanzania, Zambia). Lectotypes for &lt;i&gt;Tenerva&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collaris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Veterna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dispar,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;signitenens&lt;/i&gt; are designated. All species of the genus are keyed, important diagnostic characters are illustrated, and known information about their bionomics and ecology is summarized.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Heteroptera; Pentatomidae; Pentatominae; Cappaeini; &lt;i&gt;Tenerva&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tripanda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Veterna&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new synonym; new combination; key; Afrotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Petr</firstname>
          <lastname>Kment</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zdeněk</firstname>
          <lastname>Jindra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-47</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematic position and cladistic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Gyrasida&lt;/i&gt; Koch, a remarkable genus of Praocini (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae) from Chile</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gyrasida&lt;/i&gt; Koch (Pimeliinae: Praocini), distributed in central Chile is elevated to generic status and transferred from Asidini to Praocini on the basis of constant tribal level characters. Prior to this study &lt;i&gt;Gyrasida&lt;/i&gt; was considered a subgenus of the South African &lt;i&gt;Afrasida&lt;/i&gt; Wilke. Character states of &lt;i&gt;Gyrasida&lt;/i&gt; shared with the other genera of Praocini and not shared with genera of Asidini are discussed. A cladistic analysis of the six species of the genus is presented including: &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;propensa&lt;/i&gt; (Wilke) (type species), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucianoi&lt;/i&gt; Flores &amp; Vidal, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; Flores &amp; Vidal, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomasi&lt;/i&gt; Vidal, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franciscae&lt;/i&gt; Vidal, and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camilae&lt;/i&gt; Vidal. This article includes a redescription of the genus, habitus photographs, illustrations of external morphology and genitalic features, a cladogram, and a distribution map.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tenebrionidae; &lt;i&gt;Afrasida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gyrasida&lt;/i&gt;; Chile; Asidini; Praocini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tenebrionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Flores</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Vidal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-62</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New monotypic genera of Epipsocidae (Psocoptera: Epipsocidae) from Belize and Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new monotypic genera are described and illustrated, &lt;i&gt;Edmockfordia&lt;/i&gt; for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chiquibulensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Chiquibul Forest Reserve, Belize, and &lt;i&gt;Phallofractus&lt;/i&gt; for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thailandensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; from Chiang Mai Province, Thailand. The former is close to &lt;i&gt;Mesepipsocus,&lt;/i&gt; and the later is the sister group to the assemblage &lt;i&gt;Goja-Rogojiella-Ianthorntonia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Epipsocetae; Epipsocidae; Chiquibul Forest Reserve; Belize; Chiang Mai Province; Thailand; new genera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Epipsocetae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfonso</firstname>
          <middlename>N. García</middlename>
          <lastname>Aldrete</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
