<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1980.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Jan. 2009</title>
    <volume>1980</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triaina, &lt;/i&gt;a new genus in the Janirellidae Menzies, 1956 (Crustacea: Isopoda: Asellota), with two new species from south-eastern Australia, and a new diagnosis for the family</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The varying concepts of Janirellidae Menzies, 1956 are outlined, including its rejection by several authors. The view of Wilson and Wägele of Janirellidae being a valid family comprising &lt;i&gt;Janirella&lt;/i&gt; Bonnier, 1896 and presumably &lt;i&gt;Dactylostylis&lt;/i&gt; Richardson, 1911 (= &lt;i&gt;Spinianirella&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1962) is accepted. Diagnoses of the Janirellidae subsequent to Menzies’ original one were based on the inclusion of a diverse range of genera now recognised as not belonging in that family. A new diagnosis of Janirellidae is presented based on the inclusion of &lt;i&gt;Janirella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dactylostylis,&lt;/i&gt; and a new genus &lt;i&gt;Triaina&lt;/i&gt; with two new species, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;isodonte&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makridonte,&lt;/i&gt; from south-eastern Australia. The latter species represents the shallowest record (80 m) of the otherwise predominantly deep-water family. All species in the family are listed in an appendix, with area of type locality and depth range.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Asellota; Janirellidae; new diagnosis; &lt;i&gt;Triaina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;isodonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makridonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <lastname>Just</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species status of &lt;i&gt;Centrolene lema&lt;/i&gt; Duellman and Señaris, 2003 (Amphibia: Centrolenidae) revealed by Integrative Taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We evaluate the hypothesis of &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lema&lt;/i&gt; as a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulae&lt;/i&gt; using morphological, bioacoustic and genetic comparisons. Our results show that there are no consistent differences in any of these three areas; hence, we present &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lema&lt;/i&gt; as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulae.&lt;/i&gt; Additionally we provide new data on the distribution and ecology of the species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bioacoustics; &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulae&lt;/i&gt;; Centrolenid frogs; Distribution; Glassfrogs; Guiana Shield; Guyana; mitochondrial DNA; Synonym; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bioacoustics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Santiago</firstname>
          <lastname>Castroviejo-Fisher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>16-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Parasesarma&lt;/i&gt; De Man, 1895, from Southeast Asia (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Sesarmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of sesarmid crabs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parasesarma&lt;/i&gt; De Man, 1895, are described from mangrove forests in Southeast Asia. &lt;i&gt;Parasesarma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paucitorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from northern Sulawesi and is allied to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leptosoma&lt;/i&gt; (Hilgendorf, 1869) but differs from the latter in the form of its carapace, leg proportions, the structure of the tubercles on the cheliped dactylus, and the male first pleopods. &lt;i&gt;Parasesarma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raouli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from southern Peninsular Malaysia and is differentiated from the allied &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;charis&lt;/i&gt; Rahayu &amp; Ng, 2005, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anambas&lt;/i&gt; Yeo, Rahayu &amp; Ng, 2004, by the number and form of the tubercles on the cheliped dacylus, the shape of the male abdomen and structure of the male first pleopods.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Sesarmidae; &lt;i&gt;Parasesarma&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dwi</firstname>
          <middlename>Listyo</middlename>
          <lastname>Rahayu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres suberitis&lt;/i&gt; Giesbrecht, 1897 and &lt;i&gt;A. tenerus&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923) (Copepoda: Siphonostomatoida), including notes on &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;abyssi&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923) and &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present paper reviews the type material of four poorly described species of &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt; Boeck, 1859 deposited in the Zoologisk Museum of the University of Copenhagen. For &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssi&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923), each taxon was represented by only the poorly preserved, dissected holotype. Consequently, neither species could be redescribed in detail. As the original description of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssi&lt;/i&gt; is not sufficient to differentiate it from its congeners, we propose to regard this species as undetermined. Although only the antennule and antenna of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; were amended, this species is still considered valid based on a combination of characters that include a 21-segmented antennule, oral siphon extending beyond leg 1 insertion, and genital double-somite being longer than wide. The other two species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suberitis&lt;/i&gt; Giesbrecht, 1897 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenerus&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen, 1923), were redescribed which revealed inaccuracies in the original descriptions. &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suberitis&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by having a 21-segmented antennule, oral siphon extending to the maxilliped insertion, 2-segmented mandibular palp, and genital double-somite being wider than long. &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenerus&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished by a combination of characters that include a 21-segmented antennule, oral siphon extending to the intercoxal plate of leg 2, 2-segmented mandibular palp, relatively slimmer and longer claws on the antenna, maxilla and maxilliped, and genital double-somite being about as long as wide.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Siphonostomatoida; &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt;; Danish Ingolf expedition; Davis Strait; Naples</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Siphonostomatoida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eugenia</firstname>
          <lastname>Bandera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mercedes</firstname>
          <lastname>Conradi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new freshwater peritrichous ciliate from Harbin, China, &lt;i&gt;Epistylis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalinensis &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Sessilida: Epistylididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A freshwater peritrich ciliate, &lt;i&gt;Epistylis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., was collected from Lalin River, Harbin, China, and its morphology, infraciliature and silverline system were investigated based on living and silver-impregnated specimens. The new species measured 125-187 × 31-47 μ m &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo&lt;/i&gt; and is characterized by having green-coloured endoplasm containing symbiotic algae, single apically located contractile vacuole, one-layer peristomial collar and slender body shape. The Cshaped macronucleus is transversely located. Three equally kineties in polykinety 3 parallel to each other. Number of silverlines between peristome and aboral trochal band, 117-145; between aboral trochal band and scopula, 50-68. Comparing most other congeners, circular fibers of this species composed of internal and external layers.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Epistylis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; freshwater peritrich; infraciliature; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Epistylis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; freshwater peritrich; infraciliature; morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guilan</firstname>
          <lastname>Qi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xinlu</firstname>
          <lastname>Shi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guijie</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiaozhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Hu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bangana brevirostris&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;a new species of cyprinid fish (Teleostei: Cypriniformes) from the Lancang-Jiang (Upper Mekong River) drainage in Yunnan, Southwest China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bangana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevirostris,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the Lancang-Jiang in Yunnan, Southwest China. It can be distinguished from all other congeners by the following combination of characters: a pair of minute rostral barbels; mental groove short and shallow; dorsal fin with 12–13 branched rays; 42–44 lateral line scales; eye large, its diameter 28.1–32.9 % of head length; snout short, its length 25.5–32.7 % of head length. It shares the same postlabial groove-type with &lt;i&gt;Bangana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dero&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devdevi,&lt;/i&gt; which makes them very different from other congeners.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bangana&lt;/i&gt;; Cyprinidae; Taxonomy; Southwest China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bangana&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kai</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
