<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1992.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>1992</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">One new genus and five new species of Rhyncaphytoptinae from China (Acari: Eriophyoidea: Diptilomiopidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">One new genus and five new species of the Rhyncaphytoptinae (Acari: Eriophyoidea: Diptilomiopidae) from China are described and illustrated. They are &lt;i&gt;Brevulacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jilinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Quercus&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Fagaceae), &lt;i&gt;Cuihuacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longituberis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Cotoneaster&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Rosaceae), &lt;i&gt;Rhinophytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sericeaomeiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Rosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sericea&lt;/i&gt; spp. &lt;i&gt;omeiensis&lt;/i&gt; (Rosaceae), &lt;i&gt;Rhinotergum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shaoguanense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Ulmus&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Ulmaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Rhyncaphytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funali&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Salix&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Salicaceae). All the eriophyoid mite species described here are vagrants on the undersurface of host leaves.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">plant feeding; taxonomy; Jilin Province; Shaanxi Province; Guangdong Province</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">plant feeding</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiao-Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zi-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yue</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; Beddard, 1886 (Crustacea, Tanaidacea) from the deep sea of the tropical and southern East Atlantic Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As part of the sampling efforts during the DIVA-II expedition several Tanaidacea of the genus &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; were captured in the Guinea and the Cape Basin in the tropical and southern East Atlantic Ocean. Two different species were sampled, &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotermundiae&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from the Guinea and &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guskei&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from the Cape Basin. The distribution of both species is limited to these basins. A full description for both species is presented. &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guskei&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is the largest &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt; reported for the South Atlantic Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; &lt;i&gt;Neotanais&lt;/i&gt;; deep sea; Atlantic Ocean; Guinea Basin; Cape Basin</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <lastname>Weigmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jürgen</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerrero-Kommritz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-36</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological disparity despite genetic similarity; new species of &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; Miller &amp; Cribb, 2005 (Digenea: Cryptogonimidae) from the Great Barrier Reef and the Maldives</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Examination of the humpback red snapper, &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbus&lt;/i&gt; (Perciformes: Lutjanidae), from Lizard Island off the Great Barrier Reef and Rasdhoo Atoll, Maldives revealed the presence of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; (Digenea: Cryptogonimidae), &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from the typeand only other species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae&lt;/i&gt; by the combination of body size, oral spine number (60–81 in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus,&lt;/i&gt; 47–56 in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae)&lt;/i&gt; and number of testes (13–25 in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus,&lt;/i&gt; 9 in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae).&lt;/i&gt; Bayesian inference analysis using data from the internal transcribed spacers 1 and 2 (ITS1 and ITS2), 5.8S and the large subunit (LSU) nuclear ribosomal DNA of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae&lt;/i&gt; and species of &lt;i&gt;Beluesca,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Caulanus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neometadena,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Latuterus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Retrovarium&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Siphoderina&lt;/i&gt; was performed to explore phylogenetic relationships of species of &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; with other cryptogonimid taxa. Despite the significant morphological differences between &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae,&lt;/i&gt; these two species differed consistently by only 5 base pairs (bp) over the entire ITS region (3 bp in ITS1, 0 bp in 5.8S and 2 bp in ITS2) and 1 bp in the LSU rDNA regions examined. The ITS2 rDNA region was sequenced from metacercariae obtained from the fins, flesh or body cavities of a number of fishes belonging to the Blenniidae, Pomacentridae and Tetraodontidae and analysed using minimum evolution analysis with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae.&lt;/i&gt; This revealed the presence of two additional genotypes (putative &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; sp. A and B), which consistently differed from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; by 1 and 4 bp, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae&lt;/i&gt; by 1 and 4 bp and from each other by 3 bp over the ITS2 dataset. Although these genetic differences are relatively small, when evaluated in light of the differences observed between &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polygongylus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae&lt;/i&gt; (which are morphologically quite distinct) and differences seen in other congeneric cryptogonimid taxa, the ITS2 rDNA data alone suggest that at least two more species of &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis&lt;/i&gt; are present at Lizard Island. These data also suggest that the ITS2 rDNA region alone is suitable for resolving operational taxonomic units (OTUs) at the species level within the Cryptogonimidae based on what was observed in this and other cryptogonimid systems. A morphological description of metacercariae of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibaldiae&lt;/i&gt; obtained from two species of Pomacentridae at Heron Island, off the Great Barrier Reef is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Blenniidae; Cryptogonimidae; Digenea; Great Barrier Reef; Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis;&lt;/i&gt; Lutjanidae; &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus;&lt;/i&gt; Maldives; Opisthorchiata; Opisthorchioidea; Pomacentridae; ribosomal DNA; Tetraodontidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Blenniidae; Cryptogonimidae; Digenea; Great Barrier Reef; Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;Lobosorchis;&lt;/i&gt; Lutjanidae; &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus;&lt;/i&gt; Maldives; Opisthorchiata; Opisthorchioidea; Pomacentridae; ribosomal DNA; Tetraodontidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terrence</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Abigail</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Downie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lizard in the clouds: a new highland genus and species of Gymnophthalmidae (Reptilia: Squamata) from Maringma tepui, western Guyana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus is erected for &lt;i&gt;Pantepuisaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodriguesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; collected at 2080 m elevation on Mount Maringma, a sandstone flat-topped table mountain (tepui) located in the eastern Pakaraima Mountains, at the GuyanaBrazil border. The new genus mainly differs from all other known gymnophthalmids by the following combination of characters: distinctive ear opening and moveable eyelids, limbs pentadactyl with all digits clawed, prefrontals present, interparietal and parietals forming a jagged, irregular posterior margin, three pairs of genials, second pair of genials in contact with only one infralabial, dorsal scales hexagonal, keeled, in transverse rows only, ventral scales imbricate, hexagonal, mucronate, broadly keeled, in transverse rows only, and hemipenis weakly bilobed with series of curved transverse plicae bearing mineralized spicules.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pantepuisaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodriguesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; endemism; Guiana Shield; microteiid; Pantepui; taxonomy; tepuis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pantepuisaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodriguesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; endemism</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neovochthonius&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov. pro &lt;i&gt;Neochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Karppinen (Acari, Oribatei, Protoplophoroidea, Heterochthoniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>L. I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Judson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
