<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1969.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Jan. 2009</title>
    <volume>1969</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-01-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpoles and advertisement calls of &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema bibroni&lt;/i&gt; Tschudi and &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema kriegi&lt;/i&gt; (Müller), with notes on their geographic distribution and conservation status (Amphibia, Anura, Leiuperidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibroni&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kriegi&lt;/i&gt; are poorly known species with a troublesome taxonomic history. They are cryptic taxa, currently considered as valid species on the grounds of biogeographic and ecological differences. The first is known from much of southern Uruguay and from the northeastern region of the State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil (from sea level to 900 m a.s.l.); the latter is restricted to high grasslands of the Sierras Grandes in central Argentina, between 800–2000 m a.s.l. Herein, we compare their tadpoles and advertisement call and provide some notes on their conservation status and natural history. The tadpoles of both species are very similar, belonging to the benthic ecomorphological guild, and are characterized by: total length about 35 mm at stages 33–36; globose body; short lateral sinister spiracle posterodorsally directed; pineal end organ visible between the eyes; medial vent tube, with its opening aligned with the ventral fin, directed to the left or to the right; vent tube enclosed in a transparent saccular structure underlying the limb buds; tail length about 60% of the total length, with bluntly rounded tip; oral disc anteroventral, laterally emarginated, with very robust jaw sheaths and marginal papillae arranged in a single or double row with a large dorsal gap; labial tooth row formula 2(2)/3(1); gap in A2 wide with the upper jaw sheath partially placed within it; P3 about half the length of the other rows. The advertisement call exhibits the same temporal and spectral structure in both species. It consists of long trills (up to about 45–70 s) that are emitted sporadically; notes are about 0.044–0.062 s, separated by gaps of 0.024–0.058 s (note repetition rate 8.9–13.2/s) and have three pulses. Dominant frequency ranges between 1729 and 2162 Hz. Reproductive season of both species differed, autumn and winter for Uruguayan populations of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibroni&lt;/i&gt; and spring and summer for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kriegi.&lt;/i&gt; Defensive encounter behavior (deimatic behavior) consisting in exhibition of the eye-like lumbar glands was documented in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibroni&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kriegi&lt;/i&gt; (along with exposure of reddish flash coloration), and also in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borellii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bufoninum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaul.&lt;/i&gt; Similar behavior previously unreported for a &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; species lacking noticeable lumbar glands was observed in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tucumanum.&lt;/i&gt; The analysis of the literature, material in collections and fieldwork done by the authors over the last decade in Uruguay suggests that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibroni&lt;/i&gt; is undergoing severe decline. It was a common species up to the early 1970’s, but few populations close to each other in southeastern Uruguay are the only ones currently known. The conservation status of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibroni&lt;/i&gt; is of major concern as most known remnant populations are located in coastal areas with an increasing impact of urbanization. In contrast, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kriegi&lt;/i&gt; seem to have stable populations, many of them within protected areas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">amphibian decline; biogeography; defensive behavior; deimatic behavior; larval morphology; &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borellii&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bufoninum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaul&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pleurodema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tucumanum&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">amphibian decline</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolenc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Borteiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Baldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daiana</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferraro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Prigioni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of helminth parasites of Soricomorpha (= Insectivora) of North America north of Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A parasite-host and a host-parasite checklist of helminths found in Soricomorpha (= Insectivora) of North America north of Mexico are presented. The parasite-host checklist includes a total of 114 species of helminth parasites reported in the literature from 28 species of insectivores, totaling 349 records. These include 97 species from shrews (9 trematodes, 34 cestodes, 50 nematodes, 4 acanthocephalans) and 23 species from moles (3 trematodes, 4 cestodes, 10 nematodes, 6 acanthocephalans). Each helminth species is listed under its most current accepted taxon, with all known synonyms, distribution by state/province, and references for each geographic location. The following new combinations are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Lineolepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pribilofensis&lt;/i&gt; (Olson, 1969) n. comb. for &lt;i&gt;Hymenolepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pribilofensis&lt;/i&gt; Olson, 1969; &lt;i&gt;Monocercus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;soricis&lt;/i&gt; (Neiland, 1953) n. comb. for &lt;i&gt;Molluscotaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;soricis&lt;/i&gt; (Neiland, 1953) Spasskii &amp; Andreiko, 1971; and &lt;i&gt;Eucoleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blarinae&lt;/i&gt; (Ogren, 1953) n. comb. for &lt;i&gt;Capillaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blarinae&lt;/i&gt; Ogren, 1953. The state of knowledge of helminths of insectivores in North America is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">helminths; Soricomorpha; Insectivora; shrews; moles; North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">helminths; Soricomorpha; Insectivora; shrews; moles; North America</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kinsella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vasyl</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tkach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery and redescription of the Andean earth-snake &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagleri&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Serpentes: Colubridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagleri&lt;/i&gt; was described based on a single specimen from Humbo, Department of Boyacá on the western Cordillera Oriental of Colombia, and since its original description there is no further record for the species. In the course of examination of Colombian collections the holotype of the &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagleri&lt;/i&gt; could not be found and it is probable that it was lost, but we found three additional specimens of this poorly known snake from localities relatively close to the type locality. In this paper, we describe these specimens, and report data on meristics, morphometrics, and hemipenial variation for the species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagleri&lt;/i&gt;; Colombia; Cordillera Oriental; hemipenis; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagleri&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <lastname>Passos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arredondo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
