<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2284.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Nov. 2009</title>
    <volume>2284</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Bethylidae) and redefinition of generic limits based on morphological characters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; (Epyrinae) is a cosmopolitan genus comprised of 132 species. No morphological synapomorphies are known for the genus and the genus is characterized by a combination of characters common to most Epyrini. Herein, we performed a cladistic analysis based on morphological characters to test the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris.&lt;/i&gt; The three known subgenera of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; (Chlorepyris, &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;str.,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Trichotepyris)&lt;/i&gt; and other Epyrini (Anisepyris, &lt;i&gt;Bakeriella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Calyozina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Epyris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laelius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Trachepyris)&lt;/i&gt; were included in the ingroup. The cladistic analysis of 48 taxa (46 ingroup species and two outgroup species) and 81 structural characters yielded 72 cladograms under equal weights, and one under successive weighting. &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; was found to be polyphyletic; the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Trichotepyris&lt;/i&gt; was closely related to &lt;i&gt;Anisepyris&lt;/i&gt; whereas &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;str.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; was closely related to &lt;i&gt;Laelius.&lt;/i&gt; The subgenus &lt;i&gt;Chlorepyris&lt;/i&gt; is paraphyletic. Morphological characters are discussed in the light of the new phylogeny; novel characters are proposed and illustrated, and a new classification of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; and Epyrini is proposed. The following nomenclatural changes are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Trichotepyris&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized under &lt;i&gt;Anisepyris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;(syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.);&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chlorepyris&lt;/i&gt; is recognized as a separated genus &lt;b&gt;(stat.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;rev.);&lt;/b&gt; all 12 American species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris&lt;/i&gt; are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Laelius;&lt;/i&gt; 22 species of &lt;i&gt;Trichotepyris&lt;/i&gt; are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Anisepyris;&lt;/i&gt; 58 species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Chlorepyris.&lt;/i&gt; A remaining total of 40 species are now recognized in &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris.&lt;/i&gt; The holotype of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myrmecophilus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, the type species of &lt;i&gt;Rhabdepyris,&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Epyrinae; Epyrini; classification; &lt;i&gt;Anisepyris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Chlorepyris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Laelius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Trichotepyris&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Epyrinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cecilia</firstname>
          <lastname>Waichert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Celso</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis &lt;/i&gt;Takahashi (Hemiptera: Aphididae: Hormaphidinae), a generic account, description of a new species from China, and a key to species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The aphid genus &lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis&lt;/i&gt; Takahashi is reviewed. &lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligostricha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described on &lt;i&gt;Machilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; from Yunnan, China. A key to the known species of &lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis&lt;/i&gt; is provided in here. The type specimens studied are deposited in the Zoological Museum, Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis&lt;/i&gt;; Aphididae; Hormaphidinae; new species; new record; key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euthoracaphis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jing</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yan</firstname>
          <lastname>Fang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gexia</firstname>
          <lastname>Qiao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>30-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pachydema &lt;/i&gt;Laporte (Coleoptera: Scarabaeoidea: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae: Pachydemini) from the Canary Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pachydema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megalops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a new species from Gran Canaria (Canary Islands, Spain) is described and illustrated. A key to all Canarian &lt;i&gt;Pachydema&lt;/i&gt; Laporte species and illustrations of diagnostic structures are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New taxon; systematics; key; Gran Canaria; Spain</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New taxon</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Estefanía</firstname>
          <lastname>Micó</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Galante</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-47</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cladistic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Megachile &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Chrysosarus&lt;/i&gt;) Mitchell and revalidation of &lt;i&gt;Megachile &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Dactylomegachile&lt;/i&gt;) Mitchell (Hymenoptera, Megachilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Megachile&lt;/i&gt; is the largest genus of the family Megachilidae, being widely distributed throughout temperate and tropical areas of the world. The validity of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Chrysosarus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Dactylomegachile)&lt;/i&gt; was investigated based on a cladistic analysis of 63 characters of adult morphology of 14 taxa. The single most parsimonious tree (181 steps, CI=0.60; RI=0.63) resulting from an implied weighting analysis recovered &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Chrysosarus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Dactylomegachile)&lt;/i&gt; as monophyletic groups. Both subgenera are redescribed and the value of the most frequently used characters in the taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Megachile&lt;/i&gt; is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Leaf-cutter bees; Megachilinae; cladistic analysis; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Leaf-cutter bees</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Silvana</firstname>
          <lastname>Durante</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nora</firstname>
          <lastname>Cabrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-62</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Recognizing taxonomic units in the fieldThe case of the crickets &lt;i&gt;Oecanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulcisonans &lt;/i&gt;Gorochov 1993, and &lt;i&gt;O. pellucens &lt;/i&gt;(Scopoli, 1763) (Orthoptera: Gryllidae): implications for their distribution and conservation in Southern Europe</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recognizing taxonomic units in the field complement classical museum taxonomy. It contributes to geographical distribution assessment making possible the recognition of conservation status of conflictive and similar species. In this paper, we provide unambiguous field characters distinguishing two similar species of &lt;i&gt;Oecanthus&lt;/i&gt; in Southern Europe: &lt;i&gt;Oecanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulcisonans&lt;/i&gt; Gorochov and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pellucens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Scopoli)&lt;/i&gt; that are frequently misidentified. Whereas &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulcisonans&lt;/i&gt; is a southern rare species with an uncertain status and distribution, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pellucens&lt;/i&gt; is common and widely distributed in the Palaearctic. Song is the easiest way to distinguish between the two species in the field being continuous in the former and with regular schemes in the latter. Further, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulcisonans&lt;/i&gt; is larger, with relatively longer inner wings protruding more apically from tegmen, and with a more slender sternum, morphological traits that are detected simply with a hand magnifier.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Species identification; taxonomy; Spain; Tunisia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Species identification</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cordero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vicenta</firstname>
          <lastname>Llorente</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pau</firstname>
          <lastname>Cordero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Joaquín</firstname>
          <lastname>Ortego</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
