<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2199.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Aug. 2009</title>
    <volume>2199</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-08-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The sponge-dwelling snapping shrimps (Crustacea, Decapoda, Alpheidae, &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt;) of Discovery Bay, Jamaica, with descriptions of four new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty-two species of sponge-dwelling shrimp in the genus &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; were collected in the vicinity of Discovery Bay, Jamaica. Four of these species are new to science. &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thele&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corallinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumosetosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; belong to a group of morphologically similar species that also includes &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brooksi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bousfieldi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carpenteri,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;irie&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is a highly distinctive shrimp most similar to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mcclendoni,&lt;/i&gt; but can be distinguished from the latter by the unique bowl-shaped fingers of the major chela and the two-pronged distal protuberance on the palm of the major chela. &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;belizensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regalis&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time from outside their type localities in Belize, while &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bocas&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duffyi&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time outside their type localities in Caribbean Panama.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zuzalpheus&lt;/i&gt;; gambarelloides group; Alpheidae; Decapoda; symbiotic; coral reef; eusociality; sponges</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kenneth</firstname>
          <middlename>S</middlename>
          <lastname>Macdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kristin</firstname>
          <lastname>Hultgren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Emmett</middlename>
          <lastname>Duffy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomic status of the harvest mouse &lt;i&gt;Micromys minutus&lt;/i&gt; (Rodentia: Muridae) from Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of the harvest mouse &lt;i&gt;Micromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; from Vietnam is re-evaluated. The mtDNA analysis shows that the harvest mice from Lao Cai Province of northern Vietnam belongs to a distinct phylogenetic lineage, previously known only from a haplotype from Chengdu, Sichuan Province, southern China (Yasuda &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2005). The mtDNA analysis shows a strong genetic divergence among this lineage and all the other known haplotypes of &lt;i&gt;Micromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; (11.68% for cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene sequences). Canonical discriminant analysis of cranial and dental data, as well as of some external characters, also separate the Vietnam – South China group (also including an Indian specimen) from other Palaearctic populations. The skull of southern populations is relatively large, with a longer and broader palatine. The dorsal pelage of the Vietnamese specimens is grey, tinged with brown in comparison with the red-brown dorsal colouration sharply contrasting with the white underside in the majority of Euro-Siberian adults. The harvest mice of the Vietnam – South China group are distinguished from the typical European ones by their rather long tail that is about 120% of the body length (82 to 95% in the Palaearctic populations). Both genetic and morphological data suggest the existence of a second &lt;i&gt;Micromys&lt;/i&gt; species, occurring at least in North Vietnam and South China. The available name for this species is &lt;i&gt;Micromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythrotis&lt;/i&gt; (Blyth, 1856).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mitochondrial DNA; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; control region; skull; morphology; phylogeography; &lt;i&gt;Micromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythrotis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mitochondrial DNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexei</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Abramov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ilya</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Meschersky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Viatcheslav</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rozhnov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
