<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2167.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Jul. 2009</title>
    <volume>2167</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-07-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dialychone&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Jasmineira &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Paradialychone &lt;/i&gt;(Annelida: Polychaeta: Sabellidae) from Japan and adjacent waters, including four new species descriptions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1856, and related genera of the family Sabellidae (Polychaeta) are common members of softbottom communities. Four new species from Japanese waters are described herein: &lt;i&gt;Dialychone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okudai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from Hokkaido, &lt;i&gt;Paradialychone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katsuuraensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from Katsuura, Boso Peninsula; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edomae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from Tokyo Bay and &lt;i&gt;Jasmineira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kikuchii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from Ariake Sound, Kyushu. A re-description is also provided for a poorly known species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cincta&lt;/i&gt; Zachs, 1933. This species, originally described from the Peter the Great Bay, Eastern Russia was recorded in this study from Amakusa and Ariake Sound, Kyushu and transferred to &lt;i&gt;Paradialychone.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Jasmineira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kikuchii&lt;/i&gt; is the first record of the genus from Japan. The Japanese species described here are compared with other conspecifics of the world and a key for the sabellid genera with a glandular girdle on chaetiger 2 and thoracic acicular uncini is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dialychone&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paradialychone&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Jasmineira&lt;/i&gt;; feather duster worms; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eijiroh</firstname>
          <lastname>Nishi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Katsuhiko</firstname>
          <lastname>Tanaka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>Ana</middlename>
          <lastname>Tovar-Hernández</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <lastname>Giangrande</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the stone geckos (Squamata: Diplodactylidae: &lt;i&gt;Diplodactylus&lt;/i&gt;) of southern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The stone geckos of the &lt;i&gt;Diplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt; species-group are robust terrestrial geckos, mainly distributed through the southern half of Australia. Recent molecular analyses indicate that the current taxonomy significantly under-represents the true diversity in this group. Here we assess the morphological variation in the currently recognized species &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granariensis,&lt;/i&gt; including the subspecies &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;g.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rex.&lt;/i&gt; We redescribe &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granariensis,&lt;/i&gt; resurrect &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcosus&lt;/i&gt; from the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt; and describe &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calcicolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wiru&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from semiarid habitats in western and southern Australia. Other than &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;g.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rex,&lt;/i&gt; most taxa are very similar for such characters as scalation, body and tail shape and size, but colour patterns show species-specific modal conditions, and the largely allopatric distributions mean that most areas support only one or two species which can be distinguished through a combination of characters. Further genetic data is required to resolve the systematic status and geographic distribution of additional deeply divergent genetic lineages in eastern Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cryptic species; lizards; morphology; Squamata; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cryptic species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hutchinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Doughty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oliver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of inseminating characid fish from the rio Xingu basin (Characiformes: Characidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phallobrycon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adenacanthus,&lt;/i&gt; is described as a new genus and species belonging to Clade A characids of Malabarba &amp; Weitzman (2003). The new taxon is the only characid possessing two developed spines on unbranched portions of fifth, sixth and seventh anal-fin rays associated with intumescent glandular tissue on the anterior portion of the anal fin of sexually mature males. Other non-exclusive diagnostic features of the new genus (observed in male specimens) are: urogenital papilla modified into a copulatory organ, absence of pelvic-fin hooks and glandular tissue not organized into an organ. The presence of these features in members of Clade A and other characids is discussed in order to hypothesize the relationships of &lt;i&gt;Phallobrycon.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clade A; Histology; Systematics; Ostariophysi; Sexual dimorphism; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clade A; Histology; Systematics; Ostariophysi; Sexual dimorphism; Neotropical region</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Naércio</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menezes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Katiane</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <middlename>Luiz</middlename>
          <lastname>Netto-Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Synopsis of Amphipoda from two recent Ross Sea voyages with description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Epimeria &lt;/i&gt;(Epimeriidae, Amphipoda, Crustacea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two recent voyages to the Ross Sea in 2004 and 2008 collected over 3000 benthic Amphipoda. The composition of 30 amphipod families is presented, and a focus is given to the family Epimeriidae from which a new species described. &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from 1950 m depth, is the deepest occurring species of the genus known from Antarctic waters. This increases the number of known species of Epimeriidae from Antarctica to 27. &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larsi&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from similar species by the unique combination of following characters: coxa 5 posteroventral corner produced, epimeral plate posteroventral corner rounded, and coxa 1–3 apically rounded.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Antarctica; IPY; deep sea; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt;; Epimeriidae; Amphipoda; Crustacea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Antarctica</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anne-Nina</firstname>
          <lastname>Lörz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
