<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2058.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Mar. 2009</title>
    <volume>2058</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-03-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some shallow water octocorals (Coelenterata: Anthozoa) of the Persian Gulf</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A collection of octocorals from the Persian Gulf is examined, and all species are identified to at least genus level. &lt;i&gt;Sinularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erecta&lt;/i&gt; Tixier-Durivault, 1945; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressa&lt;/i&gt; Tixier-Durivault, 1945; &lt;i&gt;Subergorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suberosa&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas, 1766); &lt;i&gt;Junceella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;juncea&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas, 1766); and &lt;i&gt;Acanthogorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; Hiles, 1899, could be identified further. With some doubts &lt;i&gt;Trimuricea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reticulata&lt;/i&gt; (Thomson &amp; Simpson, 1909), &lt;i&gt;Menella&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;kanisa&lt;/i&gt; Grasshoff, 2000, and &lt;i&gt;Verrucella&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;reticulata&lt;/i&gt; (Thomson &amp; Simpson, 1909) are tentatively identified. &lt;i&gt;Subergorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perezi&lt;/i&gt; Stiasny, 1940 is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Subergorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suberosa&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas, 1766), and &lt;i&gt;Echinogorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahrelfarsi&lt;/i&gt; Stiasny, 1940 is assigned to &lt;i&gt;Menella.&lt;/i&gt; Three new species are described and depicted.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coelenterata; Cnidaria; Octocorallia; Alcyonacea; Alcyoniidae; benthos; Persian Gulf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coelenterata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>Samimi</middlename>
          <lastname>Namin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Ofwegen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of shallow water, yellow zoanthids (Hexacorallia: Zoanthidea: Epizoanthidae) from southern California, USA, and southern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In southern California and southern Australia, several species of hexacorals that are common at diving depths have been referred to as “Yellow Zoanthids.” We describe three new species of them in the genus &lt;i&gt;Epizoanthus&lt;/i&gt; because all have a macrocnemic mesenterial arrangement and mesogleal marginal sphincter muscle. &lt;i&gt;Epizoanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giveni&lt;/i&gt; is from southern California, and &lt;i&gt;Epizoanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karenae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Epizoanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodmani&lt;/i&gt; are from southern Australia. Distinguishing features of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giveni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are a sphincter muscle with alveoli arrayed in a single, longitudinal column, polyps no longer than 8 mm beyond the coenenchyme, obvious scapus ridges numbering 19 or fewer, and mesenteries numbering 36 or fewer. Distinguishing features of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karenae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are radiating dark-orange lines on the oral disc (in life), a broad sphincter muscle filling most of the margin distally and transversely stratified proximally, polyps no longer than 12 mm beyond the coenenchyme, obvious scapus ridges numbering 20 or fewer, and mesenteries numbering no more than 40. Distinguishing features of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodmani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are the lack of lines on the oral disc (in life), a sphincter muscle situated in the middle of the mesoglea with alveoli more elliptical than circular in section, polyps no longer than 8 mm beyond the coenenchyme, scapus ridges not obvious, and mesenteries numbering 48 or fewer.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Coelenterata; &lt;i&gt;Epizoanthus&lt;/i&gt;; Pacific Ocean; taxonomy; Zoantharia; Zoanthiniaria</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nicholas</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Philipp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daphne</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fautin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-61</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bindius triquetrus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. sp. nov. (Eutardigrada, Hypsibiidae) from Sicily (Italy)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species is described for which a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Bindius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is also instituted. This new genus belongs to the family Hypsibiidae. The claws are of the &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius&lt;/i&gt; type; the bucco-pharyngeal apparatus is of the &lt;i&gt;Diphascon&lt;/i&gt; model (i.e., with an anterior rigid buccal tube and a posterior, flexible pharyngeal tube), and it is a variant of the &lt;i&gt;Diphascon&lt;/i&gt; type; it is characterized by large apophyses for the insertion of the stylet muscles, asymmetrical with respect to the frontal plane for shape and dimensions; the dorsal apophysis is triangular in shape with rectilinear dorsal margin and posterior apex very distant from the buccal tube wall; the ventral apophysis is similar to the one of &lt;i&gt;Diphascon,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;i.e.,&lt;/i&gt; in the shape of a semilunar hook, but larger. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Bindius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triquetrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; has smooth cuticle; eye spots absent; elongated pharyngeal bulb with small apophyses and three long, rod-shaped macroplacoids; a small, very faint, microplacoid may be present; septulum absent; claws slender; lunules and other cuticular thickenings on the legs absent.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eutardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Bindius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triquetrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Sicily; Italy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eutardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
