<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2092.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 May. 2009</title>
    <volume>2092</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the marine and brackish-water species of &lt;i&gt;Testudinella &lt;/i&gt;(Rotifera: Monogononta, Testudinellidae), with the description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new morphospecies of the rotifer genus &lt;i&gt;Testudinella&lt;/i&gt; (Rotifera, Monogononta, Testudinellidae), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicorniculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from marine psammon collected in the Mediterranean. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicorniculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by two antero-lateral lorica projections; dorsal and ventral anterior margins undulate with shallow median sinus; foot opening sub-terminal, inverted U-shaped; distal foot pseudosegment short; fulcrum with proximal opening. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by its strongly elongate and striate lorica; dorsal anterior margin tri-lobed; ventral margin projecting, almost straight; foot opening sub-terminal, inverted U-shaped; distal foot pseudosegment long; fulcrum with proximal opening. The new species are related to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; Althaus, 1957, which is redescribed. Brief descriptions of the external morphology and trophi, as well as biogeographical information are provided for the other &lt;i&gt;Testudinella&lt;/i&gt; species reported from marine and brackish environments. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoclypeata&lt;/i&gt; Bērziņš, 1943 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elliptica&lt;/i&gt; (Ehrenberg, 1834).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rotifera; Flosculariaceae; &lt;i&gt;Testudinella&lt;/i&gt;; new species; marine; Mediterranean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rotifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Willem</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Smet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chromaspirina guanabarensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Nematoda: Desmodoridae) and a new illustrated dichotomous key to &lt;i&gt;Chromaspirina &lt;/i&gt;species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Chromaspirina&lt;/i&gt; is described from Bica Beach, a polluted beach situated at Ilha do Governador, Guanabara Bay on the coast of Rio de Janeiro (Brazil). The new species belongs to the group of species within the genus which bears a poorly developed dorsal tooth. The new species is characterized by large body size, conoid tail shape, small acute dorsal tooth, long slender spicules with sclerotised hooked &lt;i&gt;capitulum,&lt;/i&gt; and sexual dimorphism of the nonstriated part of the tail. A new illustrated dichotomous key to males of species of &lt;i&gt;Chromaspirina&lt;/i&gt; is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">marine nematodes; free-living; taxonomy; Guanabara Bay; Bica Beach; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">marine nematodes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tatiana</firstname>
          <middlename>Fabricio</middlename>
          <lastname>Maria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <middlename>Morgado</middlename>
          <lastname>Esteves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nicole</firstname>
          <lastname>Smol</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ann</firstname>
          <lastname>Vanreusel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wilfrida</firstname>
          <lastname>Decraemer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-36</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halichoeres sazimai, &lt;/i&gt;a new species of wrasse (Perciformes: Labridae) from the Western South Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halichoeres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Western South Atlantic. During many years it was misidentified as &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyphilus&lt;/i&gt; from the Northwestern Atlantic, but it can be distinguished from the latter by striking color differences between the two species, with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; being characterized by a white body with a midline, zigzag patterned stripe on body, black and brownish in terminal males and yellow or golden in females and juveniles. Preserved specimens can also be distinguished by the visible mid-body stripe in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai,&lt;/i&gt; which disappears in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyphilus.&lt;/i&gt; Diagnostic differences in the mitochondrial DNA cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene separate &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; from all other Western Atlantic labrids, with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyphilus&lt;/i&gt; being its sister species. Individuals of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; were observed living on the deeper parts (20-40 m) of rocky reefs and sand bottoms, apparently associated with water temperatures lower than 18°C. This species is currently known from the southeastern and southern coasts of Brazil, from Espírito Santo to Santa Catarina States.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Endemic Species; Brazilian Province; Rocky Reefs</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Osmar</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Luiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>E. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bomolochus bramus &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Copepoda, Poecilostomatoida, Bomolochidae) from the pomfrets (Bramidae) off Taiwan, with a list of nominal species and key to valid species of &lt;i&gt;Bomolochus &lt;/i&gt;von Nordmann, 1832</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of copepod, &lt;i&gt;Bomolochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bramus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Poecilostomatoida: Bomolochidae), is described from the gills of &lt;i&gt;Brama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Hilgendorf and &lt;i&gt;Eumegistus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illustris&lt;/i&gt; Jordan &amp; Jordan collected off the east coast of Taiwan. This is the first species of bomolochid copepod reported from the pomfrets (Bramidae). The new species is distinguished from its congeners by having a combination of the following characters: (1) a pair of rostral tines; (2) the fourth basal element on the antennule modified as a hook, about as long as its neighboring outer pilose setae; (3) two large patches of spinules on the ventral surface of the anal somite; (4) a large patch of spinules on the ventral surface of the caudal ramus; (5) armature formula of II, I, 5 on the terminal exopodal segment of legs 3 and 4; and (6) leg 4 endopod with a relatively short terminal segment ornamented with long setules along the outer margin and long spinules along the distal margin. In addition to the report of the above new species, a list of the nominal species of &lt;i&gt;Bomolochus&lt;/i&gt; von Nordmann, 1832, including their current taxonomic status, is provided. A key to the valid species is also included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; parasitic copepod; marine fish</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ju-Shey</firstname>
          <lastname>Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ching-Long</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new troglophilous species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Belisana &lt;/i&gt;Thorell, 1898 (Araneae, Pholcidae) from Guizhou Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new troglophilous, six-eyed pholcid spiders belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Belisana&lt;/i&gt; from caves in Shuicheng County, Zhijing County, Xishui County and Yanhe Tujia Autonomic County, Guizhou, China, are diagnosed, described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Belisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;douqing&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daji&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xishui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yanhe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov..&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pholcidae; new species; &lt;i&gt;Belisana&lt;/i&gt;; cave; Guizhou; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pholcidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hui-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng-Zhang</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
