<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2293.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Nov. 2009</title>
    <volume>2293</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-11-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Pacific lowland snakes of the genus &lt;i&gt;Atractus &lt;/i&gt;(Serpentes: Dipsadidae), with description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of the Pacific lowland &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; is revised on the basis of meristic, morphometric, colour pattern, and hemipenial characters. Geographical variation is reported for six &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; species (A. &lt;i&gt;boulengerii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clarki,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iridescens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melas,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicinctus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paucidens).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boulengerii&lt;/i&gt; is rediscovered and redescribed from a specimen from the Colombian coast. The first voucher specimens are reported for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melas.&lt;/i&gt; The current status of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microrhynchus&lt;/i&gt; is maintained based on the discovery of new material referrable to that species. Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; are described from the Pacific lowland of Colombia: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;echidna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;medusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typhon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Two new &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; species groups (multicinctus and &lt;i&gt;paucidens)&lt;/i&gt; are proposed based on external morphology, maxillary dentition, and hemipenial characters. A new key to Pacific lowland species of &lt;i&gt;Atractus&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">South America; rainforest; Pacific lowland; &lt;i&gt;multicinctus&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;paucidens&lt;/i&gt; group; taxonomy; hemipenis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">South America</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <lastname>Passos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonh</firstname>
          <middlename>Jairo Mueses-Cisneros</middlename>
          <lastname>Colombia)</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lynch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ronaldo</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-34</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new genera and species of chiltoniid amphipods (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Talitroidea) from freshwater mound springs in South Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Amphipods within the family Chiltoniidae are an abundant yet taxonomically poorly known member of Australian freshwater habitats. With only four species known from Australia, the group is inadequately defined and marked by taxonomists as difficult to identify. Recent molecular analyses of chiltoniids from mound springs in South Australia detected several distinct species, prompting a morphological revision of material from the central and southern Lake Eyre region. Clear groups defined by unique combinations of morphological characters (focusing on uropodal, coxal, male gnathopod 2, and antennal morphology) were found that closely correlated with clades found in the molecular analyses. &lt;i&gt;Arabunnachiltonia&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. is established for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murphyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Strangways Springs in South Australia. &lt;i&gt;Wangiannachiltonia&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. is established for &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guzikae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Davenport Springs in South Australia. The chiltoniid genera are discussed and a key is presented to the known Australian species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Talitroidea; Chiltoniidae; freshwater; springs; &lt;i&gt;Arabunnachiltonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Wangiannachiltonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Afrochiltonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Austrochiltonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phreatochiltonia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rachael</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>King</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and three new species of Drilonematidae (Rhabditida, Drilonematoidea) from earthworms</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and three new species of Drilonematidae (Rhabditidae, Drilonematoidea) from earthworms deposited in the collection of Natural History Museum, Smithsonian Institution are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Paradicelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bursata&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. n. is closely related to other Dicelinae genera, namely &lt;i&gt;Dicelis&lt;/i&gt; Dujardin, 1845 and &lt;i&gt;Adieronema&lt;/i&gt; Timm 1966, but is differentiated from both by the presence of a bursa and by whip-like copulatory sensilla. From &lt;i&gt;Dicelis&lt;/i&gt; the new genus differs further by the excretory pore being situated in front of the nerve ring. &lt;i&gt;Dicelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eudrilii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is the first African member of a predominantly Palearctic genus and also shares similarity with &lt;i&gt;Adieronema,&lt;/i&gt; but clearly differs from this genus by the eggs lacking a bipolar corona. &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eudrillii&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from other members of &lt;i&gt;Dicelis&lt;/i&gt; by having a narrow, conoid tail; prominent excretory pore; nerve ring being situated around the intestine in both adults and juveniles; very long spicules; and by a well-developed spermatheca. &lt;i&gt;Pharyngonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinense&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is distinguished from the only other member of the genus, &lt;i&gt;Ph.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mekongianum,&lt;/i&gt; by the shape of the head end with its minute apical tip; smaller circular lateral organs situated at mid-pharyngeal length; larger, slightly bent spicules with blunt, hooked distal process; and smaller, proximally broadened, club-shaped gubernacula. A specimen of &lt;i&gt;Ph.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinense&lt;/i&gt; is described with the distal portion of testis forked. Keys to the genera of subfamily Dicelinae and species of &lt;i&gt;Dicelis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Adieronema,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paradicelis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pharyngonema&lt;/i&gt; are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dicelinae; &lt;i&gt;Dicelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eudrilii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; earthworm parasites; Eudrilidae; Lumbricidae; Megascolecidae; &lt;i&gt;Paradicelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bursata&lt;/i&gt; gen. n.; sp. n.; &lt;i&gt;Pharyngonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinense&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dicelinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ivanova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Duane</middlename>
          <lastname>Hope</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Dendrodus &lt;/i&gt;Olivier, 2008, and validation of Dendrochaetidae Olivier, 2008 &lt;i&gt;nomen nudum &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Prostigmata)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pieter</firstname>
          <middlename>A. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Olivier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
