<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2233.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2233</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the taxonomy of the Normanellidae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida): description of a new genus from the Brazilian continental shelf and re-assignment of &lt;i&gt;Pseudocletodes vararensis &lt;/i&gt;Scott &amp; Scott, 1893 (&lt;i&gt;ex &lt;/i&gt;Nannopodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Normanellidae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida), &lt;i&gt;Paranaiara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inajae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the continental shelf off the northern coast of São Paulo State, Brazil. The new genus differs from the type genus &lt;i&gt;Normanella&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1880 and &lt;i&gt;Sagamiella&lt;/i&gt; Lee &amp; Huys, 1999 in its presence of lamelliform caudal rami, a maxillulary endopod represented by 2 setae, an unarmed maxillipedal syncoxa, and reduced setation on P2 enp-2 (without outer spine) and P3 enp-2 (with only 2 inner setae). All these apomorphic character states are shared with the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocletodes&lt;/i&gt; Scott &amp; Scott, 1893, formerly placed in the family Nannopodidae (ex Huntemanniidae) and here assigned to the Normanellidae. &lt;i&gt;Pseudocletodes&lt;/i&gt; can be differentiated from &lt;i&gt;Paranaiara&lt;/i&gt; by the loss of the P1 endopod and of the inner seta on P2–P4 enp-1, the presence of only 2 inner setae on P2 enp-2 (instead of 3) and only 1 inner seta on P4 exp-3 (instead of 2), the presence of a second inner seta on P4 enp-2 (instead of 1), the morphology of the fifth pair of legs which are not medially fused and have only 3 endopodal elements (instead of 4) in the male, and the well developed caudal ramus seta V (instead of rudimentary). It is postulated that prehensility of the P1 endopod was secondarily lost in the common ancestor of &lt;i&gt;Paranaiara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudocletodes.&lt;/i&gt; An updated family diagnosis of the Normanellidae and a dichotomous identification key to the 22 currently valid species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; meiofauna; systematics; identification key; São Paulo State; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terue</firstname>
          <middlename>Cristina</middlename>
          <lastname>Kihara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rony</firstname>
          <lastname>Huys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus &lt;/i&gt;Simon from southern California and a redescription of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus phylax &lt;/i&gt;Ivie &amp; Barrows, its probable sister species (Araneae: Linyphiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1884 from southern California is described, &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artemisiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Its probable sister species, &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phylax&lt;/i&gt; Ivie &amp; Barrows, 1935, a potential adventive species with which it now often co-occurs in southern California, is redescribed for the first time. We provide detailed descriptions of both species because an adequate definition of the genus is lacking and the conformation of the male &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; palpal bulb has been only superficially treated. We also provide a definition of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; based on examination of specimens of the type species, &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fissiceps&lt;/i&gt; (O. P.-Cambridge). Problems associated with both the conformation of the male bulb and the paracymbium morphology are discussed. Despite the lack of a phylogenetic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus,&lt;/i&gt; we propose that &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phylax&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artemisiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are sister species based on shared characters that distinguish them from all other congeners. We suggest that the presence of &lt;i&gt;Ceraticelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phylax&lt;/i&gt; in California is the result of incidental introduction rather than natural dispersal. Habitat, distribution, and phenology data are presented in the text. Illustrations and a distribution map are also furnished for both species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">coastal sage scrub; sympatric species; oak woodlands; California spiders; &lt;i&gt;Idionella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ceratinella&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">coastal sage scrub</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prentice</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Redak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-56</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new subspecies of &lt;i&gt;Batagur affinis &lt;/i&gt;(Cantor, 1847), one of the worlds most critically endangered chelonians (Testudines: Geoemydidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Estuarine &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; are among the most critically endangered chelonian species. We assess the taxonomic status of the recently discovered Cambodian relic population of &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; by phylogenetic analyses of three mitochondrial (2096 bp) and three nuclear DNA fragments (1909 bp) using sequences from all other &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; species and selected allied geoemydids. Furthermore, we calculated haplotype networks of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene for Cambodian terrapins, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baska,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kachuga&lt;/i&gt; and compare external morphology of estuarine &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; populations. Genetically, Cambodian &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; are closely related with, but distinct from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; from Sumatra and the west coast of the Malay Peninsula. Morphologically, Cambodian &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; resemble the distinctive &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; populations from the eastern Malay Peninsula that were not available for genetic study. We suggest that the &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; populations from the eastern Malay Peninsula and Cambodia represent a new subspecies of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; that once was distributed in estuaries surrounding the Gulf of Thailand (Batagur &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardmolli&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov.). Its patchy extant distribution is most probably the result of large-scale habitat alteration and century-long overexploitation. In addition, our phylogenetic analyses suggest repeated switches between riverine and estuarine habitats during the evolution of the extant &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Southeast Asia; South Asia; &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardmolli&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baska&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Batagur&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kachuga&lt;/i&gt;; endangered species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Southeast Asia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Praschag</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rohan</firstname>
          <lastname>Holloway</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Georges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Päckert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hundsdörfer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Uwe</firstname>
          <lastname>Fritz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-16</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
