<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2164.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jul. 2009</title>
    <volume>2164</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Survey of the endohelminth parasites of freshwater fishes in the upper Mezquital River Basin, Durango State, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As a part of an ongoing inventory of the helminth parasites of freshwater fishes in Mexico, 676 specimens were collected between November 2007 and December 2008 in 23 localities along the upper Mezquital River Basin in Durango State, northern Mexico. Sixteen species of hosts, mostly corresponding to Nearctic freshwater elements, were studied. A total of 1,230 individual worms were collected during this survey, representing 25 species of endohelminths of which 9 were digeneans, 3 were cestodes, 4 were acanthocephalans, and 9 were nematodes. The checklist contains 24 new hosts and 42 new locality records. The information provided in this checklist may be helpful for our understanding of the biodiversity and historical biogeography of this host-parasite system, since the Mezquital River Basin mostly contains a Nearctic freshwater fish fauna, with a few Neotropical and endemic elements and may represent a transitional area from a biogeographical point of view.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Helminths; freshwater fishes; survey; upper Mezquital River Basin; Durango; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Helminths; freshwater fishes; survey; upper Mezquital River Basin; Durango; Mexico</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>Pérez-Ponce</middlename>
          <lastname>De León</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Rosas-Valdez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mendoza-Garfias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Aguilaraguilar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Falcón-Ordaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Garrido-Olvera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pérez-Rodríguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new marine clupeoid fish from the Lower Cretaceous of the Sergipe-Alagoas Basin, northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Clupeomorph fishes are largely diversified and widespread in Cretaceous strata of northeastern Brazil. They are represented by basal clupeiforms, †ellimmichthyiforms, and advanced clupeoids. In this paper, a new clupeoid fish, †Nolfia &lt;i&gt;riachuelensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a specimen found in marine shale yielded in the Taquari Member (Albian) of Riachuelo Formation, Sergipe-Alagoas Basin. Although partially preserved (most of skull is lacking), the fish shows many informative characters, particularly in the axial skeleton. The fish is morphologically very similar to †Nolfia &lt;i&gt;kwangoensis,&lt;/i&gt; a clupeoid fish originally described from marine deposit from the Upper Cretaceous (Cenomanian) of Kipala, Democratic Republic of Congo, with which it shares: 18 caudal vertebrae; long and cylindrical pleural ribs; posteriormost pleural ribs supported by long parapophyses and gradually decreasing in size posteriorly; very reduced ural centra; presence of long and distally congruent neural spines of third, second, and first preural centra; three uroneural bones (the first probably forming the pleurostyle). Otherwise, †Nolfia &lt;i&gt;riachuelensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other clupeomorphs by a unique combination of features. The number of supraneural bones, aligned rod-like postcleithra, less than 30 rays in the anal fin, and derived absence of dorsal scutes indicate its placement within Clupeidae. As far as is known, †Nolfia &lt;i&gt;riachuelensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the most ancient clupeoid fish known from the fossil record.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">†Nolfia &lt;i&gt;riachuelensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Clupeoidei; Lower Cretaceous; northeastern Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">†Nolfia &lt;i&gt;riachuelensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Clupeoidei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Figueiredo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-32</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Devario xyrops&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of danionine fish from south-western Myanmar (Teleostei: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Devario&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xyrops&lt;/i&gt; is described from small rivers on the western slope of the Rakhine Yoma in south-western Myanmar. It is distinguished from all other species in the genus except &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anomalus&lt;/i&gt; by its colour pattern including a dark blotch or condensed series of vertical bars anteriorly on the side, separate from a posterior dark horizontal band; and distinguished from &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anomalus&lt;/i&gt; in particular by deeper body (29.9–35.8% SL, vs. 25.0–26.8 % SL) and fewer lateral line scales (31–33, modally 32 vs. 33–35, modally 34).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rakhine Yoma; Thandwe; Bangladesh; colour pattern; endemism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rakhine Yoma</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fang</firstname>
          <lastname>Fang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kullander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Danio aesculapii&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of danio from south-western Myanmar (Teleostei: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Danio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aesculapii,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from small rivers on the western slope of the Rakhine Yoma in south-western Myanmar. It is superficially similar to &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choprae&lt;/i&gt; from northern Myanmar in having a series of vertical bars anteriorly on the side, but differs from it and other species of &lt;i&gt;Danio&lt;/i&gt; in having six instead of seven or more branched dorsal-fin rays, and from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Danio&lt;/i&gt; except &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythromicron&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kerri&lt;/i&gt; in having 12 instead of 10 or 14 circumpeduncular scale rows.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rakhine Yoma; Thandwe; &lt;i&gt;Danio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choprae&lt;/i&gt;; endemism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rakhine Yoma</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kullander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fang</firstname>
          <lastname>Fang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new ground-dwelling species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis &lt;/i&gt;Strauch (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the northern Western Ghats, Maharashtra, India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of gecko of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; is described from the forests of the Western Ghats region of Maharashtra. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolhapurensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is diagnosable by the following combination of characters: dorsal scales homogenous, small and feebly keeled; no spine-like tubercles on flanks, ventrals smooth, imbricate, 20–23 scale rows across venter, between lowest rows of dorsal scales. Supralabial I narrowly contacting nasal. Paired postmentals separated by one or two enlarged gular scales. A continuous series of 24–28 precloacal-femoral pores. The continuous series of precloacal and femoral pores exhibited by this species is unique among Indian members of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; Maharashtra; description; northern Western Ghats; India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Varad</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kshamata</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gaikwad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hongkongia &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae: Gnaphosidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The spider genus &lt;i&gt;Hongkongia&lt;/i&gt; Song &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Zhu, 1998, belonging to the &lt;i&gt;Echemus&lt;/i&gt; group, is reviewed. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Hongkongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;songi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described, and the type species, &lt;i&gt;Hongkongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuae&lt;/i&gt; Song &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Zhu, 1998 is redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Gnaphosidae; &lt;i&gt;Hongkongia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Taiwan; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I-Min</firstname>
          <lastname>Tso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
