<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2300.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2009</title>
    <volume>2300</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Archaeococcoid scale insects (Hemiptera: Coccoidea) from the tropical high mountains of the Andean Cordillera, South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diversity of the archaeococcoid scale insect fauna in the Cordillera of the Andes, particularly the páramos, was studied in Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, and Venezuela. The páramos is an ecosystem in the tropical high mountains, where the temperature alternates between freezing at night and thawing during the day. Within this habitat, two new genera and several new species and new country records were discovered and are described and illustrated below. Thus, at 4200 m in the Cordillera de Mérida, Venezuela, a new monophlebid genus, &lt;i&gt;Corandesia&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; is erected for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kozári&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Monophlebidae) based on the adult female. The genus &lt;i&gt;Paramoandesia&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; (Monophlebidae) is erected for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colombiensis&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from 4200 m in Colombia, based on the adult female and male and for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadorensis&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from 4100 m in Ecuador, based on the adult females. These three new species were found on &lt;i&gt;Espeletia&lt;/i&gt; spp. (Asteraceae) in the páramos and, although living in the typically harsh environmental conditions of this habitat, do not appear to have developed special protective structures, although they have probably developed physiological adaptations and appear to exploit the protection afforded by the microhabitat at the base of large, dense leaves of their host plant. In addition, at 2000 m near Mérida, another monophlebid, &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abrahami&lt;/i&gt; (Newstead) was collected, previously only known from Guyana, and redescribed here based on the adult female and first-instar nymph. The adult and preadult females of &lt;i&gt;Mimosicerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;williamsi&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Coelostomidiidae) from 2500 m in Venezuela are described and illustrated. In addition, &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rauppi&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Callipappidae), a hypogeal species found on the roots of alfalfa in the mountains around Cusco, Peru, is described based on the adult female. This is the first record of a member of the Callipapidae from South America, as &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; Morrison was previously believed to be restricted to Australia and to New Zealand. A taxonomic key to genera based on the adult females of Coelostomidiidae in the Neotropics is provided and, also keys to the adult females of species of &lt;i&gt;Mimosicerya&lt;/i&gt; Cockerell (Coelostomidiidae), &lt;i&gt;Paramoandesia&lt;/i&gt; (Monophlebidae) and to &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; (Callipappidae).Les Archaeococcoides de la Cordillère des Andes de Colombie, de l’Equateur, du Pérou et du Venezuela sont analysés. Dans les páramos étudiés, un écosystème de haute montagne où les températures nuit-jour alternent entre congélation et décongélation, deux nouveau genres et plusieurs espèces nouvelles ont été découverts. Ainsi, dans les páramos de la Cordillère de Mérida, Venezuela, 4200 m, &lt;i&gt;Corandesia&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; est créé pour l’espèce &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kozári&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; fondée sur l’adulte femelle. (Monophlebidae). &lt;i&gt;Paramoandesia&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; est créé pour les espèces &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colombiensis&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; de Colombie, 4200 m, description fondée sur les adultes femelle et mâle et &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadorensis&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; de l’Equateur, 4100 m, (Monophlebidae). Les espèces des páramos furent toutes collectées sur &lt;i&gt;Espeletia&lt;/i&gt; spp. (Asteraceae) et, bien que vivant dans des conditions d’environnement extrêmes, elles n’ont cependant pas de structure de protection, mais ont développé probablement une adaptation physiologique, exploitent de plus l’effet protecteur du microclimat offert par les bases des larges feuilles de leurs plantes-hôtes. A une altitude inférieure près de Mérida au Venezuela, vers 2000 m, &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abrahami&lt;/i&gt; (Newstead) autre Monophlebidae, a été collectée, alors qu’elle n’était connue que de Guyana est redécrite fondée sur l’adulte femelle et de la première stade larvaire. Adulte et préadulte femelle de &lt;i&gt;Mimosicerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;williamsi&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Coelostomididae) du Venezuela, 2500 m, sont décrites et illustrées. Au Pérou, &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rauppi&lt;/i&gt; Foldi &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Callipappidae), espèce hypogée trouvée sur les racines de &lt;i&gt;Medicago&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sativa,&lt;/i&gt; sur les montagnes environnantes de Cusco, décrite fondée sur l’adulte femelle. Il s’agit de la première découverte d’un membre de la famille des Callipappidae en Amérique du Sud, le genre &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; Morrison étant jusqu’à présent considéré comme restreint à l’Australie et à la Nouvelle-Zélande. Une clef taxonomique fondée sur les adultes femelles est proposée pour les genres néotropicaux de Coelostomidiidae, ainsi que pour les espèces des genres &lt;i&gt;Mimosicerya&lt;/i&gt; Cockerell (Coelostomidiidae), &lt;i&gt;Paramoandesia&lt;/i&gt; (Monophlebidae), et &lt;i&gt;Platycoelostoma&lt;/i&gt; Morrison (Callipappidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Imre</firstname>
          <lastname>Foldi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Neotropical species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parochlus &lt;/i&gt;Enderlein, 1912 (Chironomidae: Podonominae) and new distribution in Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Adults and immatures of &lt;i&gt;Parochlus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carolinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described and figured. The specimens were collected from a stream and a river in the pampasic hills system in the centre-northern part of the San Luis Province, Argentina. The adult male is distinct in having hairy eyes. The pupa differs from other known species of the genus by the structure of the thoracic horn and the arrangement of setae on the anal spurs. The distribution of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parochlus&lt;/i&gt; Enderlein is widened from an austral Andean &lt;i&gt;Parochlus&lt;/i&gt; proper zone to a subtropical zone with Brazilian fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chironomidae; &lt;i&gt;Parochlus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; semiarid stream; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mariana</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodríguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Analía</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Paggi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <lastname>Medina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hoplosaenidea &lt;/i&gt;Laboissiere, 1933 from Malaysia (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Galerucinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohamed</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mohamedsaid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-50</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular phylogeny in 'nano-weevils': description of a new subgenus &lt;i&gt;Nanoacalles &lt;/i&gt;and two new species of &lt;i&gt;Calacalles &lt;/i&gt;from the Macaronesian Islands (Curculionidae: Cryptorhynchinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A molecular phylogeny for the eastern Atlantic weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; Peyerimhoff, 1925 is presented, using two mitochondrial genes (CO1 and 16S). Based on a phylogenetic (Bayesian) analysis, we propose the following taxonomic amendments: the new subgenus &lt;i&gt;Nanoacalles&lt;/i&gt; subg. n. is described and two new species, &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hermigua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nataliae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Canarian island La Gomera and distinguished from other species of the genus. &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmensis&lt;/i&gt; (Roudier, 1954) (formerly &lt;i&gt;Acalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wollastoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmensis&lt;/i&gt; Roudier, 1954), which is illustrated here for the first time (habitus and aedeagus), is not a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Acalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seticollis&lt;/i&gt; Wollaston, 1864, but a valid taxon. &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcarinatus&lt;/i&gt; (Israelson, 1984) from the Azores is assigned to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Crateracalles&lt;/i&gt; Stüben 2004. We also present a catalogue of all known &lt;i&gt;Calacalles&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; catalogue; new species; new subgenus; endemic species; Bayesian analysis; 16S; COI; Canary Islands; Azores; Madeira; western Palaearctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonas</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Astrin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stüben</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">ErratumMews, C. M., Mól, A. P. &amp; Sperber C. F. (2009) Crickets with phallic glands: two new genera and one new species of Brazilian Luzarinae (Grylloidea: Phalangopsidae). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2292, 3448.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
