<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2000.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2000</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the hyperiidean amphipod superfamily Lanceoloidea Bowman &amp; Gruner, 1973 (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Hyperiidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of the superfamily Lanceoloidea is presented, based predominantly on collections held by the Zoological Museum, University of Copenhagen, Denmark. Prior to this review the superfamily consisted of three families, Lanceolidae with five genera, Chuneolidae with one genus and Microphasmidae with three genera. The family Lanceolidae is here restricted to two genera, &lt;i&gt;Lanceola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Scypholanceola.&lt;/i&gt; The other three genera previously included in this family, &lt;i&gt;Prolanceola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Metalanceola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola&lt;/i&gt; all have characters that differ significantly from &lt;i&gt;Lanceola&lt;/i&gt; (and &lt;i&gt;Scypholanceola)&lt;/i&gt; as well as from each other; characters which are considered important enough to warrant their removal from the family. Thus, three new families are proposed to accommodate them; Prolanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Prolanceola,&lt;/i&gt; Metalanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Metalanceola&lt;/i&gt; and Megalanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Megalanceoloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed for &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;remipes&lt;/i&gt; (Barnard, 1932) because it posses characters that differ significantly from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephenseni&lt;/i&gt; (Chevreux, 1920), the type species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lanceola&lt;/i&gt; is the most speciose genus with fourteen species recognized in this review, including two new species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gruneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Tasman Sea and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galatheae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the tropical north-eastern Indian Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Scypholanceola&lt;/i&gt; consists of two species and &lt;i&gt;Prolanceola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Metalanceola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Megalanceoloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are currently all monospecific. The family Chuneolidae remains unchanged, with one genus and three species. The family Microphasmidae is here restricted to two genera, &lt;i&gt;Microphasma&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Microphasmoides;&lt;/i&gt; both are monospecific. The genus &lt;i&gt;Mimonecteola&lt;/i&gt; is removed from Microphasmidae and placed in a new family, Mimonecteolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; because it posses several significant characters that set it apart from &lt;i&gt;Microphasma&lt;/i&gt; (and &lt;i&gt;Microphasmoides).&lt;/i&gt; Six species of &lt;i&gt;Mimonecteola&lt;/i&gt; are recognized in this review, including &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macronyx&lt;/i&gt; Barnard, 1932 which is considered a valid species based on an examination of the type, and additional material from the &lt;i&gt;Dana&lt;/i&gt; collections, and one new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carlsbergi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Atlantic and Indian Ocean off South Africa. Keys are provided for families, genera and species and all species are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Hyperiidea; Lanceoloidea; Lanceolidae; Chuneolidae; Microphasmidae; Prolanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Metalanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Megalanceolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Mimonecteolidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lanceola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Scypholanceola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Prolanceola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metalanceola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Megalanceola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Megalanceoloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chuneola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Microphasma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Microphasmoides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mimonecteola&lt;/i&gt;; review; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zeidler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-117</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-04</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
