<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2009.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2009</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristosia &lt;/i&gt;Motschulsky, 1865 from the Nepal Himalaya: Taxonomy and Biogeography (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Sphodrini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pristosia&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, 1865 was so far only known to be highly diverse in the North-Western Himalaya and present in the Eastern Himalaya. Only a single female specimen has been documented in the literature from the Nepal Himalaya and was described as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahud&lt;/i&gt; Morvan, 1994. During a study of comprehensive carabid beetle material collected throughout Nepal, which has been deposited at several museums and private collections, a large number of &lt;i&gt;Pristosia&lt;/i&gt; specimens from six species have been identified. The only fully winged species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenata&lt;/i&gt; (Putzeys, 1873), which is widely distributed in South East Asia, was found near Dailekh and is herewith reported for the Nepalese fauna for the first time. The Eastern Himalayan species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaroides&lt;/i&gt; (Putzeys, 1877) is reported for the first time in Nepal as well and occurs in Eastern Nepal at several localities east of the Arun river. At least four species occur in the Western and Far Western Nepal Himalaya, of which three are described as new to science: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glabella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepalensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Api Himal, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Saipal Himal. An presumably additional new species is known from the north-western slope of the Dhaulagiri Himal, but is represented by a single immature female specimen only, which does not allow for a sufficient species diagnosis. The male external and genital characters of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahud&lt;/i&gt; Morvan, 1994 are now described for the first time. This species is considered to be polytypic and the geographic subspecies &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahud&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;ssp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the south slope of the Kanjiroba Himal. The species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atrema&lt;/i&gt; (Andrewes, 1926) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;championi&lt;/i&gt; (Andrewes, 1934), which occur in the Kumaon Himalaya close to the Nepalese border, are redescribed based on the examination of the type material. Diagnostic features, especially for the male genitalia of all taxa mentioned above, are figured and a key to the species from Nepal is presented. Instead of a phylogenetic analysis, which is needed for &lt;i&gt;Pristosia&lt;/i&gt; but not achievable at present, preliminary species groups for species dealt with are proposed: The Eastern Himalayan &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaroides&lt;/i&gt; species group (monotypic), the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atrema&lt;/i&gt; species group with six species from the Kumaon and Western Nepal Himalaya, the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;championi&lt;/i&gt; species group with two species from the Kumaon and Western Nepal Himalaya, and the South East Asian &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenata&lt;/i&gt; species group (monotypic). Based on the distributional and ecological data presented in this study, species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pristosia&lt;/i&gt; with reduced hind wings seem to be absent from the entire Central Nepal Himalaya, and the only Eastern Nepalese species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaroides,&lt;/i&gt; prefers largely different habitat conditions compared to the species from Western Nepal. Based on biogeographical hypotheses of other Himalayan carabid beetle genera presented in previous studies by the senior author, the observed species groups of &lt;i&gt;Pristosia&lt;/i&gt; are considered to be further examples for Tertiary Tibetan faunal components of the Himalaya. Following a diversification of the genus within the Tertiary of Southern Tibet, speciation occurred and these species groups originated from founder populations that moved into the Nepal Himalaya. The colonization of the geologically younger High Himalaya has taken place independently for each of the terminal groups via different dispersal routes and during different periods of mountain uplift.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Species groups; new species; redescription; India; Tertiary Tibetan faunal component</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Species groups</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joachim</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmidt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Matthias</firstname>
          <lastname>Hartmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A colorful new species of the digger wasp genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudoplisus &lt;/i&gt;Ashmead from the Southwestern United States (Hymenoptera: Apoidea, Crabronidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of apoid wasps, &lt;i&gt;Pseudoplisus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;willcoxi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Arizona, New Mexico, and Colorado. It is compared with all other species currently assigned to the genus. It has a remarkable overall color pattern, unique in &lt;i&gt;Pseudoplisus,&lt;/i&gt; and a restricted collecting record: only a single specimen was collected outside of the Willcox area in Arizona (defined here as including the Animas area, New Mexico). Additionally, of the 34 remaining specimens, one was collected in 1974 and all other after 2001. In the present paper, the new species is diagnosed, described, and the relevant characters are illustrated. The geographic distribution and its heterogeneous collecting record are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudoplisus&lt;/i&gt;; Apoidea; Crabronidae; Bembicinae; Gorytina; digger wasp; sand wasp; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudoplisus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohl</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-34</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new cave &lt;i&gt;Sinella &lt;/i&gt;species from South China (Collembola: Entomobryidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whitteni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a new cave species from South China is described. It is characterized by inner differentiated tibiotarsal chaetae ciliated, 2 inner small basal ungual teeth, serrate outer edge of the unguiculus, short smooth distal part of dens, presence of m1i and p4 on Th. II and 5 + 5 macrochaetae on central Abd. IV. The complete s-chaetotaxy is reported in the genus &lt;i&gt;Sinella&lt;/i&gt; for the first time. It is most close to another cave species &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trogla&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Christiansen, 1993, from which it differs in short mucronal spine, presence of m1i, m2i2, p4 and absence of m4i on Th. II, absence of unpaired tooth on unguis, and absence of large finely ciliated chaetae on manubrium.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Sinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whitteni&lt;/i&gt;; chaetotaxy; Guangxi; troglobites</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <lastname>Deharveng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus &lt;/i&gt;Loew from China (Diptera: Lauxaniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Chinese fauna of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; Loew (Diptera: Lauxaniidae) is revised, including the five new species &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acuticurvus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heteropterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longinudus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and the two previously described species &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apicalis&lt;/i&gt; (Hendel) and &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavoscutellatus&lt;/i&gt; de Meijere. Extralimital records are also given for &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavoscutellatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heteropterus,&lt;/i&gt; including paratypes of the latter species from Thailand. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; from China is presented, and a list of all described species of &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt; is provided, with information on type locality, primary type specimen(s) and depository, synonymy, and distribution.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Lauxaniidae; &lt;i&gt;Cestrotus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China; Thailand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shi</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ding</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gaimari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
