<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2022.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2022</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships within the Pylochelidae (Decapoda: Anomura: Paguroidea): A cladistic analysis based on morphological characters </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships within the “symmetrical” hermit crab family Pylochelidae were analyzed for 41 of the 45 species and subspecies currently considered valid. In the analyses, 78 morphological characters comprised the data matrix and the outgroup consisted of &lt;i&gt;Thalassina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anomala,&lt;/i&gt; a member of the Thalassinidae, and &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrispina,&lt;/i&gt; a member of the Galatheidae. A poorly resolved strict consensus tree was obtained from a heuristic parsimony analysis of unweighted and unordered characters, which showed the family Pylochelidae and the subfamilies Pylochelinae and Pomatochelinae to be monophyletic taxa – the latter two groups had the highest Bremer support values. Additionally, while the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pylocheles&lt;/i&gt; (Pylocheles) was strongly supported, the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Xylocheles,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Bathycheles&lt;/i&gt; were not. More fully resolved trees were obtained when using implied weighting, which recognized the monotypic subfamilies Parapylochelinae, Cancellochelinae and Mixtopagurinae. The subfamily Trizochelinae was found to have four distinct clades and several ambiguously placed taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Anomura; Paguroidea; Pylochelidae; phylogenetic relationships</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <lastname>Lemaitre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patsy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclaughlin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulf</firstname>
          <lastname>Sorhannus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cantellius &lt;/i&gt;and a redescription of &lt;i&gt;C. sextus &lt;/i&gt;(Hiro, 1938) (Cirripedia, Balanomorpha Pyrgomatidae) from the elephant skin coral, &lt;i&gt;Pachyseris speciosa &lt;/i&gt;(Dana, 1846) (Scleractinia, Agariciidae) from Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt; from Taiwan were identified from the elephant skin coral, &lt;i&gt;Pachyseris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speciosa&lt;/i&gt; Dana, 1846. &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sextus&lt;/i&gt; was found on the underside of the coral plate and a new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; on the upper surface. The microdistribution indicates the different requirements of the two species. In the present study, both arthropodal and opercular plate characters of these two species were investigated using SEM techniques. Morphologically, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; is close to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus.&lt;/i&gt; However, the tergal scutal margins of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus&lt;/i&gt; are curved, whilst those of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; are straight, and its spur is narrower than that of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus.&lt;/i&gt; The apex of the scutum and tergum of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; forms a honeycomb-like surface, most probably the ‘imprint’ of the chitinous primordial valves. The separation of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus&lt;/i&gt; is also supported by molecular analyses of three mitochondrial gene sequences (COI, 16S, and 12S rRNA). &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sextus&lt;/i&gt; by &gt;5% in all three mitochondrial genes (COI, 16S, and 12S rRNA) sequenced. The values of sequence divergence in 12S are comparable to the inter-specific divergence reported for other &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Savignium&lt;/i&gt; species. Interestingly, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoegi&lt;/i&gt; is not the sister group of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus,&lt;/i&gt; a morphologically similar species, in the present study. Further studies should focus on molecular phylogenetic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coral barnacles; &lt;i&gt;Cantellius&lt;/i&gt;; corals; &lt;i&gt;Pachyseris&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coral barnacles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yair</firstname>
          <lastname>Achituv</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ling</firstname>
          <middlename>Ming</middlename>
          <lastname>Tsang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Benny</firstname>
          <middlename>Kwok Kan</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and two new genera of pinnotherid crabs from the northeastern Pacific Ocean, with a reappraisal of the subfamily Pinnotherinae de Haan, 1833 (Crustacea: Brachyura: Pinnotheridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two monotypic genera, &lt;i&gt;Enigmatheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Bonita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus,&lt;/b&gt; are described to receive &lt;i&gt;Fabia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canfieldi&lt;/i&gt; Rathbun, 1918, and &lt;i&gt;Bonita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mexicana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; respectively. &lt;i&gt;Enigmatheres&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from other Pinnotheridae by the third maxilliped having a gently curved outer margin, with a carpus that is larger than the conical propodus and a dactylus that is inserted on the middle third of the ventral margin of the propodus, walking legs 2 that are asymmetrical in length and the dactyli of walking legs 1, 3 and 4 that are short, slender, conical, slightly curved up to hooked and hard tip. &lt;i&gt;Bonita&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from other Pinnotheridae by the presence of two sulci on the carapace, protruding anterolateral margins of the carapace, walking leg 3 asymmetrical in length and larger than other walking legs, and walking leg 4 with a clavate propodus. These two new genera and 25 additional ones (nine with hesitation), including &lt;i&gt;Pinnotheres&lt;/i&gt; Bosc, 1802 (type genus of Pinnotherinae de Haan, 1833), share a carapace that is soft and thin, walking legs 1-4 that are slender and feeble, antennae with a protuberance on the basal segment and the known zoea larvae being very similar, particularly with an abdomen that widens from somite 1 to 5 and a telson that is laterally convex and posteriorly trilobed. These adult and larval shared features support the monophyly of these genera and clearly diagnose the subfamily Pinnotherinae de Haan, 1833 &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Pinnotheridae; Pinnotherinae; &lt;i&gt;Enigmatheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bonita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mexicana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; Baja California; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ernesto</firstname>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-44</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus &lt;/i&gt;(Eutardigrada, Macrobiotidae) from the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, Tennessee/North Carolina, USA (North America): two new species and six new records</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As part of the All Taxa Biodiversity Inventory (http://www.dlia.org), we are conducting a large-scale multihabitat inventory of tardigrades in the Great Smoky Mountains National Park (GSMNP) in Tennessee and North Carolina, USA. Here we report our findings for the genus &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; (Eutardigrada, Macrobiotidae). Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from moss, lichen, soil and leaf litter samples. &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all other species of the &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hufelandi&lt;/i&gt; group by having a very simple buccal armature without bands of teeth, very large elliptical cuticular pores, unique characteristics of the egg, and other morphometric characters. &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other species in the &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richtersi&lt;/i&gt; group by having very small cuticular tubercles, well-developed macroplacoids, unique characteristics of the egg, and other morphometric characters. Seven additional &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; species have been identified in the GSMNP: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmsworthi&lt;/i&gt; Murray, 1907, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hufelandi&lt;/i&gt; Schultze, 1834, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; Richters, 1904, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; Murray, 1910, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallarii&lt;/i&gt; Maucci, 1954, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;recens&lt;/i&gt; Cuénot, 1932, and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonollii&lt;/i&gt; Ramazzotti, 1956. All of these except &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmsworthi&lt;/i&gt; are new records for the national park. In addition, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallarii&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for North Carolina, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for North Carolina and Tennessee, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for the eastern USA, and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;recens&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for the USA.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hufelandi&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richtersi&lt;/i&gt; group; new species; new records; Tennessee; North Carolina; USA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bartels</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diane</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nelson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barbulifer enigmaticus&lt;/i&gt;, a new seven-spined goby (Pisces: Teleostei: Gobiidae) from the southwestern Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Barbulifer&lt;/i&gt; species is described from 26 specimens. &lt;i&gt;Barbulifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enigmaticus&lt;/i&gt; differs from its congeners by the following combination of characters: body completely lacks scales, including modified basicaudal scales. Cephalic pore pattern generally B'FH' + M'O' in juveniles and B'FH' + M'NO' in adults. No median barbel on snout. A single short barbel on each side of head, flattened, flexible, and located between the eye and the upper jaw, directly below the anterior nostril. A single median pair of short barbels on chin. D1 VII, D2 13(12–13), A 11(10–11), P 19(18–20). To 24 mm SL (29 mm TL). The species is found in very shallow reef areas from Espírito Santo to São Paulo, southeastern Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gobiosoma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barbulifer&lt;/i&gt;; Gobiosomatini; Brazil; rockpools; new species; intertidal; reef</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gobiosoma&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Christophe</firstname>
          <lastname>Joyeux</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Tassell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Raphael</firstname>
          <middlename>Mariano</middlename>
          <lastname>Macieira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
