<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2045.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Mar. 2009</title>
    <volume>2045</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclatural availability of nomina of new species should always require the deposition of preserved specimens in collections: a rebuttal to Donegan (2008)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recently, a paper (Dubois &amp; Nemésio 2007) expressed general views regarding the deposition of vouchers in public collections to serve as onomatophores (name-bearing type specimens), and it was suggested that deposition should be made explicitly compulsory in the &lt;i&gt;Code,&lt;/i&gt; to avoid the growing number of descriptions that skip this process opportunistically based on some apparent ambiguities of the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; Donegan (2008) made several criticisms to that paper, defending a “liberal approach” of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; concerning the nature of type specimens. Here I present my rebuttal to Donegan (2008), showing point by point that his criticisms are the sum of misunderstandings of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; and of the ideas presented in Dubois &amp; Nemésio (2007), allied to some biased and very subjective personal interpretations. The arguments used to allow description without the deposition of voucher(s) are once more demonstrated to be based on articles of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; that do not serve to this end and the suggestions of amendment of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; presented by Dubois &amp; Nemésio (2007) are shown to adequately accommodate the concerns of conservationists regarding descriptions of species found on the brink of extinction.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">scientific collecting; taxonomy; voucher deposition; zoological nomenclature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">scientific collecting</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <lastname>Nemésio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Partial revision of freshwater shrimps from Central Sulawesi, Indonesia, with descriptions of two new species (Crustacea: Decapoda: Atyidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of freshwater shrimps of the family Atyidae from the Malili lake system, Central Sulawesi, is partially revised based on museum materials and fresh collections. &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lanceolata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;masapi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loehae&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed and neotypes are designated as all type materials for these species are no longer extant. Two new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;woltereckae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahalona,&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated in details.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Atyidae; &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;; freshwater shrimps; new species; taxonomy; Sulawesi</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yixiong</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daisy</firstname>
          <lastname>Wowor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Satish</firstname>
          <lastname>Choy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-32</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on distribution, variation and characterization of &lt;i&gt;Erythrolamprus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocorallus &lt;/i&gt;Roze, 1959 (Serpentes: Colubridae) with the first records from Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Maracaibo false coral snake &lt;i&gt;Erythrolamprus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocorallus,&lt;/i&gt; previously known only from Venezuela, is recorded from five departments in Colombia. These new data include the westernmost and the southernmost records presently known for the species. Two specimens previously identified as &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aesculapii,&lt;/i&gt; from the localities of El Valle, Distrito Federal, Venezuela, and Yarumal, Antioquia, Colombia, are now attributed to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocorallus,&lt;/i&gt; the first one representing the northeasternmost record of the species. Morphological characterization of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocorallus&lt;/i&gt; is expanded based on the new specimens.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Maracaibo false coral snake; new records; range extension; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Maracaibo false coral snake</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Felipe</firstname>
          <middlename>Franco</middlename>
          <lastname>Curcio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Santiago</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sánchez-Pacheco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonh</firstname>
          <middlename>Jairo</middlename>
          <lastname>Mueses-Cisneros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>Trefaut</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-42</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic characterization of the &lt;i&gt;Aphyosemion calliurum &lt;/i&gt;species group and description of a new species from this assemblage: &lt;i&gt;A. campomaanense&lt;/i&gt; (Cyprinodontiformes: Aplocheiloidei: Nothobranchiidae) from Southern Cameroon</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Aphyosemion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calliurum&lt;/i&gt; species group is poorly diagnosed by chromatic and meristic characteristics leading various authors to propose different species as members. We used partial sequence of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene to characterize all species that have been at one time or another included in the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calliurum&lt;/i&gt; species group. Results obtained allowed a clear definition of the group which is composed of 10 species: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ahli,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australe,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calliurum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celiae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edeanum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franzwerneri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heinemanni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lividum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pascheni,&lt;/i&gt; and a herein newly described species &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;campomaanense.&lt;/i&gt; This new species is described from 26 specimens captured in small streams of the Campo-Ma’an region within the Ntem River basin of southern Cameroon. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;campomaanense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from all the other species of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calliurum&lt;/i&gt; species group, and above all from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ahli,&lt;/i&gt; by asymmetric coloration of the caudal fin with a yellow lower margin and a white upper margin, and a body with a dark blue background against which red spots are arrayed in horizontal rows towards the head merging into vertical rows posteriorly. This species is also genetically distinguished from the other species of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calliurum&lt;/i&gt; species group by its mitochondrial genome and its karyotype, characterized by an unusually high number of chromosomes and arms (2n= 44, NF=58).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Killifish; karyotype; mitochondrial DNA; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Killifish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-François</firstname>
          <lastname>Agnèse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Randall</firstname>
          <lastname>Brummett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pierre</firstname>
          <lastname>Caminade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Josette</firstname>
          <lastname>Catalan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Etienne</firstname>
          <lastname>Kornobis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-59</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Raphidascaris (Sprentascaris) &lt;/i&gt;(Nematoda: Anisakidae) in &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus cordovae &lt;/i&gt;(Pisces: Loricariidae) from Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Raphidascaris&lt;/i&gt; (Sprentascaris) (Anisakidae) from the intestine of &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cordovae&lt;/i&gt; is described. It represents the fourth South American species, and the first species reported from Argentina. It is separated from its congeners by possessing three pairs of postanal papillae, and by the shape and size of the lips.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Raphidascaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Sprentascaris)&lt;/i&gt;; Nematoda; Parasites; freshwater fishes; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Raphidascaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Sprentascaris)&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Geraldine</firstname>
          <lastname>Ramallo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-64</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new generic homonym in the Agoristenidae (Arachnida: Opiliones)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Osvaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>Villarreal</middlename>
          <lastname>Manzanilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>Brilhante</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
