<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2223.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2223</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Bucephalids (Digenea: Bucephalidae) from marine fishes off the south-western coast of Java, Indonesia, including the description of two new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle &lt;/i&gt;and comments on the marine fish digenean fauna of Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new bucephalids are described from marine fishes from off the southern coast of Java, Indonesia. &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;danai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from the gempylid &lt;i&gt;Thyrsitoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marleyi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jayai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from the sciaenid &lt;i&gt;Johnius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macropterus.&lt;/i&gt; Neither has previously been reported as host of members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle.&lt;/i&gt; They can be distinguished from other species within the genus by a suite of characters, including the body shape, rhynchus length, pre-vitelline, pre-uterine, pre-mouth and post-testicular distances, cirrus-sac reach and egg length. &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platycephali&lt;/i&gt; is reported from the platycephalid &lt;i&gt;Sunagocia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;otaitensis.&lt;/i&gt; This identification is based on the distinctly separated testes and the position of Mehlis’ gland directly posterior to the anterior testis. To aid identification within these species-rich trematode genera, we have devised an illustrated metrical key that indicates the most similar described species. Nine distinct metrical features were recorded or calculated for all known marine species within &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; (51 known species) and &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; (64 known species) and utilised in species identification. With about 75 identified fish trematode species, only a fraction of the expected species diversity has been recorded from Indonesia, strongly suggesting the need for greater effort for fish parasitological research in the region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Bucephalidae; &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhipodocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;danai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jayai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp; &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platycephali;&lt;/i&gt; Java; Indonesia; &lt;i&gt;Thysitoides;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Johnius;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sunagocia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea; Bucephalidae; &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhipodocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;danai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Rhipidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jayai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp; &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Prosorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platycephali;&lt;/i&gt; Java; Indonesia; &lt;i&gt;Thysitoides;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Johnius;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sunagocia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodney</firstname>
          <middlename>A</middlename>
          <lastname>Bray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Harry</firstname>
          <middlename>W</middlename>
          <lastname>Palm</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new species of &lt;i&gt;Avicularia &lt;/i&gt;Lamarck 1818 and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Avicularia diversipes &lt;/i&gt;(C.L. Koch 1842) (Araneae, Theraphosidae, Aviculariinae)three possibly threatened Brazilian species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Avicularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diversipes&lt;/i&gt; (C.L. Koch 1842) known previously only from its original description is redescribed along with &lt;i&gt;Avicularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sooretama&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Avicularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gamba&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. The three species are endemic to Brazilian Atlantic rainforest. With other &lt;i&gt;Avicularia&lt;/i&gt; species, they share a procurved anterior eye row, slender embolus and medially folded spermathecae, whereas they have unusual characters, such as a very long and spiraled embolus (A. &lt;i&gt;diversipes)&lt;/i&gt; and spermathecae with multilobular apex (A. &lt;i&gt;sooretama&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.). Furthermore, the three species lack a tibial apophysis in males and share a distinctive color pattern ontogeny that is not known in any other &lt;i&gt;Avicularia&lt;/i&gt; species. The conservation status of the three species is discussed, especially with respect to endemism, illegal trafficking and habitat destruction. The creation of protected areas in southern State of Bahia, Brazil, is recommended, as well as the inclusion of these species in IUCN and CITES lists. Appendices with figures and species information are presented to facilitate correct specimen identification by custom officers, in order to limit illegal traffic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tarantula conservation; Pet trade; Brazilian Atlantic Rainforest; Protected areas; Taxonomy; Threatened species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tarantula conservation</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rogério</firstname>
          <lastname>Bertani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Caroline</firstname>
          <middlename>Sayuri</middlename>
          <lastname>Fukushima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-47</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The crab spiders of the Genus &lt;i&gt;Tmarus &lt;/i&gt;from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China (Araneae: Thomisidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new and three known crab spider species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tmarus&lt;/i&gt; are reported from the Xishuangbanna Rainforest of Yunnan, China: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;byssinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hastatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; male only), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spicatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (female only), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;undatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (female only), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;menglae&lt;/i&gt; Song and Zhao, 1994, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;songi&lt;/i&gt; Han and Zhu, 2008 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taiwanus&lt;/i&gt; Ono, 1977. The male of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;menglae&lt;/i&gt; is described for the first time. The type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; new species; Southeast Asia; tropical rainforest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guo</firstname>
          <lastname>Tang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shu-Qiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
