<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2129.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jun. 2009</title>
    <volume>2129</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-06-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Annotated key to the genera of Mymaridae (Hymenoptera: Chalcidoidea) in Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A key to the genera of Mymaridae occurring in Argentina is given, and information on the 178 determined and several undetermined species in 35 genera is provided, including data on their distribution and host associations. New host records are provided for several species of &lt;i&gt;Anagrus&lt;/i&gt; Haliday and &lt;i&gt;Gonatocerus&lt;/i&gt; Nees. The genus &lt;i&gt;Kikiki&lt;/i&gt; Huber &amp; Beardsley is recorded for the first time from the New World, and the genera &lt;i&gt;Australomymar&lt;/i&gt; Girault, &lt;i&gt;Camptopteroides&lt;/i&gt; Viggiani, &lt;i&gt;Gahanopsis&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin, &lt;i&gt;Myrmecomymar&lt;/i&gt; Yoshimoto, and &lt;i&gt;Ptilomymar&lt;/i&gt; Annecke &amp; Doutt are reported for the first time from Argentina. &lt;i&gt;Eucleruchus&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is synonymized under &lt;i&gt;Cleruchus&lt;/i&gt; Enock, and its type species &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neivai&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Cleruchus&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neivai&lt;/i&gt; (Ogloblin), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Argentina; Mymaridae; fairyflies; egg parasitoid</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Argentina</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Erica</firstname>
          <middlename>Luft</middlename>
          <lastname>Albarracin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Serguei</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Triapitsyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Virla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sternal pore plates (glandular areas) of male Thripidae (Thysanoptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Variation is illustrated in the specialized areas known as pore plates (glandular areas or areae porosae) that occur on the sternites of males of many Thysanoptera species, and the occurrence of these structures in genera of Thripidae is tabulated. Pore plates are present in more than 60% of genera in this family, and known to be absent in about 20%; males are not known in a further 20% of the genera. In families of Terebrantia other than Thripidae, pore plates also occur in Fauriellidae, Heterothripidae and Adiheterothripidae, but not in Aeolothripidae, Melanthripidae and Uzelothripidae. Females in a very few species of Thripidae have pore plates apparently similar to those of males.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">glandular areas; areae porosae; pore plates; Thripidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">glandular areas</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laurence</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mound</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Optical characterization and redescription of the South Pacific firefly &lt;i&gt;Bourgeoisia hypocrita &lt;/i&gt;Olivier (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bourgeoisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypocrita&lt;/i&gt; Olivier is an atypical species of firefly where males lack light organs in ventrite 7 and have reduced light organs in ventrite 6 and may not produce light at all, while females are flightless and produce a long-lasting glow (up to tens of seconds). Here, photobiology of females is described for the first time. Colour of produced bioluminescence ranges in the green to yellow/green. Spectrum is unimodal peaking at 575–595 nm but more complex than other fireflies in having two shoulders at 545–550 nm and 600–610 nm. A taxonomic re-examination of the species based on recent collections and type material shows that larvae and adults exhibit a peculiar dark pigmentation. Fluorescence and absorbance of adult extracts indicate this pigmentation could be involved in UV protection, in addition to possibly serving as cryptic camouflage. Fluorescence and absorbance of eggs, which have a light gold colour, indicate the luminous compound could be used as an antioxidant during this early life stage. Overall, the signal of bioluminescence shows characteristics of a basal system of flash communication in &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypocrita,&lt;/i&gt; which associates light production not only to visual communication but also possibly to UV and/or free radicals protective mechanisms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Firefly; South Pacific; Bioluminescence; Photobiology; UV protection; &lt;i&gt;Bourgeoisia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Firefly; South Pacific; Bioluminescence; Photobiology; UV protection</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dimitri</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Deheyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lesley</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ballantyne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-62</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Iocoris nodulifemoralis&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and new species of Harpactorinae (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Reduviidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new monotypic genus, &lt;i&gt;Iocoris,&lt;/i&gt; is erected to accommodate an undescribed unique species, &lt;i&gt;Iocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodulifemoralis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; in the reduviid subfamily Harpactorinae from China. A key is provided to distinguish the new genus from other closely related genera. The dorsal habitus and other diagnostic characters are illustrated. The type specimens are preserved in the Entomological Museum of China Agricultural University, Beijing.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Harpactorinae; taxonomy; China; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhaohui</firstname>
          <lastname>Luo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wanzhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
