<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2217.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2217</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Camisiidae) from &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus &lt;/i&gt;forests in Victoria, Australia, with a redescription of the fossil species &lt;i&gt;Crotonia ramus &lt;/i&gt;(Womersley, 1957)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six new species of oribatid mite belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; are described from wet forests in Victoria, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alpina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornuta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;victoriae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belong to the Capistrata species-group, having the full complement of notogastral setae in the &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; series; whilst &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;momitoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blacki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadubanudi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are members of the Cophinaria species-group, lacking setae &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; 2 . The fossil species &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramus&lt;/i&gt; (Womersley, 1957), also a member of the Cophinaria group, is redescribed from Tertiary Kauri pine resin (Agathis &lt;i&gt;yallournensis).&lt;/i&gt; The new members of the Capistrata group share an unique combination of characters, including long flagelliform setae &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; 3 , shorter setiform &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; 2 and with setae &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; 3 the shortest of the &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; series; lateral strips of the notogastral shield ornamented with fields of tubercles; narrow, blunt bothridial auriculae and elongate parallel apophyses of setae &lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt; 2 projecting horizontally. The morphological homogeneity of this cluster of species is mirrored by the members of the Cophinaria species-group described herein which, together with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyemaireneri&lt;/i&gt; Colloff, 2009 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tasmanica&lt;/i&gt; Łochyńska, 2008 from Tasmania, plus &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jethurmerae&lt;/i&gt; Lee, 1985 from South Australia, share relatively well-developed setae &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; 2 , a porose notogastral shield with narrow lateral tuberculate strips; elongate, acute bothridial auriculae; long, flagelliform setae &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; 1 and relatively short apophyses of setae &lt;i&gt;h&lt;/i&gt; 2 , divergent apically, and projecting posteriodorsally. The Victorian members of the Capistrata andCophinaria species-groups represent two homogeneous clusters of species associated with temperate rainforest refugia and wet sclerophyll forest in high-rainfall zones. An identification key is provided to the Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mite; taxonomy; morphology; refugia; biogeography; temperate rainforest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>J. Colloff And Giselle</middlename>
          <lastname>Perdomo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the mygalomorph spiders of the &lt;i&gt;Raveniola caudata &lt;/i&gt;species-group (Araneae, Nemesiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;caudata&lt;/i&gt; species-group of the genus &lt;i&gt;Raveniola&lt;/i&gt; Zonstein 1987 is newly established and reviewed. The group includes &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;redikorzevi&lt;/i&gt; (Spassky 1937) from Turkmenistan and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Tajikistan. Both members of the group differ from other congeners by the much longer posterior lateral spinnerets with long-digitiform apical segment, as well as by the characteristic, broadly-tipped and keeled embolus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; spiders; Nemesiidae; &lt;i&gt;Raveniola&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergei</firstname>
          <lastname>Zonstein</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-42</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Accelerating taxonomic discovery through automated character extraction </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper discusses the following key messages. Taxonomy is (and taxonomists are) more important than ever in times of global change. Taxonomic endeavour is not occurring fast enough: in 250 years since the creation of the Linnean &lt;i&gt;Systema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Naturae,&lt;/i&gt; only about 20% of Earth’s species have been named. We need fundamental changes to the taxonomic process and paradigm to increase taxonomic productivity by orders of magnitude. Currently, taxonomic productivity is limited principally by the rate at which we capture and manage morphological information to enable species discovery. Many recent (and welcomed) initiatives in managing and delivering biodiversity information and accelerating the taxonomic process do not address this bottleneck. Development of computational image analysis and feature extraction methods is a crucial missing capacity needed to enable taxonomists to overcome the taxonomic impediment in a meaningful time frame.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; taxonomic impediment; automated character extraction; image analysis; feature extraction; pattern recognition</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <lastname>La Salle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Quentin</firstname>
          <lastname>Wheeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Jackway</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shaun</firstname>
          <lastname>Winterton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Donald</firstname>
          <lastname>Hobern</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Lovell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-55</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Justified corrections to avian names under Article 32.5.1.1 of the International Code of Zoological Nomenclature</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Various avian names are examined in the context of Art. 32.5.1.1, a clause newly introduced in the 1999 Code, which applies retroactively; this permits clear decisions in 21 cases where qualifying corrigenda exist. In addition, we detail three names having dual original spellings, but that were not addressed by a First Reviser or in a corrigendum; they are provided as background, but they too should be captured in any planned database for actions under Art. 32.5</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Corrigendum; spellings; ZooBank; retroactivity; Code; First Reviser; prevailing usage</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Corrigendum</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Normand</firstname>
          <lastname>David</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edward</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dickinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>M. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gregory</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-66</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A potentially contentious case of correction under Article 32.5.1.1 of the International Code of Zoological Nomenclature</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Edward</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dickinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Normand</firstname>
          <lastname>David</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>M. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gregory</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
