<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2228.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2228</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A Taxonomic Review of the Australian Butterfly Ray &lt;i&gt;Gymnura australis&lt;/i&gt; (Ramsay &amp; Ogilby, 1886) and Other Members of the family Gymnuridae (Order Rajiformes) from the Indo-West Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; was examined as part of a wider review of Indo-West Pacific Gymnuridae species. The study revealed two distinct morphological variants: &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; var. eastern Australia and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; var. northern Australia. &lt;i&gt;Gymnrua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; var. eastern Australia has ≤ 3 complete or partially-complete white tail-bands and may or may not have a dorsal fin. &lt;i&gt;Gymnura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; var. northern Australia has a longer tail region, always possesses a dorsal fin and has ≥ 4 predominantly complete white tail-bands. Morphological and genetic comparisons indicate the observed differences were intraspecific (1.22% genetic gap difference). Wider morphometric comparisons between Indo-West Pacific gymnurids, revealed species differ principally in tail morphology. Dorsal-fin development in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zonura&lt;/i&gt; also varied intraspecifically. Results obtained from the study, help clarify the taxonomic status of the family and provide strong evidence that all Gymnuridae species belong to a single genus &lt;i&gt;Gymnura,&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Aetoplatea&lt;/i&gt; subsequently defined as a junior synonym.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gymnuridae; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;poecilura&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;tentaculata&lt;/i&gt;; Japan; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gymnuridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jacobsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mike</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bennett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A shallow water population of &lt;i&gt;Pronotogrammus martinicensis &lt;/i&gt;(Guichenot, 1868) (Teleostei: Serranidae: Anthiinae) from South-western Atlantic, Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A population of &lt;i&gt;Pronotogrammus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinicensis&lt;/i&gt; (Guichenot, 1868) is described and recognized as a unique shallowwater variation of the species from the Brazilian South-Eastern coast, based on genetic, morphologic and ecological data. It is distinguished from the deep water population by its smaller eye, longer snout, shorter pectoral-fin, color of the adults, and habitat depth.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Habitat depth; coloration; speciation; genomic DNA; &lt;i&gt;Anthias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicidentatus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Habitat depth</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfredo</firstname>
          <lastname>Carvalho-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>E. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <lastname>Craig</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-42</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha &lt;/i&gt;(Annelida: Dorvilleidae) from a whale-fall in the North-East Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; species are described from sites with high levels of organic carbon flux including a whale-fall at 125 m depth off the Swedish coast and sediment sampled at 104 m depth beneath a fish farm in a Norwegian fjord. Phylogenetic analyses based on the nuclear gene H3 and the mitochondrial genes COI and 16S using MrBayes and Maximum Likelihood analyses show that &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutrophila&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is a close relative to &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puerilis,&lt;/i&gt; while &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;craigsmithi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. falls together with &lt;i&gt;Palpiphitime&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobifera,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scutellus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. occur within the 'hartmanni' clade. The genus &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; is in our study monophyletic only if the genera &lt;i&gt;Iphitime&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Palpiphitime&lt;/i&gt; are included. Two representatives of &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; previously described from anthropogenically-enriched sediments are here reported for the first time in very high abundance from a naturally occurring habitat. We suggest that whale falls are important habitats for the evolution of ecosystem services such as the degradation of complex organic compounds.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polychaeta; organic enrichment; phylogeny; chemosynthetic ecosystem</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polychaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Helena</firstname>
          <lastname>Wiklund</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adrian</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Glover</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dahlgren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ocellus-bearing &lt;i&gt;Neobythites &lt;/i&gt;species (Teleostei: Ophidiidae) from the West Atlantic with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of the ophidiid genus &lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt; containing ocelli in the dorsal fin are known from the West Atlantic: &lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilli&lt;/i&gt; Goode and Bean 1885, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellatus&lt;/i&gt; Günther 1887 and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monocellatus&lt;/i&gt; Nielsen 1999. In the year 2000, 18 specimens of &lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt; were caught on the upper continental slope off eastern Brazil. This is the first documented record of a &lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt; specimen off Brazil since the holotype of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellatus&lt;/i&gt; was caught in 1873. Seventeen of the specimens are referable to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellatus&lt;/i&gt; and one to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monocellatus.&lt;/i&gt; Until now the distribution of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellatus&lt;/i&gt; was considered to be from off Atlantic Florida, the Caribbean Sea and then a gap of 4500 km to the type locality off Brazil. However, the holotype and the 17 specimens differ from the more northerly recorded specimens in pattern and number of spots and ocelli on the dorsal fin. The 18 Brazilian specimens have two distinct ocelli, one near the origin of the dorsal fin and one above the midpoint of the fish, and further back occasionally a small, black spot, while the northern specimens occasionally have a small, black spot near the origin of the fin, a distinct ocellus above the midpoint and up to three ocelli further posteriorly. Consequently a new species, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multiocellatus,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on 59 specimens from the Caribbean Sea to off Atlantic Florida. The record of the &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monocellatus&lt;/i&gt; specimen extends its distribution about 3000 km southwards. A comparison of the four ocellus-bearing species from the West Atlantic is made.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt;; Ophidiidae; Ophidiiformes; West Atlantic; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neobythites&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jørgen</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franz</firstname>
          <lastname>Uiblein</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mincarone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
