<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2106.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 May. 2009</title>
    <volume>2106</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Incorporation of nomina of higher-ranked taxa into the &lt;i&gt;International Code of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zoological Nomenclature&lt;/i&gt;: the nomenclatural status of class-series zoological nomina published in a non-latinized form</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Many new higher-ranked taxa are currently recognized by taxonomists as a result of the numerous phylogenetic hypotheses which are regularly published. The absence in the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; of Rules for the nomenclature of taxa above the rank superfamily (class-series nomenclature) is a factor of growing chaos in zoological taxonomy. This is why Dubois (2005) proposed a set of formal Rules for this nomenclature, which should be discussed and considered for incorporation into the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; This paper focuses on a particular point regarding these proposed Rules, i.e., whether class-series nomina should be considered nomenclaturally available from their first publication in any modern language, provided they were latinized subsequently, or only from their first use in a latinized form. It is argued that the first solution should be retained, not only “to render unto Caesar the things which are Caesar’s”, but also for simple internal consistency within the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; According to the Rules of the &lt;i&gt;Code,&lt;/i&gt; generic nomina may be available, with their original authors and dates, even if directly transferred unchanged from modern languages, and family-series nomina, first published in a nonlatinized form, may be available, with their original authors and dates, provided they have been subsequently latinized. These general statements are illustrated with the higher nomenclature of several taxa including amphibians. According to the proposed Rules, the following nomina, authors and dates are the valid ones for the taxa they designate: &lt;b&gt;VERTEBRATA&lt;/b&gt; Cuvier, 1800; &lt;b&gt;AMPHIBIA&lt;/b&gt; De Blainville, 1816; &lt;b&gt;GYMNOPHIONA&lt;/b&gt; Rafinesque-Schmaltz, 1814; &lt;b&gt;BATRACHIA&lt;/b&gt; Brongniart, 1800; &lt;b&gt;ANURA&lt;/b&gt; Duméril, 1806; &lt;b&gt;URODELA&lt;/b&gt; Duméril, 1806; &lt;b&gt;AMPHIPNEUSTA&lt;/b&gt; Merrem, 1820.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Higher-ranked taxa; class-series nomenclature; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; nomenclatural availability; non-latinized nomina; amphibians.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Higher-ranked taxa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some ascidians from Indonesian marine lakes (Raja Ampat Islands, West Papua)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A small collection of ascidians from Indonesian marine lakes in the Raja Ampat Islands, West Papua province, was made by biologists from the university of California, Merced and Coral Reef Research Foundation, Palau during a marine lakes macro-invertebrate diversity survey. It comprises 19 species. Some of them previously described show some modifications of their anatomical characters which may be due to a lower salinity and pH of the lake water or perhaps to evolution &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ.&lt;/i&gt; Some specimens (Aplousobranchia) could not be assigned to a species, the samples being too small, the larvae absent, and a possible modification in the number or shape of the calcareous spicules may occur. They are nevertheless described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ascidians; marine lakes; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ascidians</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Françoise</firstname>
          <lastname>Monniot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>13-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comparative morphology of the seminal receptacles of &lt;i&gt;Ocypode quadrata&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1787) (Brachyura, Ocypodoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The seminal receptacles of the Eubrachyura are an ecto-mesodermic differentiation of the genital ducts where the spermatophores are stored and fertilization takes place. The position in which the oviduct is connected to the seminal receptacles varies among species and two types, dorsal and ventral, can be distinguished. The dorsal type is frequently observed in the “soft mating system” species, while the ventral one is usually related to the “hard mating system” species. The seminal receptacles (SR) of &lt;i&gt;Ocypode&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrata&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1787) are paired, spherical and opalescent structures with a ventral connection to the oviduct and without any differences between the two members of the pair. The SR present macroscopic features that resemble other semi-terrestrial species of Ocypodoidea and Grapsoidea, but some histological characters resemble more aquatic species such as the Majoidea. The mesodermic portion of the SR is delimited by a cubic-flat secretor epithelium with three layers of muscular cells and surrounded externally by a simple capsule of conjunctive tissue. The transition between the mesodermic and the ectodermic areas is abrupt and characterized by a folded epithelium resembling that described for some Majoidea and the presence of a high cuticular layer. Only free spermatozoa were found, but no differentiated spermatophore packages or spermatophores.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; reproductive system; seminal receptacles; sperm competition; sperm storage; &lt;i&gt;Ocypode&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laura</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>López-Greco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vívian</firstname>
          <lastname>Fransozo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Lucia</middlename>
          <lastname>Negreirosfransozo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniela</firstname>
          <middlename>Carvalho Dos</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Geothelphusa makatao &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Brachyura: Potamidae), a new freshwater crab from an uplifted Pleistocene reef in Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of potamid freshwater crab, &lt;i&gt;Geothelphusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makatao,&lt;/i&gt; is described from southwestern Taiwan, based on morphological characters and mitochondrial DNA evidence. The new species differs from close congeners, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pingtung&lt;/i&gt; Tan &amp; Liu, 1998, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shernshan&lt;/i&gt; Chen, Cheng &amp; Shy, 2005, and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancylophallus&lt;/i&gt; Shy, Ng &amp; Yu, 1994 and a superficially similar species, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albogilva&lt;/i&gt; Shy, Ng &amp; Yu, 1994, in the structure of its ambulatory legs, thoracic sternum, male abdomen, and male first pleopods. The unique gene sequences of 16S rRNA and cytochrome oxidase I also support the recognition of this coastal population, which is isolated from other closely related species inhabiting montane areas. Except for &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makatao,&lt;/i&gt; the phylogenetic analysis showed that there are three additional hill subclades within the &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pingtung&lt;/i&gt; clade, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shernshan,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pingtung&lt;/i&gt; and the Liangshan subclade, situated in different watersheds of rivers or streams near the Central Range in the southwestern Taiwan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">16S rRNA; cytochrome oxidase I; &lt;i&gt;Geothelphusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makatao&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pingtung&lt;/i&gt;; Brachyura; Potamidae; Taiwan; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">16S rRNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hsi-Te</firstname>
          <lastname>Shih</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jhy-Yun</firstname>
          <lastname>Shy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Neotype designation for &lt;i&gt;Cunaxa setirostris &lt;/i&gt;(Hermann, 1804) (Acari: Prostigmata: Cunaxidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A neotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Cunaxa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setirostris&lt;/i&gt; (Hermann, 1804). A full motivation, description and drawings of both sexes are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bdelloidea; Cunaxinae; neotype designation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bdelloidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jacob</firstname>
          <middlename>Den</middlename>
          <lastname>Heyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexey</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sergeyenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
