<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2113.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 May. 2009</title>
    <volume>2113</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-05-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus &lt;/i&gt;(Siluriformes: Loricariidae) from the upper rio Uruguay, southeastern South America, with a review of the genus in the rio Uruguay basin </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; are described from the upper course of the rio Uruguay basin in Brazil: &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iota&lt;/i&gt; from the rio Chapecó drainage; &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucophrys&lt;/i&gt; from rio Rancho Grande and rio Ariranhas; &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megaloplax&lt;/i&gt; from the rio Passo Fundo drainage; and &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; from the rio Canoas drainage. The species &lt;i&gt;Epactionotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aky,&lt;/i&gt; described from the arroyo Yabotí-Guazú drainage in Argentina, is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; and rediagnosed. &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candombe&lt;/i&gt; is considered a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ringueleti.&lt;/i&gt; The new taxa, together with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigricauda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ringueleti,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;charrua,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aky&lt;/i&gt; represent the genus &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; in the rio Uruguay basin. A taxonomic key for &lt;i&gt;Hisonotus&lt;/i&gt; in the rio Uruguay basin is provided. Their distributions are discussed under biogeographic patterns previously proposed for the rio Uruguay basin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Catfishes; Hypoptopomatinae; Neotropical; Taxonomy; Biogeography; Endemism; &lt;i&gt;Epactionotus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Catfishes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tiago</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Reis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Atheris &lt;/i&gt;(Serpentes: Viperidae) from northern Mozambique</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of forest viper (Atheris Serpentes: Viperidae) is described from Mount Mabu and Mount Namuli, northern Mozambique. This is the most southerly record of the genus, and the first record from Mozambique. Features of scalation, colour, body form and behaviour distinguish the new species from all other African &lt;i&gt;Atheris,&lt;/i&gt; particularly its small size (maximum total length 384mm), retention of juvenile colouration in adults, and relatively low ventral, subcaudal and labial scale counts. It appears to be a dwarf, possibly paedomorphic, species that feeds among leaf litter on small frogs and geckos. The discovery of the new species in isolated populations in mid-altitude forest remnants on Mount Mabu and Mount Namuli, emphasizes the high conservation importance of the region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Viperidae; &lt;i&gt;Atheris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Mount Mabu; Mount Namuli; Mozambique</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Viperidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Branch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julian</firstname>
          <lastname>Bayliss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Achirus &lt;/i&gt;(Pleuronectiformes: Achiridae) from Northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight species are considered valid in the genus &lt;i&gt;Achirus&lt;/i&gt; (Lacépède), distributed on both sides of the Americas, mainly in marine and estuarine waters with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novoae&lt;/i&gt; being the only species of this genus restricted to freshwaters of the Orinoco basin and its delta. A new species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucuri,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the estuary of the Mucuri River, a small system in Bahia state, northeastern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucuri&lt;/i&gt; differs from congeners, except &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novoae,&lt;/i&gt; in having a connection between the branchiostegal membrane and the isthmus. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucuri&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novoae&lt;/i&gt; in its labial fimbriae and latero-sensory cephalic canal pattern.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">American sole; flatfishes; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">American sole</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robson</firstname>
          <middlename>T. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Telton</firstname>
          <middlename>P. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>R. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lopes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Should all other biologists follow the lead of virologists and stop italicizing the names of living organisms? A proposal</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As thousands of viruses were discovered over the years, they were given common names in English and in other languages. Then, about 20 years ago, the category “species” was introduced in virology and the vernacular names of viruses were adopted for use as species nomina and were italicized to indicate that they then referred to taxonomic entities. As a result, virologists should write that a patient was infected “with measles virus” but not “with the species &lt;i&gt;Measles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virus”&lt;/i&gt; nor with “the genus &lt;i&gt;Morbillivirus”,&lt;/i&gt; since taxonomic classes cannot cause infections. In other fields of biology the great majority of organisms only have Latin species nomina, written in italics, and no vernacular name. As a result, it will be said that a patient was infected with &lt;i&gt;Bacillus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anthracis,&lt;/i&gt; as though that taxonomic entity were able to cause a disease. What is meant, of course, is that the infection was caused by a bacterium that is a member of the species &lt;i&gt;Bacillus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anthracis.&lt;/i&gt; Attributing the infection to a species instead of an organism arises because of the absence of vernacular names for many organisms. However, this logical muddle could be avoided if the writer would use the species nomina of the disease-causing organisms but wrote them in unitalicized Roman letters, as is done with viruses. To do away with logically ill-formed statements, we propose that the names of all biological entities for which there is no common name be derived from the species nomen but written in unitalicized Roman letters. The italicized style would then be reserved for the species to which the entity belongs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Use of italics; Vernacular names; Non-equivalence of species and organisms; Taxonomy; Nomen; Nomina; Names; Taxa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Use of italics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Calisher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <middlename>H. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Regenmortel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
