<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2093.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 May. 2009</title>
    <volume>2093</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A redescription of &lt;i&gt;Metopa &lt;/i&gt;species (Amphipoda, Stenothoidae) based on the type material. 1. Zoological Museum, Copenhagen (ZMUC)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper presents redescriptions of amphipods in the genus &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; (Stenothoidae) in the type-collections of the Zoological Museum of Copenhagen. For &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clypeata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; we redescribe the type-specimens, for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glacialis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;groenlandica&lt;/i&gt; the redescriptions are based on new material and checked against the type-specimens. For all except &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; a combination of new line drawings and scanning electron microscope (SEM) pictures is provided, for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis,&lt;/i&gt; line drawings only. A summary of the other species having earlier been designed to &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; in the Copenhagen collections is given, with a list of their present taxonomic position.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt;; redescription; Zoological Museum Copenhagen; &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clypeata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glacialis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;groenlandica&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anne</firstname>
          <middlename>Helene S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tandberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wim</firstname>
          <lastname>Vader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Sycorax &lt;/i&gt;Curtis (Diptera, Psychodidae, Sycoracinae) collected on harlequin frogs (Anura: Bufonidae, &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt;) in the Ecuadorian Andes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sycorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wampukrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Amazonian slopes of the Cordillera Oriental of southern Ecuadorian Andes. This new species constitutes the first record of the genus from Ecuador. Males and females of this new species were found in contact with the dorsal surfaces of head, body and extremities of male individuals of harlequin frogs, thus establishing the second record of species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sycorax&lt;/i&gt; feeding on frog blood.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Psychodidae; Sycoracinae; &lt;i&gt;Sycorax&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Harlequin frogs; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical Region; Andes; Ecuador</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Freddy</firstname>
          <lastname>Bravo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Salazar-Valenzuela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-42</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Recent discoveries of alien &lt;i&gt;Watersipora &lt;/i&gt;(Bryozoa) in Western Europe, with redescriptions of species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We report the introduction of the encrusting bryozoan &lt;i&gt;Watersipora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtorquata&lt;/i&gt; to Atlantic coasts of Europe. This species is highly invasive, having become common on coastlines throughout cool-temperate areas of the world since the 1980s. Confusion exists over the identity of this and other &lt;i&gt;Watersipora&lt;/i&gt; species, which lack characters that are conventionally used in bryozoan systematics. &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtorquata&lt;/i&gt; has not been well distinguished from &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucullata&lt;/i&gt; which, reports dating back to the mid 1800s suggest, is native to the Mediterranean Basin or represents an early shipping introduction. &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucullata&lt;/i&gt; has been placed in synonymy with &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subovoidea,&lt;/i&gt; a taxon lacking a holotype. We designate a neotype for &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subovoidea,&lt;/i&gt; recognizing its conspecificity with &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucullata,&lt;/i&gt; and demonstrate a simple morphometric means of separating this species from &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtorquata&lt;/i&gt; using zooid feature ratios (operculum area versus total frontal shield). An orange watersiporid population that was first recognized in Guernsey, in the European-Atlantic, in 2007, is shown by morphometric and mitochondrial genetic analysis to match &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtorquata.&lt;/i&gt; It contains the commonest, widely introduced COI haplotype that, along with other evidence, suggests recent transfer via shipping traffic to Europe. A second population (previously referred alternatively to &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aterrima&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subovoidea)&lt;/i&gt; has been reported from Brittany and Bordeaux (Atlantic coastline, France). This population is also aligned with &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtorquata&lt;/i&gt; based on morphometrics and COI haplotype. In contrast to the Guernsey introduction, the earlier French-Atlantic introduction appears related to oyster imports from Japan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Invasive marine bryozoans; zooid morphometrics; colony colour; neotype; cytochrome oxidase I; transport on ships; oysters</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Invasive marine bryozoans</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ryland</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <lastname>De Blauwe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <lastname>Lord</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Joshua</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mackie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-59</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachyhypopomus gauderio, &lt;/i&gt;new species, a new example of underestimated species diversity of electric fishes in the southern South America (Gymnotiformes: Hypopomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachyhypopomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gauderio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described here from the central, southern and coastal regions of the Rio Grande do Sul state, Brazil, from Uruguay, and from Paraguay. It is diagnosed from the congeners on the basis of body coloration, meristic and morphometric characters, such as the number of anal-fin rays, the position of anal-fin origin in relation to pectoral-fin, the morphology of the distal portion of caudal filament of mature males, and body proportions. The new species has been formerly identified as &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnicaudatus&lt;/i&gt; and is herein distinguished from it.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachyhypopomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnicaudatus&lt;/i&gt;; Rio Grande do Sul; Rio Uruguay; Laguna dos Patos; Rio Tramandaí</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachyhypopomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnicaudatus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julia</firstname>
          <lastname>Giora</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Malabarba</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
