<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1684.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Jan. 2008</title>
    <volume>1684</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Identities of three taxa of the hippolytid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Heptacarpus &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea), with description of a new species from East Asian waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Taxonomy of the two previously described species of the hippolytid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Heptacarpus&lt;/i&gt; Holmes, 1900, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camtschaticus&lt;/i&gt; (Stimpson, 1860) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geniculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Stimpson, 1860), are reassessed. It has been found that &lt;i&gt;Eualus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geniculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longirostris&lt;/i&gt; Kobjakova, 1936, which has been regarded as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Heptacarpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geniculatus,&lt;/i&gt; is a valid taxon, herein reinstated as a full species. It has been found that two species were confounded in previous literature under the name &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camtschaticus,&lt;/i&gt; and one of them is described as new, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acuticarinatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Three species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camtschaticus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geniculatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longirostris,&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed. These four species all belong to an informal species group characterized by the lack of pereopodal epipods. Differences in morphology and distributional pattern among the four species are discussed. A key in aid of the identification of the Asian species belonging to the species group is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Hippolytidae; &lt;i&gt;Heptacarpus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomic identity; new species; East Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Boris</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ivanov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-34</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euphilomedes chupacabra &lt;/i&gt;(Ostracoda: Myodocopida: Philomedidae), a new demersal marine species from coastal Puerto Rico with male-biased vespertine swimming activity</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Philomedidae is described: &lt;i&gt;Euphilomedes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chupacabra&lt;/i&gt; from coastal Puerto Rico. This is the first described species of &lt;i&gt;Euphilomedes&lt;/i&gt; from the Western Atlantic, a genus of particular interest for its sexually dimorphic lateral eyes. As &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chupacabra&lt;/i&gt; can be easily caught in large numbers and may have a short generation time, it has potential to be used as a laboratory animal to study questions of dimorphic eye development. Males of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chupacabra&lt;/i&gt; are abundant in plankton for a short time; the average time of peak activity was 103.6 minutes after sunset, and the density range at the peak time on different nights was 24 to 862 males/m 3 . Males were preferentially attracted to pier lights. There is evidence that species from all myodocopid families display vespertine (post-sunset) migratory behavior, probably associated with mating. We hypothesize that vespertine planktonic mating is an adaptive behavior that exists in many myodocopids and is either the ancestral state for the group or partially or fully convergent in multiple species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">systematics; taxonomy; lateral eye; laboratory animal; behavior; sunset; plankton</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kimberly</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Syme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anastasia</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schwab</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Todd</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oakley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-57</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Pretty in pink: A new treefrog species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt;from North-Eastern Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Treefrogs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; comprise the most species-rich genus among all Malagasy frogs. In this paper we describe a new species to be added to this genus from Masoala Peninsula and nearby areas. Related populations have been found in three localities of North-Eastern Madagascar (Tsararano, Marojejy, and Anjanaharibe-Sud), and molecular data indicate that at least the Marojejy population is strongly differentiated. The new species has an attractive pink or reddish colour pattern on a green ground colour. It bears a strong similarity to &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bottae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rappiodes&lt;/i&gt; in morphological appearance, but is genetically very distinct from these and other members of the &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rappiodes&lt;/i&gt; group. &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulftunni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; belongs into a separate evolutionary lineage probably related to the &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum&lt;/i&gt; group, a lineage of highland species from Central Eastern Madagascar which otherwise have very different phenotypes and advertisement calls. We here include &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulftunni&lt;/i&gt; in a new phenetic species group, the &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulftunni&lt;/i&gt; group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Mantellidae; &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulftunni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rappiodes&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulftunni&lt;/i&gt; group; systematics; Madagascar; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wollenberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Andreone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Glaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
