<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1958.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Dec. 2008</title>
    <volume>1958</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and distribution of the Australian longicorn beetle genus &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; Hope (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Australia genus &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; consists of 39 species and its larvae are known to be borers of at least 31 genera of trees and parasitic plants in 15 families (Asteraceae, Betulaceae, Casuarinaceae, Cupressaceae, Fabaceae, Loranthaceae, Myrtaceae, Pittosporaceae, Proteaceae, Rhamnaceae, Rosaceae, Rutaceae, Sapindaceae, Sterculiaceae, and Xanthorrhoeaceae), including some economically important crops such as citrus, litchi, peach, plum, and apricot. The phylogeny and biogeographic distribution of the genus were investigated in this paper. Here, the monophylies of the genus and seven species groups are inferred based on morphological characters of 39 ingroup and four outgroup species. However, several species groups still need additional steps to become monophyletic and are currently considered paraphyletic. The &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; fauna occur in five biogeographic subregions: the Kosciuskan, Western and Eyrean in southern and central Australia, and the Torresian and Timorian in northern Australia. The fauna are richest with highest endemism in the Kosciuskan and Western. The Kosciuskan and Western are similar in faunal composition and closely related; the Eyrean has probably acted as a faunal exchange transit area between the Kosciuskan and Western, and the two northern Australian subregions have no endemic species. When the areas of endemism of each species are attached to the proposed phylogenetic tree, a clear picture of the distribution patterns of species groups in relation to phylogeny is obtained. It is suggested that the speciation and species radiation of &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; may have occurred first in the Kosciuskan, then in the Western, and finally in the Eyrean, Torresian, and Timorian.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerambycidae; Cerambycinae; &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerambycidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Duangrat</firstname>
          <lastname>Thongphak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Qiao</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt;: A new genus of Neotropical Rhyparochromidae (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Lygaeoidea) to accommodate &lt;i&gt;Neopamera brachialis &lt;/i&gt;(Stål) and four new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt; is erected to accommodate &lt;i&gt;Neopamera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachialis&lt;/i&gt; (Stål), and four new Neotropical species: &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pampeana&lt;/i&gt; from Argentina, &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lydiae&lt;/i&gt; from Brazil, &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; from Argentina and Brazil, and &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saopaulensis&lt;/i&gt; from Brazil. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachialis&lt;/i&gt; (n. comb.) known only from Brazil is redescribed and recorded for the first time from Argentina. Phylogenetic affinities of this new genus are discussed. Dorsal photographs of the species, illustrations of male genitalia, and a key to the species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rhyparochromidae; Myodochini; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Paisana&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rhyparochromidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <middlename>Matías</middlename>
          <lastname>Dellapé</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of immature stages and adult diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Stilobezzia coquilletti&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer 1917 (Diptera: Ceratopogonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The pupa and larva of &lt;i&gt;Stilobezzia&lt;/i&gt; (Stilobezzia) &lt;i&gt;coquilletti&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer are described, and a diagnosis of the adult is given. All described stages were photomicrographed and illustrated by using phase-contrast microscope, plus Scanning Electron Microscope in the case of the larva. Immature stages were collected in a shallow stream of sandy bottom nearby Manaus, Brazil. The pupa is compared with &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;fiebrigi&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, and the larva with &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;antennalis&lt;/i&gt; Coquillett.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">immatures; description; &lt;i&gt;Stilobezzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coquilletti&lt;/i&gt;; Ceratopogonidae; Manaus; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">immatures</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ronderos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cazorla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Spinelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daiane</firstname>
          <middlename>Silveira</middlename>
          <lastname>Carrasco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Central ocellus of extinct cockroaches (Blattida: Caloblattinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Third, central ocellus, lost in living cockroaches, is discovered in the diverse Upper Jurassic representatives of the family Caloblattinidae. Three new genera possessing central ocellus are described: &lt;i&gt;Decomposita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triocella&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Srdiecko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tri&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Paleovia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;praecarnia&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov. Presence of central ocellus, although a plesiomorphy, in the Caloblattinidae falsifies the last argument against their ancestral position in respect to mantises (via the Liberiblattinidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Blattida (= Blattaria = Blattodea); mantodea; head; central ocellus; Kimmeridgian; Jurassic; Karatau</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Blattida (= Blattaria = Blattodea)</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>VrAnský</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the ant genus &lt;i&gt;Forelius &lt;/i&gt;(Formicidae: Dolichoderinae) from the dry forest of Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Forelius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;damiani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the dry forest of the Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta, Colombia, and additional collections from Costa Rica and Texas (USA). This new species is separated from the other rounded spiracles &lt;i&gt;Forelius&lt;/i&gt; by the number of erect pronotal hairs, size and coloration. Comments and hypotheses about the biogeography of the genus are provided. &lt;i&gt;Forelius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pruinosus&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time for Colombia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ants; &lt;i&gt;Forelius&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical region; taxonomy; Colombia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ants</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guerrero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernández</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cheiloneurus pistaciae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Hymenoptera: Encyrtidae) a facultative hyperparasitoid of &lt;i&gt;Kermania pistaciella &lt;/i&gt;Amsel (Lepidoptera: Tineidae), a pest of pistachio trees in Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Manickavasagam</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mehrnejad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Noyes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-64</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species in the &lt;i&gt;Rhyacophila lieftincki &lt;/i&gt;Group (Trichoptera: Rhyacophilidae) from southwestern Virginia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Armitage</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
