<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1833.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1833</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Heinrich Friese (18601948): Names proposed and notes on a pioneer melittologist (Hymenoptera, Anthophila)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Heinrich Friedrich August Karl Ludwig Friese (1860–1948) was an important pioneer bee biologist (melittologist). Between 1883 and 1939 he described 1,989 new species and 564 new varieties or subspecies of insects, of which over 99% were bees. His research was global, including description of new taxa from all biogeographical regions where bees occur, belonging to all seven extant bee families and 124 genera, including &lt;i&gt;Megachile&lt;/i&gt; (with 262 species-group taxa proposed), &lt;i&gt;Bombus&lt;/i&gt; (232), and &lt;i&gt;Halictus&lt;/i&gt; (153). The present catalog provides a complete list of the taxa proposed by Friese, including a bibliography of his 270 entomological publications. The catalog lists all valid names proposed by Friese and details on the nomenclature, sex, and region of origin of each. The current combination and subgeneric placement are cited for taxa now regarded as valid species. A brief biography is followed by a discussion of how to locate and treat Friese types, a notoriously complicated issue due to Friese’s confusing labeling practices and the broad dispersion of his specimens.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Apidae; Megachilidae; Halictidae; Andrenidae; Colletidae; Melittidae; Stenotritidae; Entomologist; Biography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Apidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claus</firstname>
          <lastname>Rasmussen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ascher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-118</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
