<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1943.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1943</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The 'true' genus &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; Baird, 1843 (Crustacea: Cladocera: Anomopoda): position of the &lt;i&gt;A. quadrangularis&lt;/i&gt;-group and description of a new species from the Democratic Republic of Congo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolwezii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the Afrotropics and provide a morphological comparison with the type species of the genus &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis.&lt;/i&gt; Past classification problems of &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; indicate a potential complexity of evolution and radiation in these smaller Aloninae. We present a historical overview of systematic approaches to the genus &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; aiming towards an increased understanding of Aloninae phylogeny. A proposed delineation of “true” &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; Baird, 1843 is presented as the &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis-group,&lt;/i&gt; comprising &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolwezii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviana.&lt;/i&gt; We discuss the phylogenetic position of the &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis-group&lt;/i&gt; with a redescription of its limbs, interspecific variability and morphological adaptations to an epi-benthic mode of life.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis&lt;/i&gt; group; history; taxonomy; limb morphology; &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolwezii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kay</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Damme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Henri</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dumont</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathycongrus trimaculatus&lt;/i&gt;, a new congrid eel (Teleostei: Anguilliformes) from the southwestern Pacific, with a redescription of &lt;i&gt;Bathycongrus bleekeri&lt;/i&gt; Fowler</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathycongrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; is described from 16 specimens collected from moderately deep water off the Solomon Islands, Fiji, and New Caledonia in the southwestern Pacific. It is distinguished from all other species by the presence of three conspicuous dark spots in the dorsal and anal fins; by having the vomerine teeth in an elongate patch with all the teeth about the same size and none of them greatly enlarged; by having fewer vertebrae; and by its small size. &lt;i&gt;Bathycongrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bleekeri&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed, based on the unique holotype and two additional specimens, and compared to other species of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Teleostei; Anguilliformes; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Teleostei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emma</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Karmovskaya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-36</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The chaerilid scorpions of China (Scorpiones: Chaerilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of scorpions belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Chaerilus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1877 are registered from the Xizang (Tibet) Region of China. We provide redescriptions for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessellatus&lt;/i&gt; Qi, Zhu &amp; Lourenço, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triznai&lt;/i&gt; Kovařík, 2000. We also point out that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pictus&lt;/i&gt; (Pocock, 1890) which was described by Qi, Zhu &amp; Lourenço, 2005 was misidentified by those authors. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pictus&lt;/i&gt; (Pocock, 1890) is of doubtful distribution in China. In this paper we describe one new species to science: &lt;i&gt;Chaerilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conchiformus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and provide an identification key to the Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Chaerilus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chaerilus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Xizang (Tibet ) identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chaerilus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guang-Xin</firstname>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wilson</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lourenço</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the &lt;i&gt;Alpheus cylindricus &lt;/i&gt;Kingsley, 1878 species complex (Crustacea: Decapoda: Alpheidae), with revalidation of &lt;i&gt;A. vanderbilti&lt;/i&gt; Boone, 1930</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cylindricus&lt;/i&gt; Kingsley, 1878, previously believed to be widely distributed in the tropical eastern Pacific and western and eastern Atlantic, is revised. Two species are recognized based on morphology, color pattern and genetics. &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cylindricus&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to the tropical eastern Pacific, from the Gulf of California to the Galapagos. A neotype of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cylindricus&lt;/i&gt; from the type locality, Las Perlas Islands, is designated. On the Pacific coast of Panama, this species commonly inhabits purple sponges growing among or under large intertidal rocks. &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vanderbilti&lt;/i&gt; Boone, 1930 is formally resurrected from the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cylindricus;&lt;/i&gt; it occurs in the tropical western Atlantic, from Bermuda to Brazil, and in the tropical eastern Atlantic, around the islands of the Gulf of Guinea. In the Caribbean, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vanderbilti&lt;/i&gt; is most often encountered in large loggerhead sponges, &lt;i&gt;Spheciospongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vesparia&lt;/i&gt; (Lamarck, 1814), while in the Gulf of Guinea it inhabits sponge-lined tunnels in coral rocks. Complete synonymies and GenBank barcodes (COI) are provided. Phylogeography of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cylindricus&lt;/i&gt; complex is discussed based on molecular data.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt;; snapping shrimp; transisthmian taxa; color pattern; eastern Pacific; western Atlantic; eastern Atlantic; Caribbean; COI; barcode; molecular phylogeny; sponge; symbiosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <lastname>Hurt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nancy</firstname>
          <lastname>Knowlton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
