<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1771.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 May. 2008</title>
    <volume>1771</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis &lt;/i&gt;Strauch 1887 (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Pulau Perhentian Besar, Terengganu, Peninsular Malaysia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of gekkoind lizard, &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perhentianensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Pulau Perhentian Besar, 21 km off the east coast of the state of Terengganu, Peninsular Malaysia. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perhentianensis&lt;/i&gt; is differentiated from all other Southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in having a maximum SVL of 47.2 mm; the scales of the anterior portion of the forearm are keeled; the ventral scales are weakly keeled; there are no femoral pores; eight preanal pores; there is no linearly arranged row of tubercles on the flanks; there are paravertebral, longitudinal rows of caudal tubercles and lateral caudal rows anteriorly; the keeled subcaudals lack an enlarged median row; there are no large, shield-like subtibial or submetatarsal scales; 28–31 subdigital lamellae are on the fourth toe; distinct, large, dark spots occur on the neck and back that alternate with transverse, white markings; and there are white markings on flanks that alternate with dark blotches.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Malaysia; Pulau Perhentian Besar; Archipelago; Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perhentianensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Malaysia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chan</firstname>
          <middlename>Kin</middlename>
          <lastname>Onn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Goniurosaurus &lt;/i&gt;from Cat Ba Island, Hai Phong, northern Vietnam (Squamata: Eublepharidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the gekkonid genus &lt;i&gt;Goniurosaurus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Cat Ba Island, Hai Phong, northern Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catbaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is, by its gracile body and limbs, the thin, posteriorly protracted nuchal loop, the three (or four) thin immaculate dorsal body bands between limb insertions, without dark spotting and with dark, narrow border surrounding the body bands, the lack of postrostral (internasal) scales, the presence of a greatly enlarged row of supraorbital tubercles, the outer surface of the upper eyelid being composed of granular scales of about the same size of those on top of head and with a longish row of 6–9 enlarged tubercles, granular body scales, with 8–11 granular scales surrounding the dorsal tubercles, deep axillary pockets, claws being sheathed by four scales, and 16–21 precloacal pores. The new taxon is known only from Cat Ba Island and is the eleventh &lt;i&gt;Goniurosaurus&lt;/i&gt; species known and the fourth known species from Vietnam. We provide first data on its natural history and a key to the currently recognized &lt;i&gt;Goniurosaurus&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Northern Vietnam; Hai Phong; Cat Ba; Squamata; Eublepharidae; &lt;i&gt;Goniurosaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catbaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; morphology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Northern Vietnam</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nguyen</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Truong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmitz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roswitha</firstname>
          <lastname>Stenke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Herbert</firstname>
          <lastname>Rosler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>16-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Report on the two subfamilies Clavatulinae and Cochlespirinae (Mollusca: Neogastropoda: Turridae) from the China seas</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on the materials deposited in the Marine Biological Museum of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Qingdao, the present paper reports ten turrid species belonging to six genera of subfamilies Clavatulinae and Cochlespirinae, including two new species, i.e., &lt;i&gt;Comitas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvifusiformis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Leucosyrinx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mai&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and three species newly recorded from China seas, i.e., &lt;i&gt;Makiyamaia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreanica&lt;/i&gt; (Adams and Reeve, 1850), &lt;i&gt;Turricula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumatrana&lt;/i&gt; (Thiele, 1925) and &lt;i&gt;Nihonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santosi&lt;/i&gt; Shuto, 1969. &lt;i&gt;Comitas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvifusiformis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. was collected from South China Sea in the depth of 42-75 m, which differs from the similar species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusiformis&lt;/i&gt; (Hutton, 1877) by the stronger spiral sculpture; &lt;i&gt;Leucosyrinx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mai&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is a deep sea species, collected from Nansha Islands in the depth of 1241 m, which can be distinguished from the close species &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;julia&lt;/i&gt; Thiele, 1925 by the spire whorls sharply carinated at the middle of each whorl.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clavatulinae; Cochlespirinae; Turridae; Yellow Sea; East China Sea; South China Sea; &lt;i&gt;Comitas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvifusiformis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Leucosyrinx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mai&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov; new species; new recorded species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clavatulinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Baoquan</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xinzheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Neobatrachia) from the &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus&lt;/i&gt; forest, Coastal Range, Southern Chile, identified by its karyotype</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on morphology, distribution, and on the presence of a novel diploid number (2n = 30 chromosomes), a new species of frog &lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;norae&lt;/i&gt; from the Coastal Range, Valdivia Province temperate &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus&lt;/i&gt; forest, Southern Chile, is described. Hypothetical chromosomal rearrangements and the origin of its unusual karyotype are discussed. Among the South American frogs, the genus &lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt; is recognized by its complex relationships, and based on karyological and geographical distribution information its species are grouped in two larger groups, herein: the Andean group which is conservative, and the Coastal group which is far more variable in gross chromosome morphology. Additionally, the inclusion of &lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt; in the new family Cycloramphidae is commented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt;; chromosomes; new species; Temperate Forest; Southern Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alsodes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cesar</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Cuevas</middlename>
          <lastname>P.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus, with a new species, from Brazil (Acari: Prostigmata: Cunaxidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new cunaxid genus from Brazil, &lt;i&gt;Cunaxatricha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is erected and its type species, &lt;i&gt;Cunaxatricha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarsospinosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and figured. A key to the genera of the subfamily Cunaxinae, to which this new genus belongs, is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bdelloidea; Cunaxinae; predatory mite; identification key; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bdelloidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tatiane</firstname>
          <middlename>Marie Martins Gomes</middlename>
          <lastname>De Castro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jacob</firstname>
          <middlename>Den</middlename>
          <lastname>Heyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Authors of zoological publications and nomina are signatures, not persons</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
