<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1715.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Feb. 2008</title>
    <volume>1715</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-02-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The coastal fishes of Madeira Island-new records and an annotated check-list</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A check-list of the coastal fishes of Madeira Island is presented. The species &lt;i&gt;Rhincodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Megalops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Apterichtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caecus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Apterichtus&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Chelidonichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucernus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Caranx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crysos,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;goreensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Crystallogobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linearis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Canthidermis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sufflamen&lt;/i&gt; are recorded for the first time from Madeira waters. We have recognized 13 previous records as identification errors or registration errors and indicate 14 other records as doubtful. Including the nine new records, we list 226 species from the coastal waters of Madeira Island.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eastern Atlantic; marine biodiversity; reef fish; global warming</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eastern Atlantic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Wirtz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ronald</firstname>
          <lastname>Fricke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <middlename>Jose</middlename>
          <lastname>Biscoito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of two new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Gray 1827 (Squamata : Gekkonidae) endemic to southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the gekkonid lizard genus &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1827 are described on the basis of voucher specimens collected in isolated mountains separated from the Truong Son Mountain Range, southern Vietnam. Both species were collected from shallow caves, as have been many of the recently described &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; from across Southeast Asia. Both species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;takouensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Ta Kou Nature Reserve, Binh Thuan Province and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huynhi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Chua Chan Mountain, Dong Nai Province, are characterized by a small number of enlarged femoral scales separated from the precloacal scales by a large diastema. They may be distinguished from one another and from all other congeners by differences in rows of tubercles and ventral scales, subcaudal scalation and dorsal color pattern. These new taxa bring the number of currently recognized &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; species in Vietnam to twelve.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; new species; description; southern Vietnam; cave-dwelling</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stiphodon&lt;/i&gt; from southern Sumatra (Pisces: Gobioidei: Sicydiinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stiphodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carisa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on material collected in the southernmost watershed in Lampung Province, Sumatra, Indonesia. &lt;i&gt;Stiphodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carisa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; differs from all other congeners by a combination of characteristics that include having 9 second-dorsal fin rays; 15 pectoral-fin rays; 41–59 premaxillary teeth; predorsal scales sexually dimorphic in number, male with 5–11 and female with 8–16; 25–35 lateral scales; slightly embedded cycloid scales present on belly; male with a triangular-shaped first-dorsal fin with third and/or fourth spines longest but not filamentous and a patch of white fatty tissue posterior to pectoral-fin base; female usually with 5 (4–5) dusky to blackish blotches or spots along lateral midline from second-dorsal fin with usually 4 (3–4) posterior-most spots positioned close together on caudal peduncle, dusky band extending from anterior to eye to upper hypural base usually indistinct posterior to pectoral-fin base, with or without a dusky or black gular blotch; in some females xanthism exists which fades in preservation and in life yellow with orange to bright red markings. &lt;i&gt;Stiphodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semoni&lt;/i&gt; is a species common in hill streams of eastern Indonesia and Papua New Guinea and is reported here for the first time from streams entering the Indian Ocean in Lampung Province, Sumatra, Indonesia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gobioidei; Sicydiinae; &lt;i&gt;Stiphodon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; fresh water; Sumatra; xanthism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gobioidei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ronald</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Watson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of insular pitviper of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cryptelytrops&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Viperidae) from southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of pitviper &lt;i&gt;Cryptelytrops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;honsonensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Hon Son Island in Rach Gia Bay, Kien Giang Province of southern Vietnam based on it having unique aspects of scalation, body proportions, and color pattern. It is similar to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venustus&lt;/i&gt; in morphology and color pattern and the putative close relationship between these species would corroborate a biogeographical link across southern Indochina seen in a number of other taxa. The presence of this newly discovered insular endemic in Rach Gia Bay and other insular endemics of Rach Gia Bay addressed herein, underscores the understudied nature of these islands and the need for their continued conservation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cryptelytrops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;honsonensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venustus&lt;/i&gt;; Hon Son; Rach Gia Bay; Vietnam; Indochina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cryptelytrops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;honsonensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jesse</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
