<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1795.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jun. 2008</title>
    <volume>1795</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species and a new record of Cryptoniscoidea (Crustacea: Isopoda: Hemioniscidae and Crinoniscidae) parasitising stalked barnacles from New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of the families Hemioniscidae and Crinoniscidae are described from New Zealand waters: &lt;i&gt;Crinoniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;politosummus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scalpelloniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nieli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Mature males and females are described for all species, and the epicaridium larva is described for &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Males of the two species of &lt;i&gt;Scalpelloniscus&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicillatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;binoculis&lt;/i&gt; by coxal plate dentition, relative sizes of propodus and dactylus. &lt;i&gt;Crinoniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;politosummus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be separated from the only other congener &lt;i&gt;Crinoniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;equitans&lt;/i&gt; by the body shape of the mature females, and shape of antennule article 1 of the males. A single specimen tentatively identified as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;penicillatus&lt;/i&gt; is also recorded from New Zealand waters. These species are the first records of cryptoniscoid isopods infecting thoracic barnacles from the South West Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Epicaridea; Cryptoniscoidea; Crinoniscidae; Hemioniscidae; &lt;i&gt;Scalpelloniscus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Crinoniscus&lt;/i&gt;; parasite; barnacles; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hosie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diopatra tuberculantennata&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Onuphidae (Polychaeta) from Belize with a key to onuphids from the Caribbean Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Diopatra&lt;/i&gt; Audouin &amp; Milne-Edwards, 1833 from the intertidal zone in the vicinity of the Smithsonian field station (Carrie Bow Cay, Belize) is described. &lt;i&gt;Diopatra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculantennata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is identifiable by a combination of characters such as the presence of large lateral projections on both palpophores and antennophores, bidentate pseudocompound hooks with moderately long pointed hoods in the first five chaetigers, eyespots on the prostomium, nuchal organs forming almost a circle and very large sensory papillae on antennostyles and frontal and upper lips. Five 28-chaetiger juveniles were found inside the parental tube of one specimen. A pattern of anterior segment regeneration is described based on 12 specimens. A key for 20 species of onuphids known from the Caribbean Sea with the notes on their distribution is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">diversity; taxonomy; juveniles; regeneration; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">diversity; taxonomy; juveniles; regeneration; distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nataliya</firstname>
          <lastname>Budaeva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kristian</firstname>
          <lastname>Fauchald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-45</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Leptodactylidae) from the Atlantic Forest of Sao Paulo State, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; from Bertioga municipality, São Paulo State, Brazil is described. &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ajurauna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from others species in the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoratus&lt;/i&gt; group by its dark brown throat and the advertisement call. The taxonomy of other species in the group and the status of the population of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoratus&lt;/i&gt; sympatric with the new species are discussed. The advertisement call is also described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoratus&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ajurauna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoratus&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bianca</firstname>
          <lastname>Von Muller Berneck</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carolina</firstname>
          <middlename>Ortiz Rocha</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>Christiano</middlename>
          <lastname>De Anchietta Garcia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-56</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new family of the order Ctenopoda (Crustacea: Cladocera) from the depths of the Black Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The recently described &lt;i&gt;Pseudopenilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt; Sergeeva, 2004, found in the depths of the Black Sea and initially attributed to family Sididae (Crustacea: Cladocera: Ctenopoda), have after reinvestigation been placed in Pseudopenilidae, a new family of the cladoceran order Ctenopoda. The following set of the main diagnostic features characterize Pseudopenilidae: comparatively large antennules with long sensory seta and five aesthetascs; long and massive second antennae with two-segmented branches armed with long, one-segmented, needle-shaped setae without setules; maxillules without long setae; lack of second maxillae; closed brood pouch; six pairs of similar thoracic limbs without gnathobases and filtering setae; small epipodites present only on thoracic limbs of first pair; large postabdomen, having massive terminal claws and one-segmented, needle-shaped setae &lt;i&gt;nanatoriae&lt;/i&gt; without setules; resting eggs with hard outer shell. Among Ctenopoda, Pseudopenilidae is closest to the marine &lt;i&gt;Penilia&lt;/i&gt; (family Sididae, subfamily Penilinae) but is at the same time very different. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt; is a member of the recently discovered community of invertebrates, populating the deep anaerobic zone of the Black Sea, whose taxonomic diversity and mode of existence need further investigations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudopenilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomic description; Pseudopenilidae; hydrogen sulfide zone</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudopenilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nikolai</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Korovchinsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nelli</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sergeeva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Isodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Hedges, Duellman, and Heinicke, 2008</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Blair</middlename>
          <lastname>Hedges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duellman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heinicke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
