<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1938.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1938</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of Acanthocephala associated with the fishes of Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty-three genera comprising thirty-four named and thirteen undetermined species of acanthocephalans are associated with one hundred and nineteen marine, brackish and freshwater fish species from Brazil. These are listed, with information on their hosts, habitat, distribution and records. A key to these parasites at the generic level is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acanthocephala; biodiversity; checklist; freshwater and marine fishes; key; Neotropics; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acanthocephala</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cláudia</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gibson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>E. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tavares</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Luque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis &lt;/i&gt;Hrabě, 1982 (Clitellata: Lumbriculidae) from Lake Baikal, with re-descriptions of &lt;i&gt;P. parva&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P. olchonensis&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The recent rediscovery of specimens of the Baikalian lumbriculid &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olchonensis&lt;/i&gt; (Burow et Koshow, 1932) led to the re-examination of (1) Michaelsen’s hundred-year-old type specimens of &lt;i&gt;Lycodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus,&lt;/i&gt; assumed, for a long time, to have been wrongly attributed to the Tubificidae instead of the Lumbriculidae, and of (2) type specimens used by Hrabě (1982) for his redescription of &lt;i&gt;Lycodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus&lt;/i&gt; and its combination with the newly, subsequently created genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudolycodrilus&lt;/i&gt; Hrabě, 1982. Surprisingly enough, the original description of &lt;i&gt;Pseudolycodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus&lt;/i&gt; (Michaelsen, 1905) proved to be based on a mixing of two different species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semernoyi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., both of which are herein assigned to the recently re-established genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt; Hrabě, 1982. As a result, the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudolycodrilus&lt;/i&gt; is invalidated and must be considered as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olchonensis&lt;/i&gt; are re-described on the basis of neotypes and lectotypes, respectively. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semernoyi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is distinguished from other &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt; by having a conical prostomium, a well-marked clitellum with a honeycomb-like structure, and genital, sucker-like papillae, associated with penial setae. The description of the new species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semernoyi,&lt;/i&gt; plus a re-evaluation of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olchonensis,&lt;/i&gt; called into question the taxonomical status of &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dissimilis&lt;/i&gt; (Semernoy, 2004). This study provides new examples of genital setae in the Lumbriculidae although this character remains exceptional within the family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clitellata; Oligochaeta; Lumbriculidae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhynchelmis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Lake Baikal</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clitellata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Irina</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaygorodova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-39</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval anatomy of Andean tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;Telmatobius&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Ceratophryidae) from Northwestern Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper I study the oral, buccopharyngeal, and musculoskeletal configuration in tadpoles of nine &lt;i&gt;Telmatobius&lt;/i&gt; species from Northwestern Argentina (T. &lt;i&gt;atacamensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ceiorum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laticeps,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oxycephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinguiculus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pisanoi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;schreiteri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scrocchii,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephani;&lt;/i&gt; N = 30, Gosner stages 31–36). Specimens were prepared according to standard clearing and staining protocols; additionally, I applied landmark and outline-based geometric morphometric methods in order to quantify shape variation in chondrocrania, hyobranchial skeletons, and suprarostral cartilages. Although preliminary, results show a marked morphological uniformity on the analyzed levels, and overlapping interspecific and intraspecific variation, which renders species discrimination difficult. Some distinctive traits for the genus are bicuspidate buccal spurs, peculiar arrangement of buccal roof and floor papillae, tetrapartite suprarostral, adrostral cartilages, a lateral slip of the m. subarcualis rectus II-IV invading branchial septum IV, and a characteristic pattern of muscles inserted on the diaphragm. The conservative larval internal morphology in this genus could be explained by a recent speciation and a development possibly characterized by the postmetamorphic appearance of specific features.En este trabajo estudio la morfología oral, bucofaríngea y musculoesquelética de larvas de nueve especies de &lt;i&gt;Telmatobius&lt;/i&gt; del Noroeste argentino (T. &lt;i&gt;atacamensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ceiorum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laticeps,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oxycephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinguiculus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pisanoi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;schreiteri,&lt;/i&gt; T. &lt;i&gt;scrocchii&lt;/i&gt; y &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephani;&lt;/i&gt; N = 30, estadios de Gosner 31–36). Los especímenes se prepararon siguiendo protocolos clásicos de transparentación y coloración diferencial; adicionalmente, apliqué métodos de morfometría geométrica basada en landmarks y contornos para cuantificar la variación de formas en condrocráneos, esqueletos hiobranquiales y cartílagos suprarostrales. Aunque de carácter preliminar, los resultados muestran una notable uniformidad morfológica en los niveles analizados, y una variación intraespecífica que se superpone con la interespecífica, dificultando la distinción entre especies. Algunos rasgos distintivos del género son un par de espolones bucales bífidos, un arreglo particular de las papilas del techo y piso bucales, suprarostral tetrapartito, adrostrales, un haz del m. subarcualis rectus II-IV invadiendo el septo branquial IV, y un patrón aparentemente característico de los músculos insertos en el diafragma. La morfología larval interna conservadora en el género podría explicarse por una especiación reciente y un desarrollo posiblemente caracterizado por la aparición postmetamórfica de los rasgos específicos.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Telmatobius&lt;/i&gt;; tadpoles; buccal cavity; musculoskeletal configuration; geometric morphometrics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Telmatobius&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Florencia Vera</middlename>
          <lastname>Candioti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A third species of the rare frog genus &lt;i&gt;Holoaden &lt;/i&gt;(Terrarana, Strabomantidae) from a montane rainforest area of southeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the rare anuran genus &lt;i&gt;Holoaden&lt;/i&gt; is described from a montane rainforest area in Rio de Janeiro State, southeastern Brazil. The new species is characterized by its large body size, large head, moderately bulging dorsal glands, limbs long and slender, a deeply dark dorsal coloration, and dark ventral surface with a light abdominal blotch of variable size. The new species expands the range of the genus 200 km eastward in Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; Atlantic Forest; &lt;i&gt;Holoaden;&lt;/i&gt; Holoadeninae; Strabomantidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species; Atlantic Forest; &lt;i&gt;Holoaden;&lt;/i&gt; Holoadeninae; Strabomantidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pombal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Siqueira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thiago</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dorigo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Davor</firstname>
          <lastname>Vrcibradic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Frederico D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
