<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1948.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Dec. 2008</title>
    <volume>1948</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-12-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichoribates&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Jugatala &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Ceratozetidae) from the Central and Southern Alps, with notes on their distribution </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present paper deals with five species of oribatid mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Trichoribates&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, 1910 and two species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Jugatala&lt;/i&gt; Ewing, 1913 from high mountains of the Central and Southern Alps. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Trichoribates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scilierensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; collected from South Tyrol (Italy) is described in detail on the basis of adults. In addition, supplementary descriptions and illustrations of six known species, &lt;i&gt;Trichoribates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; (Trägårdh, 1902), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novus&lt;/i&gt; (Sellnick, 1928), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; Shaldybina, 1971, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; (C. L. Koch, 1835), &lt;i&gt;Jugatala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt; (C. L. Koch, 1839) and &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cribelliger&lt;/i&gt; (Berlese, 1904) are presented. &lt;i&gt;Trichoribates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time in Central Europe. The status of old generic names as well as the validity of some species are discussed. The synonymy of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oxypterus&lt;/i&gt; (Berlese, 1910) is rejected and its validity retained. The possible synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Jugatala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotunda&lt;/i&gt; Willmann, 1953 with &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt; is discussed. The distribution of all studied species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ceratozetoidea; new species; biogeography; Austria; Italy; Alps</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ceratozetoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Badamdorj</firstname>
          <lastname>Bayartogtokh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Heinrich</firstname>
          <lastname>Schatz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic assessment of ultrastructural and histological characters of teeth in the Anostomoidea, Hemiodontidae and Parodontidae (Teleostei: Ostariophysi: Characiformes)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The ultrastructure and histology of teeth of members of the order Characiformes, in conjunction with the examination of cleared and stained sections and teeth, revealed characters pertinent to understanding the relationships among the Anostomoidea (Curimatidae, Prochilodontidae, Anostomidae, and Chilodontidae), Hemiodontidae, and Parodontidae. The superimposition of these characters onto cladograms of Characiform phylogeny based on morphological and molecular characters confirmed the monophyly of the Anostomoidea, but resulted in conflicting interpretations concerning the relationships of the Hemiodontidae and Parodontidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical fishes; SEM; apatite crystals</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical fishes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <lastname>Scharcansky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Alberto S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lucena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-56</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of jumping pitviper of the genus &lt;i&gt;Atropoides &lt;/i&gt;(Serpentes: Viperidae: Crotalinae) from the Sierra de Botaderos and the Sierra La Muralla, Honduras</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of pitviper of the genus &lt;i&gt;Atropoides&lt;/i&gt; from the Sierra de Botaderos and La Muralla, Honduras. The new species is easily distinguished from all other members of the genus, except &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picadoi&lt;/i&gt; from Costa Rica and Panama, by possessing more ventral scales (140 vs. 103–138). This new species differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picadoi&lt;/i&gt; in being relatively small, less than 600 mm in total length (vs. reaching &gt; 750 mm), having the posterior third of the body venter heavily melanized (vs. more than 50%), less than 50% of the underside of the tail melanized, and the postorbital stripe covering more than 50% of only one or two scales from the first temporal row and covering completely only the last scale of the row, at most (vs. 3–4 more than 50% melanized and the last two scales in the row usually completely melanized). In addition to morphological characters, molecular evidence also differentiates this new species from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Atropoides&lt;/i&gt; (as recognized by Castoe &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2005). Using mitochondrial gene sequence data, they found the new species described herein to represent the sister species of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occiduus,&lt;/i&gt; with 5.7 % sequence divergence separating these two taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atropoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indomitus&lt;/i&gt; new species; &lt;i&gt;Atropoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occiduus&lt;/i&gt;; Colón; Middle America; Olancho; snakes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atropoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indomitus&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eric</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorge</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferrari-Castro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
