<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1964.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Dec. 2008</title>
    <volume>1964</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-12-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies in Australian Tettigoniidae: new Phaneropterine Katydids from Queensland Rainforests (Orthoptera: Tettigoniidae; Phaneropterinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New species of Phaneropterinae are described from the tropical rainforests of far north Queensland. A number of new species of the widespread Australian genus &lt;i&gt;Caedicia&lt;/i&gt; (C. &lt;i&gt;webberi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;goobita&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuranda)&lt;/i&gt; are described with notes on biology and ecology. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flexuosa&lt;/i&gt; I. Bolivar is recorded from Australia for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Currimundria&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Kurandoptera&lt;/i&gt; are described as new genera each with very distinctive species and a new species of &lt;i&gt;Ephippithyta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuranda,&lt;/i&gt; is also described from north Queensland. Two species of &lt;i&gt;Diastella&lt;/i&gt; are described, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuranda&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hilleri.&lt;/i&gt; One species of &lt;i&gt;Diastella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hilleri,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the mountains of southeast Queensland. Cytological information is presented for several taxa. A key to the relevant Australian genera in the “Group” Ephippithytae is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Australia; Phaneropterinae; rainforests; katydid; cytology; ecology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Australia; Phaneropterinae; rainforests; katydid; cytology; ecology; taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dcf</firstname>
          <lastname>Rentz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>You</firstname>
          <middlename>Ning</middlename>
          <lastname>Su</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Norhiro</firstname>
          <lastname>Ueshima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-39</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Parasitism of &lt;i&gt;Entedon costalis&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae) in &lt;i&gt;Glocianus punctiger&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera: Curculionidae): an example of intentional discovery of the parasitoid-host association</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The biology and morphology of early larval instars of &lt;i&gt;Entedon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; Dalman (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae), are described in detail for the first time. The parasitoid-host association of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; was revealed as a result of selection of candidate host based on combination of assumptions based on biology of related species and field surveys. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; proved to be an egg-larval parasitoid of the weevil &lt;i&gt;Glocianus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt; (Gyllenhal), which is associated with dandelion (Taraxacum &lt;i&gt;officinale&lt;/i&gt; G.H. Weber ex Wiggers). Parasitism rate of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt; by &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; was 25% in the model patch which was sampled in May, where infestation of dandelion inflorescence by &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt; was 27%. The female of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; lays her egg into the host egg, but the first instar larva hatches within the first instar host. Larvae of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt; start their feeding as internal flower-stalk borers, continue as seed-eaters in flowerheads, and then pupate underground when matured coincident with seed dispersal (generally in the end of May). Parasitized and unparasitized mature larvae of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt; pupate underground, in earthen cells, where the parasitoid larvae finally consume their hosts and pupate 2–3 days thereafter. Adults of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; emerge the following spring (about mid April), as dandelions being flowering. The morphology of immature stages and behaviour of adults is described. Various peculiarities of parasitoidhost relationships superparasitism, siblicide, host immune response are described and discussed. DNA sequences of the nuclear 28S D2 rDNA gene were obtained for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chalcidoidea; Entedoninae; &lt;i&gt;Entedon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Glocianus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiger&lt;/i&gt;; dandelion; preimaginal and adult morphology; superparasitism; siblicide</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chalcidoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alex</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gumovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
