<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1817.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1817</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of &lt;i&gt;Boreoheptagyia&lt;/i&gt; Brundin, 1966 (Chironomidae: Diamesinae) from East Asia and bordering territories, with the description of five new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Boreoheptagyia&lt;/i&gt; Brundin, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alulasetosa&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko, Wu &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ambigua&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko, Wu &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepalensis&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Endo, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sasai&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Endo, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xinglongiensis&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko, Wu &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from East Asia and bordering territories are described and figured as males. Six additional species are commented on: &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevitarsis&lt;/i&gt; (Tokunaga), &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kurobebrevis&lt;/i&gt; (Sasa &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Okazawa), &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotunda&lt;/i&gt; Serra-Tosio, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; (Chaudhuri &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Ghosh), &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetica&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Wang, and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unica&lt;/i&gt; Makarchenko. A key to the males of &lt;i&gt;Boreoheptagyia&lt;/i&gt; from East Asia and bordering territories is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chironomidae; Diamesinae; &lt;i&gt;Boreoheptagyia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; East Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eugenyi</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Makarchenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kazuo</firstname>
          <lastname>Endo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jingyang</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xinhua</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The leafhopper subgenus &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Matsumurasca&lt;/i&gt;) from China (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae: Empoascini), with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The empoascine leafhopper subgenus &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt; (Matsumurasca) Anufriev is redescribed. Four species, including three new species from China are reported: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (M.) &lt;i&gt;clypeata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (M.) &lt;i&gt;biloba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (M.) &lt;i&gt;quadrifida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; New distributional records for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (M.) &lt;i&gt;onukii&lt;/i&gt; Matsuda are provided. A key to distinguish all species of the subgenus worldwide is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homoptera; &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt; (Matsumurasca); distribution; taxonomy; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dao-Zheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Qin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ya-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-26</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ephemeroptera and Plecoptera biodiversity in central Patagonia, Chubut province, Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Aquatic insects in Central Patagonia (Andean region), Argentina, have received poor and fragmentary attention. In this paper we present the first preliminary inventory of Plecoptera and Ephemeroptera taxa for the area and include seasonal records of adult stages. We incorporate a set of environmental features for the sampling sites and biotopes as well as the main characteristics of the phytogeographical and biogeographical areas in which the species were found. Twelve species and eight genera of mayflies and eleven species and five genera of stoneflies are recorded for the first time in Chubut province. The stoneflies &lt;i&gt;Neofulla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biloba&lt;/i&gt; (Aubert), &lt;i&gt;Alfonsoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flinti&lt;/i&gt; McLellan &amp; Zwick, &lt;i&gt;Austronemoura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eudoxiae&lt;/i&gt; Froehlich, &lt;i&gt;Chilenoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semitincta&lt;/i&gt; Illies, &lt;i&gt;Neonemura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi&lt;/i&gt; Zwick and &lt;i&gt;Potamoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; Vera, and the mayflies &lt;i&gt;Andesiops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ardua&lt;/i&gt; (Lugo-Ortiz &amp; McCafferty), &lt;i&gt;Chaquihua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bullocki&lt;/i&gt; Navás. And the family Oniscigastridae are new records for Argentina. The genera &lt;i&gt;Americabaetis&lt;/i&gt; Kluge, &lt;i&gt;Camelobaetidius&lt;/i&gt; Demoulin and &lt;i&gt;Traverella&lt;/i&gt; Edmunds are confirmed for first time in the Andean region (Central Patagonia province) and four Plecoptera and two Ephemeroptera species constitute new records for the Patagonian steppe. We also include two new records for Ephemeroptera and Plecoptera for the Santa Cruz province. We reinforce the idea that patagonian aquatic environments have a highly specialized and complex insect fauna which can be correlated with biogeographical aspects but also with a great environmental heterogeneity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new records; inventory; Patagonia; Ephemeroptera; Plecoptera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new records</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <lastname>Pessacq</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Laura</middlename>
          <lastname>Miserendino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">North American species of &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips &lt;/i&gt;Diaz (Hymenoptera: Figitidae: Eucoilinae), parasitoids of Agromyzidae (Diptera): bionomics and taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt; Diaz is redescribed, as well as two species endemic to the Nearctic: &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diastrophi&lt;/i&gt; (Ashmead) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robusta&lt;/i&gt; (Ashmead). Previous to this study, only Neotropical species of &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt; were well diagnosed both taxonomically and biologically. &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt; belongs to the &lt;i&gt;Zaeucoila&lt;/i&gt; group of genera, which are Neotropical eucoilines that principally parasitize Agromyzidae (Diptera); among these genera, species of &lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt; are some of the few representatives that are found in the Nearctic. Detailed host records and biological notes are provided for the Nearctic species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phytomyza&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Liriomyza&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Agromyza&lt;/i&gt;; Agromyzidae; Eucoilinae; Figitidae; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agrostocynips&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Buffington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sonja</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Scheffer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Minute larvae of Leptotyphlinae (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae): description of three genera with discussion on the monophyly and phylogenetic position of the subfamily as inferred from larval morphology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">External morphology of larvae belonging to three unidentified genera of the rove-beetle subfamily Leptotyphlinae (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae) collected in Mexico, Chile and Australia, respectively, is described and illustrated. Larvae of Leptotyphlinae can be distinguished from all other Staphylinoidea larvae by the combination of their small size (maximum documented head width 0.128 mm), along with complete absence of eyes, lyriform frontal ecdysial lines, long coronal suture extending for about 40% of head length, short antennae not longer than 1/3 of head length, non-serrate mandibles with a single pre-apical tooth, tibiotarsi swollen in middle with two ventral spines, and indistinctly articulated short urogomphi not longer than twice their basal width. At least some of these characters are likely to support monophyly of the subfamily. Leptotyphlinae are hypothesized to belong to the Staphylinine Group of subfamilies sharing with at least some of them the following larval characters: labrum fully fused with clypeus; posterior tentorial arms extremely thin, thread-like and more than 20 times longer than wide; posterior tentorial pits short, rounded to elongate; cardo lacking transverse sclerotized ridge. The sister-group relationships of Leptotyphlinae to a clade of Pseudopsinae+Paederinae+Staphylininae is hypothesized with the following larval characters in support: lyriform frontal arms; each maxilla articulated laterally to head capsule by a condyle; maxillary mala parallel-sided (=finger-shaped) and articulated to stipes. A larval identification key to all three presently described genera is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">rove beetles; Staphylinidae; Leptotyphlinae; Neotyphlini; larvae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">rove beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vasily</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grebennikov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfred</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Newton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Idiopyrgota&lt;/i&gt; Aczel (Diptera, Pyrgotidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Aczél established the genus &lt;i&gt;Idiopyrgota&lt;/i&gt; to place a single species, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setiventris,&lt;/i&gt; based on an analysis of eight females from Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil. The species is redescribed on the basis of new available material from the type locality as well as one female specimen from Jujuy, Argentina (this is the first record of this species in this area). Adult anatomical structures are described and illustrated in detail, including information of the previously unknown male and female spermathecae. This study provides better grounds for the recognition of the taxon.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tephritoidea; Pyrgotinae; Pyrgotini; scarabaeid beetles; parasite</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tephritoidea; Pyrgotinae; Pyrgotini; scarabaeid beetles; parasite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ramon</firstname>
          <middlename>Luciano</middlename>
          <lastname>Mello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Jose Einicker</middlename>
          <lastname>Lamas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new monotypic genus of ant-mimicking Coraebini (Coleoptera: Buprestidae: Agrilinae ) from Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bellamy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
