<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1761.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 May. 2008</title>
    <volume>1761</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; Brian, 1919 (Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Ectinosomatidae) from cold-water corals in the Porcupine Seabight (NE Atlantic)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first deep-sea representative of &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; Brian, 1919 is described from samples of dead cold-water coral fragments, glass sponge skeletons and underlying sediment collected from the Porcupine Seabight (NE Atlantic). &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lopheliae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from its congeners by the dimensions of the P1 endopod and the position of the inner seta on its proximal segment. Moreover, we present the first description of a male in this genus. The occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; and three other ectinosomatid genera with prehensile first legs is remarkable in the deep sea and an indication that the hard substrates of the coral degradation zone may provide an exceptional habitat. A key to the five species of &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ectinosomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Halophytophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lopheliae&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; deep sea; &lt;i&gt;Lophelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pertusa&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ectinosomatidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Gheerardyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sybille</firstname>
          <lastname>Seifried</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ann</firstname>
          <lastname>Vanreusel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A re-description of &lt;i&gt;Accalathura crenulata&lt;/i&gt; (Richardson, 1901) from type material and the description of two new &lt;i&gt;Accalathura&lt;/i&gt; species (Crustacea: Isopoda: Cymothoida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of leptanthurid isopods in the genus &lt;i&gt;Accalathura&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schotteae,&lt;/i&gt; from collections off Panama and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kensleyi&lt;/i&gt; from Belize (material previously identified as &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenulata&lt;/i&gt; in the collections of the National Museum of Natural History, Washington D.C.). The type species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;Calathura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenulata&lt;/i&gt; Richardson, 1901, is redescribed from type material and a key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Accalathura&lt;/i&gt; in the Caribbean and an adjacent region is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cymothoida; Anthuroidea; Leptanthuridae; &lt;i&gt;Accalathura&lt;/i&gt;; Caribbean; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schotteae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kensleyi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenulata&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cymothoida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rachael</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>King</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-29</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Coreodrassus&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Gnaphosidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The formerly monotypic spider genus &lt;i&gt;Coreodrassus&lt;/i&gt; Paik, 1984, belonging to the family Gnaphosidae, is reviewed. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Coreodrassus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described, and the type species, &lt;i&gt;Coreodrassus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lancearius&lt;/i&gt; (Simon, 1893) is redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gnaphosidae; &lt;i&gt;Coreodrassus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; northwest China; Xinjiang</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gnaphosidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>30-36</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and subspecies descriptions do not and should not always require a dead type specimen</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Dubois &amp; Nemésio (2007) recently considered that the present International Code for Zoological Nomenclature (“Code”) could reasonably be interpreted as requiring the deposition of dead vouchers for new species and subspecies descriptions. They considered that, to the extent that there is lack of clarity, the Code should be amended so as to require the deposition of a dead voucher. They doubted the utility of photographs and other materials for descriptions and suggested that ethical or moral concerns about the taking of dead type specimens were poorly supported. Dubois &amp; Nemésio (2007)’s preferred interpretations of the current Code are not supported by members of the Commission. Possible reasons why the collection of a dead type specimen might not be necessary or recommended include the setting of a good example to communities in whose hands conservation action lies, government permit issues and the description of new taxa on the brink of extinction where collecting may impact populations. The Code should be liberal in relation to the nature of type specimens to enable taxonomists, who are the persons best placed to take decisions, to make appropriate judgments for particular descriptions.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nomenclatural availability; vouchers; collections; type specimen; illustrations; samples; ethics; DNA sequences; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; Commission</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nomenclatural availability</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donegan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two sympatric new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Strabomantidae) from Yanachaga Chemillen National Park (central Peruvian Andes) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two sympatric new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Strabomantidae) are described from elfin forests and puna grasslands (3363–3589 m) of the eastern slopes of the Andes of Departamento Pasco in central Peru. &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miroslawae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a medium-sized species characterized by lacking vomerine teeth and tympanic membrane, and by having dorsolateral folds, areolate ventral skin, dorsum gray with black spots, venter cream with small scattered black blotches, and iris bronze. &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nicoleae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a small species characterized by lacking tympanic membrane and by having vomerine teeth, an X-shaped middorsal fold, ventral skin areolate, dorsum tan with black stripes and bluish tubercles, and iris bronze with black reticulations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; Anura; new species; Peru; &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ignacio</firstname>
          <lastname>De La Riva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A large and enigmatic new eleutherodactyline frog (Anura, Strabomantidae) from Serra do Sincora Espinhaco range, Northeastern Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of a large eleutherodactyline frog from the mountain rocky meadows (“campos rupestres”) of the Serra do Sincorá, Espinhaço mountain range, Mucugê municipality, State of Bahia, Brazil. The new species is promptly diagnosed from all the other Brazilian eleutherodactylines by its large size (males SVL 40.3–41.1; females SVL 75.2–79.7mm), broad head (head width 43–49% of SVL), presence of frontoparietal crests, &lt;i&gt;pars&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fascialis&lt;/i&gt; of the maxilla deepened, discs absent on fingers, toes with poorly developed discs, first and second toes ridged, and tarsal fold absent. On the basis of these characters the new species is attributed to the genus &lt;i&gt;Strabomantis&lt;/i&gt; up to now restricted to southern part of Central America and northwest part of South America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Strabomantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aramunha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; Strabomantidae; Amphibia; Atlantic forest; Campos rupestres; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Strabomantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aramunha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <lastname>Cassimiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vanessa</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Verdade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
