<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1775.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 May. 2008</title>
    <volume>1775</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Homalopoltys&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Araneidae) with the genus &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Tetragnathidae) and descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Through discovery of their males, females described as &lt;i&gt;Homalopoltys&lt;/i&gt; Simon (Araneidae) are found to be congeneric with &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; O.P.-Cambridge (Tetragnathidae). Some of the character states seen in &lt;i&gt;Homalopoltys&lt;/i&gt; (type species &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incanescens&lt;/i&gt; Simon) do not fit within the current diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; so the potential transfer is tested using the data matrix of Hormiga &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (1995). It is found that the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Homalopoltys&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; is justified according to current terms of reference. Both described &lt;i&gt;Homalopoltys&lt;/i&gt; species were known only from Sri Lanka. The male of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incanescens&lt;/i&gt; (Simon) (NEW COMBINATION) is described for the first time, and the range of this species is extended to north-eastern Australia. &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albida&lt;/i&gt; (Simon) (NEW COMBINATION) is redescribed and new material is reported from Thailand but the species is still known only from females. &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mandibularis&lt;/i&gt; (Thorell), with similar morphology to &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incanescens,&lt;/i&gt; is also redescribed but is only known from a single male (Sumatra). Two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deelemanae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is from Kalimantan and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raveni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is from north-eastern Australia and New Guinea. The character states that unite the genus &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; are discussed and some potential new character systems are put forward. Some of the fresh specimens of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albida&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incanescens&lt;/i&gt; show that reflective tapeta are present in the secondary eyes and the abdominal morphology of these and the newly described species differs from that of other known &lt;i&gt;Dolichognatha&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Canoe tapetum; Sri Lanka; Borneo; Thailand; Sumatra; New Guinea; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Canoe tapetum</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Helen</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Separation of &lt;i&gt;Pleuroxus pamirensis &lt;/i&gt;(Werestschagin, 1923) from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annandalei &lt;/i&gt;(Daday, 1908) (Cladocera: Chydoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Lateral horns on valves are found in few representatives from different families of the Anomopoda (Crustacea: Cladocera). We found that populations of "horned" &lt;i&gt;Pleuroxus&lt;/i&gt; Baird, 1843 from mountains of Central Asia belong to two different species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pamirensis&lt;/i&gt; (Werestschagin, 1923) present in Pamirs, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annandalei&lt;/i&gt; (Daday, 1908), occuring in Tibetan Plateau, Baikal Rift System and Mongolian Altai. Redescriptions and a list of differences between the species are presented. Genera &lt;i&gt;Cornuella&lt;/i&gt; Werestschagin, 1923 and &lt;i&gt;Sinopleuroxus&lt;/i&gt; Chiang Sieh-chih, 1963 are suggested junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Pleuroxus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Branchiopoda; Anomopoda; taxonomy; fauna; Central Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Branchiopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexey</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kotov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Natalia</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sheveleva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Syphacia (Syphacia)&lt;/i&gt; Seurat (Nematoda: Oxyuridae) from &lt;i&gt;Pseudomys &lt;/i&gt;species (Rodentia: Muridae) from central Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Syphacia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicaudata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the desert rodents &lt;i&gt;Pseudomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desertor&lt;/i&gt; Troughton, 1936 and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hermannsburgensis&lt;/i&gt; (Waite, 1896); &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Syphacia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudomyos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hermannsburgensis&lt;/i&gt; from western Queensland and central Northern Territory, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Syphacia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicaudata&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; by having a suite of characters including an oval, dorsally and ventrally constricted cephalic plate, no cervical alae, a relatively short tail and two pairs of post-anal papillae. &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Syphacia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudomyos&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; by having a suite of characters including an oval, dorsally and ventrally constricted cephalic plate, no cervical or lateral alae, one pair of post-anal papillae, a relatively short tail and large eggs. Females of a putative species were distinct due to the lack of a cephalic plate but had other characters consistent with the genus. Two other putative species of &lt;i&gt;Syphacia,&lt;/i&gt; females only, also collected from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hermannsburgensis&lt;/i&gt; and having oval dorsally and ventrally constricted cephalic plates, could be distinguished from their congeners by a combination of characters including the presence of cervical alae, &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; sp. 2, and a protruding vulva, &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt; sp. 3. These new species are the first records of oxyurid nematodes from the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudomys,&lt;/i&gt; and from Australian arid-zone rodents.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; Oxyuridae; Muridae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudomys&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Syphacia&lt;/i&gt;; desert; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Weaver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton &lt;/i&gt;(Caudata: Salamandridae) from Guizhou Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of salamander, &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhijinensis,&lt;/i&gt; from Guizhou Province, China. The generic allocation of the new species is based on morphological and molecular characters. In morphology, it is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; but differs in having distinct gland emitting a malodorous secretion (here named scent gland), a postocular stripe, and two non-continuous, dorsolateral stripes on the dorsolateral ridges. Furthermore, neoteny was observed in most individuals of the new species. This has not been previously reported to occur in any other species of &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton.&lt;/i&gt; Analysis of our molecular data suggests that this species a third major evolutionary lineage in the genus &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caudata; Salamandridae; &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhijinensis;&lt;/i&gt; new species; scent gland; Guizhou; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caudata; Salamandridae; &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhijinensis;&lt;/i&gt; new species; scent gland; Guizhou; China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Haitao</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jing</firstname>
          <lastname>Che</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weiwei</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yongxiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Haipeng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ya-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; Manning, 1995 (Crustacea: Stomatopoda: Squillidae) from the Indo-West Pacific region with a key to the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of stomatopod crustacean, &lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nordica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from the Indo-West Pacific region (type locality: Taiwan). It is most similar to &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quinquedentata&lt;/i&gt; (Brooks, 1886), with which it has been confused. &lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quinquedendata&lt;/i&gt; is presently known only from the southern hemisphere, and most of its northern hemisphere records are referable to &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nordica.&lt;/i&gt; Records of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quinquedentata&lt;/i&gt; from India and Sri Lanka require confirmation, possibly representing a third species. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nordica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Stomatopoda; taxonomy; Indo-West Pacific region; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oratosquillina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nordica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
