<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1801.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Jun. 2008</title>
    <volume>1801</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-06-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cladistics, classification and identification of the brachycercine mayflies (Insecta: Ephemeroptera: Caenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The mayfly subfamily Brachycercinae (Pannota: Caenidae) is redefined and shown to be an apotypic, monophyletic group based on numerous synapomorphies, including, for example in the larvae, the presence of ocellar tubercles, an anterior row of long setae on the larval head capsule, a patch of long setae posterior to the base of the glossae, a broad prosternum, and the absence of toothlike claw denticles. Over 100 morphological characters of larvae, adults, and eggs discovered to be useful for phylogenetic analysis and diagnoses are detailed and illustrated. Thirty-eight species are recognized among the genera &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus&lt;/i&gt; Curtis, &lt;i&gt;Caenoculis&lt;/i&gt; Soldán, &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys&lt;/i&gt; Soldán, &lt;i&gt;Insulibrachys&lt;/i&gt; Soldán, &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Oriobrachys,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Latineosus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Susperatus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., and &lt;i&gt;Alloretochus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., by adopting a strictly phylogenetic classification, including a first tribal classification within the subfamily. &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ojibwe,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fox,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lilliei,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pomeiok,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;winnebago,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;Latineosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cayo,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cibola,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;Oriobrachys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahakam,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choctaw,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coushatta,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miccosukee,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., and &lt;i&gt;Susperatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonkawa,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. are newly described. The Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;articus&lt;/i&gt; Soldán, n. syn., and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edmundsi&lt;/i&gt; Soldán, n. syn., are shown to be equivalent to &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harrisella&lt;/i&gt; Curtis, proving the latter to be a widespread Holarctic species. &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capnicus&lt;/i&gt; (Zhou, Sun and McCafferty), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corniger&lt;/i&gt; (Kluge), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;europaeus&lt;/i&gt; (Kluge), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilliesi&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán and Landa), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; (Gose), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kabyliensis&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacustris&lt;/i&gt; (Needham), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Berner), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nasutus&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tubulatus&lt;/i&gt; (Tshernova), n. comb., &lt;i&gt;Susperatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prudens&lt;/i&gt; (McDunnough), n. comb., and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., are transferred from &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Alloretochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruanicus&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., and &lt;i&gt;Latineosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colombianus&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., are transferred from &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dangi&lt;/i&gt; (Soldán), n. comb., is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Caenoculis&lt;/i&gt; and Brachycercinae to Caeninae, and provisionally placed in &lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt; Stephens. &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; (Traver), n. comb., is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus&lt;/i&gt; and considered to be a nomen dubium. Nomenclatural history, new or revised descriptions as appropriate, diagnoses, illustrations, and keys are provided for known stage of species. Origins and evolutionary relationships of the Brachycercinae are hypothesized based on cladistic results. Brachycercinae is considered to have originated from a &lt;i&gt;Caenis-like&lt;/i&gt; ancestor. The genera &lt;i&gt;Cae-&lt;/i&gt;WORLD BRACHYCERCINAE&lt;i&gt;noculis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Insulibrachys&lt;/i&gt; represent more ancestral lineages, whereas the genera &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oriobrachys,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Latineosus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Susperatus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., &lt;i&gt;Alloretochus,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., and &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys&lt;/i&gt; appear more derived. &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pomeiok&lt;/i&gt; and other closely related species are most apotypic in terms of numbers of accumulated apomorphies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachycercinae; Caenidae; &lt;i&gt;Brachycercus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cercobrachys&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Insulibrachys&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Caenoculis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sparbarus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Oriobrachys&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Latineosus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Susperatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Alloretochus&lt;/i&gt;; mayflies; Ephemeroptera; systematics; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachycercinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lu</firstname>
          <middlename>Sun And W. P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccafferty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-239</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
