<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1764.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 May. 2008</title>
    <volume>1764</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A remarkable new genus of carnivorous, sessile bivalves (Mollusca: Anomalodesmata: Poromyidae) with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dilemma,&lt;/i&gt; a new genus of sessile septibranch bivalves is described. The new taxon encompasses at least three species, of which two are new: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frumarkernorum&lt;/i&gt; new species, from off the Florida Keys, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spectralis&lt;/i&gt; new species, from off Vanuatu, and &lt;i&gt;“Corculum”&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inexpectatum&lt;/i&gt; Crozier, 1966, from off the Three Kings Islands, New Zealand, known only from its shell. The absence of ctenidia and presence of a septum, size and arrangement of siphons and siphonal tentacles, extensive fusion of the mantle margins allocate the new genus within the septibranch bivalves. A siphonal area with 15 tentacles, a large and eversible incurrent siphon, ostial apertures in the septum, and a hermaphroditic reproductive system suggest inclusion in the Poromyidae. The presence of three paired groups of septal ostia in the new genus is a feature shared with poromyids in the genus &lt;i&gt;Cetoconcha.&lt;/i&gt; Unusual symmetry and form constitute the most striking features of the new genus. There is a strong anteroposterior compression and lateral expansion associated with ca. 30º rotation of the largest dimension (height) in relation to the anteroposterior axis. The shell hinge includes a single tooth and socket on each valve, and an external, but deeply sunken ligament. The two new species, mutually distinguishable by shell and anatomical characters, are known from live-collected specimens found adhering to rocks by means of robust byssus, which indicates attachment for life. The presence of ostracod remains in the digestive tract of one specimen of one of the new species and of a cirolanid isopod in the stomach of the holotype of the second new species are evidence of predation. Although predation by infaunal and free-living bivalves is known to occur throughout the Anomalodesmata, in particular within the septibranchs, discovery of the new genus reveals an unusual instance of predation by sessile, permanently attached mollusks.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Septibranchia; &lt;i&gt;Dilemma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cetoconcha&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Poromya&lt;/i&gt;; deep-sea; bathyal</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Septibranchia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on morphology and ecological difference between species of pontoniine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Crinotonia&lt;/i&gt; Marin (Caridea: Palaemonidae) associated with shallow-water feather stars &lt;i&gt;Phanogenia&lt;/i&gt; spp. (Crinoidea: Comasteridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Freshly collected material of the pontoniine genus &lt;i&gt;Crinotonia&lt;/i&gt; Marin, 2006 allows ecological separation of two known species. &lt;i&gt;Crinotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attenuatus&lt;/i&gt; (Bruce, 1971) inhabits the common yellow feather star &lt;i&gt;Phanogenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; (Hartlaub, 1890) (Crinoidea: Comasteridae) whereas С &lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anastasiae&lt;/i&gt; Marin, 2006 is a symbiont of the black-colored &lt;i&gt;Phanogenia&lt;/i&gt; sp., probably, &lt;i&gt;Phanogenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multibrachiata&lt;/i&gt; (Carpenter, 1888) or an undescribed comasterid species. The species of &lt;i&gt;Crinotonia&lt;/i&gt; are also distinguished by coloration, size and depth range with С &lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anastasiae&lt;/i&gt; being smaller and deeper dwelling than &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antenuatus.&lt;/i&gt; Remarks on coloration, morphology and ecology of the shrimps and hosts are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Palaemonidae; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Crinotonia&lt;/i&gt;; coloration; ecology; crinoids; &lt;i&gt;Phanogenia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Palaemonidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola chabadamsoni&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;G. tba&lt;/i&gt; (Dinnik 1933) (Nematoda, Oxyuroidea) from tadpoles of the hybridogenetic complex &lt;i&gt;Rana lessonae-esculenta&lt;/i&gt; (Amphibia, Ranoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two morphological types of the viviparous oxyurid nematode &lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt; were recovered from waterfrog tadpoles in France (Ain department, Rhône-Alpes region) and assigned to two species: &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tba&lt;/i&gt; (Dinnik 1930), redescribed, and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chabadamsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tba&lt;/i&gt; is close to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batrachiensis&lt;/i&gt; (Walton 1929) and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chabaudi&lt;/i&gt; Araujo and Artigas 1982 in that the female possesses a long tail and few cuticular buccal flaps. The new species, type host &lt;i&gt;Rana&lt;/i&gt; kl. &lt;i&gt;esculenta,&lt;/i&gt; is distinct by several characters: in females, by the 12 cuticular buccal flaps with internal crests, short caudal filament, short ovary producing embryonated eggs and large uterine pouch containing males and embryos, like in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti 1938, and narrower thick-shelled eggs with subapical elongated operculum; in males, by the round genital cone, the third caudal pair of papillae at mid tail, length of the body and caudal part. &lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tba&lt;/i&gt; and the new species were found in &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lessonae&lt;/i&gt; and in the hybrid &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; kl. &lt;i&gt;esculenta&lt;/i&gt; but each with different seasonal infection rates. Comparative analyses of the data from the five &lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt; species were done. All females have one genital tract producing thick-shelled female eggs. The second genital tract is one of four types corresponding to different reproductive patterns: i) it forms a uterine pouch containing males in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chabadamsoni&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica;&lt;/i&gt; ii) it forms a slender uterus containing numerous autoinfective larval stages in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batrachiensis&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clamitans;&lt;/i&gt; iii) it forms a slender uterus containing only a few embryos in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tba&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chabaudi;&lt;/i&gt; and iv) it has regressed in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batrachiensis&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americanus.&lt;/i&gt; Haplodiploidy is expected or proved for types i) and ii) and thelytoky for types iii) and iv).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt;; Oxyuroidea; tadpoles; &lt;i&gt;Rana&lt;/i&gt;; uterine pouch; viviparous; haplodiploidy; thelitoky</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gyrinicola&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Planade</firstname>
          <lastname>Brigitte</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bain</firstname>
          <lastname>Odile</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lena</firstname>
          <lastname>Jean-Paul</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Joly</firstname>
          <lastname>Pierre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new jellyfishes (Cnidaria: Scyphozoa) from tropical Australian waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of scyphozoan jellyfishes from tropical Australian waters are described. The first, &lt;i&gt;Sanderia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pampinosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from waters off northern Western Australia, represents the first record of the genus from Australia. It differs from its only other congener, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malayensis&lt;/i&gt; Goette, 1886, in having: (1) almost double the number of gonadal papillae at about half the body size; (2) horseshoe-shaped gonadal rings; and (3) eradial tentacles that are flattened in the oral-aboral direction and have nematocyst clusters on all sides. The second species, &lt;i&gt;Netrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Great Barrier Reef region, has been erroneously identified in the past as &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coerulescens.&lt;/i&gt; Species distinctions in the genus rely on the number and relative position of warts or papillae on the central dome; in contrast, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda&lt;/i&gt; lacks warts and papillae, and instead has a large gelatinous knob at the apex of the bell. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Netrostoma&lt;/i&gt; is provided, along with a synoptic list of previous reports of scyphozoans in tropical Australian waters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">tropical Australia; Western Australia; Northern Territory; Queensland; Scyphozoa; Pelagiidae; Cepheidae; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">tropical Australia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lisa-Ann</firstname>
          <lastname>Gershwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zeidler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cave millipeds of the United States. VII. New species and records of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudotremia&lt;/i&gt; Cope. I. Species from West Virginia, USA (Diplopoda, Chordeumatida, Cleidogonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The milliped genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudotremia&lt;/i&gt; as it occurs in West Virginia, USA, is reviewed, with new records, mostly from caves. Four new species, &lt;i&gt;Pseudotremia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;handi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kerboi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fongi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schneiderae&lt;/i&gt; are described, for a total known West Virginia fauna of 11 species, though additional species are predicted to occur. &lt;i&gt;Pseudotremia&lt;/i&gt; species could be useful model organisms for the study of speciation and phylogeography in cave-dwelling animals.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Troglobionts; speleobiology; caves; West Virginia; &lt;i&gt;Pseudotremia&lt;/i&gt;; Cleidogonidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Troglobionts</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shear</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-65</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery of the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Ditaxodon taeniatus&lt;/i&gt; (Peters in Hensel, 1868) (Serpentes: Colubridae) and invalidation of the neotype designation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renato</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bernils</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christoph</firstname>
          <lastname>Kucharzewski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julio</firstname>
          <middlename>Cesar</middlename>
          <lastname>De Moura-Leite</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Axel</firstname>
          <lastname>Kwet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-05-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
