<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1735.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Mar. 2008</title>
    <volume>1735</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-03-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Catalogue of the Stick and Leaf-insects (Phasmatodea) of China, with a faunistic analysis, review of recent ecological and biological studies and bibliography (Insecta: Orthoptera: Phasmatodea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A complete taxonomic catalogue of the Stick and Leaf-insects (Phasmatodea) recorded or described from the mainland China (excluding Taiwan) is presented. 241 valid species are listed, which are currently attributed to 50 genera, 5 families and 7 subfamilies. Genera and species are listed alphabetically. All available type-data is provided based mainly on literary sources for species described by Chinese workers from 1986 to 2006, including documented depository of typespecimens. The catalogue therefore also provides complete lists of the type-material of Phasmatodea housed in the following Chinese institutions: Administration of Baishuijiang Natural Reserve (ABNR), Beijing Forestry University, Beijing (BFU), China Agricultural University, Beijing (CAU), Geological Museum of China, Beijing (GMC), Inca Science Ltd., Chongqing (INCA), Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing (IZCAS), Department of Biology, Nankai University, Tianjin (NKU), Northwest Sci-Tech University of Agriculture and Forestry, Shaanxi (NWAU), Institute of Zoology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi’an (SNU), Institute of Entomology, Sun Yat-sen University (ICRI), Shanghai Institute of Entomology, Academia Sinica, Shanghai (SIES), Tianjin Natural History Museum, Tianjin (TMNH), Zhejiang Museum of Natural History, Hangzhou (ZMNH). The known distribution of each species, inmeans of provinces is provided as well. 14 species are shown to have been recorded from China in error, several of these based on misidentifications. The “Phasmatodea-like” fossil taxa described from the Late Jurassic Yixian Formation of North Hebei and West Liaoning are listed in a separate section. Two new generic synonyms are recognized: &lt;i&gt;Arthminotus&lt;/i&gt; Bi, 1995 synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Lopaphus&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1859 (n. &lt;b&gt;syn.)&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Dianphasma&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1997 synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Parasosibia&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 (n. &lt;b&gt;syn.).&lt;/b&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Linocerus&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835 (Type-species: &lt;i&gt;Linocerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835) was erroneously synonymised with the mediterranean &lt;i&gt;Bacillus&lt;/i&gt; St. Fargeau &amp; Audinet-Serville, 1825 and is here re-established in Phasmatidae: Pachymorphinae: Gratidiini (rev. &lt;b&gt;stat.).&lt;/b&gt; Relationship to &lt;i&gt;Clonaria&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 (= &lt;i&gt;Gratidia&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875, = &lt;i&gt;Paraclonaria&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1893), &lt;i&gt;Sceptrophasma&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Seow-Choen, 2000 and &lt;i&gt;Macellina&lt;/i&gt; Uvarov, 1940 is obvious. 21 species are transferred to other genera (new &lt;b&gt;combinations):&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Asceles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dilatatus&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 2004 and &lt;i&gt;Asceles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadriguttatus&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1996 to &lt;i&gt;Pachyscia&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908, &lt;i&gt;Arthminotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; Bi, 1995 to &lt;i&gt;Lopaphus&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1859, &lt;i&gt;Baculum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolichocercatum&lt;/i&gt; Bi &amp; Wang, 1998 and &lt;i&gt;Baculum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;politum&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1997 to &lt;i&gt;Medauroidea&lt;/i&gt; Zompro, 1999, &lt;i&gt;Dixippus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hainanensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 2002, &lt;i&gt;Dixippus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huapingensis&lt;/i&gt; Bi &amp; Li, 1991, &lt;i&gt;Dixippus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigroantennatus&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 2002, &lt;i&gt;Dixippus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 2002 and &lt;i&gt;Entoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bobaiensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen, 1986 to &lt;i&gt;Lonchodes&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obvius&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1995 to &lt;i&gt;Sinophasma&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1940, &lt;i&gt;Paramyronides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biconiferus&lt;/i&gt; Bi, 1993, &lt;i&gt;Paramyronides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leishanensis&lt;/i&gt; Bi, 1992, &lt;i&gt;Lonchodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1907, &lt;i&gt;Lonchodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confucius&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1859 and &lt;i&gt;Phasgania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glabra&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1940 to &lt;i&gt;Phraortes&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875, &lt;i&gt;Gratidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bituberculata&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1889 and &lt;i&gt;Leptynia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xinganensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1993 to &lt;i&gt;Sceptrophasma&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Seow-Choen, 2002, &lt;i&gt;Prosentoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bannaensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1997 to &lt;i&gt;Paraentoria&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 1997, and &lt;i&gt;Mantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;squeleton&lt;/i&gt; Olivier, 1792 to &lt;i&gt;Phanocloidea&lt;/i&gt; Zompro, 2002. &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sichuanensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; He, 2001 remains of unknown generic assignment, but is shown to be not a member of the Australian genus &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835. Furthermore, as &lt;i&gt;Baculum&lt;/i&gt; Saussure, 1861 is a neotropical genus and most Old World species previously attributed to this genus are now listed in &lt;i&gt;Ramulus&lt;/i&gt; Saussure, 1861, all Chinese species described in &lt;i&gt;Baculum&lt;/i&gt; Saussure are consequently transferred to &lt;i&gt;Ramulus&lt;/i&gt; Saussure. Other changes of specific placements are based on published literature and concern to the following three synonymies not recognized by Chinese workers: &lt;i&gt;Abrosoma&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1906 (= &lt;i&gt;Prosceles&lt;/i&gt; Uvarov, 1940), &lt;i&gt;Necroscia&lt;/i&gt; Audinet-Serville, 1838 (= &lt;i&gt;Aruanoidea&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908), &lt;i&gt;Lopaphus&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1859 (= &lt;i&gt;Paramyronides&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908). &lt;i&gt;Megalophasma&lt;/i&gt; Bi, 1995 is transferred from Necrosciinae to Lonchodinae. Four lectotypes are designated and three new specific synonyms revealed. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Rhamphophasma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modestus&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1893, the type-species of &lt;i&gt;Rhamphophasma&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1893, in order to fix this genus and species. The male paralectotype is shown to be a male of &lt;i&gt;Parapachymorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigra&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1893, the type-species of &lt;i&gt;Parapachymorpha&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1893. &lt;i&gt;Clitumnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;porrectus&lt;/i&gt; Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1907 is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Bacillus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;?&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artemis&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1859 and a lectotype designated for the former (n. &lt;b&gt;syn.).&lt;/b&gt; A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Oxyartes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamellatus&lt;/i&gt; Kirby, 1904 in order to fix this taxon and confirm the synonymy established by Dohrn, 1910 (= &lt;i&gt;Oxyartes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;honestus&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908, = &lt;i&gt;Oxyartes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosissimus&lt;/i&gt; Carl, 1913). &lt;i&gt;Paracentema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephanus&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 is shown to have been erroneously synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Neohirasea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; (de Haan, 1842) and here synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Neohirasea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maerens&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner v. Wattenwyl, 1907) (n. &lt;b&gt;syn.).&lt;/b&gt; In order to fix this new synonymy a lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Paracentema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephanus&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908. Finally, a biogeographic analysis of the Chinese phasmid fauna is presented. This includes brief background information on the topography and biogeography of China along with maps showing the seven zoogeographical subregions currently recognized as well as the 4 municipalities, 23 provinces, 5 autonomous regions and 2 special administrative regions of China. A summary of the taxonomic compilation of the fauna is provided and its relationships with neighbouring regions, of both the Palaearctic and Oriental realms, are discussed. A study is presented on the distribution of the taxa and species densities of each province / autonomous region. Recent ecological studies are summarized and list of the host plants of 42 different species attached. The pest status of certain species which have become of serious importance for agriculture in China is briefly summarized based on literary sources.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phasmatodea; China; catalogue; type-depositories; new combinations; new synonyms; biogeography; biology; ecology; bibliography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phasmatodea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hennemann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oskar</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weiwei</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-77</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
