<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1809.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Jun. 2008</title>
    <volume>1809</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mata Atlantica enchytraeids (Parana Brazil): The genus &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt; (Oligochaeta, Enchytraeidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Among terrestrial enchytraeid oligochaetes, species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt; are conspicuous by their complete absence of chaetae. Knowledge of &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt; species in South America is scarce, only four species were known so far. Here we describe three more species of &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt; from South America, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hanagarthi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paranensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singularis&lt;/i&gt; spp. nov., and we provide revised and type-based redescriptions of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropica&lt;/i&gt; Č ernosvitov, 1937 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piti&lt;/i&gt; Bittencourt, 1974. The species were found in the framework of the German-Brazilian project " SOLOBIOMA, Soil biota and biogeochemistry in the Atlantic rainforest of Brazil", which monitors forest regeneration on previously degraded areas by comparing successional stages from pastures to old-growth forests. Species descriptions are based on observations of specimens &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo&lt;/i&gt; and as stained whole mounts; special attention is given to variations among specimens. The three new species are ascribed to a single author (Schmelz). They lack pyriform glands and have spermathecal ectal pores in lateral position. Further distinguishing traits concern the location of preclitellar nephridia, coelomocyte texture, distribution pattern of epidermal and clitellar gland cells, and the inner topography of the prostomium, the latter a new character in &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt; taxonomy. In &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hanagarthi&lt;/i&gt; all sexual organs except the spermathecae are shifted one segment forward. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singularis&lt;/i&gt; is most peculiar by a short and deeply incised brain and by the apparent absence of a suboesophageal ganglion, the ventral ganglia of segments II, III, and IV being separate. This species was only found in forests and is possibly a true representative of the old autochthonous forest soil fauna. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hanagarthi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singularis&lt;/i&gt; are similar to the ill-described &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvatica&lt;/i&gt; Nurminen, 1973; the latter is considered as a &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda&lt;/i&gt; here. Type reinvestigations revealed that contrary to the original descriptions, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piti&lt;/i&gt; has six segmental pyriform glands and reproductive organs except spermathecae shifted one segment forward, and that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropica&lt;/i&gt; has the first preclitellar nephridium at 6/7 and ectal spermathecal pores inlateral position. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropica&lt;/i&gt; is highly variable and probably a species aggregate, difficult to resolve with traditional light-microscopical methods. The recently described &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;becki&lt;/i&gt; Schmelz &amp; Collado 2005 is tentatively included in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropica.&lt;/i&gt; The taxonomic descriptions contribute to the general anatomy of the genus; our study further serves as a guide to neotropical species of &lt;i&gt;Achaeta.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oligochaeta; Enchytraeidae; &lt;i&gt;Achaeta&lt;/i&gt;; systematic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oligochaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rudiger</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schmelz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rut</firstname>
          <lastname>Collado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorg</firstname>
          <lastname>Rombke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Labeonine Genus &lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from South China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; was recently diagnosed by Su &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2003) as consisting of nine species, i.e. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bamaensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guizhouensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liuchengensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibullus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microstomatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrovittatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiatus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillolabrus.&lt;/i&gt; It is actually a catch-all genus that is composed of some species misidentified from &lt;i&gt;Pseudocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hongshuia.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; is here redefined based mainly on the details of the lower lip morphology; it is easily separated from all other Asian Labeonini genera in possessing a lower lip with its median lobe modified into a densely papillated, greatly protruded, crescentic fold and a papillose, slightly protruded, triangular fleshy pad which is posteriorly continuous with the mental region. Two species are recognized in this genus: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guizhouensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiatus.&lt;/i&gt; Detailed redescriptions are given for the two species. All remaining species do not fit with the new definition of &lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus;&lt;/i&gt; six species, i.e. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillolabrus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrovittatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bamaensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibullus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liuchengensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentis,&lt;/i&gt; should be moved to &lt;i&gt;Pseudocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microstomatus&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Hongshuia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt;; generic diagnosis; redescription of species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinocrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Le-Yang</firstname>
          <lastname>Yuan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yan-Fei</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of two &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; halacarid mites (Acari, Halacaridae) from Zanzibar, Tanzania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two halacarid species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; (Acari, Halacaridae) collected from the east coast of Unguja, Zanzibar, Tanzania, are described. &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matemwensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by an anterodorsal plate with 3 areolae, posterior dorsal plate with 2 costae, pair of ventromedial areolae between lateral and posterior setae on anterior epimeral plate, areolae present on lateral side of anterior half of genitoanal plate tending to join the areolae laterally to the genital opening area, rostrum elongate, tibiae I and II each with 1 denticulate process proximoventrally. The male of &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corallorum&lt;/i&gt; (Trouessart, 1899) is reported for the first time and described; leg morphology for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corallorum&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; marine Halacaridae; East Africa; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tapas</firstname>
          <lastname>Chatterjee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marleen</firstname>
          <lastname>De Troch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Benny</firstname>
          <middlename>K. K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Adcatomus&lt;/i&gt; Karsch (Araneae: Sparassidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Adcatomus&lt;/i&gt; Karsch, 1880 is revised. The male of the type species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciudadus&lt;/i&gt; Karsch, 1880 is redescribed based on recently collected material from Venezuela, and the female is described for the first time based on material from the same locality. In addition, the monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Spatala&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1897 is considered a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Adcatomus&lt;/i&gt; and thus, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavovittata&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1897 also described from Venezuela is transferred to that genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Taxonomy; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cristina</firstname>
          <middlename>Anne</middlename>
          <lastname>Rheims</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclatorial changes in Triaenonychidae: &lt;i&gt;Sclerobunus parvus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Paranonychus brunneus&lt;/i&gt; (Banks), &lt;i&gt;Mutusnonychus&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Paranonychus&lt;/i&gt; Briggs, and Kaolinonychinae Suzuki is a junior synonym of Paranonychinae Briggs (Opiliones: Triaenonychidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shear</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shahan</firstname>
          <lastname>Derkarabetian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
