<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1827.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1827</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Alien True Bugs of Europe (Insecta: Hemiptera: Heteroptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper reviews the alien (non-native, non-indigenous, exotic) true bug (Heteroptera) species in Europe. Forty-two established alien Heteroptera are recognized, of which 12 species are alien to Europe (originating outside Europe: eight from North America, three from the Eastern Palaearctic, one from New Zealand), 24 species are alien within Europe (translocated within Europe), and six cryptogenic species are of unknown origin. Since 1990 an approximate arrival rate of 7 species per decade has been observed. A recent trend of increased introductions from North America to Europe is suggested. The most important pathway of alien Heteroptera is translocation as contaminants (49 %), usually with ornamental plants, followed by unintentional introduction through natural dispersal (unaided) across political borders within Europe (28 %), and translocation as stowaways within a transport vector (21 %). The taxonomic composition of the alien Heteroptera of Europe is dominated by Miridae (17 species, 40 %), Tingidae (8 species, 19 %), and Anthocoridae (5 species, 12 %), all of which are overrepresented compared to the native European Heteroptera fauna. More than half of the species are phytophagous (24 species, 57 %) and the advantage of trophic specialization in invasion success is discussed. Most species are currently known to occur in the Czech Republic (19 species) and Germany (17 species), followed by Western European countries (Belgium 15 sp., France and United Kingdom 14 sp. each, and Netherlands 13 sp.), resulting in an apparent (north)west–(south)east gradient probably reflecting horticultural tradition in Europe. No unambiguousevidence exists so far for negative ecological or economical impacts, but more research is needed to investigate possible effects. Introductions of alien Heteroptera to and within Europe will increase, and deserve further consideration.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">non-native; non-indigenous; exotic; Hemiptera; pathway; impact</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">non-native</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Rabitsch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Fontidessus &lt;/i&gt;Miller and Spangler, a new genus of Bidessini from Venezuela (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae: Hydroporinae) with three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Fontidessus&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., and three new species &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toboganensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wheeleri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from Venezuela. The new genus is similar to &lt;i&gt;Uvarus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Bidessodes&lt;/i&gt; but is distinguished from all other Bidessini (including these) by a combination of the following: 1) transverse occipital line absent, 2) basal pronotal striae present, 3) basal elytral stria absent, 4) elytral sutural stria faintly present in some specimens, 5) anterior clypeal margin unmodified, 6) elytron without longitudinal carinae, 7) epipleuron without transverse carina at humeral angle, 8) lateral lobes of aedeagus two-segmented, 9) habitus elongate, oval, with lateral pronotal and elytral margins nearly continuously and shallowly curved, and 10) metatrochanter extremely large relative to metafemur, approximately 0.6 × length of metafemur.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">diving beetles; classification; taxonomy; new genus; new species; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">diving beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kelly</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Spangler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Afrotropical ponerine ant genus &lt;i&gt;Asphinctopone&lt;/i&gt; Santschi (Hymenoptera: Formicidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Afrotropical ponerine ant genus &lt;i&gt;Asphinctopone&lt;/i&gt; is revised. Two species are recognised, of which one (differens) is described as new, and two names are established as new junior synonyms of the type-species &lt;i&gt;silvestrii&lt;/i&gt; (lucidus and &lt;i&gt;lamottei).&lt;/i&gt; A new diagnosis of the genus is presented, based on the female castes (male remains unknown) and critical morphological characters are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Asphinctopone&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Asphinctopone&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Barry</firstname>
          <lastname>Bolton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fisher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-61</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Neopsittaconirmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palaeornis &lt;/i&gt;(Eichler) (Phthiraptera: Philopteridae) from &lt;i&gt;Psittacula derbiana &lt;/i&gt;(Psittaciformes: Psittacidae), with a new synonymy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oldrich</firstname>
          <lastname>Sychra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Palma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-64</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The status of Mesnil's 1949 &lt;i&gt;Die Fliegen&lt;/i&gt; genus-group names (Diptera: Tachinidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Neal</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Evenhuis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>O'hara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
