<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1683.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Jan. 2008</title>
    <volume>1683</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Postembryonic development of the dorsal chaetotaxy in &lt;i&gt;Seira dowlingi &lt;/i&gt;(Collembola, Entomobryidae); with an analysis of the diagnostic and phylogenetic significance of primary chaetotaxy in &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Chaetotaxy is probably the most important character system used to diagnose species in Entomobryidae, but its use in studies of phylogenetic relationships of suprageneric taxa has been hampered by difficulties in identifying the homology of individual setae. Currently there is developmental information for three (Orchesella, &lt;i&gt;Entomobrya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lepidocyrtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato)&lt;/i&gt; of the four largest groups of entomobryids. &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt; is the only major genus for which the postembryonic development of the chaetotaxy has not been described. To fill this gap a complete description of the postembryonic development of the dorsal chaetotaxy of &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dowlingi&lt;/i&gt; (Wray, 1953) is presented. Based on this description and by comparisons with up to 96 additional &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt; species, it is suggested that the loss of second abdominal segment primary setae &lt;b&gt;m4&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;p4&lt;/b&gt; (by transformation into scales during postembryonic development) is the only chaetotaxic character diagnostic for the genus. The posterior botriothricum (homologous to &lt;b&gt;D3)&lt;/b&gt; on the fourth abdominal segment is absent only in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (Afroseira) &lt;i&gt;rowani&lt;/i&gt; Yosii, from South Africa. It is suggested that the presence of seta &lt;b&gt;p3&lt;/b&gt; and absence of &lt;b&gt;p4&lt;/b&gt; on the third abdominal segment support a more recent relationship between &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lepidocyrtus/Pseudosinella&lt;/i&gt; than between &lt;i&gt;Seira&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Entomobrya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Entomobryidae; Lepidocyrtinae; Seirinae; primary chaetotaxy; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Entomobryidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Felipe</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Soto-Adames</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-31</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Platambus &lt;/i&gt;from China (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt; Thomson (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae) is described from China: &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has to be included within &lt;i&gt;sawadai-group,&lt;/i&gt; characterized by its broadly oval shape, indistinct pronoto-elytral angle, and the strong puncturation on the upper surface. &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wulingshanensis&lt;/i&gt; Brancucci, 2005 is recorded from Hubei (China) for the first time and the widely distributed species &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;excoffieri&lt;/i&gt; Régimbart, 1899 is recorded from Hainan and Shaanxi Chinese Provinces for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; &lt;i&gt;Platambus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dong-Ju</firstname>
          <lastname>Bian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lan-Zhu</firstname>
          <lastname>Ji</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osakatheta yasukoae&lt;/i&gt;, a new intertidal genus and species of athetine rove beetles (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae, Aleocharinae) from Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osakatheta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yasukoae&lt;/i&gt; Maruyama, Klimaszewski &amp; Gusarov gen. et sp. nov. (Aleocharinae) is described based on specimens collected from the intertidal zones in Ôsaka-wan, Ôsaka-fu and Ise-wan, Mie-ken, Honshû, Japan. This is the first record of true intertidal species of Athetini from the West Pacific coast (East Palearctic). &lt;i&gt;Osakatheta&lt;/i&gt; may be readily distinguished from other genera of Athetini by the long and erect setae covering its whole body.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Aleocharinae; Athetini; &lt;i&gt;Osakatheta&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new genus; new species; Ôsakafu; Mie-ken; Honshû; Japan; West Pacific coast; East Palearctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Munetoshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Maruyama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jan</firstname>
          <lastname>Klimaszewski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Gusarov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of Culex (Culex) dolosus (Lynch Arribálzaga) (Diptera: Culicidae), based on specimens from Pico do Itapeva, Serra da Mantiqueira, São Paulo, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt; (Culex) &lt;i&gt;dolosus&lt;/i&gt; (Lynch Arribálzaga, 1891) is re-described and compared with &lt;i&gt;Cx.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eduardoi&lt;/i&gt; Casal &amp; Garcia (1968) based on morphological characteristics. Both species are morphologically similar, and they have been largely misidentified throughout Brazil. Adult male and female, fourth instar larvae, and pupae of &lt;i&gt;Cx.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolosus&lt;/i&gt; were examined, based on specimens from Pico do Itapeva, Pindamonhangaba Municipality, Serra da Mantiqueira, São Paulo State, southern Brazil. Male genitalia, larvae and pupae are illustrated. Geographical distribution is summarized from published records, and information on bionomics is based on the literature and field data.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mosquito; Culicidae; &lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolosus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mosquito</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luana</firstname>
          <middlename>Valente</middlename>
          <lastname>Senise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Anice Mureb</middlename>
          <lastname>Sallum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and key to known species of genus &lt;i&gt;Oxya &lt;/i&gt;Serville (Orthoptera: Acrididae: Catantopinae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During routine identification of the grasshoppers of the Dasa river, Guizhou Province of China in 2004, a new species [Oxya &lt;i&gt;guizhouensis&lt;/i&gt; sp, nov.] of the genus &lt;i&gt;Oxya&lt;/i&gt; Serville (Orthoptera, Acrididae, Catantopinae) was discovered. It is described here. A key to all known species of the genus from China is given. The type specimens are deposited in the Museum of Hebei University (MHU), Baoding, Hebei, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiang-Chu</firstname>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong</firstname>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jing-Yu</firstname>
          <lastname>Zheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
