<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1714.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Feb. 2008</title>
    <volume>1714</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic review of the stem-inhabiting trehala-constructing&lt;i&gt; Larinus&lt;/i&gt; Dejean, 1821 (Coleoptera: Curculionidae): New species, systematics and ecology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Trehala are unusual insect pupal chambers that are sweet and have been used as human food. They are formed by only four &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; Dejean species which develop in plant stems. This group is revised taxonomically, and a new key is provided. A new synonymy is proposed: &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nidificans&lt;/i&gt; Guibourt, 1858 [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multiguttatus&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1901, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.].&lt;/b&gt; Lectotypes for &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; Gyllenhal, 1836, &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hedenborgi&lt;/i&gt; Boheman, 1845, and &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudicollis&lt;/i&gt; Petri, 1907 are designated. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capsulatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from northeastern Turkey is described, and a differentiating redescription of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudicollis&lt;/i&gt; is provided. Ecological information on the trehala-building &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capsulatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudicollis&lt;/i&gt; is presented. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hedenborgi&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for Turkey, Iran and Egypt.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curculionidae; ecology; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomic revision; trehala constructing</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curculionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Levent</firstname>
          <lastname>Gultekin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Nesocricos &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Tanycricos&lt;/i&gt; (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Naucoridae: Cheirochelinae: Tanycricini) in the mountains of West Papua, Indonesian New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Tanycricini are described from mountain streams of Indonesian New Guinea. Both species were collected at 1,348 m elevation from Ingging River in West Papua. &lt;i&gt;Nesocricos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ingging&lt;/i&gt; Sites &lt;b&gt;n.sp.&lt;/b&gt; was represented by macropterous and submacropterous forms. &lt;i&gt;Tanycricos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inequalis&lt;/i&gt; Sites &lt;b&gt;n.sp.&lt;/b&gt; was represented by macropterous and brachypterous forms. &lt;i&gt;Nesocricos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evops&lt;/i&gt; La Rivers is reported from the Baliem Valley of Indonesian New Guinea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Insecta; Hemiptera; new species; distribution; Naucoridae; New Guinea; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Insecta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Suputa</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Australian bee flies (Diptera: Bombyliidae, Bombyliinae) with affinities to the New World &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum&lt;/i&gt; Macquart</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Diptera: Bombyliidae) is described based on a large series of specimens from the Northern Territory of Australia. The specimens represent a single new species &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The genus belongs to the Bombyliinae, and has remarkable anatomical affinities to the New World genus &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum&lt;/i&gt; Macquart. In particular, the head of &lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt; has a sinuous posterior eye margin, but lacks a line bisecting the facets as found in most Anthracinae that also share such an eye margin. A sinuous posterior eye margin is uncommon in the subfamily Bombyliinae, being only found in &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum&lt;/i&gt; and four other genera found in the New World, Afrotropical and Palaearctic regions. Additionally, &lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt; shares with &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum&lt;/i&gt; alone an unusual wing venation, with cell R 5 closed, and the apex of cell dm-cu meeting the fork of M 1 and M 2 , there being no stem of M 1+2 . The male genitalia of &lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt; are generalized bombyliine in form, and do not share the particular unique features of &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum&lt;/i&gt; such as the large recurved epiphallus and the gonostylus with apical beak-like process. The female genitalia of &lt;i&gt;Apiformyia&lt;/i&gt; lack the sand chamber, acanthophorite spines and presents spermathecae with elongated bulbs, spermathecal ducts more than twice as long as sperm pump and sclerotized collars well developed, also differentiating the genus from &lt;i&gt;Heterostylum.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new genus; Bombyliidae; Bombyliinae; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new genus</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yeates</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-36</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of tribe Macrosiphini (Hemiptera, Aphididae) from northeast China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brevisiphonaphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirsutissima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from specimens collected in northeast China on &lt;i&gt;Artemisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argyi&lt;/i&gt; H.Lév. &amp; Vaniot (Asteraceae). The genus is illustrated with the biometric data for apterous viviparous females. This aphid genus is closely related to &lt;i&gt;Microsiphum&lt;/i&gt; Cholodkovsky, 1902 and &lt;i&gt;Microsiphoniella&lt;/i&gt; Hille Ris Lambers, 1947. Type specimens are deposited at the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China, and at the Zoological Institute, Russian Academy of Science, St. Petersburg, Russia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aphididae; &lt;i&gt;Brevisiphonaphis&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aphididae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrey</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stekolshchikov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Qiao</firstname>
          <lastname>Ge-Xia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Identification and host associations of some Thysanoptera Phlaeothripinae described from Australia pre-1930</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Among Australian fungus-feeding Thysanoptera, five new synonyms are recognised in &lt;i&gt;Horistothrips&lt;/i&gt; Morgan, and among leaf-feeding species, three new synonyms are recognised in &lt;i&gt;Teuchothrips&lt;/i&gt; Hood and one in &lt;i&gt;Neocecidothrips&lt;/i&gt; Moulton. &lt;i&gt;Horistothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curviseta&lt;/i&gt; Girault is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Neocecidothrips&lt;/i&gt; as the second species in that genus and its host-plant is identified. &lt;i&gt;Cryptothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;additamentus&lt;/i&gt; Karny is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Gynaikothrips&lt;/i&gt; Zimmermann and identified as a common kleptoparasite in the leaf roll galls of &lt;i&gt;Gynaikothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; Bagnall. A key is provided to 13 Australian species remaining in &lt;i&gt;Teuchothrips;&lt;/i&gt; host-plants are recognised for six of these, but seven remain known only from their original fragmented specimens.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Teuchothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neocecidothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gynaikothrips&lt;/i&gt;; synonyms; host-plants</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Teuchothrips&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laurence</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mound</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Neanurinae and Morulininae of Moldova (Collembola: Neanuridae), with description of &lt;i&gt;Neanura moldavica &lt;/i&gt;sp.nov.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Ten species of &lt;i&gt;Neanurinae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Morulininae&lt;/i&gt; are listed from Moldova, of which 8 are first records for the country. The new species &lt;i&gt;Neanura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moldavica&lt;/i&gt; (Collembola: Neanuridae: Neanurinae: Neanurini) is described. It differs from &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muscorum,&lt;/i&gt; its closest relative, by the absence of chaeta Di3 on Abd V, the position of chaeta E on the edge of tubercle Af (free in &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muscorum)&lt;/i&gt; and the additional chaeta of Ant I placed more laterally.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; new species; faunistic; Moldova</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Galina</firstname>
          <lastname>Busmachiu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <lastname>Deharveng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the senior authorship of &lt;i&gt;Musca oleae&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Tephritidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfio</firstname>
          <lastname>Raspi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gennaro</firstname>
          <lastname>Viggiani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
