<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1925.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1925</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; (Amphibia: Anura: Rhacophoridae) from the Truong Son Range, Quang Binh Province, central Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the rhacophorid genus &lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; from the Truong Son, based on two voucher specimens from montane evergreen and karst forests within Quang Binh Province, central Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quyeti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from all other small-sized rhacophorid treefrogs with reduced finger webbing by the combination of the following characters: size relatively small; head longer than wide; vomerine teeth absent; tympanum distinct, rounded, wider than disc of finger III; supratympanic fold indistinct; dermal fringe along outer side of forearm, tibia, tarsus and toe IV absent; skin not lumpy or spinulous, dorsal head, back and upper part of flank rough with small sharp tubercles; dark brown pattern forming an inverse Y, notably a triangular spot between eyes that is separated into two bands that continue posteriorly on the back; throat and margin of throat and chest yellow white with brown marbling.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rhacophoridae; &lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quyeti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.;&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Quang Binh Province; Truong Son; central Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rhacophoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nguyen</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Truong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ralf</firstname>
          <lastname>Hendrix</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Böhme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vu</firstname>
          <middlename>Ngoc</middlename>
          <lastname>Thanh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-13</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae) from Guarapari, Espirito Santo, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of pontoniine shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guarapari&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described from Espirito Santo, Brazil. The new species belongs to the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iridescens&lt;/i&gt; complex and is closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iridescens,&lt;/i&gt; from which it may be distinguished by the armature of the second pereiopod and differences in the spination of the third pereiopod. The hosts of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guarapari&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. are the plexaurid gorgonians, &lt;i&gt;Muricea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flammea&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Plexaurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandiflora.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Pontoniinae; Alcyonacea; Brazil; symbiosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>14-22</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of Neothrombiidae (Acari: Trombidioidea) from Yemen</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Solistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mitrae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated from an unknown host collected with a light trap at Al Kowd, Yemen. This is the first record of the family Neothrombiidae in Yemen. The new taxon is based on the larva; deutonymphs and adults remain unknown.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neothrombiidae; new genus; larva; key; Yemen</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neothrombiidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alireza</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edward</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ueckermann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonius</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Harten</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apareiodon agmatos&lt;/i&gt;, a new species from the upper Mazaruni river, Guyana (Teleostei: Characiformes: Parodontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apareiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agmatos,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the upper Mazaruni River and its tributaries, Essequibo Basin, in western Guyana. The new species is distinguishable from all other species of Parodontidae by having an incomplete lateral line. The scales of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agmatos&lt;/i&gt; are more numerous than in any previously described parodontid. It has five incisorlike pedunculate teeth on the premaxilla aligned in a straight row, each with a large central spatulate cusp bordered on each side by a minute lateral cusp. The maxilla has two or infrequently three incisors. It shares an unusual pigmentation pattern of one dorsomedial and four lateral black stripes with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gransabana,&lt;/i&gt; which was described from the neighboring upper Río Caroní drainage, Orinoco Basin. &lt;i&gt;Apareiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agmatos&lt;/i&gt; also shares with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gransabana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Parodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guyanensis&lt;/i&gt; a higher number (5 versus 4) of teeth than other members of the genus in the premaxillary. &lt;i&gt;Apareiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agmatos&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gransabana&lt;/i&gt; may also share an absence of thickening of the anterior pleural ribs noted by Starnes &amp; Schindler (1993) for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gransabana.&lt;/i&gt; While beyond the scope of this work, these features may prove sufficient to diagnose this group of species from the genus &lt;i&gt;Apareiodon&lt;/i&gt; as currently recognized.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Teleostei; freshwater fish; Essequibo; Neotropical; endemism; isolation; biogeography; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Teleostei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Donald</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Taphorn</middlename>
          <lastname>B.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hernán</firstname>
          <lastname>López-Fernández</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Calvin</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bernard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Gecko on the rocks: an enigmatic new species of &lt;i&gt;Gonatodes&lt;/i&gt; (Sphaerodactylidae) from Inselbergs of the Venezuelan Guayana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of diurnal gecko of the genus &lt;i&gt;Gonatodes&lt;/i&gt; is described from Inselbergs (granite outcrops) on the western peripheral lowlands of the Guiana Shield, Venezuela. The new species can be distinguished from all congeners by the following characters: large size (the new species is the largest known sphaerodactyl gecko), supraciliary spine absent, females with immaculate brown dorsal coloration, and a subcaudal scale pattern found in only one other species in the genus. The new species is also unique in the genus in being restricted to rock outcrops and shows potential adaptations to this type of habitat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gonatodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infernalis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Sphaerodactylidae; Gekkota; Inselbergs; Venezuelan Guayana</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gonatodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infernalis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gilson</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rivas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Walter</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schargel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The millipede family Diplomaragnidae Attems 1907 in the Korean Peninsula, with the descriptions of a new genus and new species (Diplopoda, Chordeumatida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diplopod family Diplomaragnidae Attems 1907 appears to be represented in the Korean Peninsula by five genera and ten species. One genus and three species are described here as new to science: &lt;i&gt;Koreagna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; with the type species &lt;i&gt;Koreagna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtecta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tokyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tokyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phialiferum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Keys and taxonomic and distributional notes are given for all species of diplomaragnids currently known from Korea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Millipedes; Chordeumatida; Diplomaragnidae; Korea; new taxa; description; taxonomy; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Millipedes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kil-Young</firstname>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-61</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The status of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; Tenora, Gulyaev &amp; Kamiya, 1999 (Cestoda: Anoplocephalidae), parasites of the endemic Japanese field mice (&lt;i&gt;Apodemus &lt;/i&gt;spp.)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study reconsiders the status of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; Tenora, Gulyaev &amp; Kamiya, 1999 by examining available specimens of the type species &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apodemi&lt;/i&gt; (Iwaki, Tenora, Abe, Oku &amp; Kamiya, 1994) (syn. &lt;i&gt;Andrya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apodemi)&lt;/i&gt; and comparing them with related anoplocephaline cestodes. It is shown that &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apodemi&lt;/i&gt; does not differ fundamentally from related genera in the development of the reproductive organs, contrary to the argument of Tenora &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (1999). In &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; and related genera (Anoplocephaloides Baer, 1923 &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;str.&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Microcephaloides&lt;/i&gt; Haukisalmi, Hardman, Hardman, Rausch &amp; Henttonen, 2008), sperm appears in the seminal receptacle (female organ) simultaneously or slightly earlier than in the seminal vesicles (male organs) and the ovary and vitellarium are absent in postmature proglottides where testes still persist and usually reach their maximum size. However, &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; is considered here a valid genus differentiated from the related genera by its unique uterine structure and development. Presently, &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala&lt;/i&gt; includes two host-specific species [H. &lt;i&gt;apodemi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baeri&lt;/i&gt; (Rausch, 1976) n. comb. (= &lt;i&gt;Anoplocephaloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baeri&lt;/i&gt; Rausch, 1976)] parasitizing endemic Japanese field mice (primarily &lt;i&gt;Apodemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argenteus).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anoplocephaloides;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Andrya;&lt;/i&gt; Anoplocephalidae; Cestoda; &lt;i&gt;Apodemus;&lt;/i&gt; Hokkaido; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hokkaidocephala;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anoplocephaloides;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Andrya;&lt;/i&gt; Anoplocephalidae; Cestoda; &lt;i&gt;Apodemus;&lt;/i&gt; Hokkaido; Japan</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Voitto</firstname>
          <lastname>Haukisalmi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mitsuhiko</firstname>
          <lastname>Asakawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>András</firstname>
          <lastname>Gubányi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
