<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1924.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1924</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">South American Monogenealist of species, hosts and geographical distribution from 1997 to 2008</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A list of 135 monogenean species is presented updating the papers published by Kohn &amp; Cohen (1989) and Kohn &amp; Paiva (2000), increasing to 658 the number of known species in South America. After 1997, 104 monogeneans had been described as new species: 65 from Brazil, 13 from Argentina, 10 from Venezuela, 04 from Chile, two from Guyana, one from French Guyana, Peru and Uruguay each. Some species had been originally described in the same publication from more than one country: 04 from Brazil, Peru and Venezuela, two from Brazil and Peru, two from Brazil and Argentina and one from Argentina and Uruguay. More 31 known species had been reported for the first time in South America: 02 from Argentina, 24 from Brazil, one from Colombia and Brazil, one from Chile and Peru, one from Surinam and Brazil and two from Peru. It was also included in the present paper, 62 species which were already listed in Kohn &amp; Cohen (1998) and reported after 1997 in different South American countries. From, Ecuador, Falkland, Galapagos and Paraguay none species had been reported in this period. A host-parasite list is also presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Monogena; South America; freshwater and marine fishes; amphibians</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Monogena; South America; freshwater and marine fishes; amphibians</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simone</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cohen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <lastname>Kohn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some lithodid crabs (Crustacea: Decapoda: Lithodidae) from Taiwan and adjacent waters, with the description of one new species from Guam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven species of Lithodid crabs were collected during cruises off Taiwan and Guam. One new species, &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi&lt;/i&gt; is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Neolithodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nipponensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Paralomis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dofleini&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatispinosa&lt;/i&gt; are reported from these islands for the first time, extending the distributional range in each case. &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi&lt;/i&gt; closely resembles &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispina&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1971, from off Japan and the central Pacific, but can be differentiated by the branchial region possessing two long dorsal spines and only one long marginal spine, whereas &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispina&lt;/i&gt; has only one long dorsal spine, situated at level of cardiac spines, and two long marginal spines. The description of a juvenile of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arae&lt;/i&gt; Macpherson, 2001, is also included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">king crab; &lt;i&gt;Neolithodes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paralomis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Pacific Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">king crab</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Enrique</firstname>
          <lastname>Macpherson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new insular species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from the Langkawi Archipelago, Kedah, Peninsular Malaysia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the gekkonid lizard, &lt;i&gt;Cytrodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrotuberculatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Pulau Langkawi of the Langkawi Archipelago located off the northwest coast of Peninsular Malaysia in the state of Kedah. This species had been previously recognized as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchellus&lt;/i&gt; but is differentiated here from that species and all other Sunda Shelf &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of its strong tuberculation and other scale and color pattern characteristics. This represents the second endemic species known from the Langkawi Archipelago.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Malaysia; Langkawi; Archipelago; Kedah; &lt;i&gt;Cytrodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;macrotuberculatus&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Malaysia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Norhayati</firstname>
          <lastname>Ahmad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
