<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1685.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jan. 2008</title>
    <volume>1685</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of flower-dwelling melicharid mites (Acari: Mesostigmata: Ascoidea) phoretic on bats and insects in Costa Rica and Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Spadiseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; of the ascoid family Melicharidae is described, based on all instars of two newly described species in Costa Rica and adults of four undescribed species in Costa Rica and Brazil. These mites undergo their life histories quickly in spike or spadix inflorescences of their plant hosts in lowland tropical rainforests, where they apparently feed on nectar or pollen. One inflorescence may bear hundreds of the developing mites in all instars. Pollen is found on all instars of these mites, which may act as miniature pollinators of their plant hosts. Adult males are strongly sexually dimorphic, with bizarrely modified setae peripherally on the body dorsum and on dorsal surfaces of the legs. These structures are thought to be used competitively for mates, in much the same way as in males of the related hummingbird flower mite genera &lt;i&gt;Rhinoseius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tropicoseius.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Spadiseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calyptrogynae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; lives in inflorescences of a palm, &lt;i&gt;Calyptrogyne&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ghiesbreghtiana,&lt;/i&gt; and has a phoretic association both with perching bats of the genus &lt;i&gt;Artibeus,&lt;/i&gt; which are major pollinators of this plant, and scarab beetles of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lagochile,&lt;/i&gt; which feed destructively on flowers of this plant. &lt;i&gt;Spadiseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spathiphyllae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; lives in inflorescences of an aroid, &lt;i&gt;Spathiphyllum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;friedrichsthalli,&lt;/i&gt; and is phoretic on meliponine bees of the genus &lt;i&gt;Trigona&lt;/i&gt; that pollinate this plant. Polymorphism among adult males occurs in both species. In male &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calyptrogynae&lt;/i&gt; a “warty” ornamentation of the dorsal shield seems to be correlated with extreme elongation of certain body and leg setae, while in male &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spathiphyllae&lt;/i&gt; such disproportionate setal elongation seems correlated with more robust individuals of greater body and leg dimensions. Several newly recognized morphological attributes are noted among species of &lt;i&gt;Spadiseius,&lt;/i&gt; including apically forked salivary styli.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Melicharidae; Ascoidea; flower mites; polymorphism; phoresy; bats; insects</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Melicharidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Evert</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lindquist</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moraza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stygomomonia &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;manchurica&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of water mite (Acari: Hydrachnidia: Momoniidae) from the Far East of Russia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stygomomonia&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;manchurica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Hydrachnidia: Momoniidae) from the Kedrovaya River, Primory Territory of the Russian Far East is described. The affinity of the new species to its congeners is discussed with emphasis on biogeographical relationships. An annotated checklist of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Stygomomonia&lt;/i&gt; and geographical map of the distribution of Palaearctic species of this subgenus is compiled using published records.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">water mites; &lt;i&gt;Stygomomonia&lt;/i&gt;; interstitial habitat; Far East; Russia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">water mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ksenia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Semenchenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-46</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Fishes of La Venta River in Chiapas, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Although Chiapas is recognized as home to some of the most interesting fishes in Mexico, there are still regions of the state that are poorly surveyed. Our objective was to document the fish species in La Venta River, as well as that of some of its largest tributaries and Netzahualc\yotl Reservoir. To this aim, field collections were made during three consecutive years and preserved specimens from the ichthyological collection at El Colegio de la Frontera Sur, San Crist\bal, Chiapas were reviewed. We identified 42 species including new records for the state of Chiapas (3 species), the Grijalva River watershed (3 species), and Netzahualc\yotl Reservoir (2 species). Species composition differed between the upper and lower portions of La Venta River, most likely due to historical factors, and the physical and chemical differences between the two areas. The species composition of the upper parts of La Venta River was distinctive within the watershed but similar to neighboring hydrologic systems, suggesting that this area was recently connected to other rivers. Our results revealed that the Grijalva River-Tuxtla GutiJrrez watershed is species rich and may be important for describing the distribution patterns of several groups of fishes in Mexico.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biogeography; Grijalva; Poeciliids; Cichlids; Selva El Ocote; New records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biogeography</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfonso</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ngel</firstname>
          <lastname>Gonz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lez-Dqaz</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rebecca</firstname>
          <middlename>Marqa</middlename>
          <lastname>Quiyones</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Josi</firstname>
          <lastname>Vel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zquez-Martqnez</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rocqo</firstname>
          <lastname>Rodiles-Hern</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ndez</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-54</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the Neotropical water snake &lt;i&gt;Hydrops triangularis&lt;/i&gt; (Serpentes, Colubridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six subspecies of &lt;i&gt;Hydrops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triangularis&lt;/i&gt; (Wagler 1824) are currently recognized on the basis of differences in the number of ventral and subcaudal scales and dorsal coloration (viz., the number of bands on the body, the extent of bands on the body, and the occurrence of projections of the bands on the body). Analysis of a larger sample from throughout the distribution of the species revealed overlapping variation in all of these characters across regional boundaries. The available evidence is therefore unable to objectively delimit multiple geographic races, and we therefore consider the subspecies of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triangularis&lt;/i&gt; to be subjective synonyms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydrops&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Hydropsini; Xenodontinae; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydrops&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nelson</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Albuquerque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thales</firstname>
          <lastname>De Lema</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Phyllonastes &lt;/i&gt;Heyer and &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus peruvianus &lt;/i&gt;(Noble) (Lissamphibia, Anura): resurrection of &lt;i&gt;Noblella &lt;/i&gt;Barbour</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ignacio</firstname>
          <lastname>De La Riva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
