<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1757.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1757</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records and within-species variability of Iberian tardigrades (Tardigrada), with comments on the species from the &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus blumi-canadensis&lt;/i&gt; series</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present report describes the results obtained from a survey on the tardigrade communities of five microhabitats (leaf litter, and mosses and lichens on rocks and tree trunks) in the Sierra de Guadarrama (Madrid, Spain). Sampling design was conducted according to a spatially mixed stratified-random procedure. A list with new records for Europe, the Iberian Peninsula and Madrid is provided. I have added two species to the European check list, increased number of known species in the Iberian Peninsula from 118 to 131, and duplicated the number of species known in the Madrid Province. Besides, some variations in morphological characters have been observed within-species, the majority related to structures of the buccal-pharyngeal apparatus and claws. More within-species variability studies are needed to determine their validity as diagnostic characters. A specific discussion is made about morphological variability within the &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blumi-canadensis&lt;/i&gt; series, as a result of observations among and within species from the series.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">terrestrial; leaf litter; lichen; moss; Spain; Eutardigrada; Heterotardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blumi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canadensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediantus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bisetosus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trisetosus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">terrestrial</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Noemi</firstname>
          <lastname>Guil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; (Teleostei: Loricariidae) from the upper Rio Parana basin, Brazil, with description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paranensis&lt;/i&gt; was the only &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; species known from the upper Rio Paraná basin, and it was diagnosed from its congeners mainly by the absence or reduction of the adipose fin. In this study we describe three new &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; species. All of them are promptly differentiated from &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paranensis&lt;/i&gt; by having a well-developed adipose fin. Furthermore, the new species are differentiated from congeners by morphometric and meristic traits, in addition to color pattern. &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paranensis&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed. We also provide an identification key to all &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">catfishes; freshwater; Neotropical; Ostariophysi; Siluriformes; ichthyology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">catfishes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <middlename>Henrique</middlename>
          <lastname>Zawadzki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>Simone</middlename>
          <lastname>Pavanelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Langeani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A partial revision of the &lt;i&gt;Ameerega hahneli&lt;/i&gt; complex (Anura: Dendrobatidae) and a new cryptic species from the East-Andean versant of Central Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of poison frog from central Peru which has been referred to as &lt;i&gt;Ameerega&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hahneli&lt;/i&gt; for the past thirty years. To our knowledge the new species is endemic to Peru and occurs throughout the east-Andean versant between roughly 6 and 10 degrees south latitude. Recent phylogenies using molecular data show that the new species and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hahneli&lt;/i&gt; are not closely related despite being similar in pattern, color, and morphology. Our data suggest that the new species is a sister taxon to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubriventris,&lt;/i&gt; which is readily distinguishable from the new species by its reddish venter. The new species can be distinguished furthermore from other &lt;i&gt;Ameerega&lt;/i&gt; species by possessing white (rather than yellow or cream) dorsolateral stripes, and from the similar &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hahneli&lt;/i&gt; by differences in advertisement calls and larval morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ameerega&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;altamazonica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Dendrobatid frogs; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hahneli&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Peru; poison frogs; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ameerega&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;altamazonica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Evan</firstname>
          <lastname>Twomey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jason</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brown</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-65</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A family-series nomen based on a junior synonym is not thereby made invalid: the case of Adamansini Huber, 2007 (Cyprinotontiformes, Nothobranchiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
