<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1739.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1739</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Terrestrial planarians (Platyhelminthes, Tricladida, Terricola) from the Iberian Peninsula: new records and description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Little is known about the taxonomy and distribution of terrestrial planarians on the Iberian Peninsula. Few studies have tried to investigate the local diversity of these animals, due to both their lack of economic interest and their low abundance. In this study we have made extensive searches and collections of terrestrial planarians from the Iberian Peninsula, thus gathering new information on their taxonomy and biogeography. The study includes the description of three new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Microplana,&lt;/i&gt; viz. &lt;i&gt;Microplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aixandrei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Microplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grazalemica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;Microplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadesensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. We present distribution maps summarizing published and new records of land planarians. The present work substantially increases our knowledge on this group of animals in Spain and Portugal and at the same time also evidences the scarcity of data and studies on the biology of these organisms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes; Tricladida; Rhynchodemidae; &lt;i&gt;Microplana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rhynchodemus&lt;/i&gt;; Iberian Peninsula; Andalusia; Grazalema; biogeography; taxonomy; spermatophore</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Miquel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vila-Farre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Mateos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ronald</firstname>
          <lastname>Sluys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <lastname>Romero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new genera and two new species of troglobitic false spider crabs (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Hymenosomatidae) from Indonesia, with notes on &lt;i&gt;Cancrocaeca &lt;/i&gt;Ng, 1991</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are established for two new species of cave-dwelling false spider crabs (Hymenosomatidae) from Muna Island, Sulawesi Tenggara, and Kalimantan Timur, Indonesia, respectively. &lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ensifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are distinguished from each other by carapace, rostral, pereopodal, abdominal and male gonopodal characters. &lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; share with &lt;i&gt;Cancrocaeca&lt;/i&gt; Ng, 1991, another troglobitic hymenosomatid, cave-adapted characters like reduced eyes, pale coloration and slender ambulatory legs. However, the gonopods, abdomens and egg-brooding features of &lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; are closer to those of the epigeal &lt;i&gt;Neorhynchoplax&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1938, whereas those of &lt;i&gt;Cancrocaeca&lt;/i&gt; are closer to those of the epigeal &lt;i&gt;Limnopilos&lt;/i&gt; Chuang &amp; Ng, 1991, and &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1917. It appears that the hypogeal lifestyles of &lt;i&gt;Sulaplax-Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cancrocaeca&lt;/i&gt; species have resulted in many convergent characters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ensifer&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Guaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; &lt;i&gt;Cancrocaeca&lt;/i&gt;; troglobitic freshwater crabs; Hymenosomatidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sulaplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ensifer&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tohru</firstname>
          <lastname>Naruse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniele</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa lixianensis&lt;/i&gt;, a new nemacheiline loach species (Pisces: Balitoridae) from the upper Yangtze River drainage in Sichuan Province, South China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lixianensis,&lt;/i&gt; a new nemacheiline loach species, is described from the Min Jiang of the upper Yangtze River drainage in Sichuan Province, South China. It can be separated from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; by having a unique combination of the following characters: posterior chamber of gas bladder greatly reduced or absent; caudal peduncle columnar with a roughly round cross-section at its beginning; anterior edge of lower jaw completely exposed or uncovered by lower lip; intestine short, forming a zigzag loop below stomach; dorsal-fin origin closer to caudal-fin base than to snout tip; pelvic fin inserted anterior to dorsal-fin origin; snout length 50.6–57.5 % of head length; eye diameter 12.3– 15.4 % of head length; caudal peduncle length 25.1–27.1 % of standard length; anal fin with five branched rays; lower lip greatly furrowed with two thick lateral lobes; and body smooth or scaleless.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; upper Yangtze River drainage; Sichuan Province</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chunlin</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhaobin</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; (Brachiopoda: Delthyridoidea) from the Dra Valley, Morocco (Lower Devonian)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Lower Devonian Assa Formation of the Dra Valley (Morocco). &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamadae&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. differs from the other taxa of &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; in having a smaller shell, fewer costae, a lower ventral interarea, a smaller ventral process, and a less conspicuous dorsal adductor field. Due to their micro-ornamentation, the capillate Rhenish delthyridoid genera, &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mauispirifer,&lt;/i&gt; are excluded from the fimbriate family Acrospiriferidae and put together in the new family Filispiriferidae. The evolutionary lineage of &lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt; and its palaeobiogeographic occurrence are briefly described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt;; Filispiriferidae; Delthyridoidea; Brachiopoda; Lower Devonian; Morocco</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Filispirifer&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mena</firstname>
          <lastname>Schemm-Gregory</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
