<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1847.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Aug. 2008</title>
    <volume>1847</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; (Polychaeta: Syllidae) from the Mediterranean and Canary Islands with a re-description of &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis arenae&lt;/i&gt; and comments on the taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; and some morphologically similar genera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nunezi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from shallow sandy substrates in the Mediterranean and the Canary Islands. The new species is distinguished by a unique combination of characters: teeth of the shafts of the compound chaetae covered by hyaline hood; 1–2 lateral tips formed by the hyaline hood covering the blades of the compound chaetae; strongly serrated dorsal simple chaetae which appear as 2–4 robust teeth when viewed laterally. The re-description of its closest congener, the type species &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenae&lt;/i&gt; Webster and Benedict, 1884, is also provided based on the type material, as well as a key to the currently valid species and table of characters for the genus. Finally, some comments are made for the characters distinguishing the genera &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Syllides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anoplosyllis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Astreptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Streptospinigera,&lt;/i&gt; which are listed in a table and a potential key for their identification is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mediterranean; Canary Islands; sandy substrate; &lt;i&gt;Astreptosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Streptospinigera&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Syllides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Anoplosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Streptosyllis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nunezi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mediterranean</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sarah</firstname>
          <lastname>Faulwetter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aikaterini</firstname>
          <lastname>Vasileiadou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nafsika</firstname>
          <lastname>Papageorgiou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christos</firstname>
          <lastname>Arvanitidis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of coralsnake of the genus &lt;i&gt;Calliophis &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Elapidae) from the Central Province of Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of coralsnake, &lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haematoetron,&lt;/i&gt; from central Sri Lanka. This is the second species of coralsnake known from the island country, after &lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanurus.&lt;/i&gt; It differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanurus&lt;/i&gt; in coloration, possessing a relatively unpigmented head (vs. capped with black from rostrum to nuchal collar), no light spots posterolateral to the parietal plates (vs. one at each side), a banded body dorsum (vs. unicolored), a bright red body venter (vs. orange or yellow through most of the length), and red pigment lateral to the blue under-tail color (vs. no red on tail). It also differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanurus&lt;/i&gt; in aspects of lepidosis, in having a frontal that is shorter or equal in size (vs. longer) than the interparietal suture and a first sublabial that does not touch the second pair of chin-shields (vs. first sublabial broadly touching second pair of chin-shields). The new species is easily distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; species in nearby India and Southeast Asia by characters of external morphology and coloration.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haematoetron&lt;/i&gt; new species; &lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanurus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinhaleyus&lt;/i&gt;; India; Wasgomuwa National Park</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Calliophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haematoetron&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eric</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kelum</firstname>
          <lastname>Manamendra-Arachchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ruchira</firstname>
          <lastname>Somaweera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-33</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zygoribatula colemani &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov (Acari, Oribatida, Oribatulidae) from Granite Outcrops in Georgia, USA, with a highly variable translamella</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The oribatid mite &lt;i&gt;Zygoribatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colemani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Oribatulidae) is described and illustrated based on adults collected from shallow soils in depression pits found in granitic outcrops of the Piedmont Plateau in Georgia (USA). By definition, members of &lt;i&gt;Zygoribatula&lt;/i&gt; always possess a translamella on the prodorsum, the only feature distinguishing this genus from &lt;i&gt;Oribatula.&lt;/i&gt; But &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colemani&lt;/i&gt; shows a full range of variation, from having the translamella well developed to entirely absent; this brings the distinction of these genera into question and points out the need for a careful revision of generic concepts in Oribatulidae. Depending on the specimens examined, &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colemani&lt;/i&gt; could be placed in either genus, but we tentatively include it in &lt;i&gt;Zygoribatula,&lt;/i&gt; since in some specimens the translamella is complete and well delineated. A tentative diagnostic key to differentiate the species of &lt;i&gt;Zygoribatula&lt;/i&gt; previously reported in the USA is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diamorpha&lt;/i&gt;; Granite outcrops; &lt;i&gt;Oribatula&lt;/i&gt;; Piedmont Plateau; soil mites</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diamorpha&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Franklin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roy.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Norton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Crossley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Epimeriidae (Crustacea, Amphipoda) from New Zealand with a description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;horsti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; collected from New Zealand seamounts at 970–1156 m depth, is described in detail. This increases the number of known species of New Zealand Epimeriidae to four. Additionally &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bruuni&lt;/i&gt; Barnard, 1961, previously known only from the Kermadec Trench at 2470 m depth, is redescribed using new material collected from Young Nicks Seamount, Hikurangi Plateau. A key is provided for all New Zealand epimeriids. &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;horsti&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from similar species by the unique combination of the following characters: eyes present; dorsal carinae starting on pereon 6; epimera 1–2 posterolateral corner rounded; epimeron 3 posterolateral corner produced.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New Zealand; seamounts; deep sea; taxonomy; new species; &lt;i&gt;Epimeria&lt;/i&gt;; Epimeriidae; Amphipoda; Crustacea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New Zealand</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anne-Nina</firstname>
          <lastname>Lorz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-61</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A 100 million year old gecko with sophisticated adhesive toe pads, preserved in amber from Myanmar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of gecko is described from a posterior lower limb and foot, and a partial tail, preserved in Lower Cretaceous amber from Myanmar that is 97–110My old. It appears to be the oldest unequivocal fossil gecko, predating fragmentary skeletal remains from the Upper Cretaceous and being 43–56 My older than &lt;i&gt;Yanatarogecko&lt;/i&gt; from the Lower Eocene, previously the oldest known gecko preserved in amber. It also provides firm evidence that gekkotans and possibly gekkonids were in Asia at this time. The Myanmar specimen shows, that the distinctive foot proportions and sophisticated adhesive mechanism, involving pads on the toes with transverse lamellae probably bearing numerous hairlike setae found in many modern geckos, had already evolved around 100My ago. The specimen is very small, even compared with juveniles of the smallest living geckos. However, the high numbers of lamellae on its toe pads suggest it is from a juvenile of a species with relatively large adult body size.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gecko; Gekkota; amber; Myanmar; Lower Cretaceous; adhesive pad</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gecko</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>Nicholas</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>George</firstname>
          <lastname>Poinar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
