<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1946.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Dec. 2008</title>
    <volume>1946</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-12-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on Acridoidea (Orthoptera) with some new records from Fezzan, Libya</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study is based on the specimens of Acridoidea during the course of a survey (1993–1996) from various agricutural areas of different regions of Fezzan. Nearly 4,230 specimens were collected from 68 localities and identified down to specific level. From this 50 species of Acridoidea representing 28 genera and 3 families of Acridoidea were identified. Their distinguishing characters and economic importance are given. Bio-ecological data on the species and their relationship with vegetation are also provided. A key to the genera examined is provided. Furthermore, the data resulting from the survey established new records for genera and species of Acridoidea previouly known to occur elsewhere in the country and many new localities recorded for others. Among the present material from Fezzan, fifteen genera, twenty-seven species, and eight subspecies are recorded for the first time. Also, three species and three subspecies are reported for the first time from Libya.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Acridoidea; diversity; Identification key; Fezzan; Libya</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Kamil</middlename>
          <lastname>Usmani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-41</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of mature larvae of &lt;i&gt;Allodynerus rossii&lt;/i&gt; (Lepeletier), &lt;i&gt;Ancistrocerus auctus &lt;/i&gt;(Fabricius), &lt;i&gt;Euodynerus dantici &lt;/i&gt;(Rossi) and &lt;i&gt;Symmorphus murarius &lt;/i&gt;(Linnaeus) (Hymenoptera, Vespidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The mature larvae of four species of Eumeninae, &lt;i&gt;Allodynerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rossii&lt;/i&gt; (Lepeletier), &lt;i&gt;Ancistrocerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auctus&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius), &lt;i&gt;Euodynerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dantici&lt;/i&gt; (Rossi) and &lt;i&gt;Symmorphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murarius&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus), are described. The mature larvae of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rossii&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by the number, morphology and distribution of sensilla of the labrum and epipharynx. The last instar larva of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auctus&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by having an epipharynx with 14 sensilla. The most apparent differences between the mature larvae of &lt;i&gt;Euodynerus&lt;/i&gt; lie in the number of sensilla of maxillary and labial palpi and antennae. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dantici&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by presenting the antennae with four apical sensilla and maxillar and labial palpi with five sensilla on apex. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murarius&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by having the opening into subatrium armed with spines and maxillary palpi with two sensilla at apex. The larval morphology of &lt;i&gt;Allodynerus&lt;/i&gt; is described for first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Preimaginal stages; Eumeninae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Preimaginal stages</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <lastname>Tormos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlo</firstname>
          <lastname>Polidori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Josep</firstname>
          <middlename>Daniel</middlename>
          <lastname>Asís</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gayubo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-54</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new ortheziid (Hemiptera: Coccoidea) from Australia associated with &lt;i&gt;Acropyga myops&lt;/i&gt; Forel (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) and a key to Australian Ortheziidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A peculiar new genus of Ortheziidae is described from Queensland, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Acropygorthezia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;williamsi&lt;/i&gt; LaPolla &amp; Miller, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&amp;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was discovered in two localities in the nests of &lt;i&gt;Acropyga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myops.&lt;/i&gt; Descriptions and illustrations are provided for the adult female, adult male, first-instar nymph, prepupa, and pupa; descriptions only are provided for the secondand third-instar nymphs. Prior to this study, &lt;i&gt;Acropyga&lt;/i&gt; ants were known to enter into trophobiotic relationships only with mealybugs (Hemiptera: Pseudococcidae). Therefore, this study represents the first non-mealybug association between a scale insect and &lt;i&gt;Acropyga.&lt;/i&gt; The new ortheziid genus has a number of unusual morphological attributes: no definite wax plates; no ovisac; an anal ring lacking setae and pores, located dorsally in the middle of the abdomen; simple, large metasternal and mesosternal apophyses; numerous spines over the body, and various instars that are so similar that they are difficult to separate. These characteristics may represent adaptations to its relationship with ants. A key is provided to the Australian Ortheziidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mealybug; trophobiosis; trophophoresy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mealybug</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lapolla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chris</firstname>
          <lastname>Burwell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Seán</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brady</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Douglass</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
