<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1750.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1750</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Hydromedusae (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa) from the temperate southwestern Atlantic Ocean: a review</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Hydromedusae are one of the best-represented planktonic groups in waters of the South Atlantic Ocean in terms of species richness. Nevertheless, medusae of the region are inadequately known because earlier studies have been limited and restricted to few areas. During the last two decades, almost 2000 samples from 54 research cruises have been collected, mostly within the continental shelf of Argentina and Uruguay (33 – 55º S). These samples provide an opportunity to significantly augment knowledge of the richness of the medusa fauna in the southwest Atlantic. Forty species of hydromedusae (six of them new records for the area), including 15 of Anthomedusae, 14 of Leptomedusae, three of Limnomedusae, four of Narcomedusae, and four of Trachymedusae, were identified. Our results indicate that previous lists overestimated species richness of hydromedusae in the area. When misidentifications, updated species synonymies, and doubtful records are taken into account, 71 valid species are recognized here from the study area. Based upon this corrected inventory list, the data suggest that the number of species of hydromedusae decreases markedly with increasing latitude, corresponding with that observed in other planktonic groups of invertebrates.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hydrozoa; hydromedusae; southwestern Atlantic Ocean; biodiversity; checklist; plankton</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hydrozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Genzano</firstname>
          <lastname>Gabriel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hermes</firstname>
          <lastname>Mianzan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <lastname>Bouillon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Diversity of cryptic Metazoa in Australian freshwaters: a new genus and two new species of sessile rotifer (Rotifera, Monogononta, Gnesiotrocha, Flosculariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Rotifers are obligate aquatic animals that are reputed to have particularly efficient mechanisms to survive extreme, or prolonged periods of drought, in the form of inconspicuously small resting stages, hidden between plant litter and sediment. In order to study this phenomenon, we conducted a hatching experiment on dry sediment from two billabongs in Victoria, Australia, which had been stored under dehydrated conditions for about one year. Here, we report on the diversity of rotifers that hatched during the experiment. A total of 48 species, a majority of which belong to groups of sessile rotifers, were recorded, including several new or interesting taxa. Two new taxa are described: &lt;i&gt;Floscularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wallacei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pentatrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigantea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.,&lt;/b&gt; the largest rotifer ever recorded. &lt;i&gt;Ptygura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ctenoida&lt;/i&gt; Koste &amp; Tobias, 1990 is raised to species rank.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hatching experiment; dry sediment; resting stages</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hatching experiment</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Segers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Russell</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shiel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-31</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new red-eyed &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Kanchanaburi Province, Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of gekkonid lizard, &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nutaphandi,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Kanchanaburi Province in central western Thailand. It is a member of the large-bodied &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gecko&lt;/i&gt; group and within this group is probably most closely related to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; Grossmann &amp; Ulber, 1990 with which it shares a similar dorsal pattern of transverse series of white spots on a drab background. It differs from &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; in its greater number of precloacal pores, lower number of dorsal tubercle rows, and in having red (versus green) eyes. Comparisons are also made with several other nominal &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; species currently synonymized with &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gecko&lt;/i&gt; and with undescribed, but well-characterized “forms” of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gecko.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is one of many recently described Southeast Asian geckos that appears to be restricted to limestone habitats and their surroundings.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; Thailand; description; &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gecko&lt;/i&gt; group; limestone</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Montri</firstname>
          <lastname>Sumontha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olivier</firstname>
          <middlename>S. G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pauwels</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptathanas powelli&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., sp. nov, a new infaunal alpheid shrimp associated with upogebiid mudshrimps in Nigeria (Crustacea, Decapoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new alpheid shrimp genus and species is described from the Niger delta in Nigeria. &lt;i&gt;Leptathanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;powelli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; appears to be associated “commensally” with burrows of mudshrimps, &lt;i&gt;Upogebia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcata&lt;/i&gt; (Aurivillius, 1898) (Thalassinidea, Upogebiidae). &lt;i&gt;Leptathanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is superficially similar to &lt;i&gt;Leptalpheus&lt;/i&gt; Williams, 1965, a genus composed exclusively of infaunal species. However, it is more closely related to a generic complex around &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1814, and in particular to &lt;i&gt;Athanopsis&lt;/i&gt; Coutière, 1896. The main diagnostic features of &lt;i&gt;Leptathanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are the presence of an articulated plate on the sixth pleonite; the frontal margin of the carapace with a very short rostral projection and without orbital teeth; the asymmetrical and unequal chelipeds carried folded, with the propodus fitting in a ventral excavation of the merus; and the presence of stout cuspidate setae on the protopod of the uropod.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Alpheidae; &lt;i&gt;Leptathanas&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; infaunal shrimp; Nigeria; West Africa; eastern Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Heteroparasitus&lt;/i&gt; Juvara-Bals 1975 from Karavanke, Austria (Acari: Parasitidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new mite species &lt;i&gt;Heteroparasitus&lt;/i&gt; (Heteroparasitus) &lt;i&gt;mariae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Parasitidae) is described from southern Austria (Karavanke Mountains). A key to the four known species in the genus is given, and the definition of the genus is revised.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Parasitidae; &lt;i&gt;Heteroparasitus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; mite taxonomy; Karavanke</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wojciech</firstname>
          <lastname>Witalinski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of night-lizard of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Xantusiidae) from the Cuicatlan Valley, Oaxaca, Mexico </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; from the Biosphere Reserve area of Tehuacan-Cuicatlan, Oaxaca, Mexico, is described. This new species, &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuicateca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is known from two areas in the Cuicatlan Valley. &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuicateca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a member of the &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaigeae&lt;/i&gt; species Group and is characterized by its small body size, small size of tubercular body scales, poorly differentiated caudal whorls and interwhorls, and relatively large dorsal, ventral and gular scales. It lives in shady places, below rocks along the Apoala River, and is commonly found in plantain, sapodilla, cherimoya, mango and coffee plantations, as well as tropical deciduous forest. The description of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuicateca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; increases the number of species in the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaigeae&lt;/i&gt; Group to five.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaigeae&lt;/i&gt; Group; &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuicateca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species; Xantusiidae; Mexico; Oaxaca</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <lastname>Canseco-Marquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guadalupe</firstname>
          <lastname>Gutiierez-Mayen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andres</firstname>
          <middlename>Alberto</middlename>
          <lastname>Mendoza-Hernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum ( PEREZ-SCHULTHEISS &amp; CRESPO (2008). A new species of &lt;i&gt;Parhyalella &lt;/i&gt;Kunkel, 1910 (Amphipoda, Talitroidea, Dogielinotidae) from the coast of Chile. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 1724, 61-68.)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
