<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1760.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1760</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A comparative analysis of the spatangoid echinoid genera &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Metalia&lt;/i&gt;: a new genus and species of spatangoid (Echinodermata: Echinoidea: Brissopsidae) from the Philippines and the reassignment of &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis persica &lt;/i&gt;to &lt;i&gt;Metalia&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brissalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vannoordenburgi&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., sp. nov. occurs at depths of 200 meters off Siquijor Island in the Philippines and is typical of the family Brissopsidae in having specialised aboral tube feet in ambulacra III within the peripetalous fasciole used for funnel building. It is distinct from species of &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Metalia&lt;/i&gt; in having a shield-shaped subanal fasciole in conjunction with confluent posterior petals. This species has a particularly diverse array of highly localised pedicellariae, with three distinct forms of globiferous pedicellaria (simple fistulate, fanged fistulate and fanged open-bladed), three forms of straight bladed tridentate (narrow-valved, spatulate and terminal-toothed) as well as typical spatangoid rostrate, ophicephalous and triphyllous pedicellariae. &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persica&lt;/i&gt; is the only species in the genus that has a shield-shaped subanal fasciole. However, this species has divergent posterior petals, simple (non-lobed) anterior aboral tube feet, enlarged tubercles along the anterior ambulacrum, no anal fasciole, and lacks both globiferous and ophicephalous pedicellariae. These findings demonstrate that this &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persica&lt;/i&gt; does not belong in &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt; but should be placed in &lt;i&gt;Metalia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Echinoid; Brissopsidae; &lt;i&gt;Brissalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vannoordenburgi&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Brissopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metalia&lt;/i&gt;; Philippines; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Echinoid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coppard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new reports of &lt;i&gt;Hyalella &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea, Amphipoda, Dogielinotidae) from Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Hyalella&lt;/i&gt; includes about 51 species, which occur only in the Americas. At present, 7 species are recorded from Argentinean hydrographic basins. Collections in streams in Argentina made during the years 2001, 2004, and 2005 revealed the presence of several species of &lt;i&gt;Hyalella.&lt;/i&gt; The occurrence of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;araucana&lt;/i&gt; in the Province of Santa Cruz was confirmed. The distribution of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kochi,&lt;/i&gt; previously recorded in Chile, Peru, and Bolivia, was extended to the provinces of Jujuy and Tucumán. A new species was found in the Province of Buenos Aires, and is described here. These new records increase from 7 to 9 the number of species known from Argentina and the Falkland Islands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diversity; Argentina; Amphipoda; Dogielinotidae; &lt;i&gt;Hyalella&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lucia Freitas Dos</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paula</firstname>
          <middlename>Beatriz</middlename>
          <lastname>Araujo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Georgina</firstname>
          <lastname>Bond-Buckup</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-36</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval development in the lutjanid subfamily Lutjaninae (Pisces): the Indo-Pacific genus &lt;i&gt;Pinjalo&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larvae of the two species of &lt;i&gt;Pinjalo&lt;/i&gt; are described for the first time based on seven specimens of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinjalo&lt;/i&gt; (4.3–7.5 mm) and 23 specimens of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lewisi&lt;/i&gt; (5.6–15.0 mm) captured in plankton tows and midwater trawls in the eastern Indian and western Pacific Oceans. Identification was confirmed by fin meristics. These deep-bodied, compressed larvae share all the characteristics of lutjanid larvae, and have some of the most well-developed head spination and fin spines of any lutjanids. The robust spines of the dorsal, anal and pelvic fins bear strong serrations. The preopercular spines are particularly enlarged, some bear fine serrations, and the anterior end of the maxilla also has fine serrations: these fine serrations are rare in lutjanine lutjanids. The two species of &lt;i&gt;Pinjalo&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished by the meristics of dorsal and anal fins, the relative lengths of the first spine of the dorsal fin and the spine of the pelvic fin. The larvae have distinctive pigment on the dorsal fin, head and caudal peduncle. The body shape, pigment pattern, fin-spine morphology, and the fine serrations on the head spines of the two &lt;i&gt;Pinjalo&lt;/i&gt; species are very similar to the larvae of &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythropterus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malabaricus,&lt;/i&gt; and may indicate a close relationship among these four species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Larva; Ontogeny; Lutjanidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Larva</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>M</middlename>
          <lastname>Leis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-49</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Re-description of the tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola falcipes&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Leiuperidae), with comments on larval diversity of the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; consists of 12 Neotropical species, whose biology is not well known. Only four larvae of this genus have been described. The first one to be described was &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes,&lt;/i&gt; but available reports are incomplete and the morphology description is inconsistent, especially in oral disc configuration. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes&lt;/i&gt; was posteriorly re-described based only on adult specimens, and its geographic distribution was restricted. Therefore, there is a need to examine tadpole morphology of this genus in order to provide a new larval description. In this paper we re-describe the tadpole of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes&lt;/i&gt; and compare it with other species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola.&lt;/i&gt; Our description is based on specimens collected at three different localities in northern Uruguay, with series reared in the laboratory. We report a novel oral disc configuration: the uniserial marginal papillae present a wide upper gap and a narrow lower gap followed by two lateral gaps. We also analyze the previously ignored oral disc diversity among Leiuperidae larvae, which must be taken into account in comparisons between species for systematic purposes and ecological studies. Morphometric comparisons with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviana&lt;/i&gt; tadpole reveal that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes&lt;/i&gt; is larger, having a narrower and shorter snout, and a greater narial-ocular distance. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes&lt;/i&gt; larvae belong to the lentic bentonic ecomorphological guild.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">larval morphology; &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcipes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviana&lt;/i&gt;; Uruguay</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">larval morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gabriel</firstname>
          <lastname>Laufer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barreneche</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of cyproideid amphipod associated with unstalked crinoids on the Great Barrier Reef, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gbroidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dingaalana,&lt;/i&gt; a new genus and species of cyproideid amphipod is described from Lizard Island, Great Barrier Reef, Australia. The species is associated with the unstalked crinoids, &lt;i&gt;Comathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;briareus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Comatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotalaria&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Zygometra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microdiscus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Cyproideidae; &lt;i&gt;Gbroidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dingaalanaa&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; Great Barrier Reef; Australia; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>A. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Azman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
