<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1961.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Dec. 2008</title>
    <volume>1961</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">C-heterochromatin variation in the karyotype reflects species level distinction between &lt;i&gt;Erinaceus roumanicus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;E. concolor &lt;/i&gt;(Eulipotyphla: Erinaceidae) in Turkey</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The distributions of C-heterochromatin blocks and nucleolar organizer regions (NORs) were studied in hedgehogs from the European (Thrace) and the Asiatic (Anatolia) parts of Turkey. Karyotypes with 48 chromosomes were found in all the specimens examined. The distribution of large heterochromatic blocks in autosomes was different between samples from Thrace and Anatolia in respect of the presence of a distal block in the autosome no. 15. These two chromosomal types correspond to the karyotypes designated as E II and E I by Mandahl (1978). The comparison with other published data shows that the karyotype E II is found within the range of &lt;i&gt;Erinaceus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roumanicus,&lt;/i&gt; whereas the karyotype EI occurs within the range of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concolor.&lt;/i&gt; Both the species thus differ consistently in the distribution of C-heterochromatin blocks in their karyotypes. The NORs were found in five autosomal pairs of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roumanicus,&lt;/i&gt; and in four autosomal pairs of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concolor.&lt;/i&gt; The position of NORs in individual autosomal pairs may be variable, and two distinct variants were observed in the samples from northern and central/southern Anatolia, respectively. This variation may reflect the presence of two lineages within &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concolor&lt;/i&gt; that were indicated in previous phylogeographic studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">chromosomes; G-banding; C-banding; NORs; distribution; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">chromosomes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Atilla</firstname>
          <lastname>Arslan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jan</firstname>
          <lastname>Zima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Haluk</firstname>
          <lastname>Özparlak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-10</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">One new and four newly recorded species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; (Decapoda: Caridea: Palaemoindae) from Guangdong Province, southern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study, based on a faunistic and ecological survey of the genus &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; from Guangdong Province, expands the knowledge of morphology, coloration, and distribution of an undescribed species and four new records for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosense&lt;/i&gt; Bate, 1868, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inflatum&lt;/i&gt; Liang &amp; Yan, 1985, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatum&lt;/i&gt; Liang &amp; Yan, 1980 and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meridionalis&lt;/i&gt; Liang &amp; Yan, 1983. A more complete diagnosis of these five species is presented. &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterorhynchos,&lt;/i&gt; new species, can be distinguished from its congeners by a combination of characters which includes rostral sexual dimorphism, the two teeth at the proximal part of the cutting edge of the fixed finger of the second pereiopod, the non-inflated palm, and the distinctly longer merus compared which is distinctly longer than the palm or the ischium.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt;; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhao-Liang</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shun-Lian</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>11-25</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploops antarctica &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Crustacea: Gammaridea: Ampeliscidae): the first species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Haploops &lt;/i&gt;from the Southern Antarctic Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described based on an female adult collected in the Antarctic peninsula (Bellingshausen Sea). This is the first species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Haploops,&lt;/i&gt; which is a genus of generally deep boreal amphipods, to be found in the Southern Antarctic Ocean. Morphological characteristics that distinguish this new species from its congeners are the antenna formula A1&gt;pedA2, the A1 and A2 &lt; body length, the lobe of pereopod 7 expanded and densely setose, and the presence of one apical spine and one seta on the telson. In this paper, the new species is fully described and compared with related species; the relationship between &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; and the geographical distribution of the genus is discussed; and a complete key of the 18 valid species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt;; Antarctic Ocean; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Denise</firstname>
          <lastname>Bellan-Santini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean-Claude</firstname>
          <lastname>Dauvin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-36</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phase morphs and phoresy: New species of &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Vitzthumia&lt;/i&gt;) mites (Acari: Mesostigmata: Ascidae) associated with pyrophilous carabids (Carabidae: &lt;i&gt;Sericoda &lt;/i&gt;spp.) in Alberta, Canada</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The mite genus &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius&lt;/i&gt; is composed of free-living species in soil and litter, as well as species that are phoretic on carabid beetles as adult females. Among approximately 60 described &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius&lt;/i&gt; species, one North American species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janus,&lt;/i&gt; was found in laboratory cultures to have two female morphs: one granular, free-living morph, and one smooth, putatively phoretic morph. We here describe the adult females of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perseus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; collected from under the elytra of carabid beetles (Sericoda &lt;i&gt;quadripunctata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bembidioides)&lt;/i&gt; associated with recently burned forests in Alberta, Canada. We also describe the female and male of a distinct, granular, non-phoretic morph of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perseus,&lt;/i&gt; obtained from soil and by rearing the offspring of phoretic females. A key to the females of &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius&lt;/i&gt; species having an ambulacrum on leg I (i.e. subgenus &lt;i&gt;Vitzthumia)&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">predatory mites; phoretic morph; dimorphism; ground beetles; fire fauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">predatory mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Frédéric</firstname>
          <lastname>Beaulieu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Déchêne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-57</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of the quill mite genus &lt;i&gt;Picobia &lt;/i&gt;Heller, 1880 (Acari: Syringophilidae) parasitizing birds in the Australian Region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions of four new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Picobia&lt;/i&gt; are given: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lemi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Manucodia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chalybatus&lt;/i&gt; (Forster) (type host) and from &lt;i&gt;Manucodia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ater&lt;/i&gt; (Lesson) (Passeriformes: Paradisaeidae) from New Guinea; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;epthianura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Epthianura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurifrons&lt;/i&gt; Gould (Passeriformes: Meliphagidae); &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corcoracus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Corcorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanorhamphos&lt;/i&gt; (Vieillot) (Passeriformes: Grallinidae) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glossopsitta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Glossopsitta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;porphyrocephala&lt;/i&gt; (Dietrichsen) (Psittaciformes: Psittacidae) from Australia. A list of all known species of the family Syringophilidae (Acari: Prostigmata) parasitizing birds of Australian Region is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Syringophilidae; quill mites; ectoparasites; new taxa; Australia; New Guinea; &lt;i&gt;Picobia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Syringophilidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maciej</firstname>
          <lastname>Skoracki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eliza</firstname>
          <lastname>Glowska</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bozena</firstname>
          <lastname>Sikora</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-12-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
