<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1845.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Aug. 2008</title>
    <volume>1845</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-08-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comparative morphology of internal reproductive systems in leaf beetles of the Donaciinae and Criocerinae (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae) and its implication for the phylogeny</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We compared the morphology of the internal and external reproductive organs of both sexes among species of the leaf beetle subfamily Donaciinae and its sister taxon Criocerinae. Using nine characters of the reproductive system, we attempted to reconstruct the phylogenetic tree for the two subfamilies combined. For this study, we used 11 Japanese species (including 2 subspecies) of 2 genera in the Donaciinae and 16 Japanese species of 4 genera in the Criocerinae. Morphological comparison revealed that the internal reproductive system exhibits a large diversity even in each subfamily. In particular, the morphology of the spermathecal organ varies greatly among genera or subgenera. In the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Lema,&lt;/i&gt; we found a marked apomorphic state, that is, an extremely extended spermathecal duct in females and a similarly extended filiform structure on the internal sac in males. Phylogenetic analysis yielded two most parsimonious trees, which differ in criocerine relationship. In seven of the nine characters, the evolution of an apomorphic state was consistent with previous phylogenetic hypotheses.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">internal reproductive system; &lt;i&gt;Crioceris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lema&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Donacia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Plateumaris&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">internal reproductive system</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yoko</firstname>
          <lastname>Matsumura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kunio</firstname>
          <lastname>Suzuki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis &lt;/i&gt;group of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; Fallen (Diptera: Syrphidae) with description of a new species from the Balkan Peninsula </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis&lt;/i&gt; species group of the aphidophagous genus &lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; Fallén is defined as a monophyletic unit and the European species of this group are revised. Based on material from Serbia found at two lowland localities, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteibarba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described. This species is closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis&lt;/i&gt; Zetterstedt and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;accola&lt;/i&gt; Violovitsh. A key for the West Palaearctic species of the &lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis&lt;/i&gt; species group is provided and records of all species from the Balkan Peninsula are presented. The distribution of the new species is discussed and conservation implications considered.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteibarba&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Syrphidae; Balkan Peninsula; West Palaearctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pipiza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteitarsis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ante</firstname>
          <lastname>Vujic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Snezana</firstname>
          <lastname>Radenkovic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dubravka</firstname>
          <lastname>Polic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Life history and larval chaetotaxy of &lt;i&gt;Ahmetia achaja &lt;/i&gt;(Lepidoptera, Lycaenidae, Lycaeninae, Theclini, Cheritrina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Aspects of the life history of &lt;i&gt;Ahmetia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;achaja&lt;/i&gt; (Fruhstorfer) and a description of the immature stages are presented. Larval chaetotaxy and morphological features of the eggs and pupae suggest a close phylogenetic relationship with some other members of the subtribe Cheritrina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megaladena&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;indo-chinensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cheritra&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cowania&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Drupadia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Horaga&lt;/i&gt;; larval chaetotaxy; setal nomenclature; Siamese onyx</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megaladena&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;indo-chinensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gregory</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ballmer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wright</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-59</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Russian &lt;i&gt;Zavrelia&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer (Diptera: Chironomidae), with the description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Zavrelia&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elenae&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudopentatoma&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from the Russian Far East are described and figured as male, pupa and larva. The generic diagnosis is emended to accommodate the new species. Keys to the males, pupae and larvae of the Russian &lt;i&gt;Zavrelia&lt;/i&gt; species are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chironomidae; Tanytarsini; &lt;i&gt;Zavrelia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; Russian Far East</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chironomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oksana</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zorina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
