<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1850.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Aug. 2008</title>
    <volume>1850</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A re-evaluation of the Dynomenidae Ortmann, 1892 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Brachyura, Podotremata), with the recognition of four subfamilies</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A re-evaluation of the Dynomenidae Ortmann, 1892, on the basis of morphological characters, allows four subfamilies to be recognised, viz. Acanthodromiinae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.,&lt;/b&gt; Dynomeninae Ortmann, 1892, Metadynomeninae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.,&lt;/b&gt; and Paradynomeninae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; Sequences of character states for each homologous character (morphocline) show a similar polarity. The Acanthodromiinae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; exhibits a plesiomorphic condition, both in body shape and fronto-orbital disposition as well as in the condition of the thoracic sternum, abdominal holding mechanism and gill structure. Both the Metadynomeninae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; and Dynomeninae are more advanced, the latter being more “carcinized” and the most derived. The Paradynomeninae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; evolved a specialised frontal and buccal region, by forming a projecting “face”. The family Dynomenidae, which presently comprises merely five extant genera and 21 species, but with a worldwide distribution, is amongst the most ancestral brachyuran families, with a good fossil record from the Late Jurassic onwards. A few fossil genera such as &lt;i&gt;Kromtitis&lt;/i&gt; Müller, 1984, and &lt;i&gt;Kierionopsis&lt;/i&gt; Davidson, 1966, appear to conform to the Paradynomeninae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; A key to the subfamilies of extant Dynomenidae is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Dynomenidae; podotremes; fossil Brachyura; new subfamilies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniele</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of African Forest Robin from Gabon (Passeriformes: Muscicapidae: &lt;i&gt;Stiphrornis&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of forest robin from the Gamba Complex in southwest Gabon. This common bird, &lt;i&gt;Stiphrornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrrholaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; inhabits primary lowland forest and forages on or near the ground like the other members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Stiphrornis&lt;/i&gt; of central and western Africa. Unique phenotypic features of the new species include the male’s bright orange chin, throat, and breast, creamy yellow belly, olive green back and rump, and gray flanks. Mitochondrial sequence divergence corroborates our assessment based on its distinct physical characteristics that this is a new species, and suggest that &lt;i&gt;Stiphrornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythrothorax&lt;/i&gt; is likely the most closely related congener.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">African forest robin; &lt;i&gt;Stiphrornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrrholaemus&lt;/i&gt;; Gamba Complex; Moukalaba–Doudou National Park</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">African forest robin</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schmidt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Foster</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>George</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Angehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kate</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Durrant</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fleischer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rhabditid nematodes found from a rocky coast contaminated with treated wastewater of Casey Station in East Antarctica, with a description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Dolichorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; Andrassy, 1983 (Nematoda: Rhabditidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three unknown species of rhabditid nematodes were found from sediment collected in a rocky coast area at Budd Coast, Wilkes Land, East Antarctica. The sediment was contaminated with treated wastewater which had been discharged through a pipeline extending from Casey Station (Australia). The most abundant of the three species is described here as &lt;i&gt;Dolichorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tereticorpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; based on female specimens. &lt;i&gt;Dolichorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tereticorpus&lt;/i&gt; resembles &lt;i&gt;Dolichorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolichuroides&lt;/i&gt; (Anderson &amp; Sudhaus, 1985) but is distinguished by the features of body length, pharyngeal corpus, and vulval lips. The remaining two undetermined species, Rhabditidae sp. 1 and Rhabditidae sp. 2, are briefly reported because the specimens obtained were inadequate in condition or number for detailed taxonomic analysis. It is suggested that these three species are peculiar to this rocky coast, although it is not certain yet whether they are specific to the habitat contaminated with the discharged effluent of the station.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; Rhabditidae; &lt;i&gt;Dolichorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tereticorpus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; human impact; wastewater; pollution; Antarctica</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kenji</firstname>
          <lastname>Kito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yoshikuni</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohyama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The arachnid order Schizomida in the Brazilian Atlantic Forest: a new species of &lt;i&gt;Rowlandius&lt;/i&gt; and new records of &lt;i&gt;Stenochrus portoricensis&lt;/i&gt; (Schizomida: Hubbardiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of hubbardiid microwhipscorpions (Schizomida: Hubbardiidae) are recorded from the Brazilian Atlantic Forest. &lt;i&gt;Rowlandius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linsduarteae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated based on specimens from Mata do Buraquinho forest reserve, João Pessoa, state of Paraíba, northeastern Brazil. This species is apparently related to &lt;i&gt;Rowlandius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sul&lt;/i&gt; Cokendolpher &amp; Reddell 2000, the only species of the genus known from continental South America, and represents new evidence of a biogeographic relationship between Amazonia and the northeastern Brazilian Atlantic Forest. &lt;i&gt;Stenochrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;portoricensis&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, a widely distributed species, is newly recorded from the states of São Paulo and Bahia, respectively, in southeastern and northeastern Brazil. The latter record refers to several female specimens associated with abandoned arboreal termite nests in a cocoa plantation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Biogeography; Termite nest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adalberto</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sidclay</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brescovit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pollyanna</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Poeciloneta&lt;/i&gt; Kulczyn'ski, 1894 (Araneae: Linyphiidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hui</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-64</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The goldrim surgeonfish (&lt;i&gt;Acanthurus nigricans&lt;/i&gt;; Acanthuridae) from Diego Garcia, Chagos Archipelago: first record for the central Indian Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Craig</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
