<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1918.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1918</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Diversity of small Amazonian &lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Hylidae): another new species from northern Bolivia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new small species of &lt;i&gt;Dendrospsophus&lt;/i&gt; is described from lowland Amazonia of the Departamento Pando, northern Bolivia. The new species is mainly characterized by smooth dorsal skin with scattered minute tubercles, relatively large distal subarticular tubercle on first toe, lack of tarsal folds, light brown to dark reddish or purple brown dorsum with numerous small dark markings and spots, dark colouration of loreal-tympanic region sharply outlined and contrasting against dorsal head colouration, one or two small white spots below the eye, yellow vocal sac in life, and advertisement call consisting of two notes with strong amplitude modulation. The new species is tentatively grouped with species placed in the &lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microcephalus&lt;/i&gt; group. It has rather arboreal habits and occurs in the tree canopy along swampy or flooded shores of smaller streams running through terra firme rainforest.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Hylidae; &lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichlei&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Bolivia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jiri</firstname>
          <lastname>Moravec</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <lastname>Aparicio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerrero-Reinhard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gonzalo</firstname>
          <lastname>Calderon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorn</firstname>
          <lastname>Kohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two distinctive new species of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Strabomantidae) from the Cordillera Oriental with a distributional synopsis of strabomantids in Central Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; (Pristimantis) that are tentatively placed in the &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unistrigatus&lt;/i&gt; Group are described from the Yanachaga-Chemillén region in Departamento Pasco, Peru, where 24 species of strabomantid frogs are known. Both new species inhabit the humid montane forest on the slopes of the Andean Cordillera Oriental, and one of the new species apparently is a cryptic relative of another inhabitant of the region. Among 60 species of strabomantids recorded in a two-degree wide transect from the Amazonian lowland to the crest of the Cordillera Oriental, only three of the species restricted to mid-elevations are known from transects in northern or southern Peru. High elevations are dominated by terrestrial &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus,&lt;/i&gt; whereas the lowlands and forested slopes of the Andes are dominated by arboreal &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis.&lt;/i&gt; Within clades there is no elevational correlation with the presence or absence of a tympanum.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Andes; central Peru; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duellman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>Carlos</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>12-25</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new arboreal &lt;i&gt;Lepidodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Gekkonidae) from Espiritu Santo Island, Vanuatu: from egg to holotype</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buleli&lt;/i&gt; is a new gecko from Espiritu Santo Island, central Vanuatu, Melanesia. This species most closely resembles &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulcher&lt;/i&gt; from Admiralty Islands (Papua New Guinea) by its elevated number of midbody scale rows, and belongs to Brown and Parker’s (1977) Group II based on having an entire terminal scansor on all digits followed by two or three divided or deeply notched subterminal scansors on digits II–V. It differs from other Group II species in having the following combination of character states: a high number of scales around midbody, relatively weak dilation of digits, slight webbing of toes III and IV, cloacal spurs, and an original coloration. This species lives in myrmecophilous plants hanging high on trees in the deep primary forest on the west dry coast of Espiritu Santo Island. It also is the first lizard known from a holotype collected as an egg in the field, hatched in captivity, and grown until reaching adult size, allowing its description.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reptilia; Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Lepidodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buleli&lt;/i&gt; new species; Espiritu Santo; SANTO 2006 expedition; Vanuatu; Melanesia; myrmecophilous plants</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reptilia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Ineich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Anolis rubribarbaris&lt;/i&gt; (Kuhler, McCranie, &amp; Wilson 1999), a poorly-known Mesoamerican cloud forest anole (Squamata: Polychrotidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubribarbaris&lt;/i&gt; (Köhler, McCranie, &amp; Wilson 1999) was described based on a single adult male specimen collected in 1994, which lacked color notes or everted hemipenes. We recently collected three additional specimens of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubribarbaris,&lt;/i&gt; one male and two females, from near the type locality in Parque Nacional Montaña de Santa Bárbara. We present a redescription of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubribarbaris&lt;/i&gt; based on this new material, which includes the first description of the hemipenis, the first description of a female, and the first description of the color in life of both sexes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Honduras; Iguania; &lt;i&gt;Norops&lt;/i&gt;; Nuclear Central America; Parque Nacional Montaña de Santa Bárbara; Sauria</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Honduras</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Josiah</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Townsend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Larry</firstname>
          <middlename>David</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ileana</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Luque-Montes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lorraine</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ketzler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-44</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus corantijniensis&lt;/i&gt;, a new species from the Guyana Shield (Siluriformes: Loricariidae) with a molecular and morphological description of the&lt;i&gt; Pseudancistrus barbatus&lt;/i&gt; group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corantijniensis&lt;/i&gt; is described based on specimens captured in the Corantijn River in Suriname. It is diagnosed by a particular arrangement of whitish spots, very small in the anterior three quarters of the head and large from the posterior part of the head to the caudal peduncle. As indicated by our molecular phylogeny based on mitochondrial D-loop sequences, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corantijniensis&lt;/i&gt; is a member of the &lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; group comprising Guyanese derived &lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus&lt;/i&gt; bearing hypertrophied odontodes along the snout and nonevertible cheek plates. Other members of this group are &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;depressus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrescens.&lt;/i&gt; The closest relative to the new species is &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrescens,&lt;/i&gt; while &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;depressus&lt;/i&gt; are sister species. The known distribution range of each of the four members of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; group is disjoint. A key is provided for the identification of the four members of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Armored catfish; Guyanas region; Suriname; endemic; D-loop phylogeny; Corantijn</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Armored catfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sophie</firstname>
          <lastname>De Chambrier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Montoya-Burgos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Pamphorichthys &lt;/i&gt;(Cyprinodontiformes: Poeciliidae: Poeciliini) from central Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pamphorichthys&lt;/i&gt; is described from Preto river, tributary of the São Francisco river drainage. The new species is the sister group of the remaining species of &lt;i&gt;Pamphorichthys,&lt;/i&gt; showing synapomorphies of the genus, including the reduced number of gonapophyses and gonapophyses tips parallel to the vertebral spine. The diagnosis is given by the following unique features: outer row of teeth on pre-maxilar and dentarium with bilobed incisive teeth; distal segments of the third ray of the gonopodium and an elongated anterior branch of the fourth ray with a putative origin in the fusion of several distal segments; anterior and posterior branches of gonopodium ray 6 with distal segments fused into only one segment; six dorsal-fin rays in males; and urogenital region of reproductive females with heavy dark pigmentation all around the anus and urogenital opening.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; Taxonomy; Poeciliinae; Livebearer; Endemism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Augusto</middlename>
          <lastname>Figueiredo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
