<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1752.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1752</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A catalogue of the Antarctic and sub-Antarctic Phoxocephalidae (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Gammaridea) with taxonomic, distribution and ecological data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An up-to-date catalogue of Antarctic and sub-Antarctic Phoxocephalidae is presented, including 35 species. Extensive list of bibliographical references with synonymy, detailed information on geographic and bathymetric distribution, ecological data, museum locations of type-material, remarks on taxonomic and biogeographical status, are provided for each species. The catalogue is based on taxonomic and ecological literature until 31 December 2006. Additional unpublished records of species from the Antarctic and sub-Antarctic collections held at the Alfred Wegener Institut für Polarund Meeresforschung, Bremerhaven, and at the Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales “Bernardino Rivadavia”, Buenos Aires, have been included. The taxonomic status of all the Southern Ocean species has been checked. Species allocated to the genera &lt;i&gt;Paraphoxus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Parharpinia,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Fuegiphoxus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uncinatus&lt;/i&gt; require further study to clarify or confirm the genus allocation. Most of the Southern Ocean phoxocephalids have a wide bathymetric distribution, equally present in the Antarctic and sub-Antarctic regions. The highest species richness is found above 200 meters depth in the sub-Antarctic region. Of 35 phoxocephalid species reported, 25 are endemic to the Southern Ocean &lt;i&gt;s.l.,&lt;/i&gt; 15 are endemic to the Antarctic region and 6 are endemic to the sub-Antarctic region, the latter distributed only in the Magellan province. Endemicity at genus level attains 22% for the whole Southern Ocean, with 3 genera restricted to the Magellan province and one genus to the West Antarctic, Magellan and sub-Antarctic islands provinces. Habitat and substrate preferences, dietary and burrowing behaviours are scarcely known for most of the phoxocephalid species from the Southern Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Phoxocephalidae; checklist; distribution; ecological notes; Southern Ocean; Antarctic and subAntarctic areas</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gloria</firstname>
          <middlename>M. Alonso</middlename>
          <lastname>De Pina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Rauschert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claude</firstname>
          <lastname>De Broyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Thyasiroidea (Mollusca: Bivalvia) from the mud volcanoes of the Gulf of Cadiz (NE Atlantic)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Thyasiroidea collected from the mud volcanoes of the Gulf of Cadiz are reviewed. Of the seven species identified only one, &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vulcolutre&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is closely associated with a chemosynthetic setting. This species has anatomical features typical of chemosymbiotic taxa and is compared with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarsi&lt;/i&gt; (Philippi, 1845), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;southwardae&lt;/i&gt; Oliver &amp; Holmes, 2006, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oleophila&lt;/i&gt; Clarke, 1989 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;methanophila&lt;/i&gt; Oliver &amp; Sellanes, 2005. The other six, &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Parathyasira)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosa&lt;/i&gt; (Monterosato, 1874), &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortuosa&lt;/i&gt; (Jeffreys, 1881), &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obsoleta&lt;/i&gt; (Verrill &amp; Bush, 1898), &lt;i&gt;Axinulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croulinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Jeffreys, 1847), &lt;i&gt;Mendicula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferruginosa&lt;/i&gt; (Forbes, 1844) and &lt;i&gt;Leptaxinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; Verrill &amp; Bush 1898, are previously known from typical deep-water benthic settings. Of these only &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croulinensis&lt;/i&gt; is known to harbour chemosymbionts although the gill anatomy of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortuosa&lt;/i&gt; suggests that it might also be chemosymbiotic. &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vulcolutre&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to active seeps but there is no pattern in the distribution of the other species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt;; new species; bathyal; seep</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Clara</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>Graham</middlename>
          <lastname>Oliver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marina</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cunha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-56</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of carnivorous sponges (Porifera: Poecilosclerida, Cladorhizidae) from the deep N-E Pacific, and remarks on the genus &lt;i&gt;Neocladia&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new sponge collected from 2,024 m depth on the Vance Seamount in the north-east Pacific by the ROV ‘Tiburon’ is described in the family Cladorhizidae as a new genus and new species, &lt;i&gt;Lollipocladia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tiburoni.&lt;/i&gt; The sponge, 112 mm in total height, is in the shape of a pedunculate disc, like several cladorhizid sponges of the genera &lt;i&gt;Abyssocladia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neocladia.&lt;/i&gt; It differs from these genera and from all carnivorous poecilosclerids by its microsclere complement, consisting of palmate isochelae, sigmancistras, and strongly curved anchorate isochelae superficially resembling those of &lt;i&gt;Neocladia.&lt;/i&gt; A re-examination of the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Neocladia&lt;/i&gt; indicates that it is a valid genus different from &lt;i&gt;Chondrocladia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; carnivorous sponge; Deep Pacific; new genus; new species; Cladorhizidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera; carnivorous sponge; Deep Pacific; new genus; new species; Cladorhizidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <lastname>Vacelet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-65</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chersine&lt;/i&gt; Merrem, 1820 and &lt;i&gt;Chersina&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1831: a nomenclatural survey</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <lastname>Bour</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annemarie</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
