<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1680.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jan. 2008</title>
    <volume>1680</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of taxonomic concepts in the Nannoniscidae (Isopoda, Asellota), with a key to the genera and a description of &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus oblongus&lt;/i&gt; Sars</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Owing to recent taxonomic changes to the Nannoniscidae Hansen, the concepts of the taxa within the family require clarification. Specimens of &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oblongus&lt;/i&gt; Sars, putatively those examined by G.O. Sars, and specimens from Hjeltefjord, Norway were illustrated to clarify the concept of the type genus of the Nannoniscidae. Specimens used by Siebenaller and Hessler (1981) and several other recently-described taxa were evaluated. Standard views are argued to provide more consistent illustrations of morphology. The somite articulations of the posterior body were found to be variable and often inaccurately illustrated feature in nannoniscid taxonomy; this character complex is therefore unreliable for taxonomic concepts in the family. In replacement, new characters that distinguish this family from the Desmosomatidae Sars are described. These include the proximal segmentation of the antennal flagellum, a subdistal dorsal tooth on the left mandible incisor process and ventral pereonal insertions of the coxae. The composition and classification of the family is adjusted using this new information. Subfamilies recently proposed for the Nannoniscidae by George (2001) based on somite articulations are rejected. Diagnoses of several genera, including &lt;i&gt;Saetoniscus&lt;/i&gt; Brandt, were reconsidered using this new information. This latter genus is found to be indistinguishable from &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus&lt;/i&gt; Sars and is placed in junior synonymy. A new diagnosis and a new key to the genera of the Nannoniscidae use the new character information, omitting somite articulations as a primary descriptor. New diagnoses for &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus&lt;/i&gt; Sars and &lt;i&gt;Nannonisconus&lt;/i&gt; Schultz, and revised compositions for these genera are proposed. &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; Siebenaller &amp; Hessler is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Nannonisconus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rapaniscus&lt;/i&gt; Siebenaller &amp; Hessler is diagnosed and pereopods I–II of its type species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dewdneyi&lt;/i&gt; are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nannoniscidae; sexual dimorphism; terminal male; &lt;i&gt;Nannoniscus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nannonisconus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rapaniscus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Exiliniscus&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; standard views; somite articulation; mandible incisor process</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nannoniscidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>George</firstname>
          <middlename>D. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Glassfrogs (Anura: Centrolenidae) of Kaieteur National Park, Guyana, with notes on the distribution and taxonomy of some species of the family in the Guiana Shield</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We provide new distribution records and discuss the taxonomy of three species of Glassfrogs from the Guiana Shield: &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taylori.&lt;/i&gt; These three species were collected in Kaieteur National Park in west-central Guyana. Taxonomic changes were based on morphological, bioacoustic and genetic (a fragment of the mitochondrial ribosomal gene 16S) comparisons. We consider &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillahallicum&lt;/i&gt; to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulai.&lt;/i&gt; We assign the Venezuelan population of &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oyampiensis&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Co.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae&lt;/i&gt; and describe the phenotypic variation of this taxon. We refine the description of &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oyampiensis&lt;/i&gt; and transfer it to the &lt;i&gt;Co.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; species group. We propose the new name &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae&lt;/i&gt; Group for those species of &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; assigned to the former &lt;i&gt;Co.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oyampiensis&lt;/i&gt; Group. We report the first record of &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;midas&lt;/i&gt; for French Guiana, and the first record of &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nouraguense,&lt;/i&gt; new emendation, for Suriname.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Centrolenid frogs; &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulai&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillahallicum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ametarsia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;midas&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oyampiensis&lt;/i&gt;; French Guiana; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mondolfii&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nouraguense&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taylori&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial DNA; Suriname</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Centrolenid frogs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-53</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tadpole and vocalizations of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis hudsoni &lt;/i&gt;(Anura, Microhylidae) in Central Amazonia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Domingos</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Menin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Albertina</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karl</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mokross</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of rare dasydytid gastrotrich &lt;i&gt;Setopus tongiorgii &lt;/i&gt;(Balsamo, 1982) from central Europe with some biological data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Kieneke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ole</firstname>
          <lastname>Riemann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-61</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crystallaria cincotta&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of darter (Teleostei: Percidae) from the Elk River of the Ohio River drainage, West Virginia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of percid, &lt;i&gt;Crystallaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cincotta,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Cumberland, Elk, Green, and Muskingum river drainages of the Ohio River basin, USA. It differs from populations of &lt;i&gt;Crystallaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asprella&lt;/i&gt; of the Gulf Coast, lower Mississippi River, middle Mississippi River, upper Mississippi River, and Wabash River drainages by having a reduced number of cheek scale rows restricted to the post-orbital region, a falcate margin on the pelvic fins, a preorbital blotch distinctly separate from the anterior orbital rim, and a wide mouth gape. The Elk River population is also divergent genetically from populations of the Gulf Coast, lower Mississippi River, and upper Mississippi River drainages. &lt;i&gt;Crystallaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cincotta,&lt;/i&gt; discovered in the Elk River of the Ohio River drainage in 1980, is a rare species with the only extant population represented by 12 individuals collected from 1980–2005 from the lower 36 km section of the Elk River, West Virginia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; darter; Percidae; &lt;i&gt;Crystallaria&lt;/i&gt;; Elk River</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stuart</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Welsh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wood</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
