<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1897.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1897</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New edaphic mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Veigaia&lt;/i&gt; from Slovakia and Bulgaria, with a key to the European species (Acari, Mesostigmata, Veigaiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new European mite species (Acari: Veigaiidae) are described from the Carpathian Mountains in Slovakia and the Stara Planina Mountains in Bulgaria: &lt;i&gt;Veigaia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carpathica&lt;/i&gt; Mašán &amp; Fenďa, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incisilobata&lt;/i&gt; Mašán, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentachaeta&lt;/i&gt; Mašán, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;slovaca&lt;/i&gt; Mašán, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermiculifera&lt;/i&gt; Mašán, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Ecological information is provided for the most common and abundant species, &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carpathica&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;slovaca.&lt;/i&gt; A new key to the females of the European species of &lt;i&gt;Veigaia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Veigaiidae; &lt;i&gt;Veigaia&lt;/i&gt;; description; new species; identification key; Slovakia; Bulgaria</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Masan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Fenda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Uvan</firstname>
          <lastname>Mihal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1873 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Goneplacidae) from Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1873 (Crustacea: Brachyura: Goneplacidae) is described from the Lesser Sunda Islands, Indonesia. It differs from known congeners by possessing a relatively broader carapace and distinctive male first gonopod. The affinities of the new species with the superficially similar &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1873, and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigacarcinicus&lt;/i&gt; Clark &amp; Ng, 2005, are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Goneplacidae; &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Indonesia.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Clark</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-26</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of sea anemone from the Chilean fjord region, &lt;i&gt;Paraisanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabiani&lt;/i&gt; (Actiniaria: Isanthidae), with a discussion of the family Isanthidae Carlgren, 1938</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Paraisanthus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabiani,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Chile, the eighth species of this small family of mesomyarian anemones. Specimens of this species are characterized by six pairs of macrocnemes and 18 pairs of microcnemes in the middle and lower column and a fourth incomplete cycle of extremely small mesenteries in the uppermost column, between 66 and 110 tentacles, and a smooth column without holotrichs or heterotrichs. Specimens occur from the shallow subtidal to at least 30 m around exposed islands and in less protected channels of the fjord region between Chiloé Island (41°7’04.8’’S; 73°53’02.4’’W) and the Madre de Dios Archipelago (50°20’23.1’’S; 75°22’39.2’’W). They often protrude from small rocky crevices or between polychaete tubes, so that &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; only the oral disc is visible. The description is based on examination of 27 specimens collected between 1997 and 2007 and on documentation of live specimens in both their natural environment and aquaria. &lt;i&gt;Paraisanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabiani&lt;/i&gt; was found at only 15 of over 150 study sites along the Chilean coast. If it was present at a site, generally more than 10 specimens were found. For the first time, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; photographs are provided for a member of the family Isanthidae. In addition, live photographs are provided for the type species of the family Isanthidae, &lt;i&gt;Isanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capensis&lt;/i&gt; from South Africa. Family Isanthidae constitutes five genera, which are distinguished mainly by number of macrocnemes, texture and division of the column, and direction of growth of mesenteries.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coelenterata; Cnidaria; Anthozoa; benthos; shallow water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coelenterata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Verena</firstname>
          <lastname>Häussermann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Günter</firstname>
          <lastname>Försterra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species and a new subspecies of &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; (Cirripedia: Thoracica) from the Cainozoic of Australia and New Zealand and a consideration of the significance of tubiferous walls</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A tubiferous cirripede &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;judiciae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., previously known only from two isolated and incomplete shell wall plates identified as &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; sp. cf. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurascens&lt;/i&gt; (Wood, 1815), is described from the early Miocene of Victoria, Australia; a further taxon, &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurascens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miocenica&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov., occurs in the late Miocene-Pliocene of Victoria, and specimens from the early Miocene of New Zealand, previously recorded as &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; sp. cf. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurascens&lt;/i&gt; (Wood, 1815) are redesignated as &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodicostata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. &lt;i&gt;Tetraclitella&lt;/i&gt; is the first cirripede genus known to have had tubiferous walls. Incorporation of chitinous stringers within the shell wall of early tetraclitids (e.g. &lt;i&gt;Epopella)&lt;/i&gt; may have facilitated the development of the tubiferous shell wall, which permitted sessile barnacles to maximise the shell strength to calcite ratio: in doing so, these chitinous stringers not only reduced the diversion of energy required to extract calcium carbonate from seawater, but improved the effectiveness of the shell wall in resisting predators. It is also argued here that the presence of chitin within the shell increased resistance to both corrasion and corrosion, the latter becoming an increasing problem for calcareous shelled organisms following a drop in the pH of seawater after the PalaeoceneEocene Thermal Maximum.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tubiferous barnacles; Sessilia; early Miocene; Australasia; oceanic pH</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tubiferous barnacles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Buckeridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Alainodaeus&lt;/i&gt; Davie, 1993 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Xanthidae) from Balicasag Island, Philippines, with a key to the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Alainodaeus&lt;/i&gt; Davie, 1993, is described from Balicasag Island in the central Philippines. &lt;i&gt;Alainodaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filipinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; can be differentiated from congeners by the characters of its carapace, chelipeds, ambulatory legs and male first gonopods. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Alainodaeus&lt;/i&gt; is provided. The occurrence of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filipinus&lt;/i&gt; in the Philippines represents a remarkable extension in the range of this genus, which was previously known only from islands in the southern and southwestern Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Xanthidae; &lt;i&gt;Alainodaeus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Philippines; Balicasag Island</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Christopher E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mendoza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-63</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the generic position of &lt;i&gt;Typton australis&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1973 (Decapoda: Palaemonidae: Pontoniinae), with a new diagnosis for the pontoniine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Onycocaridella&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1981</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Clarification of the nomenclatural status of &lt;i&gt;Gymnodiptychus integrigymnatus&lt;/i&gt; (Cypriniformes, Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiaoyong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Junxing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
