<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1754.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1754</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Classification, natural history, and evolution of Epiphloeinae (Coleoptera: Cleridae). Part VII. The genera &lt;i&gt;Hapsidopteris &lt;/i&gt;Opitz, &lt;i&gt;Iontoclerus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, &lt;i&gt;Katamyurus &lt;/i&gt;Opitz, &lt;i&gt;Megatrachys &lt;/i&gt;Opitz, &lt;i&gt;Opitzia&lt;/i&gt; Nemesio, &lt;i&gt;Pennasolis&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pericales&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pteroferus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, new genus, and &lt;i&gt;Turbophloeus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, new genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study deals with minimally speciose epiphloeine genera. &lt;i&gt;Hapsidopteris,&lt;/i&gt; based on &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diastenus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, (type locality: México: Jalapa), is the presumed sister taxon of &lt;i&gt;Opitzia&lt;/i&gt; Nemésio [type species: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chiapas&lt;/i&gt; (Opitz), type locality: México: Chiapas: 39 km NW Comitán] a bitypic genus that also includes &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apicula,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: Bolivia: Santa Cruz: Amboro Road, above Achira Campo). Two species define &lt;i&gt;Iontoclerus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humeralis&lt;/i&gt; (Klug) (type locality: Brazil: Parà) and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sericeus&lt;/i&gt; (Klug) (type locality: Brazil: Rondonia: 62 km SE Ariquemes), whose presumed sister genus is the monotypic &lt;i&gt;Pericales,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, based on &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albogilvus,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: Haiti: Sud-Ouest: Massif de La Selle, Morne d’Enfer). The Middle American bitypic &lt;i&gt;Katamyurus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz [type species: &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paxillus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz, type locality: Nicaragua: Cerro Chimborazo], which also includes &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopaniculus,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: México: Sinaloa: 14 km NE La Cap. del Taxte), is considered the sister taxon to &lt;i&gt;Ellipotoma&lt;/i&gt; Spinola (type species: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuiformis&lt;/i&gt; Spinola. Type locality: Colombia). &lt;i&gt;Megatrachys&lt;/i&gt; Opitz (type species: &lt;i&gt;Megatrachys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paniculus&lt;/i&gt; Opitz (type locality: México: Chiapas: 8 km W San Cristóbal) contains two additional species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibara,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: Guatemala: Zacapa: 2 km San Lorenzo) and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatia,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: México: Chiapas: 47.5 km NW Comitán) and is the hypothesized sister taxon to &lt;i&gt;Pennasolis,&lt;/i&gt; new genus [type species; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;merkeli&lt;/i&gt; (Horn), type locality: Arizona: Cochise County, South West Research Station, 8 km W Portal], which in addition to the type species also contains &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; (Van Dyke) (type locality: California: Yosemite National Park, Yosemite Valley. The phylogenetic relationships of two South American monotypic genera have not been deciphered; these are &lt;i&gt;Pteroferus,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, based on &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zolnerowichi,&lt;/i&gt; new species (type locality: Brazil: Santa Catarina: Nova Teutonia), and &lt;i&gt;Turbophloeus,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, based on &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; (Schenkling) whose type locality is Bolivia: Santa Cruz: Amboro National Park, Los Volcanes. Lectotypes are designated for &lt;i&gt;Pennasolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;merkeli&lt;/i&gt; (Horn), &lt;i&gt;Iontoclerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humeralis&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sericeus&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), and &lt;i&gt;Turbophloeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; (Schenkling). The latter binomial represents a new combination whose specific epithet was originally associated with &lt;i&gt;Epiphloeus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera: Cleridae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Weston</firstname>
          <lastname>Opitz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Costa Rican species of &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Chloropidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Costa Rican species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt; are revised. There are seven described species in the region: &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attenuata&lt;/i&gt; (Adams); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coniotrigona&lt;/i&gt; Duda; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fucosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Costa Rica: Santo Domingo de Heredia); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melinifrons&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Costa Rica: San José); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queposana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Costa Rica: Quepos); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubida&lt;/i&gt; Becker and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacculicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Enderlein). An additional species (Elachiptera sp. A) is known from a single female specimen and is not formally described. Only one of these species (E. &lt;i&gt;attenuata)&lt;/i&gt; had previously been recorded from Costa Rica.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chloropidae; &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julia</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mlynarek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Terry</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wheeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-51</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of three little-known monotypic empidoid genera (Diptera: Empidoidea: Brachystomatidae), assigned to Trichopezinae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The monotypic genera &lt;i&gt;Boreodromia&lt;/i&gt; Coquillett, &lt;i&gt;Ceratempis&lt;/i&gt; Melander and &lt;i&gt;Sematopoda&lt;/i&gt; Collin are reviewed with redescriptions of their respective type species and distributions outlined. The male and female terminalia of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; (Loew) and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; Melander are here described and illustrated for the first time. The male terminalia of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elata&lt;/i&gt; Collin are illustrated in detail for the first time. The assignment of these genera to the Trichopezinae is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Boreodromia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ceratempis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sematopoda&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; Canada; North America; United States; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Boreodromia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bradley</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinclair</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allocapnia tsalagi&lt;/i&gt;, sp. n. and notes on &lt;i&gt;A. recta&lt;/i&gt; (Claassen) from the Cumberland Plateau region of northeastern Alabama, U.S.A.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of eastern Nearctic snowfly, &lt;i&gt;Allocapnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tsalagi,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Jackson Co., Alabama, U.S.A. The new species is distinguished from closely-related &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malverna&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mohri&lt;/i&gt; by details of the epiproct. Additionally, the dorsal process of the 8 th abdominal tergite of morphologically-variable &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;recta&lt;/i&gt; is illustrated from the Cumberland Plateau region of northeastern Alabama.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plecoptera; Capniidae; &lt;i&gt;Allocapnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tsalagi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Allocapnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;recta&lt;/i&gt;; Alabama; Cumberland Plateau</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plecoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Scott</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grubbs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
