<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1891.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1891</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revised species checklist of the Paracolletinae (Hymenoptera, Colletidae) of the Australian Region, with the description of new taxa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Colletid bees are widely distributed, but most of their diversity is found in southern continents, particularly Australia and South America. A major obstacle for the classification of Colletidae has been the lack of a well-resolved phylogenetic hypothesis encompassing representatives from all the main lineages of this family. A molecular phylogenetic study recently completed shed light on the subfamilial delimitation and relationships within Colletidae, and included a thorough enough sampling of Paracolletinae that genus-level classification could be evaluated. In this article a revised genus-level classification is presented for the Australian Paracolletinae, an attempt to make it more congruent with the phylogenetic relationships, as well as consistent with the classification of the South American paracolletine generic classification. According to the classification proposal presented here, Paracolletinae comprise 425 species, 298 of them endemic to the Australian Region. All subgenera of &lt;i&gt;Leioproctus&lt;/i&gt; and of &lt;i&gt;Paracolletes&lt;/i&gt; are elevated to the level of genus, thus raising the number genera occurring in the Australian Region to 25. According to a recent phylogenetic analysis of Colletidae, the Australian genus &lt;i&gt;Callomelitta&lt;/i&gt; does not form a monophyletic group with the remaining genera of Paracolletinae. &lt;i&gt;Callomelitta&lt;/i&gt; is hence removed from Paracolletinae and placed on a subfamily of its own, Callomelittinae, subfamily nov. Additionally, a new species of the Australian Paracolletinae genus &lt;i&gt;Andrenopsis&lt;/i&gt; Cockerell is described as &lt;i&gt;Andrenopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;michenerianus,&lt;/i&gt; sp.n..</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">bee; Apoidea; taxonomy; supraspecific classification; new species; new subfamily</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">bee</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <middlename>A. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Almeida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Plumaroides&lt;/i&gt; Brothers (Hymenoptera, Chrysidoidea, Plumariidae) from Santiago del Estero, Argentina: male and female description</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This work describes a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Plumaroides&lt;/i&gt; Brothers called &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tiphlus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; This new species was collected in the province of Santiago del Estero, Argentina. Both sexes are described for this species, and this work represents the first association and description of the female for this genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plumariidae; Argentina; &lt;i&gt;Plumaroides&lt;/i&gt;; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plumariidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patricia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Siphonoperla&lt;/i&gt; species from the Eastern Alps (Plecoptera: Chloroperlidae), with comments on the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of stonefly from the genus &lt;i&gt;Siphonoperla,&lt;/i&gt; from a glacial refuge in the Eastern Alps of Austria. The species’ unique genitalia among congenitors as well as high genetic divergence from the co-occuring &lt;i&gt;Siphonoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt; strongly support its status as a distinct species. We describe &lt;i&gt;Siphonoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ottomoogi&lt;/i&gt; nov. sp. based on morphological and genetic characteristics as well as provide notes on its presumed habitat and distribution. Further notes on the biogeography of the genus are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stoneflies; &lt;i&gt;Siphonoperla&lt;/i&gt;; Soboth; glacial refuge; genitalia; COI</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stoneflies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wolfram</firstname>
          <lastname>Graf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <lastname>Stradner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Steve</firstname>
          <lastname>Weiss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the subfamily Araeopteroninae Fibiger, 2005 in the Russian Far East and neighbouring countries with a description of four new species (Lepidoptera, Noctuidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The subfamily Araeopteroninae Fibiger, 2005 from the Russian Far East and neighbouring countries is revised. Six species occur in Russia, three of which are new: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ussurica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;makikoae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragmenta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nebulosa&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time for Russia. In South Korea five species occur, two of which are new: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Three species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoena,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nebulosa,&lt;/i&gt; and A. &lt;i&gt;fragmenta&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time from China. The formerly described Far Eastern species (A. &lt;i&gt;amoena,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nebulosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragmenta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flaccida)&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed based on morphological characters. Adultss of all species from northern East Asia treated in the article are illustrated in color with their male and female genitalia. Distribution maps of the species in the Russian Far East are presented, along with an alphabetic checklist of 36 described species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Noctuidae; Araeopteroninae; &lt;i&gt;Araeopteron&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Russian Far East; Korea; China; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Fibiger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Kononenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-54</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Stegana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coleoptrata&lt;/i&gt; species group (Diptera: Drosophilidae) from mainland China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nine species of the &lt;i&gt;Stegana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coleoptrata&lt;/i&gt; species group are found from mainland China, including six newly described: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (Stegana) &lt;i&gt;melanostoma&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;pililobasa&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;psilolobosa&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Hubei Province; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;arcygramma&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;melanostigma&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;monodonata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Yunnan Province. A key to all species of the group from the mainland China is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">China; &lt;i&gt;coleoptrata&lt;/i&gt; group; new species; &lt;i&gt;Stegana&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xi-Peng</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-65</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Zeoliarus&lt;/i&gt;, for the endemic New Zealand species &lt;i&gt;Oliarus atkinsoni&lt;/i&gt; Myers and &lt;i&gt;O. oppositus&lt;/i&gt; (Walker) (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha: Cixiidae: Cixiinae: Pentastirini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marie-Claude</firstname>
          <lastname>Larivierèe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Murray</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fletcher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
