<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1726.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Mar. 2008</title>
    <volume>1726</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology of the larval stages of the spider crab &lt;i&gt;Herbstia condyliata&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1787) (Brachyura: Majoidea: Pisidae) obtained in laboratory conditions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The complete larval development of the majoid crab &lt;i&gt;Herbstia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;condyliata&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1787) from the western Mediterranean was obtained from laboratory culture. All larval stages (two zoeal stages and the megalopa) are described and illustrated in detail for the first time. The morphology of the zoeae and megalopa is compared with the corresponding stages of other known species of the family Pisidae. The zoeal stages of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;condyliata&lt;/i&gt; present a pleon with unusual characters within the Pisidae such as the presence of dorsolateral processes in pleomere 3, two dorsal setae in pleomeres 2–4 (second zoea) and the very long posterolateral processes in pleomeres 3–4. The megalopa can be differentiated from other Pisidae species by the presence of a very developed cardiac tubercle on the carapace and the absence of plumose setae on the basal segment of the first maxilliped exopod.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">zoea; megalopa; larval development</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">zoea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pere</firstname>
          <lastname>Abello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Coral</firstname>
          <lastname>Hispano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic Relationship between the Carmine Spider Mite &lt;i&gt;Tetranychus cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt; (Boisduval) and the Two-spotted Mite &lt;i&gt;T. urticae &lt;/i&gt;Koch in China Based on the mtDNA COI and rDNA ITS2 Sequences</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The population structure of the Chinese carmine spider mite &lt;i&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt; (Boisduval) was investigated by amplifying and sequencing a portion of the mitochondrial DNA gene coding for cytochrome oxidase I (COI, 453bp) and a portion in the second internal transcribed spacer (ITS2, ˜645bp) of rDNA. Nineteen &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt; populations of various geographical origins were sampled from all over China. Intraspecific variation analysis showed that 81 nucleotide positions (17.9% of the total length) were found polymorphic in COI sequences, of which 88.9% were silent substitutions. Compared with COI sequences, there were only 11 differences (five transversions, five transitions and one 2bp insertion/deletion) in the ITS2 sequences among these populations. We argue that the reasons for less ITS2 divergences might be that ancestral polymorphism was generally lower for ITS2 than for COI. From the trees established by MEGA based on Kimura-2-parameter distance, we found that the phylogenetic relationships inferred from COI and ITS2 sequences approximately accorded with their geographical relationships. It has long been considered in China that &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urticae&lt;/i&gt; are two independent species. However, the molecular phylogeny obtained by mtDNA and rDNA analyses indicated that &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urticae&lt;/i&gt; from China were not clearly distinguished from each other.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urticae&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial DNA; cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI); ribosomal DNA; the second internal transcribed spacer (ITS2); phylogenetic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinnabarinus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Xie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rong-Rong</firstname>
          <lastname>Xie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kai-Jun</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yue</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-32</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biogeography of Glandulocaudinae (Teleostei: Characiformes: Characidae) revisited: phylogenetic patterns, historical geology and genetic connectivity</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The biogeography of the Glandulocaudinae (former Glandulocaudini) is reviewed. The major pattern of diversification presented by this group of freshwater fishes can be clearly associated to the main aspects of the tectonic evolution of the southern portion of the Cis-Andean South American Platform. The phylogenetic relationships within the group suggest that the clade represented by &lt;i&gt;Lophiobrycon&lt;/i&gt; is the sister-group of the more derived clade represented by the genus &lt;i&gt;Glandulocauda&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lophiobrycon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Glandulocauda&lt;/i&gt; occur in areas of the ancient crystalline shield of southeastern Brazil and their present allopatric distribution is probably due to relict survival and tectonic vicariant events. Populations of &lt;i&gt;Glandulocauda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanogenys&lt;/i&gt; are found in contiguous drainages in presently isolated upper parts of the Tietê, Guaratuba, Itatinga, and Ribeira de Iguape basins and this pattern of distribution is probably the result of river capture caused by tectonic processes that affected a large area in eastern and southeastern Brazil. The species of &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates&lt;/i&gt; are predominantly distributed along the eastern and southeastern coastal areas, but &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microlepis&lt;/i&gt; is additionally found in the rio Iguaçu and Tibagi basins. &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barberi&lt;/i&gt; occurs in both SW margin of the upper rio Paraná basin and the lower Paraguay and &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; occurs in the upper Paraguay river basin. Tectonic activations of the Continental Rift of Southeastern Brazil along the eastern margin of the Upper Paraná basin promoted population fragmentation responsible of the present day distribution presented by &lt;i&gt;Glandulocauda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanogenys.&lt;/i&gt; We hypothesize that occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates&lt;/i&gt; along the lowland area around the Paraná basin was due to a single or a multiple fragmentation of populations along the W-SW border of the upper Paraná Basin, probably due to the major tectonic origin of the Chaco-Pantanal wetland foreland basins since the Miocene as well as Cenozoic tectonic activity along the borders of the upper Paraná basin, such as in the eastern Paraguay, in the Asunción Rift. Distributional pattern of &lt;i&gt;Mimagoniates&lt;/i&gt; suggests that its initial diversification may be related to the tectonic evolution of the Chaco-Pantanal foreland basin system and a minimum age of 2.5 M.Y are proposed for this monophyletic group. Previous hypotheses on sea level fluctuations of the late Quaternary as being the main causal mechanism promoting cladogenesis and speciation of the group are critically reviewed. Phylogeographic studies based on molecular data indicate significant differences among the isolated populations of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microlepis.&lt;/i&gt; These findings suggest that a much longer period of time and a paleogeographic landscape configuration of the Brazilian southeastern coastal region explain the present observed phylogenetic and biogeographic patterns.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biogeography; Glandulocaudinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biogeography</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Naercio</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menezes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stanley</firstname>
          <lastname>Weitzman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Torres</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of four new species of &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; (Decapoda: Atyidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species, &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venusta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,C.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;tumida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meridionalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from Guangdong Province, China. &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venusta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are popular in the commercial pet markets as ornamental shrimp.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;; new species; ornamental shrimp; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liqing</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiangqiu</firstname>
          <lastname>Liang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fan</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species limits in Antbirds (Aves: Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae): an evaluation of Plumbeous Antvireo (&lt;i&gt;Dysithamnus plumbeus&lt;/i&gt;) based on vocalizations</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Through most of the 20th Century, &lt;i&gt;Dysithamnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumbeus&lt;/i&gt; was considered to comprise three geographically remote subspecies based on plumage: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumbeus&lt;/i&gt; of the lowlands of southeastern Brazil; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucostictus&lt;/i&gt; of the east slope of the Andes from central Colombia to extreme northern Peru; and &lt;i&gt;D&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;.p&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tucuyensis&lt;/i&gt; endemic to the mountains of northern Venezuela. Some recent authors have elevated these taxa to species status without providing additional evidence. We analyzed vocal differences among these taxa and compared the extent of diagnostic differences to a benchmark for species status under the Biological Species Concept (BSC). Vocalizations of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumbeus&lt;/i&gt; differed sufficiently from the others for &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumbeus&lt;/i&gt; to be considered specifically distinct. Although both calls and loudsongs of the two remaining taxa differed from each other in some aspects, the differences did not meet our benchmark for species separation. We therefore recommend that they be designated as D. leucostictus leucostictus and D. leucostictus tucuyensis pending the acquisition of additional vocal recordings or other contrary evidence.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">speciation; Neotropics; &lt;i&gt;Dysithamnus&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; vocalizations; Thamnophilidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">speciation</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Morton</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Isler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Phyllis</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Isler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bret</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whitney</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
