<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1718.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Mar. 2008</title>
    <volume>1718</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; Ozaki, 1936 (Digenea, Gyliauchenidae Fukui, 1929), including the description of two species from acanthuroid fishes from the Great Barrier Reef, Queensland, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of the Gyliauchenidae Fukui, 1929 (Digenea) has been confounded historically by 2 main factors: difficulty in specimen preparation and varying opinion as to the consistency of morphological characters, such as the morphology of the oesophagus and the position of the ovary. Distinction between &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; Ozaki, 1936 and &lt;i&gt;Gyliauchen&lt;/i&gt; Nicoll, 1915 has been blurred by overlap in the diagnoses of these genera. Here we provide a diagnosis for &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema,&lt;/i&gt; definitively separating it from &lt;i&gt;Gyliauchen.&lt;/i&gt; We define &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; as possessing an oesophagus with at least 1 loop, an intertesticular ovary, and a cilia-like lining of the genital atrium, and also by the position of the genital pore definitely posterior to the intestinal bifurcation. We redescribe the type-species, &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;convolutum&lt;/i&gt; Ozaki, 1936 from &lt;i&gt;Prionurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scalprum&lt;/i&gt; (Acanthuridae) from Japanese waters, based on our examination of type material and the literature, and describe 2 new cryptic species from acanthuroid fishes of the Great Barrier Reef, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amphitrite&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from &lt;i&gt;Prionurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; from Heron Island, Great Barrier Reef, Australia and &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reburrus&lt;/i&gt; is described from &lt;i&gt;Siganus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Siganidae) from the same location. We also record &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reburrus&lt;/i&gt; from 3 other species of &lt;i&gt;Siganus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corallinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doliatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vulpinus&lt;/i&gt; from Heron and Lizard Islands, Australia. Distinction between &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amphitrite&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reburrus&lt;/i&gt; is difficult, and is based on the combination of morphometric data and sequence data from ITS2 and 28S (D1–D3) rDNA and ND1 mtDNA genes. We provide a taxonomic key to species of &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; and discuss the taxonomy and biogeography of the group. The description of 2 new species from acan-thuroid fishes on the Great Barrier Reef, Australia, expands the geographic range of &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; from Japan to the greater western Pacific Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amphitrite&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reburrus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; Ozaki; 1936; Gyliauchenidae; Digenea; &lt;i&gt;Prionurus&lt;/i&gt;; Acanthuridae; &lt;i&gt;Siganus&lt;/i&gt;; Siganidae; Great Barrier Reef; Australia; Indo-West Pacific; taxonomic key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Flagellotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amphitrite&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kathryn</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Expanding horizons... The first report of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae, Mysmenidae) from continental North America, with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quebecana,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of the spider family Mysmenidae is here described. &lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quebecana&lt;/i&gt; was discovered in a spider bio-inventory survey of the Yamaska National Park (Québec, Canada). We therefore report the first occurrence of the family in this province, as well as the first member of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt; for continental North America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt;; Yamaska National Park; Canada; bio-inventory</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mysmena&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lara</firstname>
          <lastname>Lopardo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nadine</firstname>
          <lastname>Duperre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pierre</firstname>
          <lastname>Paquin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-44</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Amaryllididae and Lysianassidae (Amphipoda: Lysianassoidea) from off the central coast of Brazil (11&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;S-22&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;S), with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Material collected on the central Brazilian coast from the REVIZEE Benthos Program was analyzed and three new species were herein described. Knowledge about sexual dimorphism on &lt;i&gt;Bonassa&lt;/i&gt; is improved. The hypothesis of endemism of the genus &lt;i&gt;Amaryllis&lt;/i&gt; to Australia is contested with the discovery of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Amaryllis&lt;/i&gt; in the Southwestern Atlantic Ocean. A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lysianassa&lt;/i&gt; is described, and its differences to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; are commented too. &lt;i&gt;Lysianopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concavus&lt;/i&gt; Senna, 2007 is herein described with more details in description and figures. The distributions of the described species are given. Keys to identification of Brazilian Lysianassoidea families and Lysianassidae species are presented in this paper.&lt;b&gt;Key-words:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Amaryllis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bonassa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lysianassa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lysianopsis,&lt;/i&gt; taxonomy, Brazilian province</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andre</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Senna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cristiana</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Serejo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
