<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1717.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Mar. 2008</title>
    <volume>1717</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of two new crayfishes of the genus &lt;i&gt;Fallicambarus&lt;/i&gt; from southeast Texas with notes on the distribution of &lt;i&gt;F. (F.) macneesei&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new burrowing crayfish species, &lt;i&gt;Fallicambarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(F.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;houstonensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(F.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kountzeae,&lt;/i&gt; are described from six and two southeastern Texas counties respectively. &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(F.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;houstonensis&lt;/i&gt; can be distingished from other members of the subgenus by the following characters: ischia of third and fourth pereiopods bear hooks; mesial ramus of uropod with distolateral and distomedian spines, distomedian spine never projecting beyond margin of ramus; cheliped with sufflamen. &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(F.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kountzeae&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;houstonensis,&lt;/i&gt; but the cheliped lacks sufflamen. New distributional records are given for &lt;i&gt;Fallicambarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(F.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macneesei,&lt;/i&gt; a close relative which also occurs in southeast Texas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">crawfish; crayfish; distribution; species descriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">crawfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Johnson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological measurements of manta rays (&lt;i&gt;Manta birostris) &lt;/i&gt;with a description of a foetus from the east coast of Southern Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions and morphological measurements from manta rays (Manta &lt;i&gt;birostris)&lt;/i&gt; caught in bather-protection nets in eastern South Africa are presented and compared to a &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birostris&lt;/i&gt; foetus from southern Mozambique. Specimens examined from South Africa had disc widths ranging between 2230–2370 mm and were immature. The foetus was 1328 mm in disc width. External examination of the foetus revealed the presence of teeth on the lower jaw and spot patterning on the ventral surface. The ventral spot patterning, which is commonly used in photo-identification studies, was similar in style and colour to the patterning recorded in both the examined juveniles and free-swimming manta rays. The presence of a distinctive ventral spot arrangement in this foetus establishes that spot patterns develop before birth. Morphological differences between the foetus and the juvenile specimens are attributed to the folded position of the foetus’s pectoral fins &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utero&lt;/i&gt; and its developmental state. The presence of 1300–1700 mm DW free-swimming individuals from the southern Mozambican area suggests that the foetus was near-term. This study on western Indian Ocean specimens provides the first diagnostic description, morphometric measurements and photographs of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birostris&lt;/i&gt; from this region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Elasmobranch; Reproduction; Development; Ventral Spot Patterning; Photo-identification</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Elasmobranch</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marshall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pierce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bennett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-30</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the sessile crinoid &lt;i&gt;Holopus&lt;/i&gt; d'Orbigny from the tropical western Atlantic, with comments on holopodid ecology (Echinodermata: Crinoidea: Holopodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Holopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mikihe&lt;/i&gt; new species is only the sixth extant holopodid crinoid to be described. It differs from all other extant holopodids in having large and distinct raised tubercles in the center line of the aboral surface of proximal secundibrachials, giving it the appearance of a mailed fist. The holotype, from 758 m, also comes from outside the known depth range of the other tropical western Atlantic species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rangii&lt;/i&gt; d’Orbigny. Some comments are provided on the ecology of Caribbean holopodids, based upon data obtained during dives of the &lt;i&gt;Johnson-Sea-Link&lt;/i&gt; manned submersibles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Holopus&lt;/i&gt;; Crinoidea; systematics; ecology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Holopus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donovan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pawson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An interactive identification key for genets and oyans (Carnivora, Viverridae, Genettinae, &lt;i&gt;Genetta &lt;/i&gt;spp.&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Poiana &lt;/i&gt;spp.) using Xper&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We built an interactive identification key (IIK) to provide a user-friendly tool for the problematic identification of the Genettinae species (Genetta spp. and &lt;i&gt;Poiana&lt;/i&gt; spp.) using Xper², a knowledge platform dedicated to taxonomic description and identification. A total of 45 qualitative characters were described after the observation of &gt; 4500 specimens, representing 19 species. Assessing among-species discrimination efficiency per character partition and character, we were able to establish a list of 13 characters from skull and coat likely to optimize species identification among Genettinae. &lt;i&gt;Genetta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;“letabae”,&lt;/i&gt; which belong to the large-spotted genet complex, was the only species pair that could not be distinguished. The IIK of Genettinae we propose herein (http://lis.snv.jussieu.fr/apps/xper/data/genettes/ web/) may be used to assist regular-basis update of distribution ranges, a needed effort for several poorly known species of high conservation concern.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mammals; Africa; taxonomy; knowledge platform; Xper index; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mammals</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <lastname>Gaubert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antoine</firstname>
          <lastname>Chalubert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guillaume</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; Koslowsky, 1898 and description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; (Iguania: Liolaemidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; is re-described, and its type locality restricted to the Sierra de Fiambalá, Catamarca Province, Argentina. Also, &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scrocchii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a new species of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; belonging to the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; series, previously confused with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; , is described. This new species inhabits the phytogeographic region of Puna in Argentina at 3500 m. and is distributed in Jujuy and northwestern Salta provinces. Diagnostic characters include the color pattern, (composed of transverse paravertebral spots, that are band shaped and never reach the lateral region, and never contact the vertebral zone), and the number of scales around midbody. Several populations from different localities were considered &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; because of their color pattern and squamation. Even though part of this confusion is clarified in this contribution, some populations still require further study.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lizards; &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; group; Koslowsky; Northwestern Argentina; Puna highlands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lizards</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andres</firstname>
          <middlename>Sebastian</middlename>
          <lastname>Quinteros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cristian</firstname>
          <middlename>Simon</middlename>
          <lastname>Abdala</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>Jose</middlename>
          <lastname>Lobo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-67</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apocaligonellidus&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov. for &lt;i&gt;Echinopsis&lt;/i&gt; Fan &amp; Chen, 1996, preoccupied (Acari: Prostigmata: Raphignathoidea: Xenocaligonellididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Q.-H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-03-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
