<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1678.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Jan. 2008</title>
    <volume>1678</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-01-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tanaidacea (Crustacea: Peracarida) from Japan. IV. Shallow-water species from Akajima with notes on the recolonization potential of tanaids</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of tanaids were collected from colonization traps deployed in a shallow water, sandy habitat off Akajima, Nansei Islands. One new parapseudidaen, &lt;i&gt;Parapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenamans,&lt;/i&gt; and one new nototanaidaen genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Paranesotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicephalus,&lt;/i&gt; are described herein. A preliminary phylogenetic analysis of the closest genera confirms the validity of the new genus and suggests a close affinity between the Leptocheliidae and Nototanaidae. &lt;i&gt;Paranesotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicephalus&lt;/i&gt; was by far the most abundant species in the habitat. &lt;i&gt;Parapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenamans&lt;/i&gt; is faster in colonization of vacant substrate (opportunistic species), while being an inferior competitor to &lt;i&gt;Paranesotanais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicephalus&lt;/i&gt; later in succession. A key to &lt;i&gt;Nesotanais&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paranesotanais&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Nototanaidae; Parapseudidae; &lt;i&gt;Parapseudes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paranesotanais&lt;/i&gt;; Colonization potential; Japanese fauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kim</firstname>
          <lastname>Larsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michitaka</firstname>
          <lastname>Shimomura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt; (Isopoda: Sphaeromatidea: Ancinidae) from Japan, with descriptions of two new species and redescription of &lt;i&gt;B. parallela&lt;/i&gt; Birstein</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt; Tattersall, 1905 are described from Japan. &lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oculata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. differs from its congeners in having laterally rounded pleonite 1, well-developed eye lobes with 43–57 ommatidia, uropod about 4–4.7 times as long as wide, blunt and broadly rounded distal corner of carpus of pereopod 1, and the propodus of male pereopod 2 about 2.9 times as long as carpus. &lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dicarina&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is distinctive in having pleotelson with two dorsal carinae and the merus and carpus of male pereopod 2 slightly longer than ischium. &lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parallela&lt;/i&gt; Birstein, 1963 is redescribed using newly collected specimens from the region of the type locality. A key to species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Bathycopea&lt;/i&gt;; Ancinidae; Sphaeromatidea; Isopoda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michitaka</firstname>
          <lastname>Shimomura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-49</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Scissurella &lt;/i&gt;from the Azores with discussions on &lt;i&gt;Sinezona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semicostata&lt;/i&gt; Burnay &amp; Rolan, 1990 and &lt;i&gt;Sinezona cingulata&lt;/i&gt; (O.G. Costa, 1861) (Gastropoda: Vetigastropoda: Scissurellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Scissurella&lt;/i&gt; d’Orbigny, 1824 from the Azores is described and compared to similar species from the eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean areas: &lt;i&gt;Sinezona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulata&lt;/i&gt; (O.G. Costa, 1861), &lt;i&gt;Scissurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costata&lt;/i&gt; d’Orbigny, 1824, &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semicostata&lt;/i&gt; Burnay &amp; Rolán, 1990, &lt;i&gt;Sci.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobini&lt;/i&gt; (Burnay &amp; Rolán, 1990) as well as two representatives from the Caribbean, &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confusa&lt;/i&gt; Rolán &amp; Luque, 1994 and &lt;i&gt;Sci.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;redferni&lt;/i&gt; (Rolán, 1996). The description and comparisons are based on shell and radula morphology examined by scanning electron microscopy. The species that are considered here are described by features including: shell shape, shell sculpture, shape of teleoconch I, which begins after the protoconch and ends at the onset of the selenizone and teleoconch II which extends from the selenizone to the aperture, presence or absence of a slit or foramen, details of the umbilical region and protoconch sculpture and width. &lt;i&gt;Scissurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;azorensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is characterized by the protoconch sculpture, which contains axial cords on the outer margins only, having a open umbilicus region, teleoconch I being greater then one whorl and the amount of strong axial cords over the entire shell. The distributional range for &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semicostata&lt;/i&gt; is extended to the Salvage Islands. &lt;i&gt;Sinezona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fayalensis&lt;/i&gt; (Dautzenberg, 1889), &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;depressa&lt;/i&gt; (Watson, 1897) and &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crossei&lt;/i&gt; (Folin, 1869) are compared to &lt;i&gt;Sin.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulata&lt;/i&gt; to show synonymy.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">protoconch sculpture; slit; foramen; synonyms; eastern Atlantic; distributional range</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">protoconch sculpture</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jaya</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nolt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gymnothorax baranesi&lt;/i&gt;, a new moray eel (Anguilliformes: Muraenidae) from the Red Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gymnothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baranesi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from three specimens collected in moderately deep water in the Gulf of Aquaba, Red Sea, Israel. It is characterized by irregular, pale, rosette-like spots on a dark background. The snout is somewhat slender. The intermaxillary teeth are arranged in one peripheral and one median row. The maxillary teeth are arranged in 1–2 rows, the inner row, when present, consists of only two depressible teeth. The new species is compared to other pale-spotted species in the Indian Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eran</firstname>
          <lastname>Brokovich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shai</firstname>
          <lastname>Einbinder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-01-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
