<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1826.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1826</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review and analysis of altitudinal distribution of the Andean anurans in Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In the following work we examine the richness and altitudinal distribution of Colombian Andean anurans trying to emphasize patterns of distribution. We also supply an updated checklist of Andean anurans in Colombia. At present, Colombian harbors about 396 Andean frogs: 153 species in the Cordillera Occidental, 187 species in the Cordillera Central, and 131 species in the Cordillera Oriental. Of these, the Cordillera Oriental presents the higher number and percentage of endemic species. The frequency distribution of altitudinal ranges for Colombian Andean frogs shows that the majority of species have narrow altitudinal ranges, less than 500 m altitude, and only a few species have broad altitudinal distributions. On the other hand, lowland species have broader altitudinal ranges than do highland species. The hypothesis of a wider altitudinal range of highland anurans is therefore not supported. Finally, the averages of the Jaccard similarity indices for the Andean anurans along altitudinal gradients in Colombian are approximately similar to those of other tropical anurans reported by Huey (1978), but notably lower than those of anurans of temperate localities. Thus, these results are in concordance with Janzen’s hypothesis (1967) about a broader altitudinal range for temperate species, likely because of their higher thermal tolerance.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Checklist; richness; altitude; temperature; Janzen’s hypothesis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Checklist</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <middlename>Hernando</middlename>
          <lastname>Bernal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lynch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Overview of South African &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; (Monogenea: Monocotylidae), with descriptions of 2 new species from stingrays (Dasyatidae) kept in public aquaria</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;citrosa&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. off &lt;i&gt;Dasyatis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysonota&lt;/i&gt; (Smith) from Two Oceans Aquarium in Cape Town and off &lt;i&gt;Himantura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerrardi&lt;/i&gt; (Gray) from uShaka Sea World in Durban and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ukuthena&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. off &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerrardi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uarnak&lt;/i&gt; (Forsskål) also from uShaka Sea World in Durban, are described. These can be distinguished from previously described &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; species by the morphology of the distal portion of the male copulatory organ and the proximal part of the vagina. Vaginal morphology is proposed as an important diagnostic character for species in the genus. &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colorni&lt;/i&gt; Chisholm, Whittington &amp; Kearn, 2001 which was originally recorded from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uarnak&lt;/i&gt; in Israel, was discovered on &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uarnak&lt;/i&gt; sympatrically with &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ukuthena&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and with &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;citrosa&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ukuthena&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. off &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerrardi.&lt;/i&gt; Minor differences in the number of papillary sclerites, the presence of septal tripartite sclerites and in the number of eyespots were seen between &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colorni&lt;/i&gt; collected from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uarnak&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerrardi&lt;/i&gt; from uShaka Sea World and those originally described off &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uarnak&lt;/i&gt; from Israel. We demonstrate that the position of the marginal hooklets can be used to determine the orientation of the haptor of all representative &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; species with or without hamuli. We conclude that &lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt; species may not be as host-specific as previously believed and that minor differences in morphology are host or geographically induced.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt;; Monogenea; Monocotylidae; &lt;i&gt;Himantura&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dasyatis&lt;/i&gt;; public aquaria; stingrays</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendromonocotyle&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Vaughan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leslie</firstname>
          <lastname>Chisholm</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <lastname>Christison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-44</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Pamphobeteus &lt;/i&gt;Pocock 1901 (Araneae: Mygalomorphae: Theraphosidae) from Brazil, with a new type of stridulatory organ</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Pamphobeteus&lt;/i&gt; Pocock 1901 are described from Brazil: &lt;i&gt;Pamphobeteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassifemur&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Pamphobeteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Pamphobeteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigricolor,&lt;/i&gt; formerly described from Colombia, Ecuador and Bolivia, is recorded from Brazil and its distribution in Ecuador and Bolivia is questioned. A new type of stridulatory organ is described from legs III and IV of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassifemur&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. The structure consists of spiniform setae. Stridulation occurs when the spider moves the legs III and IV, sometimes while shedding urticating hairs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tarantula; Taxonomy; Morphology; Amazon; Stridulatory organ</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tarantula</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rogerio</firstname>
          <lastname>Bertani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Caroline</firstname>
          <middlename>Sayuri</middlename>
          <lastname>Fukushima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>Ismael</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva Junior</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-58</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cladonema timmsii&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of hydromedusa (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa) from a salt lake in South Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cladonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;timmsii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Blue Lagoon, an inland saline lake on Eyre Peninsula, near Cactus Beach, due south of Penong, Australia. It is a small medusa with a bell height and diameter of about 2.0mm. It differs from its congeners in having (1) sexually dimorphic gonads, i.e., the males bearing six radially arranged gonadal pouches on the stomach wall, the females lacking gonadal pouches, having instead smooth gonads; (2) different arrangements of nematocyst warts on the main tentacle branches (two rows) and side branches (one row). It is further characterized by having (1) nine simple radial canals, each corresponding with a tentacle bulb bearing a 7-branched stinging tentacle and about six suctorial branches; (2) six oral tentacles with very short stalks, each bearing a terminal nematocyst knob; (3) dark red, lensed ocelli. This is the first report of a species of &lt;i&gt;Cladonema&lt;/i&gt; from Australian waters; members of the genus are also reported herein from the Northern Territory and New South Wales.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladonematidae; &lt;i&gt;Cladonema&lt;/i&gt;; hydromedusae; salt-lake; South Australia; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladonematidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lisa-Ann</firstname>
          <lastname>Gershwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zeidler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
