<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1860.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Sep. 2008</title>
    <volume>1860</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Edwardsiid sea anemones of California (Cnidaria: Actiniaria: Edwardsiidae), with descriptions of eight new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Edwardsiid anemones are common elements of the benthic marine infauna. The group is best known and most speciesrich in the North Atlantic. The Pacific fauna is poorly known, with only one species, &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; McMurrich, 1913, described from the eastern Pacific Ocean. We describe eight new species collected from sediment in California: &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;handi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;juliae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mcmurrichi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olguini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profunda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paraedwardsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scolanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scamiti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Scolanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triangulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; To differentiate the species and address some taxonomic confusion, we redescribe &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; and provide a key to the species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Scolanthus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paraedwardsia&lt;/i&gt;; coelenterates; burrowing; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Edwardsia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marymegan</firstname>
          <lastname>Daly</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ljubenkov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revised and updated checklist of the lizards of Peninsular Malaysia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A revised and updated checklist of the lizard fauna of Peninsular Malaysia includes 17 species not present in the most recent checklist (Das &amp; Norsham 2007). Ten of these 17 species were omitted due to apparent oversight and seven others are additions based on subsequent descriptions. An updated taxonomy is employed for the lizard fauna that also alters the species content, bringing the total number of species currently recognized in Peninsular Malaysia from 95 to 108.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>28-34</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes sulcatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a new pontoniine shrimp (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae) from Vietnam </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe and illustrate a new species of pontoniine shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcatus.&lt;/i&gt; This new species is unique among the shallow water &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; species in having multiple dorsal telson spines, from four to six pairs. A relatively large and swollen faceted accessory pigment spot on the eyestalk, a subtriangular process on the fourth thoracic sternite, and a feebly developed second pair of chelipeds, only slightly larger than the first pair, are among other remarkable characteristics of this new species. The new species was collected in southeastern Vietnam, the South China Sea, in shallows at low tide. It densely inhabits seagrass meadows, but also occurs on other substrata down to 4 m.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcatus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Vietnam; South China Sea; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zdeněk</firstname>
          <lastname>Ďuri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivona</firstname>
          <lastname>Horká</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Chromosomal analysis of three Brazilian "eleutherodactyline" frogs (Anura: Terrarana), with suggestion of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The karyotypes of four Brazilian “eleutherodactyline” samples were analyzed aiming to provide additional cytogenetic data for future understanding of the evolutionary and systematic relationships of this large anuran group. The populations consisted of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; (Chapada dos Guimarães and Rondonópolis, Mato Grosso), &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; (Aripuanã, Mato Grosso) and &lt;i&gt;Ischnocnema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai&lt;/i&gt; (Ilhéus, Bahia). The data revealed that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; have 2n=28 chromosomes, whereas &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai&lt;/i&gt; has 2n=30. All pairs of chromosomes were telocentric, except for the subtelocentric pair 4 in &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai.&lt;/i&gt; Differences in Ag-NOR pattern and interstitial heterochromatin positions clearly distinguished &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dundeei,&lt;/i&gt; and differentiated them from &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai.&lt;/i&gt; The specimens of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai&lt;/i&gt; showed two distinct color patterns, but they did not differ in their cytogenetic characteristics. Karyotypes with 2n=28 and 2n=30 chromosomes have not been previously described for Brazilian “eleutherodactylines” which, to date, had been characterized as 2n=20, 2n=22 and 2n=34. The NOR position differences identified between &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;dundeei,&lt;/i&gt; allied to their known distinct behavior and ecological data, suggested that the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;dundeei&lt;/i&gt; from the Aripuanã sampling location is a new species. Similarities between &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulodutrai&lt;/i&gt; and species currently assigned to &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; are herein discussed on the basis of chromosome number and morphological characteristics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ischnocnema&lt;/i&gt;; cytogenetics; karyotype; NOR; C-banding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sérgio</firstname>
          <lastname>Siqueira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Odair</firstname>
          <lastname>Aguiar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christine</firstname>
          <lastname>Strüssmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Lúcia</middlename>
          <lastname>Del-Grande</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shirlei</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Recco-Pimentel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Venezuelan genus of Hubardiidae (Arachnida: Schizomida) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new Amazonian genus and species of Schizomida is described from Tobogán de la Selva, Amazonas state in Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Piaroa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virichaj&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. and n. sp is the seventh species of the order described for Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Piaroa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virichaj&lt;/i&gt; gen. and n. sp. is distinguished by having the metapeltidium entire; abdominal segment IX – XII elongated in the male; male without posterodorsal abdominal process on segment XII; male flagellum flattened dorsoventrally, very elongated, with two small dorsomedian depressions; pedipalps not sexually dimorphic; spermathecae with lateral lobes slender and curved, with the base swollen, ending in slightly trifid bulbs; medial lobes absent; gonopod absent. The locality where the species was collected is shown in a map, a discussion on the taxonomic characters of the new genus and species, the relationships of the new genus and the interrelationship of some species in Hubardiidae are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropics; Venezuela; Amazonia; Schizomida; taxonomy; new genus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Osvaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>Villarreal</middlename>
          <lastname>Manzanilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <middlename>Ponce</middlename>
          <lastname>De Leão Giupponi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lúcia</middlename>
          <lastname>Tourinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
