<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1759.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Apr. 2008</title>
    <volume>1759</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of the &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; species (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Monophlebidae) of the southwestern United States and Mexico, including description of a new species from Baja California</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A recent phylogenetic study of the scale insect tribe Iceryini (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Monophlebidae) based on morphological and molecular data led to a revised generic classification, including redefinition of three genera, one of which was &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; Cockerell. The new concept of &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; encompasses 22 described species, all of which are found in the New World. Nine species are scattered throughout the deserts of the southwestern United States and Mexico. Here these species are redescribed and one new species, &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bursera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Baja California, Mexico. The adult female and first-instar nymph are illustrated for nine of the 10 species. A key to the adult females of the southwestern species and morphologically similar species of &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Iceryini; taxonomy; North America deserts; &lt;i&gt;Acacia&lt;/i&gt; sp.; &lt;i&gt;Bursera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microphylla&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Brethesiella&lt;/i&gt; sp.; &lt;i&gt;Crypticerya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genistae&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Iceryini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Corinne</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Unruh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Philophylla&lt;/i&gt; Rondani (Diptera: Tephritidae: Trypetini) from New Caledonia, recognized based on female postabdominal structure and molecular sequence data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Philophylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;millei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from New Caledonia is described and its relationship analyzed. This species was recorded previously as &lt;i&gt;Anastrephoides&lt;/i&gt; sp. based on a single female, which closely resembles the eastern Palaearctic species &lt;i&gt;Anastrephoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matsumurai&lt;/i&gt; Shiraki. Whether this similarity reflects the close relationship of these species or a case of convergent evolution was examined using morphology and molecular data. We examined both male and female specimens of the New Caledonian trypetine species and sequenced the mitochondrial 16S ribosomal RNA gene of this species and related trypetine species. This new species is a member of the genus &lt;i&gt;Philophylla&lt;/i&gt; Rondani based both on the female postabdominal structure as well as DNA sequence data.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Tephritidae; Trypetini; &lt;i&gt;Philophylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;millei&lt;/i&gt;; New Caledonia; 16S</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ho-Yeon</firstname>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Allen</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Norrbom</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of &lt;i&gt;Pachyodes&lt;/i&gt; GuenJe, 1858, with descriptions of two new species (Lepidoptera: Geometridae, Geometrinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pachyodes&lt;/i&gt; Guenée, 1858 is reviewed, and two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from South China and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jianfengensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Hainan Province, China. The six previously known species are redescribed, and a lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pratti&lt;/i&gt; (Prout, 1927). Illustrations of adults and genitalia are presented. The holotype and paratypes of the new species are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geometrinae; &lt;i&gt;Pachyodes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geometrinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hongxiang</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Han</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dayong</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xue</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-04-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
