<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1882.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Sep. 2008</title>
    <volume>1882</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-09-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Glypthelmins &lt;/i&gt;Stafford, 1905 (Platyhelminthes: Digenea: Plagiorchiida), parasites of anurans in the Americas </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogeny of the genus &lt;i&gt;Glypthelmins&lt;/i&gt; has previously been examined using molecular data. Based on those results, congeneric species can now be defined by a combination of phylogenetic, morphological and geographical criteria. The 10 putative congeneric species (G. &lt;i&gt;quieta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californiensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;facioi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shastai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pennsylvaniensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hyloreus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intestinalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brownorumae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuxtlasensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva)&lt;/i&gt; form a monophyletic group. In this work, morphological descriptions are provided for these 10 species, including a full list of synonymies, diagnoses, hosts, geographic distributions and details of specimen deposition in museum collections, comments on their life cycles, and references to gene sequences deposited in GenBank. An amended diagnosis of the genus and a key to identify the species is presented, based on a combination of morphological traits.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; &lt;i&gt;Glypthelmins&lt;/i&gt;; Anurans; México; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>U.</firstname>
          <lastname>Razo-Mendivil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>Pérez-Ponce</middlename>
          <lastname>De León</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the pandalid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Pandalus&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea) from the Sea of Okhotsk off eastern Sakhalin, Russian Far East</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the pandalid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Pandalus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1814, &lt;i&gt;Pandalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ivanovi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described on the basis of material from the Sea of Okhotsk off eastern Sakhalin, at depths of 150–200 m. It is morphologically closest to &lt;i&gt;Pandalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypsinotus&lt;/i&gt; Brandt, 1851, a commercially important species widely distributed in the northern North Pacific. Because of the strong similarities between the new species and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypsinotus,&lt;/i&gt; we have examined syntypes of the latter species in order to confirm the specific identity. The new species can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypsinotus&lt;/i&gt; by the more strongly upturned rostrum, the relatively low postrostral ridge on the carapace, fewer carpal articles of the left second pereopod and the small body size. The coloration in life is also different between the two. There is an indication of protandry in the new species, like other congeneric species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <lastname>Eletskaya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-56</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A rare alpine skink &lt;i&gt;Oligosoma pikitanga &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Reptilia: Scincidae) from Llawrenny Peaks, Fiordland, New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of alpine skink, &lt;i&gt;Oligosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pikitanga,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Llawrenny Peaks, Fiordland, New Zealand. This species is diagnosed on the basis of strong morphological, ecological, and genetic differentiation from the following relatives &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acrinasum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infrapunctatum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;otagense,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taumakae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waimatense.&lt;/i&gt; The species is characterized by a shiny black base colour with bright green dorsal blotches, lateral pinkish spots and a vivid orange belly. It appears this new taxon is extremely rare, and at enhanced risk from introduced mammalian predators.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oligosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pikitanga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.;&lt;/b&gt; Sinbad skink; Scincidae; Reptilia; taxonomy; morphology; genetics; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acrinasum&lt;/i&gt;; Llawrenny Peaks; Milford; Fiordland; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oligosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pikitanga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.;&lt;/b&gt; Sinbad skink; Scincidae; Reptilia; taxonomy; morphology; genetics; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acrinasum&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Trent</firstname>
          <middlename>P</middlename>
          <lastname>Bell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Geoff</firstname>
          <middlename>B</middlename>
          <lastname>Patterson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-09-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
