<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1919.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1919</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of chirostylid crustaceans (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Chirostylidae) from Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of chirostylid crustaceans from Taiwan are described. &lt;i&gt;Eumunida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chani&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is characterized by the absence of a pad of densely-packed setae on the pereopod 1, the anterior branchial margin bearing two spines, and the carpus of first pereopod with only two spines. &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anacaena&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatonus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. are similar but separated from each other by the shape of sternite 4 and relative length of the antennal scale. These species closely resemble &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maori&lt;/i&gt; Borradaile, 1916 and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; Baba, 1986, but lack a ventral subterminal spine on the ischium of pereopod 1. &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is separated from &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occidentalis&lt;/i&gt; Faxon, 1893 by the shorter antennal scale and P2–4 dactyli with ultimate and penultimate spines subequal in size. &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singularis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; (Henderson, 1885) by the single, unpaired terminal spine on the flexor margin of pereopods 2–4.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">chirostylid crustaceans</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">chirostylid crustaceans</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Keiji</firstname>
          <lastname>Baba</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chia-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic consideration of eight Chinese bisexual &lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt; populations, based on the morphology of frontal knob and gonopod and the result of cross-breeding tests</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic assignment of the &lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt; from Qinghai-Xizang Plateau has been argued. In the present paper, the morphology of frontal knobs and gonopods of five &lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt; populations from Qinghai-Xizang Plateau (Lagkor Co, Cam Co, Dagdong Co and Jibu Caka, Tibet; Jingyu Hu, Xinjiang) and three populations from North China (Badain Jaran and Yimeng, Inner Mongolia; Xiechi Lake, Shanxi) is described and compared with four non-Chinese species, the results of cross-breeding tests between the eight Chinese populations are documented and the taxonomic assignment of these &lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt; populations is discussed. Morphological observations show that gonopods of the Chinese populations are significantly longer than those of the other species; distal gonopods of the Chinese populations possess spines that can be classified into three groups (posterior spines, exolateral spines and orthostichous spines). In the four non-Chinese species, however, orthostichous spines are absent (thus providing a morphological separation between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urmiana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetiana)&lt;/i&gt; and the number of spines is much smaller than those of the Chinese populations. Discriminant analysis on numerical characters showed that three North China populations were divergent from four Tibetan populations, with Jingyu Hu population intermediate. Compared with the North China populations, the Tibetan populations possess a longer gonopod (longer gonopod, longer distal gonopod and longer finger-like tip), larger basal gonopod spine, larger percent of frontal knob spines that emerge by 2 spines from the same region and smaller percent of frontal knob spines that emerge by 4 and 5 spines from the same region. The &lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt; from Jingyu Hu is morphometrically close to the Tibetan populations by possessing a larger basal gonopod spine, larger percent of frontal knob spines emerging by 2 spines from the same region and smaller percent of frontal knob spines emerging by 4 and 5 spines from the same region, but different from the latter by having a shorter gonopod (shorter gonopod, shorter distal gonopod and shorter finger-like tip), fewer frontal knob spines, more distal gonopod spines and more posterior spines. The results of cross-breeding tests showed that isolating barrier did not exist among the three North China populations or among the five Qinghai-Xizang Plateau populations, while they might exist between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urmiana&lt;/i&gt; and the populations of Xiechi Lake (type locality of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinica)&lt;/i&gt; and Lagkor Co (type locality of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetiana)&lt;/i&gt; and between the Qinghai-Xizang Plateau populations and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinica.&lt;/i&gt; The present results thus support the validity of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetiana.&lt;/i&gt; Among the eight Chinese populations, the five populations from Qinghai-Tibet Plateau belong in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetiana,&lt;/i&gt; whereas three populations from North China belong in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinica.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt;; frontal knob; gonopod; cross-breeding test; taxonomy; Chinese salt lakes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bo</firstname>
          <lastname>Zheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shi-Chun</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-44</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An updated checklist of inland Cladocera (Crustacea: Orders Ctenopoda and Anomopoda) from Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An updated checklist of cladoceran orders Ctenopoda and Anomopoda from inland aquatic habitats in Venezuela is provided, containing a total of 112 species grouped into 39 genera. Recorded cladoceran species of Venezuela represent 30% of the world’s described 370 species of Ctenopoda and Anomopoda. The most representative genera are &lt;i&gt;Alona,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Diaphanosoma,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Moina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Macrothrix,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chydorus&lt;/i&gt; with 19, 10, 7, 6, and 5 species, respectively. Most records (45%) are Neotropical and about 4% are endemic species. Some aspects related to geographical distribution and species richness in the Venezuelan hydrographic basins are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Freshwater cladocerans; geographical distribution; species richness; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Freshwater cladocerans</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Evelyn</firstname>
          <middlename>Zoppi</middlename>
          <lastname>De Roa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>López</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of an early pea crab stage on &lt;i&gt;Tonicia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; (Frembly, 1827) (Mollusca, Polyplacophora)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roland</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Melzer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Enrico</firstname>
          <lastname>Schwabe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alain raymondi,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of deepwater pinnotherid crab (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura) from the Philippines, commensal with holothurians</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The second species of the deepwater holothuriophilus pinnotherid genus, &lt;i&gt;Alain&lt;/i&gt; Manning, 1998, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raymondi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Philippines. &lt;i&gt;Alain&lt;/i&gt; was originally, but erroneously diagnosed as having a 6-segmented male abdomen. All species of &lt;i&gt;Alain,&lt;/i&gt; however, have a 7-segmented abdomen in both sexes; the generic diagnosis is emended. An unusual feature of species of &lt;i&gt;Alain&lt;/i&gt; is male androgyny, a phenomenon otherwise known among pinnotherids only from &lt;i&gt;Nepinnotheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;androgynous&lt;/i&gt; Manning, 1993b. We also take the opportunity to report the first case of male androgyny in &lt;i&gt;Pinnotheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novaezelandiae&lt;/i&gt; Filhol, 1885, a New Zealand species that is herein transferred to &lt;i&gt;Nepinnotheres.&lt;/i&gt; Among pinnotherids, androgynous males are now known from four species in two genera. Little is known of the biology of most pinnotherids, and androgyny may be significantly more prevalent than currently recognized.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Pinnotheridae; &lt;i&gt;Alain&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raymondi&lt;/i&gt;; new species; androgyny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
