<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1907.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1907</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ibericancridae, a new dakoticancroid family (Decapoda, Brachyura, Podotremata) from the upper Campanian (Upper Cretaceous) of Spain </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A small faunule of crabs from the upper Campanian (Upper Cretaceous) of Valencia, eastern Spain, is described as &lt;i&gt;Ibericancer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanchoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and assigned to a new family, the Ibericancridae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.,&lt;/b&gt; which is placed in the Dakoticancroidea Rathbun, 1917, until now known to comprise a single family, Dakoticancridae Rathbun, 1917, restricted to the Upper Cretaceous of North America and northeast Mexico. The Ibericancridae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; shares with the Dakoticancridae the general shape and size of the carapace, the arrangement of dorsal regions of the carapace, a pleural suture situated at carapace flanks, insertion of a sternal thoracic portion between abdomen and coxae of the pereiopods, and long P2 and P3. &lt;i&gt;Ibericancer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the four genera currently included in the Dakoticancridae (Dakoticancer Rathbun, 1917; &lt;i&gt;Tetracarcinus&lt;/i&gt; Weller, 1905; &lt;i&gt;Avitelmessus&lt;/i&gt; Rathbun, 1923 and &lt;i&gt;Seorsus&lt;/i&gt; Bishop, 1988), in having P4 and P5 conspicuously reduced and subdorsal in position, a narrower thoracic sternum, and distinct frontal and orbital features. Because the male and female gonopores are located on the pereiopods, P5 and P3 coxae, respectively, and the spermathecal aperture is at the extremity of the thoracic suture 7/8, the Dakoticancroidea conforms to the Podotremata Guinot, 1977. It is here interpreted as a carcinised podotreme superfamily, the broadening of the thoracic sternum being weak in the Ibericancridae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.,&lt;/b&gt; but distinct in the Dakoticancridae. Dakoticancroid crabs probably employed a carrying behaviour, as do most podotremes, and were characterised by an abdominal holding of the press button type. Morphological characters of the Ibericancridae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; add significantly to our knowledge of the evolutionary processes within the Podotremata.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Carcinisation; Podotremata; Dakoticancroidea; Dakoticancridae; &lt;i&gt;Dakoticancer&lt;/i&gt;; Ibericancridae; new family; Upper Cretaceous; Spain</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Carcinisation</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Artal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danièle</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barry</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Bakel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <lastname>Castillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Notogynaphallia &lt;/i&gt;Ogren &amp; Kawakatsu (Platyhelminthes: Tricladida: Terricola) from Southern Brazil&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Notogynaphallia&lt;/i&gt; Ogren &amp; Kawakatsu, 1990, from South Brazil, are described. &lt;i&gt;Notogynaphallia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoceciliae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Notogynaphallia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arturi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., present elongate bodies with parallel margins and the dorsum with five dark longitudinal stripes on a yellowish background. Additionally, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arturi&lt;/i&gt; has two large lateral bands of brown pigment between the paramedian and lateral stripes. Both species, which are appended to a complex of striped species previously described for the genus &lt;i&gt;Notogynaphallia,&lt;/i&gt; show a unique combination of characters of external and internal morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geoplaninae; striped species; taxonomy; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geoplaninae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Virgínia</firstname>
          <middlename>Silva</middlename>
          <lastname>Lemos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal-Zanchet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>28-46</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The karyotype of &lt;i&gt;Blarinomys breviceps&lt;/i&gt; (Mammalia: Rodentia: Cricetidae) with comments on its morphology and some ecological notes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The geographic distribution of &lt;i&gt;Blarinomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;breviceps&lt;/i&gt; (Winge) includes few localities in forested areas in the Atlantic Rainforest from Bahia state in Brazil up to Misiones province in Argentina. Here we add 14 new records for the species in the region of southeastern Brazil. These findings provided information on morphology, natural history and the first karyological data for the species. During two short surveys, one in Santuário da Serra da Concórdia, Valença municipality and another in Fazenda Marimbondo, Mauá municipality, Rio de Janeiro State, Brazil, six specimens were collected in pit fall traps. The specimen trapped in Serra da Concórdia was a sub adult male (age class 3 according to the upper molar row wear). In Fazenda Marimbondo, four adult males and one adult female were captured. Serra da Concórdia is a secondary vegetation in a semideciduous forest type, being a small fragment of 220 ha. The second locality, Fazenda Marimbondo is a high montane forest in an evergreen forest type. Karyotype of the specimen collected in the first locality presented a diploid number of 28 chromosomes and an autosomal number of 50. The specimen collected in Serra da Concórdia was kept alive for seven days. During this period it was fed with live arthropods, what confirms their insectivorous feeding habit, consistent with the molar teeth morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Karyotype; new records; feeding habits; Atlantic rainforest small mammal</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Karyotype</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lena</firstname>
          <lastname>Geise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Helena</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bergallo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>E. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Esbérard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>F. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Monique</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Sluys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of marsupial frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; Fitzinger (Anura: Amphignatodontidae) from the State of Bahia, Northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; is described from Serra da Jibóia, Municipality of Santa Terezinha, State of Bahia, Northeastern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flamma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by the following combination of traits: SVL 55.3 mm; skin on dorsum weakly granulate; skin adherent on head; snout truncate in dorsal view and nearly vertical in profile; tympanum rounded; presence of two small supraocular tubercles (anterior tubercle bigger than posterior one); webbing poorly developed between fingers II-III and III-IV; calcars present; distinct color pattern. Comments on species habitat are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Amphignathodontidae; &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flamma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Atlantic Rain Forest; Northeastern Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Flora</firstname>
          <middlename>Acuña</middlename>
          <lastname>Juncá</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Nunes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
