<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1819.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1819</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular and morphological evidence reveals three species within the California sister butterfly, &lt;i&gt;Adelpha bredowii&lt;/i&gt; (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae: Limenitidinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In recent decades the butterfly &lt;i&gt;Adelpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii&lt;/i&gt; (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae), known in the USA as the California Sister, has been considered to be a polytypic array of taxa, composed of two, three or four subspecies. The most recent review of the genus (Willmott 2003a) recognized three: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eulalia&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;guatemalensis)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica.&lt;/i&gt; We used mitochondrial (COII) and nuclear (Tpi) DNA sequence data, coupled with a reevaluation of traditional morphological characters, to determine the phylogenetic relationships between members of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii&lt;/i&gt; complex, and to elucidate their taxonomic status. Phylogenetic analysis of molecular data corroborated the monophyly of each of the three subspecies (sensu Willmott), with the following topology: (bredowii + (eulalia + &lt;i&gt;californica)).&lt;/i&gt; Average levels of &lt;i&gt;COII&lt;/i&gt; variation among these taxa were much greater than the average variation within each taxon (3.4% vs. 0.2%, respectively). There were no shared alleles among these taxa, even from localities where two lineages (bredowii and &lt;i&gt;eulalia)&lt;/i&gt; were collected in exact sympatry and synchrony. The degree of genetic divergence, reciprocal monophyly, and absence of shared alleles between taxa, coupled with unique morphological and distributional attributes of each, strongly suggest that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eulalia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; are all species-level taxa, as they are treated herein (rev. stat.). &lt;i&gt;Adelpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii&lt;/i&gt; is endemic to western, central and southern Mexico: the syntype female (herein designated Lectotype) most likely originated near Oaxaca City, Oaxaca. &lt;i&gt;Adelpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eulalia&lt;/i&gt; occurs from Guatemala, through much of Mexico, to Arizona, New Mexico and Texas, United States (as permanent residents; further north as vagrants), and occurs in exact sympatry with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bredowii&lt;/i&gt; at least in Oaxaca, Mexico, but potentially in much of western and southwestern Mexico. The syntype female of &lt;i&gt;eulalia&lt;/i&gt; (herein designated Lectotype) most likely originated from south-central Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Adelpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; is allopatric with respect to the other two species, occurring in northern Baja California, much of California, far western Nevada, Oregon and Washington. Our results highlight the continuous need for systematic scrutiny of familiar taxa, and raise the prospect that the genus &lt;i&gt;Adelpha&lt;/i&gt; may be comprised of many more hidden species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">phylogeny; DNA barcoding; Mexico; molecular systematics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kathleen</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prudic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Warren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorge</firstname>
          <lastname>Llorente-Bousquets</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;the Yunnan shoot borer,&lt;i&gt; Tomicus yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; Kirkendall &amp; Faccoli sp. n. (Curculionidae, Scolytinae), an unusually aggressive pine shoot beetle from southern China, with a key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new and highly aggressive species of pine shoot beetle, &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; Kirkendall &amp; Faccoli, which has been decimating &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; forests in southwest China for almost three decades. This species was confused with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; until recent molecular studies showed the SW China populations to be quite divergent from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; of northeast China and Europe. The clearest morphological differences between these two species lie in the surface sculpture of the elytra: the new species has more widely spaced interstrial granules on the elytral disc, the punctures of interstria 2 on the declivity arranged irregularly and those of striae 1 and 3 smaller. The new species also has dense small hairs on the tip of the antennal club, while &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; has only scattered small hairs on that segment. Mature &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; specimens are uniformly black, while those of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; have the bulk of the elytra lighter than the base of the elytra and the pronotum. The new species is actually more similar to the Mediterranean species &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;destruens,&lt;/i&gt; which differs in geographical distribution and in having the punctures of interstria 2 dense on the declivity and light-colored antennae. Species of &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; are of general concern to foresters because of their impact on conifer growth, but good illustrations for many species are lacking. We here provide a detailed key to all seven species of the genus (T. &lt;i&gt;minor,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;destruens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevipilosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; and the virtually unknown &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puellus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilifer)&lt;/i&gt; as well as diagnostic photographs and drawings. We summarize the biological differences between the new species and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; and recommend improved communication between taxonomists and forest entomologists, as avoidable taxonomic confusion such as that of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;destruens&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt; hinders the combatting of outbreaks of forest insects.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Yunnan; &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt;; bark beetle; forest pest; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piniperda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;destruens&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevipilosus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puellus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilifer&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Yunnan</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kirkendall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Massimo</firstname>
          <lastname>Faccoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hui</firstname>
          <lastname>Ye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-39</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Distinguishing between &lt;i&gt;Leptidea sinapis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L. reali&lt;/i&gt; (Lepidoptera: Pieridae) using a morphometric approach: impact of measurement error on the discriminative characters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A morphometric approach was used to test the possibility of discriminating between &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinapis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reali&lt;/i&gt; by taking into account some new genitalic characters in addition to those used in previous surveys. Principal component analysis, performed on the size-and-shape data sets and on the size-adjusted data sets, has allowed two completely separate morphotypes to be detected, both in males and in females. Discriminant analysis has confirmed the separation of previously detected morphotypes and has correctly classified 100% of the specimens in both sexes with six discriminative characters being identified in males and two in females. However, some of these discriminative characters were not considered reliable enough because of the high associated measurement error and the scarce discriminative power. Reliable discriminative characters were: &lt;i&gt;vinculum&lt;/i&gt; (≈ &lt;i&gt;valve)&lt;/i&gt; width, length of &lt;i&gt;phallus&lt;/i&gt; (≈ &lt;i&gt;aedoeagus&lt;/i&gt; ≈ &lt;i&gt;aedeagus),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saccus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;uncus&lt;/i&gt; in males and &lt;i&gt;ductus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bursae&lt;/i&gt; length in females. The main topics discussed are: a comparison of the discriminative characters with previous studies, the sources of measurement error and the devices used to reduce it, as well as the between and within-species variability of the characters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">sibling species; repeatability; size-adjustments; principal component analysis; discriminant analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">sibling species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michele</firstname>
          <lastname>Fumi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-54</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of&lt;i&gt; Myrsidea &lt;/i&gt;Waterston (Phthiraptera: Menoponidae) from antshrikes and antbirds (Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Myrsidea&lt;/i&gt; parasitic on members of the avian family Thamnophilidae are described herein. They and their type hosts are &lt;i&gt;Myrsidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klickai&lt;/i&gt; ex the Northern Slaty Antshrike, &lt;i&gt;Thamnophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Shaw, 1809), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dacostai&lt;/i&gt; ex the Barred Antshrike, &lt;i&gt;Thamnophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doliatus&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1764), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spellmani&lt;/i&gt; ex the Spotted Antbird, &lt;i&gt;Hylophylax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naevioides&lt;/i&gt; (Lafresnaye, 1847), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;milleri&lt;/i&gt; ex the Rufous-throated Antbird, &lt;i&gt;Gymnopithys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufigula&lt;/i&gt; (Boddaert, 1783), and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mayermae&lt;/i&gt; ex the White-faced Antbird, &lt;i&gt;Pithys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albifrons&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1766). A portion of the mitochondrial COI gene for some of these and other species of &lt;i&gt;Myrsidea&lt;/i&gt; was sequenced to compare genetic divergences.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">chewing lice; sequence; mitochondrial COI</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">chewing lice</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Price</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Johnson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dalgleish</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Himacerus&lt;/i&gt; from South Africa (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Nabidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Himacerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frater&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the western part of the Republic of South Africa. It is closely related to &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hottentotta&lt;/i&gt; (Reuter). A key to the Afrotropical species of &lt;i&gt;Himacerus&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Nabidae; &lt;i&gt;Himacerus&lt;/i&gt;; South Africa; new species; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Izyaslav</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kerzhner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dawid</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jacobs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-67</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum ( Fox, E.G.P &lt;i&gt;et al. &lt;/i&gt;(2007) On the immature stages of the crazy ant &lt;i&gt;Paratrechina longicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Latreille 1802) (Hymenoptera: Formicidae). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 1503, 1-11.)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
