<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1913.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Oct. 2008</title>
    <volume>1913</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-10-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus solenopsis &lt;/i&gt;Tinsley (Sternorrhyncha: Coccoidea: Pseudococcidae), an invasive mealybug damaging cotton in Pakistan and India, with a discussion on seasonal morphological variation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since at least 2005, a possibly introduced mealybug of the genus &lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; has been causing serious damage to cotton (Gossypium &lt;i&gt;hirsutum)&lt;/i&gt; over much of the Sindh and Punjab districts of Pakistan and in north-western India. Some short papers have been published locally giving details on the structure and biology of this species and suggesting the name &lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gossypiphilous&lt;/i&gt; Abbas, Arif &amp; Saeed (2005) but without designating type specimens or depositories. This name is here considered a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudum.&lt;/i&gt; A detailed morphological study has been unable to separate this species from many specimens of &lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; from the Neotropics that are believed to be &lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; Tinsley. The material from the Indian subcontinent shows considerable morphological variation in the frequency of multilocular disc pores and oral collar tubular ducts on the ventral submargin of the abdomen; this appeared to be related to conditions under which this species was reared, with those cultured in a screen-house during the non-cotton-growing season being indistinguishable from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; from the Neotropics &lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt; This paper re-describes the adult female of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; Tinsley based on the type specimens from New Mexico, and designates a lectotype. The type material was compared with specimens considered to be &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; from elsewhere in the New World, and from West Africa and several areas in Asia, particularly Pakistan and India. Based of our present understanding of the morphology of adult female &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis,&lt;/i&gt; it is concluded that the species is rather variable, that this variability may be environmentally induced, and that the species currently causing widespread damage to cotton on the Indian subcontinent is referable to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis.&lt;/i&gt; Adult male &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; from North America, Pakistan and India were also studied and again no significant differences were found. Descriptions are provided of the adult male and all the immature stages of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis,&lt;/i&gt; based on material from India and Pakistan. Keys are provided to (a) separate &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; from similar species of &lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; currently known from Asia and (b) to identify all instars. The morphological differences between &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solani&lt;/i&gt; Ferris and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;defectus&lt;/i&gt; Ferris are reviewed and, based on the morphological variation found in the Asian material, it is considered that there is some support for the suggestion that these three species might be environmentally induced variants of a single species. A few details are given of the biology of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; on cotton in Pakistan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gossypii&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;madeirensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt;; Malvaceae; Thailand; Taiwan; Benin; Nigeria; Camaroon; New Caledonia; North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phenacoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gossypii&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chris</firstname>
          <lastname>Hodgson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ghulam</firstname>
          <lastname>Abbas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Muhammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Jalal</middlename>
          <lastname>Arif</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shafqat</firstname>
          <lastname>Saeed</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Haider</firstname>
          <lastname>Karar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Athousius&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1905 of China, and re-establishment of the genus &lt;i&gt;Thacana &lt;/i&gt;Fleutiaux, 1936 (Insecta: Coleoptera, Elateridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Athousius&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1905 from China are revised, described, illustrated, a key to species is given, and some systematic characters are discussed. The genus &lt;i&gt;Thacana&lt;/i&gt; Fleutiaux, 1936 is re-established as a bona gen. and is excluded from the Chinese fauna in this paper. The following species are introduced as new to science: &lt;i&gt;Athousius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gansuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiuzhaigonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muyupingensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shaanxiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">entomology; taxonomy; Coleoptera; Elateridae; &lt;i&gt;Athousius&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Thacana&lt;/i&gt; bona gen.; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">entomology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rainer</firstname>
          <lastname>Schimmel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dariusz</firstname>
          <lastname>Tarnawski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-48</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contribution to the knowledge of Seychellois Scirtidae (Coleoptera: Scirtoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scirtes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confinis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavohumeralis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Seychelles Archipelago. &lt;i&gt;Cyphon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumductus&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularius&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924. &lt;i&gt;Cyphon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularius&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biperforatus&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahensis&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924, and &lt;i&gt;Scirtes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seychellensis&lt;/i&gt; Champion, 1924 are redescribed and illustrated; lectotypes and paralectotypes of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seychellensis&lt;/i&gt; are designated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scirtidae; &lt;i&gt;Scirtes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cyphon&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; new synonym; redescriptions; Seychelles Archipelago</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scirtidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rafal</firstname>
          <lastname>Ruta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-10-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
