<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1839.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Aug. 2008</title>
    <volume>1839</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-08-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">DNA barcodes for Cladocera and Copepoda from Mexico and Guatemala, highlights and new discoveries</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">DNA barcoding, based on sequence diversity in the mitochondrial COI gene, has proven an excellent tool for identifying species in many animal groups. Here, we report the first barcode studies for freshwater zooplankton from Mexico and Guatemala and discuss the taxonomic and biological implications of this work. Our studies examined 61 species of Cladocera and 21 of Copepoda, about 40% of the known fauna in this region. Sequence divergences among conspecific individuals of cladocerans and copepods averaged 0.82% and 0.79%, respectively, while sequence divergences among congeneric taxa were on average 15-20 times as high. Barcodes were successful in discriminating all species in our study, but sequences for Mexican &lt;i&gt;Daphnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exilis&lt;/i&gt; overlapped with those of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinulata&lt;/i&gt; from Argentina. Our barcode data revealed evidence of many species overlooked by current classification systems —for example, based on COI genotypes the &lt;i&gt;Diapahanosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birgei&lt;/i&gt; group appears to include 5 species, while &lt;i&gt;Ceriodaphnia&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;rigaudi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Moina&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;micrura,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mastigodiaptomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albuquerquensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mastigodiaptomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidae&lt;/i&gt; all include 2–3 taxa. The barcode results support recent taxonomic revisions, such as recognition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leberis,&lt;/i&gt; and the presence of several species in the &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birgei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sphaericus&lt;/i&gt; complexes. The present results indicate that DNA barcoding will provide powerful new insights into both the incidence of cryptic species and a better understanding of zooplankton distributions, aiding evaluation of the factors influencing competitive outcomes, and the colonization of aquatic environments.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">CO1; mitochondrial DNA; Anomopoda; Ctenopoda; Branchiopoda; Maxillopoda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">CO1</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Elias-Gutierrez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>Martinez</middlename>
          <lastname>Jeronimo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Natalia</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ivanova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martha</firstname>
          <lastname>Valdez-Moreno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>D. N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hebert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Western Pacific Tonguefish (Pleuronectiformes: Cynoglossidae): The first Pleuronectiform discovered at active Hydrothermal Vents</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thermophilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; described from 16 specimens collected by submersibles, ROV, epibenthic sled and dredge, occurs on a variety of substrata at several active hydrothermal sites located at 239–733 m between 21°N and 35°S in the western Pacific Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thermophilus,&lt;/i&gt; the only pleuronectiform fish known to inhabit hydrothermal vent areas, is characterized by the combination of a 1–2–2–2–2 pattern of interdigitation of dorsal proximal pterygiophores and neural spines, 14 caudal-fin rays, 5 hypurals, 9 abdominal vertebrae, 47–51 total vertebrae, 88–94 dorsal-fin rays, 74–80 anal-fin rays, 100–112 scales in longitudinal series, ocular-side pigmentation pattern featuring 5–8, black, mostly incomplete crossbands, uniformly white blind side, and black peritoneum. Of specimens examined, seven including the holotype, were collected on Kaikata Seamount off southern Japan; one specimen was collected at the Kasuga-2 hydrothermal vent, Marianas Islands; and six were collected at sites on the Kermadec Ridge. In addition to specimens captured, many other &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thermophilus&lt;/i&gt; were observed from submersibles and ROVs at hydrothermal sites in the western Pacific including those in the Marianas Islands, at Nikko Seamount near Minami-Iohjima Island, and at Minami-Ensei Knoll, Mid-Okinawa Trough. Many of the specimens examined have skeletal anomalies including fused bones in the caudal skeleton, and missing or partially developed and/or misshapen fin rays.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">flatfish; &lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt;; hydrothermal vents</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">flatfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Munroe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun</firstname>
          <lastname>Hashimoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-59</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Glyptothorax coracinus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of hillstream catfish from Cambodia (Teleostei: Sisoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Glyptothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coracinus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from the western face of the Krâvanh (Cardamom) Mountains and Dâmrei (Elephant) Mountains in southwestern Cambodia. It can be distinguished from congeners by its color pattern consisting of blackish brown body with indistinct pale longitudinal stripes on the lateral line and mid-dorsal regions of the body, pale markings on the nuchal plate absent, length of adipose-fin base 12.3–14.5% SL, length of caudal peduncle 18.6– 21.0% SL, depth of caudal peduncle 7.9–9.4% SL, body depth at anus 11.0–14.6% SL, eye diameter 6.3–7.2% HL, 36– 37 vertebrae, tubercles on the dorsal surface of the head with a single, median ridge, and anastomosing striae absent on thoracic adhesive apparatus that does not reach the level of the base of the last pectoral-fin ray.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sisoroidea; Ostariophysi; Siluriformes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sisoroidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Walter</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rainboth</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
