<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1709.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Feb. 2008</title>
    <volume>1709</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-02-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Catalogue of Blattaria (Insecta) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper is an updated catalogue of the cockroach species recorded in Brazil. It brings a list of species, their distribution in the different states of the country, the housing institution of the types, and an updated list of references. The results indicate 644 (plus 3 incertae sedis) species, belonging to 6 families, 18 subfamilies and 107 genus presently recognized. The types of these species are distributed in at least 29 institutions. The study of species distribution in the different states shows that many cockroaches can be found all over the country, even if 7,7% of the species are only known to occur in Brazil. The states with highest number of records were Rio de Janeiro (169), Pará (132) and Amazonas (120), and the poorest ones are the states in northeast of Brazil where Caatinga and Cerrado are the dominant ecosystems. However species number seems to be locally strongly associated to the research effort. Species accumulation curve indicates a remarkably growing number of species described along time, and it is still in its ascending part with no tendency of stabilization. This information, along with the other results, indicates that the fauna of cockroach from Brazil is still very poorly known, and suggests that the total number of species in the country can be at least five or six times higher.</abstract>
        <abstract locale="pt">Este artigo é um catálago atualizado das espécies de baratas registradas no Brasil. Ele traz uma lista de espécies, sua distribuição nos diferentes estados do país, a instituição na qual os tipos estão depositados e uma lista de referências atualizada. Os resultados indicam 644 (mais 3 incertae sedis) espécies, pertencentes a 6 famílias, 18 subfamílias e 107 gêneros atualmente reconhecidos. Os tipos destas espécies estão distribuídos em pelo menos 29 instituições. O estudo da distribuição das espécies nos diferentes estados mostra que muitas podem ser encontradas em todo o país, ainda que para 7,7 % das espécies apenas sabe-se que elas ocorrem no Brasil. Os estados com maior número de ocorrências foram Rio de Janeiro (169), Pará (132) e Amazonas (120) e os mais pobres foram os estados do Nordeste, onde a Caatinga e o Cerrado são os ecossistemas dominantes. Entretanto, o número de espécies parece fortemente associado com o esforço de pesquisa. A curva cumulativa de espécies indica um número marcadamente crescente de espécies descritas ao longo do tempo, a qual ainda está ascendente, sem tendência de estabilização. Esta informação, juntamente com os outros resultados, indica que a fauna de baratas do Brasil ainda é muito pouco conhecida e sugere que o número total de espécies no país pode ser pelo menos cinco ou seis vezes superior.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dictyoptera; cockroaches; geographical records by states; type housing institutions; updated references; checklist.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dictyoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roseli</firstname>
          <lastname>Pellens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <lastname>Grandcolas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-109</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
