<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1810.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Jun. 2008</title>
    <volume>1810</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Synopsis and annotated checklist of Recent marine Bryozoa from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We present here a checklist of recent marine bryozoans recorded in the literature from Brazil. The total number of species recorded is 346. The most diverse group is the order Cheilostomata with 271 species, followed by the order Ctenostomata, with 42 species, and the order Cyclostomata, with 33 species. Included in the checklist are records by state and citations for species with synonyms utilized in Brazilian works.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bryozoa; checklist; marine fauna; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bryozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leandro</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vieira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alvaro</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Migotto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Judith</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Winston</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-39</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Discovery of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rybocyclops&lt;/i&gt; Dussart, 1982 (Crustacea, Copepoda, Cyclopoida) in subterranean groundwaters of southeastern India, with the description of a new species and its biogeographic significance</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rybocyclops&lt;/i&gt; Dussart, 1982 is a little-known stygobitic genus, hitherto represented by its type and only species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pauliani&lt;/i&gt; (Lindberg, 1954), from Madagascar. A second species, named &lt;i&gt;Rybocyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dussarti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described herein from an agricultural bore-well in southeastern India. The new species has a unique combination of morphological characters, which, &lt;i&gt;inter&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alia,&lt;/i&gt; include: genital double-somite enlarged; anal operculum moderately large; furcal rami somewhat outcurved and about twice as long as wide; female antennules 11-segmented; legs 1–4 with spine formula 2.2.2.2, and setal formula 5.5.5.4; legs 1 and 4 without seta on inner margin of coxa and basis; leg 4 male with one seta more than in female on second endopodal segment; leg 5 fused to somite and represented by vague protuberance, bearing three setae; and leg 6 reduced to two setae. The generic diagnosis is partially amended for accommodating the new species. The discovery of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dussarti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is of much biogeographic interest because it is the first record of &lt;i&gt;Rybocyclops&lt;/i&gt; from Asia and only the second freshwater stygobitic cyclopoid taxon from India, with apparent Gondwanan distribution.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">copepod; cyclopoid; stygofauna; &lt;i&gt;Rybocyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dussarti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Gondwanan distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">copepod</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yenumula</firstname>
          <middlename>Ranga</middlename>
          <lastname>Reddy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danielle</firstname>
          <lastname>Defaye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Range, sexual dimorphism and bilateral asymmetry of rostral tooth counts in the smalltooth sawfish &lt;i&gt;Pristis pectinata&lt;/i&gt; Latham (Chondrichthyes: Pristidae) of the southeastern United States</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Rostral tooth counts of &lt;i&gt;Pristis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectinata&lt;/i&gt; specimens from museum collections, research surveys, and fisheries activities were examined to provide information on sexual dimorphism, bilateral asymmetry, and to aid in the resolution of the taxonomic uncertainty that surrounds the Pristidae. Counts were taken from 105 smalltooth sawfish captured in Florida and Georgia, USA, from 1834 to 2007. The number of rostral teeth present was 22 to 29 per side and 45 to 56 in total. These counts were more constrained, and mean values lower, than historically reported for this species in the literature. &lt;i&gt;Pristis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectinata&lt;/i&gt; rostral tooth counts exhibited sexual dimorphism, with males on average having more rostral teeth than females. Bilateral asymmetry in rostral tooth counts was displayed in 73% of individuals, with no consistent side on which the greatest count occurred. No significant difference between left and right side rostral tooth counts was found.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">rostral teeth; endangered species; systematics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">rostral teeth</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tonya</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wiley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Colin</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Simpfendorfer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vicente</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Faria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdavitt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An overview of Suctorian ciliates (Ciliophora, Suctorea) as epibionts of halacarid mites (Acari, Halacaridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Scant information is available regarding the prevalence and distribution of suctorian ciliates on halacarid mites. However, using this limited information and data from our laboratory on the systematics, biology, ecology and distribution of suctorian ciliates that are epibionts of halacarid mites, we redescribed four suctorian species: &lt;i&gt;Limnoricus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ceter&lt;/i&gt; (Jankowski), &lt;i&gt;Praethecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halacari&lt;/i&gt; (Schulz), &lt;i&gt;Thecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calix&lt;/i&gt; (Schroder) and &lt;i&gt;Acineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcata&lt;/i&gt; Dons. We also recognized &lt;i&gt;Lissacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;allgeni&lt;/i&gt; Jankowski and &lt;i&gt;Thecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;allgeni&lt;/i&gt; (Jankowski) as synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Praethecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halacari&lt;/i&gt; (Schluz), and &lt;i&gt;Thecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laophontis&lt;/i&gt; Jankowski and &lt;i&gt;Paracineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moebiusi&lt;/i&gt; Kahl as synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Thecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calix&lt;/i&gt; (Schroder). Many suctorians have been reported, but not properly identified in the halacarid literature. So, we have attempted to identify those suctorians to species level. Lastly, the interactions between the suctorians and their hosts are also discussed and &lt;i&gt;Praethecacineta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;halacari&lt;/i&gt; is also reported for the first time from the Indian coast.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ciliophora; Suctorea; Halacaridae; epibionts</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ciliophora</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Igor</firstname>
          <lastname>Dovgal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tapas</firstname>
          <lastname>Chatterjee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Baban</firstname>
          <lastname>Ingole</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
