<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1856.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Aug. 2008</title>
    <volume>1856</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The life cycle of &lt;i&gt;Eucheilota medusifera&lt;/i&gt; ? (Torrey, 1902), comb. nov. [=&lt;i&gt;Campalecium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;medusiferum&lt;/i&gt;] (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa: Lovenellidae) from the Bay of Biscay (northeastern Atlantic), including a description of the adult medusa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The life cycle of &lt;i&gt;Campalecium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;medusiferum&lt;/i&gt; ? Torrey, 1902 (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa) was traced in the laboratory from material collected from the Bay of Biscay (northeastern Atlantic). Both newly released and one-month-old male medusae with fully-grown gonads are described, with remarks on their biology and behaviour. The adult medusa corresponds with the diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Eucheilota&lt;/i&gt; McCrady, 1859, and the species is reassigned from Haleciidae Hincks, 1868 to Lovenellidae Russell, 1953. The genus &lt;i&gt;Campalecium&lt;/i&gt; Torrey, 1902 can be considered valid only if the characters of a species with &lt;i&gt;Halecium-like&lt;/i&gt; polyps and &lt;i&gt;Eucheilota-like&lt;/i&gt; medusae are considered of generic significance. Instead, the species studied here is assigned to &lt;i&gt;Eucheilota,&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;medusifera&lt;/i&gt; ? (Torrey, 1902) (comb. nov.), and &lt;i&gt;Campalecium&lt;/i&gt; is considered a likely synonym of that genus. The medusa is different from &lt;i&gt;Lovenella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cirrata&lt;/i&gt; (Haeckel, 1879), type species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mitrocomium&lt;/i&gt; Haeckel, 1879, previously suggested to have been linked to the same hydroid in the Mediterranean. A supposed connection between medusae of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cirrata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Halecium-like&lt;/i&gt; hydroids cannot be supported, and assigning these hydroids to &lt;i&gt;Mitrocomium&lt;/i&gt; is rejected. Future studies may prove that &lt;i&gt;Halecium-like&lt;/i&gt; hydroids release medusae of diverse genera within the family Lovenellidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Hydrozoa; &lt;i&gt;Campalecium&lt;/i&gt;; adult medusa; &lt;i&gt;Eucheilota&lt;/i&gt;; Bay of Biscay; northeastern Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alvaro</firstname>
          <lastname>Altuna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A preliminary checklist of the millipedes (Diplopoda) of the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Great Smoky Mountains National Park, the most visited National Park in the United States, is home to a wide diversity of millipede species. A preliminary list of these species is provided, based on literature records and new collections from the All-Taxa Biodiversity Inventory and the author’s research. This report establishes that the Park’s presently known fauna consists of 62 species (one of which contains two subspecies) in 21 families and all 10 orders known from eastern North America, and includes at least five new state records and 18 new Park records. In the near future several undescribed species will likely be added to the list, as well as described species that are currently known to occur near the Park, but have never been reported from within the Park’s boundary.Key words: Appalachian Mountains, ATBI, North Carolina, Tennessee, biodiversity, inventory, GSMNP</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bruce</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Snyder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>16-32</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; (Perciformes: Cichlidae) from the Ventuari River, Upper Orinoco River Basin, Amazonas State, Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; Heckel, 1840, from the Ventuari River, a tributary of the Orinoco River in southern Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebrina&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from all other species in the genus by its unique coloration pattern, including the combination of a large, dark, vertically oriented, more or less oval-shaped humeral spot, and thin, dark bars, separated by narrow, vertical, yellowish bars extending between the dorsal and anal fin base on the caudal half of the body. &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebrina&lt;/i&gt; is included in the putative &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutirostris&lt;/i&gt; group (9 species) and represents the only species in the group known to date from the Orinoco basin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Orinoco; Ventuari River; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carmen</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Montana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hernan</firstname>
          <lastname>Lopez-Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Donald</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Taphorn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-40</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New description of &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus scabrospinosus&lt;/i&gt; Fontoura, 1982, and description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; (Heterotardigrada) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A redescription of &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabrospinosus&lt;/i&gt; Fontoura, 1982, is presented. A comparison with the more similar species is made, based on information available since the original description. A previously unreported cuticular feature (a central dark ring in the light spots) is described for &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginatus&lt;/i&gt; Binda &amp; Pilato, 1994. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from China. This new species has a double plate ornamentation with numerous dark polygons and fewer light spots, forming transverse stripes on the plates. Longitudinal stripes are also present on the scapular plate. The new species has lateral filaments A and spines B, C, D, and E, as well as dorsal spines C d and D d .</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; Heterotardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginatus&lt;/i&gt;; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <lastname>Fontoura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Clark</firstname>
          <lastname>Beasley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trigonuropoda&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Baloghiatrigon&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;dominicana&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from the Dominican Republic, with notes on the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Baloghiatrigon&lt;/i&gt; Hirschmann, 1979 (Acari: Uropodina: Trigonuropodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species &lt;i&gt;Trigonuropoda&lt;/i&gt; (Baloghiatrigon) &lt;i&gt;dominicana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Trigonuropodidae) is described from the Dominican Republic. Diagnoses and identification key to all known species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Trigonuropoda&lt;/i&gt; (Baloghi- &lt;i&gt;atrigon)&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Uropodina; &lt;i&gt;Trigonuropoda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Baloghiatrigon&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeno</firstname>
          <lastname>Kontschan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eulobomyia&lt;/i&gt;, a new replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Lobomyia&lt;/i&gt; Woodley &amp; Arnaud (Diptera: Tachinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Norman</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Woodley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnaud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum ( Pfingstl, T. &lt;i&gt;et al. &lt;/i&gt;(2008) Intraspecific morphological variation of Scutovertex sculptus Michael (Acari: Oribatida: Scutoverticidae) and description of its juvenile stages. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 1829, 31-51.)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-08-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
