<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1700.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Feb. 2008</title>
    <volume>1700</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lineacoelotes&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Coelotinae from China (Araneae: Amaurobiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of Coelotinae, &lt;i&gt;Lineacoelotes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., is described. &lt;i&gt;Lineacoelotes&lt;/i&gt; includes five species from central and western China. The females of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicultratus&lt;/i&gt; (Chen, Zhao &amp; Wang, 1991) comb. nov. from Hubei (transferred from &lt;i&gt;Coelotes),&lt;/i&gt; the males and females of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funiushanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Hu, Wang &amp; Wang, 1991) comb. nov. from Henan (transferred from &lt;i&gt;Draconarius),&lt;/i&gt; the females of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; (Li &amp; Zhang, 2002) comb. nov. from Hubei (transferred from &lt;i&gt;Coelotes)&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed, the males of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; are described for the first time. Two new species from both males and females, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicephalus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Sichuan and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strenuus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Hubei, are described. The females of this new genus have distinct, unusually long spermathecal heads, and the males have a broad, long patellar apophysis and a strongly modified conductor but lack a lateral tibial apophysis and a conductor dorsal apophysis. Comparison of male palps of &lt;i&gt;Lineacoelotes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. suggests that none of the modified apophyses on the dorsal edge of the conductor is homologous to the conductor dorsal apophysis found in many other Coelotinae, but this assumption should be tested in a future phylogenetic analysis. As in other Coelotinae, spinnerets of representatives of &lt;i&gt;Lineacoelotes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. have PMS with 2 cylindrical spigots on the lateral sides and 2 minor ampullate spigots on the middle, and PLS long with 1–2 cylindrical spigots on its base, and the trichobothrium has a transversely striped large hood and a smooth small hood.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; taxonomy; phylogenetic relationships; biogeography; Holarctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xin-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new ground-dwelling &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Maharashtra, with a key to the &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; of India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A distinctive new species of ground-dwelling gecko of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; is described from the plateaus of the Western Ghats of Maharashtra, India. It is a member of a group of chiefly terrestrial Indian &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; species that have undivided, or only partly divided subdigital lamellae. The new species is most similar in appearance to the lowlandinhabiting &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albofasciatus&lt;/i&gt; Grandison &amp; Soman, 1963, but can be distinguished by its larger size and a suite of distinctive scalation and coloration characters. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; currently known from the Republic of India is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; India; Maharashtra; description; northern Western Ghats</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Varad</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-34</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Eutropis&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Scincidae) from Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of lygosomine scincid lizard of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eutropis&lt;/i&gt; is described from the dry and intermediate zones of the lowlands (0–190 m asl) of Sri Lanka. &lt;i&gt;Eutropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tammanna&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is compared with congeners from Sri Lanka and those from southern Peninsular India, and is diagnosable by molecular data and by the following combination of morphological characters: body size small, up to 52.3 mm; transparent window-like disk absent on lower eyelids; prefrontals in broad contact; a single pair of nuchals; postnasal absent; ear opening larger than adjacent scales; dorsal scales with 6–7 keels; midbody scale rows 28–29; paravertebral scale rows 37–40; ventral scales 41–48; lamellae under fourth toe 15– 16; dark labial bars present in both sexes, which are more distinct in males; dark postocular stripe absent; males brown on dorsum, with dark flanks speckled with cream; females similar to males, the pattern less contrasting, lacking paired series of black markings, pale vertebral stripes or dark longitudinal stripes on dorsum. In addition, the rostral, labials, and gular region of presumed breeding males are bright flame scarlet.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eutropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tammanna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; Scincidae; systematics; morphology; Sri Lanka; Bayesian; ND2; DNA; SH test</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eutropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tammanna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; Scincidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Indraneil</firstname>
          <lastname>Das</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anslem</firstname>
          <lastname>De Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Austin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-52</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Petracola&lt;/i&gt; and re-description of &lt;i&gt;P. ventrimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Gymnophthalmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe &lt;i&gt;Petracola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and re-describe the poorly known &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventrimaculatus,&lt;/i&gt; both high-Andean gymnophthalmids from northern Peru. The new species is diagnosed by gracile habitus, smooth dorsal scales, an anterior superciliary that extends onto the dorsum, absence of loreal, three genials, 36–49 transverse dorsal scale rows, 23–28 transverse ventral scale rows, 0–7 femoral pores, absence of subocular-labial fusion, and a color pattern consisting of dark spots or fine lines or bands on a pale brown background. &lt;i&gt;Petracola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waka&lt;/i&gt; is known from the middle &lt;i&gt;Río&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Marañon&lt;/i&gt; and CajamaraCajabamba basin (Río &lt;i&gt;Crisnejos&lt;/i&gt; drainage) from small isolated syngamic systems at 2650–2900 m and is parapatrically distributed with respect to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventrimaculatus,&lt;/i&gt; which occurs at higher elevations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; lizard; new species; Peru; Reptilia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Kizirian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sarah</firstname>
          <lastname>Bayefsky-Anand</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>April</firstname>
          <lastname>Eriksson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Minh</firstname>
          <lastname>Le</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maureen</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnelly</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum &lt;/i&gt;(Monogenea: Ancyrocephalinae), gill parasite of &lt;i&gt;Geophagus brasiliensis &lt;/i&gt;(Quoy &amp; Gaimard) (Teleostei: Cichlidae) from reservoirs in the State of Parana Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frequens&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from the gills of the acará, &lt;i&gt;Geophagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; (Cichlidae), from nine reservoirs in the State of Paraná, Brazil. The new species differs from the others members of &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; in the following features: dorsal anchors more than twice as long as the ventral anchors and hook pair 5 reduced in size. &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frequens&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is similar to species of this parasite genus from South America by having the male copulatory organ comprising less than 2 rings, and to species of &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; from Central America and southeast Mexico by the presence of longitudinal lateral grooves on the shafts and points of the ventral and dorsal anchors. This new species is the first species of &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; in South America with longitudinal lateral grooves on shafts and point of the ventral and dorsal anchors. It is the first dactylogyrid described from &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis,&lt;/i&gt; and it is the first species of &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; described from Southern Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">acará; Ancyrocephalinae; Brazil; Cichlidae; &lt;i&gt;Geophagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt;; Monogenea; &lt;i&gt;Sciadicleithrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frequens&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">acará</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sybelle</firstname>
          <lastname>Bellay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>Massato</middlename>
          <lastname>Takemoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <middlename>Hideki</middlename>
          <lastname>Yamada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gilberto</firstname>
          <middlename>Cezar</middlename>
          <lastname>Pavanelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
