<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1792.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jun. 2008</title>
    <volume>1792</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On &lt;i&gt;Putaoa&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;a new genus of the spider family Pimoidae (Araneae) from China, with a cladistic test of its monophyly and phylogenetic placement</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The spider genus &lt;i&gt;Putaoa&lt;/i&gt; new genus (Araneae, Pimoidae) is described to place two species of pimoids from China, &lt;i&gt;Putaoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huaping&lt;/i&gt; new species (the type species) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacantha&lt;/i&gt; (Xu &amp; Li, 2007) new combination. Parsimony analysis of morphological characters provides support for the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Putaoa&lt;/i&gt; and for its sister group relationship to the genus &lt;i&gt;Weintrauboa&lt;/i&gt; Hormiga, 2003 and corroborates the monophyly of Pimoidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phylogeny; Taxonomy; Morphology; Araneoidea; Linyphiidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <lastname>Hormiga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lihong</firstname>
          <lastname>Tu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular evidence for a polyphyletic genus &lt;i&gt;Japonia&lt;/i&gt; (Architaenioglossa: Cyclophoridae) and with the description of a new genus and two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Cyclophoridae is the dominant family of operculated terrestrial snails in East Asia. The group consists of four subfamilies and approximately 300 species that are currently classified into 34 genera. The species occupy various habitatsand show a high morphological diversity. The molecular phylogenetic relationships of this group have not previously been discussed. In order to uncover the relationships within the family, we sequenced parts of the mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) and of the 16S rRNA gene from 32 species of 10 genera of cyclophorid and established the phylogenetic tree using neighbor joining, Bayesian and maximum likelihood analyses to construct phylogenetic trees. The results based on mtDNA sequences suggest that the genera &lt;i&gt;Cyclophorus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cyclotus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leptopoma,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cyathopoma&lt;/i&gt; are monophyletic while the traditional genus &lt;i&gt;Japonia&lt;/i&gt; appeared polyphyletic and then &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebra&lt;/i&gt; should be moved to the new genus &lt;i&gt;Pilosphaera.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, &lt;i&gt;Pilosphaera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yentoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Japonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boonkioensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described in this paper.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">COI; 16S rRNA; &lt;i&gt;Pilosphaera&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;yentoensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;boonkioensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">COI</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yen-Chen</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kuang-Yang</firstname>
          <lastname>Lue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wen-Lung</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-38</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; species (Chilopoda: Scolopendromorpha: Scolopendridae) of Greece (E-Mediterranean): a theoretical approach on the effect of geography and palaeogeography on their distribution</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 are very widely distributed in the Mediterranean region. Current knowledge is summarized, with references to material derived mainly from the well-explored islands of the Aegean Archipelago, several localities in continental Greece and old bibliographic reports. We suggest that &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; species represent examples of both paradigms of historical biogeography, namely vicariance and dispersal. We propose that the dispersal routes of &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; species in Greece were mainly influenced by late Miocene and upper Pleistocene palaeogeography. The formation of the Mid-Aegean trench (c. 12 – 9 Mya) considered as a remarkable geographical barrier between the Anatolian peninsula and mainland Greece, prevented the entry of certain &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; species westwards. In total, five &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; species have been recorded from mainland and insular Greece. A vicariance event that occurred in the area more than 17 Mya, when the Aegean region was part of a united landmass, better explains the biogeographical history of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canidens.&lt;/i&gt; Cyclades harbours remnants of the ancient populations of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canidens,&lt;/i&gt; whereas during the late Pleistocene (c. 400.000 21.000 ya) &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canidens&lt;/i&gt; was isolated in Dodecanese. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cretica&lt;/i&gt; is the only endemic, being distributed in Crete and its adjacent islets. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavipes&lt;/i&gt; in E-Mediterranean and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dalmatica&lt;/i&gt; in W-Mediterranean evolved from ancient &lt;i&gt;canidens&lt;/i&gt; populations. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulata&lt;/i&gt; entered central and southern Europe from the east (c. 20 – 11 Mya), while the formation of the Mid-Aegean trench (c. 12 – 9 Mya) prevented its entry in Crete.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aegean archipelago; colonizer; competitive exclusion; Crete; Cyclades; dispersal routes; Dodecanese; Miocene; Mid-Aegean trench; Pleistocene; vicariance</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aegean archipelago</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stylianos</firstname>
          <lastname>Simaiakis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Moisis</firstname>
          <lastname>Mylonas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-53</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An overlooked threatened species of eagle: Legge's Hawk Eagle &lt;i&gt;Nisaetus kelaarti &lt;/i&gt;(Aves: Accipitriformes) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species delimitation is fundamental to many areas of biology, and in cases where taxonomic status has not been sufficiently clarified the ramifications can be as serious as extinction due to the failure to implement conservation measures. Since 1931, the Mountain Hawk Eagle &lt;i&gt;Nisaetus&lt;/i&gt; (Spizaetus) &lt;i&gt;nipalensis&lt;/i&gt; Hodgson has included the allopatric Sri Lankan and southern Indian taxon &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kelaarti&lt;/i&gt; (Legge) as a subspecies, and its taxonomic status has not been re-evaluated. We found that &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kelaarti&lt;/i&gt; differs considerably from &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nipalensis&lt;/i&gt; in its relatively much larger bill and claws and short primary projection, and that it also differs consistently in numerous plumage characters and other mensural characters. Its vocalizations differ distinctly, and an earlier study found a moderate degree of genetic differentiation (4.4% in cyt b and 3.1% in CR) from &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nipalensis.&lt;/i&gt; The available evidence thus strongly and unambiguously supports the specific distinctness of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kelaarti.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; phylogeography; vocalization; &lt;i&gt;Spizaetus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nipalensis&lt;/i&gt;; Mountain Hawk Eagle; India; Sri Lanka</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gjershaug</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diserud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rasmussen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Warakagoda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-66</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The casque-headed tree-frog&lt;i&gt; Corythomantis greeningi:&lt;/i&gt; clarifying some points on its biology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Jared</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marta</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Antoniazzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
