<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1823.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1823</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the &lt;i&gt;Ranitomeya fantastica&lt;/i&gt; species complex with description of two new species from Central Peru (Anura: Dendrobatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new species of poison frogs (genus &lt;i&gt;Ranitomeya)&lt;/i&gt; from the central Rio Huallaga drainage and adjacent Cordillera Azul in central Peru. Both species were previously considered to be members of &lt;i&gt;Ranitomeya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica,&lt;/i&gt; a species described from the town of Yurimaguas, Peru. Extensive sampling of putative &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica&lt;/i&gt; (including near-topotypic material) throughout central Peru, and the resulting morphological and phylogenetic analysis has led us to conclude that &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato is a complex of three closely related species rather than a single, widely distributed species. The first of these species occurs near the type locality of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica&lt;/i&gt; but bears significant dissimilarity to the original type series and forms a monophyletic clade that is distributed throughout an expansive lowland zone between Rio Huallaga and Rio Ucayali. This species is diagnosable by its brilliant red head and advertisement call differences. The second new species has long been considered a color morph of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica,&lt;/i&gt; although our analysis shows that it is genetically distinct from even adjacent populations of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica.&lt;/i&gt; This species is restricted to the Huallaga Canyon near Chazuta and is primarily diagnosed on the basis of nucleotide sequences, although it does possess additional morphological and vocal characteristics which are distinct from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fantastica.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;benedicta&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dendrobates&lt;/i&gt;; Dendrobatidae; &lt;i&gt;fantastica&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ranitomeya&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;summersi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;benedicta&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jason</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brown</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Evan</firstname>
          <lastname>Twomey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Pepper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <middlename>Sanchez</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodriguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of the trapdoor spider genus &lt;i&gt;Promyrmekiaphila&lt;/i&gt; Schenkel (Araneae, Mygalomorphae, Cyrtaucheniidae, Euctenizinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The mygalomorph spider genus &lt;i&gt;Promyrmekiaphila&lt;/i&gt; comprises two species known from northern and central California. The type species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clathrata&lt;/i&gt; (Simon), is considered a senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gertschi&lt;/i&gt; Schenkel and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebra&lt;/i&gt; (Chamberlin &amp; Ivie); male and female exemplar specimens are described. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Promyrmekiaphila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;winnemem,&lt;/i&gt; from Shasta and Tehama Counties in northern California, is described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">California Araneae; spider taxonomy; Mygalomorphae; &lt;i&gt;Promyrmekiaphila&lt;/i&gt;; Euctenizinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">California Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Amy</firstname>
          <middlename>K. Stockman And Jason E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bond</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-41</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new, long-standing misidentified species of &lt;i&gt;Psychrophrynella &lt;/i&gt;Hedges, Duellman &amp; Heinicke from Departamento Cusco, Peru (Anura: Strabomantidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We present the description of a new species of the recently described genus &lt;i&gt;Psychrophrynella.&lt;/i&gt; Hitherto, frogs of this new species were traditionally misidentified as &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruvianus.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is known only from elevations of 3270–3450 m in the vicinity of the type locality in the Cordillera de Paucartambo, Departamento Cusco, Peru. It is unique within &lt;i&gt;Psychrophrynella&lt;/i&gt; in having a marked, oblique inner tarsal tubercle. The geographically closest species &lt;i&gt;Psychrophrynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bagrecito&lt;/i&gt; Lynch, also possesses a tarsal tubercle.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Strabomantidae; &lt;i&gt;Noblella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Psychrophrynella&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; Andes; Peru</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ignacio</firstname>
          <lastname>De La Riva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-50</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and a new genus of Cirolanidae (Isopoda: Cymothoida: Crustacea) from groundwater in calcretes in the Pilbarra, northern Western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kagalana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonde&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Haptolana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yarraloola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from subterranean water in calcretes in the Pilbarra region, Western Australia. &lt;i&gt;Kagalana&lt;/i&gt; is characterised by haptorial dactylus on pereopod 1, short antennule and antenna peduncles, and pleonites 4 and 5 narrow, laterally overlapped by margins of pleonite 3 and pleonite 5 narrower than the pleotelson anterior margin. &lt;i&gt;Haptolana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yarraloola&lt;/i&gt; is the second record of the genus from Australia, both species of which are from Western Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cirolanidae; Isopoda; &lt;i&gt;Haptolana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Kagalana&lt;/i&gt;; Australia; cave fauna; phreatic fauna; Western Australia; Pilbarra</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cirolanidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Niel</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-64</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First description of the female of &lt;i&gt;Ozyptila utotchkini&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Thomisidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marusik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mikhail</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Omelko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
