<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1922.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1922</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of West Palaearctic Limoniidae, Pediciidae and Cylindrotomidae (Diptera) from the collections of the Zoological Museum, Amsterdam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Records of altogether 85 species of the families Limoniidae, Pediciidae and Cylindrotomidae (Diptera) are published, based on the material from the collections of the Zoological Museum, Amsterdam, representing various additions to their distribution in West Palaearctic countries. For &lt;i&gt;Euphylidorea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crocotula&lt;/i&gt; (Séguy, 1941) a lectotype is designated and figures are provided of male genital structures of this and two other species of &lt;i&gt;Euphylidorea,&lt;/i&gt; as well as two species of &lt;i&gt;Gonomyia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Limoniidae; Pediciidae; Cylindrotomidae; new records; lectotype designation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jaroslav</firstname>
          <lastname>Staru</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pjotr</firstname>
          <lastname>Oosterbroek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus &lt;/i&gt;Arrow (Coleoptera: Lucanidae: Lucaninae) of southern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The southern South American genus &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus&lt;/i&gt; Arrow is revised (Coleoptera: Lucanidae: Lucaninae). The genus contains two species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacchus&lt;/i&gt; (Hope in Westwood, 1845) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; (Deyrolle in Parry, 1870). &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; is reinstated as a valid species, having previously been treated as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacchus.&lt;/i&gt; Both species are redescribed and illustrated, and information on biology and geographic distribution are included.Se revisa el género &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus&lt;/i&gt; Arrow (Coleoptera: Lucanidae: Lucaninae) de América del Sur Austral. El género contiene dos especies, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacchus&lt;/i&gt; (Hope en Westwood, 1845) y &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; (Deyrolle en Parry, 1870). &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; es reinstalada como una especie válida, la cual previamente había sido tratada como sinónimo menor de &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacchus.&lt;/i&gt; Se redescriben e ilustran ambas especies, y se incluye información sobre la biología y distribución geográfica.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lucanidae; systematics; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Apterodorcus&lt;/i&gt;; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lucanidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Mondaca</middlename>
          <lastname>E.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Paulsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-32</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological and molecular characterization of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Diabrotica&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Galerucinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new species &lt;i&gt;Diabrotica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wartensis&lt;/i&gt; Cabrera &amp; Sosa-Gómez was found feeding on roots and leaves of sunflower and soybean in the north of the state of Paraná. A set of characters of diagnostic value: mouthparts, hind wing venation, binding patch, metendosternite, and details of male and female genitalia previously overlooked in the genus was provided. In addition to the morphological characterization, the molecular analyses of the COI mitochondrial gene and the ITS-1 rDNA nuclear region were included. The analysis of the ITS-1 nuclear region alone suggests proximity of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wartensis&lt;/i&gt; to the &lt;i&gt;Diabrotica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fucata&lt;/i&gt; group, whereas molecular evidence based on combined analysis of COI and ITS-1 region suggest that this new species is distantly related to the Diabroticina with known sequences deposited in the GenBank.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diabrotica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wartensis&lt;/i&gt;; Chrysomelidae; Galerucinae; Brazil; systematics; molecular techniques</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diabrotica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wartensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nora</firstname>
          <lastname>Cabrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>R. Sosa</middlename>
          <lastname>Gómez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <lastname>Micheli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the larvae of three species of &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt; Leach and comments on the phylogenetic relationships of the Laccophilinae (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larvae of three Neotropical species of the diving beetle genus &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt; Leach (Laccophilus &lt;i&gt;obliquatus&lt;/i&gt; Régimbart, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paraguensis&lt;/i&gt; Régimbart and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testudo&lt;/i&gt; Régimbart) are described and illustrated for the first time, with an emphasis on morphometry and chaetotaxy of the cephalic capsule, head appendages, legs, last abdominal segment and urogomphi. Larvae of these species lack the primary setae LA10 and LA12, and have the primary seta CO7 articulated proximally on all coxae, two apomorphies that define the subfamily Laccophilinae. They are also characterized by a frontoclypeus truncate proximally in the first instar, the presence of pectens on legs, and the presence of secondary setae on first urogomphomere. These character states are apomorphies that define the genus &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt; Leach. The absence of pore PAc and the presence of a dense group of secondary spiniform setae dorsally at the base of the siphon in instar III may also characterize this genus, as similar states are not found in other dytiscids. On the other hand, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paraguensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testudo&lt;/i&gt; differ from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt; known in detail in the presence of an additional seta on the stipes and in the absence of pore ABc. Brief comments on the putative phylogenetic relationships of Laccophilinae and &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt; inferred from larval morphology, as well as on the characters potentially useful in studying relationships within the group are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diving beetles; Laccophilinae; &lt;i&gt;Laccophilus&lt;/i&gt;; larvae; chaetotaxy; phylogenetic relationships</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diving beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mariano</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Michat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-61</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Lygephila&lt;/i&gt; Billberg, 1820 (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae, Catocalinae) from Russian Far East and North China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Lygephila&lt;/i&gt; Billberg, 1820, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubatolovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; was discovered in the Primorye territory of Russian Far East and in the Liaoning province of North China. The new species is compared with its closest relatives &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maxima&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ludicra.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, the East Asian &lt;i&gt;Lygephila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigricostata&lt;/i&gt; (Graeser, 1890) is established as a new synonym of the European &lt;i&gt;Lygephila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;procax&lt;/i&gt; Hübner, [1813].</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Noctuidae; Catocalinae; &lt;i&gt;Lygephila&lt;/i&gt;; new species; synonymy; Russian Far East; North China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Noctuidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Fibiger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kononenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danny</firstname>
          <lastname>Nilsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
