<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1822.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jul. 2008</title>
    <volume>1822</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-07-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia &lt;/i&gt;with the description of two new species and a reanalysis of the phylogeny of the genera of the Hypostominae (Siluriformes: Loricariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; contains 12 described species, eight of which are considered valid. &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenaria,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filicaudata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ucayalensis&lt;/i&gt; are recognized as synonyms of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bachi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuhlmanni&lt;/i&gt; is recognized as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, two new species are described. The type species of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltichthys&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sophiancistrus&lt;/i&gt; are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bachi&lt;/i&gt; and both genera are recognized as junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia.&lt;/i&gt; The species of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; range throughout much of the Amazon basin, the upper Orinoco, the upper Essequibo, and perhaps the Maroni, and can be identified from most other ancistrins by having dentaries that form angle of 90° or less and from others with angled dentaries by lacking the synapomorphies of those genera. The species of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; vary from one another mostly in coloration. &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;braueri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caenosa&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavatica&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; lack spots on the head while the other species have them. &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;braueri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavatica&lt;/i&gt; have orange bands in the dorsal and caudal fins and have the bones and plates of the head and nape outlined in black (vs. no orange bands and head plates and bones not outlined in black in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caenosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caenosa&lt;/i&gt; has a color pattern consisting of dark vermiculations on the head and abdomen (vs. saddles or blotches on the head and faint dark spots on the abdomen in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata).&lt;/i&gt; Among the species with spots on the head, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineola&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermiculata&lt;/i&gt; have some of the spots combining to form vermiculations (vs. spots free in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bachi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;oligospila)&lt;/i&gt; with the vermiculations larger than the pupil in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineola&lt;/i&gt; and narrower in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermiculata&lt;/i&gt; and the vermiculations radiating from a central point in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermiculata&lt;/i&gt; vs. no such pattern in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineola.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bachi&lt;/i&gt; can be identified from the other species by having widened pelvic-fin spines that can be pulled ventrally such that they are completely ventral and parallel to the body (vs. pelvic-fin spines narrow and cannot be adducted ventral to body) and by having the eye low on the head (vs. high). &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevis&lt;/i&gt; can be identified from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligospila&lt;/i&gt; by having well-developed dorsal saddles (vs. saddles faint), no spots on the body behind the nape (vs. spots generally present behind the nape); from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligospila&lt;/i&gt; by having bands in the caudal fin (vs. spots); and from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcata&lt;/i&gt; by having the lower caudal-fin spine longer than the upper (vs. upper spine longer). &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcata&lt;/i&gt; can be identified from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligospila&lt;/i&gt; by having the upper caudal-fin spine longer than the lower (vs. lower spine longer) and by having bands in the caudal fin (vs. spots). &lt;i&gt;Ancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaravi&lt;/i&gt; had been recognized as a species of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia.&lt;/i&gt; The type of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaravi&lt;/i&gt; is lost, but the original description suggests that the species is the senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Neblinichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roraima.&lt;/i&gt; A revised morphological phylogeny demonstrates the lack of support for &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hemiancistrus&lt;/i&gt; as monophyletic, and phenetic definitions are provided for the two genera. The phylogeny also demonstrates a lack of support of the genus &lt;i&gt;Watawata.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ancistrini; &lt;i&gt;Hemiancistrus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neblinichthys&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropics; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ancistrini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Armbruster</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-76</pages>
        <date_published>2008-07-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
