<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1932.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Nov. 2008</title>
    <volume>1932</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2008</year>
    <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic position of &lt;i&gt;Pontonides sympathes&lt;/i&gt; De Ridder &amp; Holthuis and species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis (Decapoda, Palaemonidae, Pontoniinae) with the description of a new genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The type specimens of &lt;i&gt;Pontonides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sympathes&lt;/i&gt; De Ridder &amp; Holthuis, 1979, &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratifrons&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951, and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevifrons&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951 were re-examined. &lt;i&gt;Pontonides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sympathes&lt;/i&gt; is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951, based on morphological similarity with &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratifrons,&lt;/i&gt; the type species of the genus. At the same time, a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pseudoveleronia&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., is erected for &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevifrons.&lt;/i&gt; Detailed re-descriptions of all studied species as well as a key to the genera &lt;i&gt;Pontonides&lt;/i&gt; Borradaile, 1917, &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudoveleronia&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pontonides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Veleronia&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new combination; gorgonarians</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pontonides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The largest blindsnake in Mesoamerica: a new species of &lt;i&gt;Typhlops&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Typhlopidae) from an isolated karstic mountain in Honduras</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A distinctive new species of &lt;i&gt;Typhlops&lt;/i&gt; is described from Parque Nacional Montaña de Santa Bárbara, 1550 m elevation, Departamento de Santa Bárbara, Honduras. The holotype and only known specimen of this new taxon is the largest specimen of the genus thus far reported from Mexico and Central America, and is further differentiated from all other Mesoamerican &lt;i&gt;Typhlops&lt;/i&gt; by having 22–22–22 scales around the body and by having a dark brownish gray dorsum with a well-defined pale yellowish gray to immaculate white ventral coloration. This species is a member of the Caribbean Arc Group of &lt;i&gt;Typhlops.&lt;/i&gt; An updated key to the Typhlopidae of Mesoamerica is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cloud forest; Karst; Nuclear Central America; Parque Nacional Montaña de Santa Bárbara; Reptilia; Scolecophidia; Serpentes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cloud forest</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Josiah</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Townsend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Larry</firstname>
          <middlename>David</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lorraine</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ketzler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ileana</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Luque-Montes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-26</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new cleaner species of &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt; (Actinopterygii: Gobiidae) from the Southwestern Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of cleaner goby, &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phthirophagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Fernando de Noronha Archipelago, off northeastern Brazil. It differs from its congeners of the putative “randalli-evelynae” cleaning clade by the following combination of characters: mouth subterminal, pale (bright yellow in life) elliptical spot on dark snout, width of lateral pale (bright yellow in life) stripe almost equal as eye diameter (slightly narrower in live individuals), light purplish sheen (in life) extending laterally from below eye to tail origin, no blue line (in life) from below eye to end of opercular margin, teeth multiserial on the distal portion of both jaws, males with 3 enlarged and recurved teeth on dentary inner row. The new species was recorded at depths ranging from 3 to 18 m and is ubiquitous in the archipelago islets. It tends cleaning stations on coral heads, sponges, and rocky substrata, with up to 15 individuals present in large stations, particularly those on sponges. &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phthirophagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; was recorded to clean about 30 species of fish clients, including large carnivores such as the shark &lt;i&gt;Carcharhinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perezi&lt;/i&gt; and smaller carnivores such as the grouper &lt;i&gt;Cephalopholis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulva,&lt;/i&gt; besides small clients like the planktivorous damselfish &lt;i&gt;Chromis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multilineata&lt;/i&gt; and the zoobenthivorous butterflyfish &lt;i&gt;Chaetodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellatus.&lt;/i&gt; The new species increases to three the number of cleaner gobies recorded for Southwestern Atlantic, one from the coast and two from oceanic islands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Gobiidae; reef fish; oceanic islands; Southwestern Atlantic; cleaning symbiosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Sazima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfredo</firstname>
          <lastname>Carvalho-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cristina</firstname>
          <lastname>Sazima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-32</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waisihani&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of nemacheiline loach from Northwest China (Pisces: Balitoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waisihani,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of nemacheiline loach, is described from the Kax River, a tributary of the Ili River drainage in Xinjiang-Uighur Autonomous Region of Northwest China. It can be assigned to the &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiata&lt;/i&gt; species group characterized by having widely separated anterior and posterior nostrils and no breeding tubercles on the sides of the head. &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waisihani&lt;/i&gt; resembles &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;herzensteini,&lt;/i&gt; but differs from both in cephalic sensory-canal pattern and the structure of the gas bladder; from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiata&lt;/i&gt; in the structure of the pelvic girdle and absence or presence of the fourth basibranchial; and from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;herzensteini&lt;/i&gt; in the shape of the anal fin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nemacheilinae&lt;/i&gt;; Ili River drainage; Northwest China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nemacheilinae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liang</firstname>
          <lastname>Cao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of Artotrogidae&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(Copepoda, Siphonostomatoida) from the southeastern coast of Pernambuco State, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new copepod species, &lt;i&gt;Bradypontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancistronus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cryptopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aesthetascus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cryptopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;expletus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; of the siphonostomatoid family Artotrogidae are described based on specimens from sponge and algal hosts collected along the Brazilian coast. These findings represent the first records of artotrogid copepods from Brazil. Male &lt;i&gt;Bradypontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancistronus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; was found in association with sponges, and is characterized by having an unarmed P4 endopod that bears a distal hook-like projection on the third segment. Male &lt;i&gt;Cryptopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aesthetascus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; also recorded from sponges, differs from its congeners by a combination of characters that include a 12-segmented antennule, 2 setae on the inner lobe of the maxillule, 7 elements on the third exopodal segment of P1 and 9 elements on the third exopodal segment of P4. Female &lt;i&gt;Cryptopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;expletus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; was recorded on algae, and can be distinguished from its congeners by having an 8-segmented antennule, 6 elements on the third endopodal segment of P1, 9 elements on the third exopodal segment of P4 and 3 setae on P5 exopod.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Artotrogidae; Siphonostomatoida; &lt;i&gt;Cryptopontius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bradypontius&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Copepoda; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Artotrogidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Neves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <lastname>Johnsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-60</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the systematic position of &lt;i&gt;Dino&lt;/i&gt; Loman and &lt;i&gt;Toccolus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer (Opiliones, Laniatores, Epedanidae), with the description of a new species from western Java, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Toccolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nova,&lt;/b&gt; is described from a rainforest in Gunung Puncak, western Java, Indonesia. It is the fourth species of the genus, which was hitherto known only from continental SE Asia. It possesses a low ocularium and general body shape strongly resembling &lt;i&gt;Dino&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weberi&lt;/i&gt; Loman from Sumatra. The relationships of &lt;i&gt;Toccolus&lt;/i&gt; are discussed and the closely related genus &lt;i&gt;Dino&lt;/i&gt; Loman is transferred from Podoctinae (Podoctidae) to Epedaninae (Epedanidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Harvestmen; Dibuninae; Podoctidae; Podoctinae; Sumatra; Indo-Malaya; Grassatores</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2008-11-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
