<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1971.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Jan. 2009</title>
    <volume>1971</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-01-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Crinoid-associated shrimps of the genus &lt;i&gt;Laomenes &lt;/i&gt;A.H. Clark, 1919 (Caridea: Palaemonidae: Pontoniinae): new species and probable diversity</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Laomenes&lt;/i&gt; A.H. Clark are described as symbionts of feather stars (Crinoidea: Comatulida) from shallow waters of Nhatrang Bay, Vietnam. Including these new species, the genus comprises 8 species and can be arranged into 3 suggested groups of species. The “L. &lt;i&gt;amboinensis”&lt;/i&gt; species group with 4 species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amboinensis&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1888), &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornutus&lt;/i&gt; (Borradaile, 1915), &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clarki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pardus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; characterized by the presence of ventral rostral teeth, distoventral spines on propodus of pereiopod III and a fixed tooth on distolateral margin of uropodal exopod. The “L. &lt;i&gt;jackhintoni”&lt;/i&gt; species group includes 2 species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jackhintoni&lt;/i&gt; (Bruce, 2006) and &lt;i&gt;Laomenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; characterized by the absence of ventral rostral teeth, extremely elongated apical papilla on cornea of eyes, the presence of fixed tooth on exopod of uropod, the absence of distoventral spines on propodus and the presence of large accessory tooth on dactylus of pereiopod III. The “L. &lt;i&gt;ceratophthalmus”&lt;/i&gt; species group includes 2 species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ceratophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; (Borradaile, 1915) and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudirostris&lt;/i&gt; (Bruce, 1968), characterized by the absence of ventral rostral teeth and distoventral spines on propodus of pereiopod III, the presence of small accessory tooth on dactylus of pereiopod III, tiny marginal dorsal spines on telson and the absence of a fixed distolateral tooth on exopod of uropod. Remarks and a key for all species of the genus as well as a discussion of the undescribed diversity of the genus are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Laomenes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; shrimp; feather stars</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-49</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The complete mitochondrial genome of the Formosan black bear (&lt;i&gt;Ursus thibetanus formosanus&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A complete mitochondrial genome of the Formosan black bear (Ursus &lt;i&gt;thibetanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosanus)&lt;/i&gt; was obtained by PCR amplification and DNA sequencing. The genome spans 17,044 bp that includes 13 protein-coding genes, 22 tRNA genes, and two rRNA genes. The base composition of the heavy strain is 31.0% A, 25.6% C, 15.7% G, and 27.7% T. The control region (CR) is located between tRNA-Pro and tRNA-Phe, consists of 1,595 bp, and comprises 9.4% of the whole genome. The DNA sequence shares 98.7%, 96.3%, 91.0%, 91.8%, and 91.7% similarity with those of &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;t.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibetanus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;t.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mupinensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americanus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arctos,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt; respectively. Phylogenetic analyses suggest that the Formosan black bear is more closely related to &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;t.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibetanus&lt;/i&gt; than to &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;t.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mupinensis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mitochondrial genomes; phylogeny; Taiwan; &lt;i&gt;Ursus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibetanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosanus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mitochondrial genomes; phylogeny; Taiwan; &lt;i&gt;Ursus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibetanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosanus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chi-Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Tsai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yii-Cheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Chou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chih-Chin</firstname>
          <lastname>Shih</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsi-Chi</firstname>
          <lastname>Cheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chieh-Chung</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsiao-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Kao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of copepod (Siphonostomatoida: Caligidae) parasitic on the striped trumpeter, &lt;i&gt;Latris lineata &lt;/i&gt;(Forster), from Tasmania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of caligid copepod (Siphonostomatoida), &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuenonnae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on material collected from the body surface of striped trumpeter [Latris &lt;i&gt;lineata&lt;/i&gt; (Forster)] reared at the Tasmanian Aquaculture and Fisheries Institute, Marine Research Laboratories, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuenonnae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterised by the following combination of features: 1) female genital complex with a mid-lateral indentation and highly concave posterior margin; 2) 1-segmented abdomen in the female that is about one-third the length of the genital complex; 3) distinctly broader first abdominal somite relative to the second abdominal somite in the male; 4) antenna with a spatulate process on the proximal segment; 5) recurved postantennal process without a basal accessory process; 6) female maxilliped with a proximal ridged protrusion on the corpus; 7) sternal furca with widely separated, apically truncate tines; 8) distal exopodal segment of leg 1 with a lateral flange on each apical spine and an accessory process on apical spines two and three; 9) leg 3 protopod with two adhesion pads on the dorsolateral surface; 10) leg 4 exopod 2-segmented, with I-0; I, III armature; 11) terminal exopodal segment of leg 4 with the outer apical spine being slightly shorter than the middle apical spine; 12) male maxillulary dentiform process with numerous small points embossed on the surface; and 13) male legs 5 and 6 represented by distinct lobate projections.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt;; parasitic copepods; marine fish; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Melanie</firstname>
          <lastname>Andrews</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nathan</firstname>
          <lastname>Bott</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <lastname>Battaglene</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barbara</firstname>
          <lastname>Nowak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
