<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2006.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2006</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and records of &lt;i&gt;Pyrgulopsis &lt;/i&gt;(Gastropoda: Hydrobiidae) from the Snake River basin, southeastern Oregon: further delineation of a highly imperiled fauna</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Here we describe two new species from southeastern Oregon based on morphologic and molecular (mtCOI) evidence. &lt;i&gt;Pyrgulopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fresti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; commonly known as the “Owyhee hot springsnail” and long considered to be distinct and critically imperiled, lives in thermal springs along a short reach of the Owyhee River above Three Forks. This snail differs from other regional species in its squat shell; penial ornament consisting of a large, disc-shaped ventral gland; absence of a seminal receptacle; and mtCOI sequences. &lt;i&gt;Pyrgulopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;owyheensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; ranges among five disjunct groups of springs in the Owyhee and Malheur river drainages and is occasionally sympatric with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fresti.&lt;/i&gt; This snail is closely similar to another regional congener, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt; (Tryon, 1865), but is smaller and further differentiated by its typically disjunct inner shell lip, longer and narrower penial filament, more distally positioned ventral gland of penis, and mtCOI sequences. The type locality (Owyhee Spring) population of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;owyheensis&lt;/i&gt; is genetically differentiated from the other geographical subunits of this species (1.5–1.8% sequence divergence) and should perhaps be managed as a separate conservation unit. New records are provided for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt; which extends the range of this conservation priority species into the lower Owyhee River basin. We also show that the “Malheur springsnail,” which has been listed in various conservation-related publications and documents, is the same as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia.&lt;/i&gt; This study provides critical information for the conservation of springsnails in southeastern Oregon and underscores the need for additional field surveys in the region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">springs; Owyhee River; Malheur River; springsnails; mitochondrial DNA; conservation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">springs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Hershler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsiu-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax griseus &lt;/i&gt;Pellegrin, 1931, with descriptions of three new species of schizothoracine fishes (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; Pellegrin, 1931, is clarified and the species redescribed. Three new species previously identified as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris,&lt;/i&gt; from the Lancang Jiang, China; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterophysallidos,&lt;/i&gt; from the Nanpan Jiang, China; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis,&lt;/i&gt; from the upper Beipan Jiang, China. The group comprising &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterophysallidos&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis&lt;/i&gt; can be diagnosed from other members of this genus by the absence of an obvious horny sheath on the lower jaw; lower lip developed with three labial lobes in mature individuals; postlabial groove continuous, with a small labial lobe present in the middle of the lower lip; last unbranched dorsal-fin ray strong, its posterior edge with numerous serrae; and scales absent on ventral surface between pectoral fins in adults (except in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterophysallidos&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis&lt;/i&gt; by the presence (vs. absence) of concealed scales in the skin on the ventral surface between the pectoral fins in adults; the presence (vs. absence) of a shallow ethmoidal groove before the nostrils; and having barbels much longer than eye diameter (eye diameter 33.4–93.7 % (vs. 57.2–160.0) of maxillary-barbel length). &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterophysallidos&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis&lt;/i&gt; in having only the proximal ¾ (vs. entirety) of the last unbranched dorsal-fin ray strong; pelvic-fin origin opposite or posterior (vs. opposite or anterior) to vertical through dorsal-fin origin; and irregular black spots present (vs. absent) on side of body. &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterophysallidos&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis&lt;/i&gt; in having a larger posterior chamber of the air bladder (vs. posterior chamber as large as, or slightly larger than, anterior one), length of posterior chamber 3–6 (vs. 2) times length of anterior chamber. &lt;i&gt;Schizothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beipanensis&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; by the absence (vs. presence) of scales on the thorax in mature individuals; absence (vs. presence) of black spots on side of body; and having the maxillary barbel 58.5–120.1 % SL (vs. 33.4–93.7 % SL).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; snow barbel; Yangtze River; Lancang Jiang; Beipan Jiang; Nanpan Jiang</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiaoyong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Junxing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crenicichla mandelburgeri&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of cichlid fish (Teleostei: Cichlidae) from the Paraná river drainage in Paraguay</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mandelburgeri,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the streams Tembey, Pirayuy, Pirapó and Poromoco which are Paraguayan tributaries to the Paraná River. It is similar in particular to &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niederleinii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucuryna,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jaguarensis,&lt;/i&gt; distinguished by relatively small size (114 mm SL), low scale counts, and details of the colour pattern.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">PROVEPA; Arroyo Tembey; Arroyo Poromoco; &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jaguarensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Crenicichla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niederleinii&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">PROVEPA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kullander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of blenniid fishes from Fernando de Noronha Archipelago, Brazil, with description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Scartella &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Blenniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the family Blenniidae from Fernando de Noronha Archipelago (03°51’S, 32°26’W), an oceanic island 345 km off northeastern Brazil, are reviewed in this study, which includes the description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Scartella.&lt;/i&gt; The new species differs from its congeners by the combination of the following characters: well-marked diagonal dark line just under the eye, tiny black spots on the head, small black and white spots along the body, 14 segmented dorsal-fin rays, 15 segmented anal-fin rays, and 23 caudal vertebrae. This is the second &lt;i&gt;Scartella&lt;/i&gt; species described from Brazilian oceanic islands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ophioblennius&lt;/i&gt;; oceanic islands; endemism; Western South Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rangel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Liana</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mendes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-61</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Nomisia &lt;/i&gt;Dalmas, 1921 (Araneae: Gnaphosidae) from Turkey with some faunistical remarks</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nomisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated from Turkey. Morphological features and detailed description based on collected material of &lt;i&gt;Nomisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt; Dalmas, 1921 are presented. &lt;i&gt;Nomisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;negebensis&lt;/i&gt; Levy, 1995 is recorded for the first time from Turkey.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Gnaphosidae; &lt;i&gt;Nomisia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Osman</firstname>
          <lastname>Seyyar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nusret</firstname>
          <lastname>Ayyildiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aydın</firstname>
          <lastname>Topçu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
