<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2307.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Dec. 2009</title>
    <volume>2307</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-12-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Annotated checklist of the freshwater fishes of continental and insular Honduras</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The freshwater fishes of Honduras were surveyed for a period of four years (2005–2008). Surveys were supplemented with both literature and museum collection reviews. Our results show that there are at least 172 species of fishes inhabiting Honduran mainland and insular freshwater systems, 166 native and six exotic. Primary freshwater fish diversity was low, with only eigth species (4.8%). The remaining species were either secondary freshwater (47 species, 28.3%) or peripheral (111 species, 66.9%). This checklist includes 36 new records for Honduras, and 12 range expansions. Nine species were found to be endemic; however, just two of them (Amphilophus &lt;i&gt;hogaboomorum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Theraps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wesseli)&lt;/i&gt; are already described. The depauperate primary freshwater fishes fauna of Honduras (8) is congruent with low primary freshwater fishes diversity found in the region between the Usumacinta River and the Nicaraguan great lakes. Although many previously unsampled regions of Honduras were visited as part of this project, there are a variety of remote areas that remain unstudied. While this paper contributes much to the understanding of the distribution and diversity of Honduran freshwater fishes, it is likely that much diversity there remains undocumented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Central America; Nuclear Middle America; Obligate freshwater fishes; Primary freshwater fishes; Distribution; Ichthyofauna; Fish fauna; Biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Central America</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wilfredo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Matamoros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jacob</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schaefer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kreiser</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeography of the &lt;i&gt;Habronattus amicus &lt;/i&gt;species complex (Araneae: Salticidae) of western North America, with evidence for localized asymmetrical mitochondrial introgression</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The frequency and significance of hybridization and gene introgression in spiders (Araneae) is unclear, largely because few studies have combined multiple lines of evidence in the study of systems where introgression is likely. Here we consider multiple types of data to gauge the prevalence and importance of mitochondrial introgression for three species of the &lt;i&gt;Habronattus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amicus&lt;/i&gt; species complex distributed in western North America. A comprehensive phylogeographic sample recovers some geographically-coherent mitochondrial clades, but conspicuously fails to resolve nominal species as monophyletic. This pattern of discordance between molecules and morphological taxonomy is studied in more detail for two species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amicus&lt;/i&gt; (Peckham and Peckham) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ustulatus&lt;/i&gt; (Griswold), found in syntopy on three dune systems in south-central Oregon. Here, multivariate morphological analyses clearly distinguish these two species, but also reveal a narrow window of size overlap between small &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amicus&lt;/i&gt; females and large &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ustulatus&lt;/i&gt; males. A quantitative assessment of microhabitat use shows that these species occupy different microhabitats at two of three dune systems, but that this difference breaks down at a single site (Summer Lake). Consistent with the size overlap and ecological data, mitochondrial data suggest interspecific gene flow at Summer Lake, which is apparently asymmetric from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amicus&lt;/i&gt; into &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ustulatus.&lt;/i&gt; The introgression dynamics revealed in south-central Oregon impact our interpretation of mitochondrial gene trees for the entire species complex, and provide important insight into how hybridization may be influencing evolution in this diverse spider genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hybridization; incomplete lineage sorting; morphometrics; habitat selection; gene tree incongruence</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hybridization</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marshal</firstname>
          <lastname>Hedin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Sphaerodoridae) from off southeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sphaerodorids belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis&lt;/i&gt; were collected on the outer continental shelf and slope off the coast of São Paulo State, during the REVIZEE/Score Sul/Benthos Program. &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guayanae&lt;/i&gt; Hartman and Fauchald 1971 from off Guyana is the only species previously known in this genus. &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shivae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guayanae&lt;/i&gt; in having a longer body, macrotubercles with smaller terminal papillae, and simple chaetae not as pointed distally; eyes are absent in the new species. Four macrotubercles with terminal papillae were observed on the pygidium of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shivae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Such macrotubercles were not reported in &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guayanae,&lt;/i&gt; although the specimens are complete; the presence of these structures in the new species necessitating emendation of the genus diagnosis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sphaerodoridae; &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shivae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ephesiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guayanae&lt;/i&gt;; new species; São Paulo (SE Brazil)</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sphaerodoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandra</firstname>
          <middlename>Elaine</middlename>
          <lastname>Rizzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">ErratumMASROOR, R. (2009) A new arboreal species of Cyrtopodion (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Deh Akro-II Wetlands Complex, Sindh, Pakistan. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2243, 5767.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
