<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2218.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2218</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cladistic analysis of the subfamily Arsenurinae (Lepidoptera, Saturniidae) based on adult morphology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Saturniidae is distributed on all continents except polar areas, and includes about 1528 species in 162 genera, being the group with the largest diversity among Bombycoidea. Approximately 970 species are known from the New World. However, recent molecular studies indicate 1861 species in 162 genera and nine subfamilies. The family Arsenurinae consists of 63 species distributed exclusively in ten Neotropical genera, with phylogenetic relationships poorly understood. The goal of this study was to test the monophyly of the subfamily, tribes and genera using cladistic analysis of adult morphological characters. The subfamily, tribes and genera were all recovered as monophyletic groups with the following relationships among genera: (Almeidaia ((Loxolomia, &lt;i&gt;Copiopteryx)&lt;/i&gt; ((Rhescyntis) ((Grammopelta, &lt;i&gt;Arsenura)&lt;/i&gt; ((Caio) ((Dysdaemonia, &lt;i&gt;Titaea)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paradaemonia)))))).&lt;/i&gt; Both tribes, Arsenurini and Almeidaiini, share several characters, but morphological study of Almeidaiini demonstrates that it also presents significant differences.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Saturniidae; Arsenurinae; cladistic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Amabílio</firstname>
          <middlename>J. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Camargo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olaf</firstname>
          <middlename>H. H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mielke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mirna</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Casagrande</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-34</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Marjuman trilobite &lt;i&gt;Cedarina &lt;/i&gt;Lochman: thoracic morphology, systematics, and new species from western Utah and eastern Nevada, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cedarina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schachti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the Marjuman (Cedaria Zone) Weeks Formation of western Utah, USA, provides the first information on thoracic morphology within the genus. Its thorax is radically different from those of species of &lt;i&gt;Cedaria&lt;/i&gt; Walcott, with which &lt;i&gt;Cedarina&lt;/i&gt; Lochman has been classified in Cedariidae Raymond, but strikingly similar to those of plesiomorphic remopleuridoideans grouped in the paraphyletic Richardsonellinae Raymond. If &lt;i&gt;Cedarina&lt;/i&gt; and the remopleuridoideans are genuinely related it follows that 1) Cedariidae as traditionally conceived is paraphyletic; 2) &lt;i&gt;Cedarina&lt;/i&gt; is a plesiomorphic sister taxon of the remopleuridoideans; and 3) the remopleuridoideans are not a component of the Order Asaphida. Silicified material of a second new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevensis&lt;/i&gt; from the Marjuman (Crepicephalus Zone) Lincoln Peak Formation of eastern Nevada, confirms the presence of a long thoracic axial spine and provides the first information on ontogenetic development and ventral morphology within the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trilobita; Cedariidae; Remopleuridoidea; &lt;i&gt;Cedarina&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Cambrian</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trilobita</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Adrain</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shanan</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peters</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Westrop</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of chimaera, &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus melanophasma &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Chondrichthyes: Chimaeriformes: Chimaeridae), from the eastern North Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of chimaera, &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanophasma&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Chimaeridae), is described from the eastern North Pacific. It is distinct from other eastern Pacific chimaeroids by the following characteristics: a large slightly curved dorsal fin spine extending beyond dorsal fin apex, a long second dorsal fin of uniform height throughout, large pectoral fins extending beyond the pelvic fin insertion when laid flat, trifid claspers forked for approximately one-quarter the total clasper length and a uniform black coloration throughout. The new species is compared to other eastern Pacific members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus&lt;/i&gt; including &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alphus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colliei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrophthalmus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mccoskeri.&lt;/i&gt; Remote Operated Vehicle (ROV) video footage has identified and documented &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanophasma&lt;/i&gt; from the Gulf of California. ROV observations suggest that individuals typically occur over soft-bottom habitats or cobble patches with minimal vertical relief. This is in contrast to other eastern Pacific &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus&lt;/i&gt; species that tend to occur in areas of high rocky relief. The known distribution of this new species at present extends from southern California, U.S.A., along the Pacific coast of Baja California, Mexico, and into the Gulf of California.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chimaeridae; &lt;i&gt;Hydrolagus&lt;/i&gt;; Gulf of California; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chimaeridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kelsey</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>James</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ebert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Douglas</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Long</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dominique</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Didier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
