<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2060.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Apr. 2009</title>
    <volume>2060</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Relationships, evolution and biogeography of Semaphore geckos, &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata, Sphaerodactylidae) based on morphology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Sphaerodactylid gecko genus &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; has at least 20 recognised species in Arabia, the Socotra archipelago, and northeast Africa with an isolate 4500km away in Mauritania. Analysis of nineteen variable morphological characters in the Sphaerodactylidae suggests &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; is most closely related to &lt;i&gt;Quedenfeldtia&lt;/i&gt; of Morocco and then successively to the Spaerodactylini and &lt;i&gt;Saurodactylus.&lt;/i&gt; This contrasts with recent studies using nuclear DNA, which place &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; in a basal polychotomy in the family. If the molecular tree is correct, there must have been considerable parallelism in anatomy in these taxa. Within &lt;i&gt;Pristurus,&lt;/i&gt; parsimony analysis was carried out on a set of 72 variable morphological characters (equivalent to 86 binary ones) from external features, skeleton, musculature and behaviour. Apparent relationships are as follows: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celerrimus&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;insignis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insignoides)&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;guichardi&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;socotranus&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;abdelkuri&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;rupestris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;popovi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavipunctatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gallagheri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adrarensis,&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;i&gt;Spatalura&lt;/i&gt; clade)))). Relationships within the &lt;i&gt;Spatalura&lt;/i&gt; clade are: (P. &lt;i&gt;minimus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simonettai)&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;crucifer,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phillipsi&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;somalicus&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;saada&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;collaris&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;ornithocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carteri))))).&lt;/i&gt; The more basal &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; were apparently primitively heliothermic rock climbers with one lineage becoming tree dwelling. These forms are now confined to the North Oman mountains of eastern Arabia and the Socotra archipelago and may have been replaced elsewhere in Arabia and perhaps northern Africa by a radiation of more morphologically advanced species. Most of these have similar niches to the more primitive forms, but one lineage that gave rise to the &lt;i&gt;Spatalura&lt;/i&gt; clade became ground dwelling and partly nocturnal. Many morphological changes on the phylogeny of &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; may be functionally associated with shifts in ecology and behaviour.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt;; Semaphore gecko; Sphaerodactylidae; evolution; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species and one newly recorded species of oonopid spiders (Araneae: Oonopidae) from Hainan, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species and one newly recorded species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Gamasomorpha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Xestaspis&lt;/i&gt; collected from Hainan Island, China, are diagnosed, described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Gamasomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gamasomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virgulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Xestaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loricata&lt;/i&gt; (L. Koch, 1873) and &lt;i&gt;Xestaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostrata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Xestaspis&lt;/i&gt; is firstly recorded from China. The type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences (IZCAS).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Gamasomorpha&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Xestaspis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yanfeng</firstname>
          <lastname>Tong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-32</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anguina paludicola &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Tylenchida: Anguinidae): The nematode associated with &lt;i&gt;Rathayibacter toxicus &lt;/i&gt;infection in &lt;i&gt;Polypogon monspeliensis &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Lachnagrostis filiformis &lt;/i&gt;in Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anguina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paludicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from &lt;i&gt;Polypogon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monspeliensis&lt;/i&gt; from southeastern South Australia and &lt;i&gt;Lachnagrostis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filiformis&lt;/i&gt; from northern New South Wales, following an examination of nematode populations by allozyme electrophoresis and morphological analysis. Genetic differences were consistent with those expected from conspecific allopatric populations and were based on geography rather than host. Morphological differences between nematodes from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monspeliensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filiformis&lt;/i&gt; were inconsistent and varied between different gall types on the same host plant. The new species is characterised by adults with irregular and variable tail termini, which appear lobed; females may have a process of vestigial ovary extending from the post uterine sac towards the tail; males are dorsally curved with a single reflexed testis; and the haploid chromosome complement is n=18.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anguinidae; allozyme electrophoresis; flood plain staggers; morphology; new species; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anguinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terry</firstname>
          <lastname>Bertozzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kerrie</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davies</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the genera &lt;i&gt;Galeolaria &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopolon &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Serpulidae), with discussions on opercular insertion as a character in their taxonomy and relationships, and their zoogeography</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">While earlier works have shown that the operculum is inserted in the position of the first or second branchial radiole in serpulimorph taxa, the present paper shows that it is inserted independently of the branchial radioles of both sides in the genera &lt;i&gt;Galeolaria&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopolon.&lt;/i&gt; Although both genera possess several characters in common with the group consisting of &lt;i&gt;Pomatoleios,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pomatoceros&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Spirobranchus,&lt;/i&gt; a cladistic analysis revealed that they form two distinct clades, as sister groups to each other. Extant species of &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopolon&lt;/i&gt; occur mainly in the Caribbean region, and of &lt;i&gt;Galeolaria&lt;/i&gt; in eastern Australia and New Zealand. However, there is palaeontological evidence indicating that fossil species of &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopolon&lt;/i&gt; had a wider geographical distribution, having existed in Europe during geological times.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Opercular insertion; taxonomy; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Opercular insertion</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>Gottfried</middlename>
          <lastname>Pillai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus Paramesotriton (Caudata: Salamandridae) from Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, southern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Asian warty newt, &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ermizhaoi,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region in southern China. This species is easily distinguished from other congeners by external morphology and osteology. Phylogenetic analyses based on mitochondrial data place &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ermizhaoi&lt;/i&gt; as a possible sister taxon to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hongkongensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis.&lt;/i&gt; The number of trunk vertebrae varies from 12 to 13 in the new species. The relationship between &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ermizhaoi&lt;/i&gt; and a potentially new &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton&lt;/i&gt; species (Pachytriton C), and the Guangxi population of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caudata; Salamandridae; new species; &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ermizhaoi;&lt;/i&gt; southern China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caudata; Salamandridae; new species; &lt;i&gt;Paramesotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ermizhaoi;&lt;/i&gt; southern China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yunke</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sean</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rovito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Theodore</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Papenfuss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanken</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
