<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2054.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Mar. 2009</title>
    <volume>2054</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-03-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of New World species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Oosternum &lt;/i&gt;Sharp (Coleoptera: Hydrophilidae: Sphaeridiinae) I. Definition of species groups and revision of the &lt;i&gt;Oosternum aequinoctiale &lt;/i&gt;group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Oosternum&lt;/i&gt; Sharp, 1882 is divided into ten species groups based on external adult characters. An identification key to the species groups and a table of diagnostic characters as well as many charater state illustrations for each group are provided. Representatives of the newly defined &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aequinoctiale&lt;/i&gt; species group are revised. Six species of this group are recognized, all occurring in the Neotropical region: &lt;i&gt;Oosternum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(Honduras,&lt;/b&gt; Costa Rica, Nicaragua), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aequinoctiale&lt;/i&gt; (Motschulsky, 1855) (Bolivia, Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Mexico, Panama, Peru, Venezuela), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attenuatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Panama, Colombia, Ecuador), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbicolle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Ecuador, Panama), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holosericeum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Argentina), and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Lesser Antilles: St. Vincent Island). A key to the species and drawings or SEM photographs of diagnostic characters are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydrophilidae; Sphaeridiinae; &lt;i&gt;Oosternum&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical Region; Oriental Region; Palearctic Region; species groups; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Fikáček</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franz</firstname>
          <lastname>Hebauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Hansen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Dolichopodidae)&lt;i&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt; is reviewed and a key is provided for the four known species, three of which are described here: &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aetheoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;akidoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramseyensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; The type species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exalloptera&lt;/i&gt; Runyon &amp; Hurley, is redescribed and the male genitalia illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt; is known from Arizona (3 spp.) and California (1 sp.), and males are notable for their modified wings, most exceptionally those of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exalloptera&lt;/i&gt; whose left wing is of a different shape and size than the right wing. The occurrence of directional wing asymmetry in insects is reviewed to place the unique wings of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exalloptera&lt;/i&gt; in context. Observations of &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt; courtship behavior are provided, and the potential adaptive significance of asymmetrical and modified wings of &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt; is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nearctic; Sympycninae; wings; directed asymmetry; courtship display; long-legged flies; &lt;i&gt;Erebomyia&lt;/i&gt;; Dolichopodidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nearctic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hurley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Justin</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Runyon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and affiliation of European Anthomyzidae (Diptera) based on mitochondrial 12S and 16S rRNA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogenetic Bayesian analysis of combined mitochondrial 12S and 16S rRNA gene markers in European representatives of Anthomyzidae supported the monophyly of the family, confirmed the validity of the genera and provided a resolution of the generic affiliation of some aberrant species. The interrelationships of most genera have not been resolved definitively due to insufficient posterior probability values. Despite this, the clade clustering the genus &lt;i&gt;Anthomyza&lt;/i&gt; Fallén, 1810, &lt;i&gt;Fungomyza&lt;/i&gt; Roháček, 1999 and the &lt;i&gt;Anthomyza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;socculata&lt;/i&gt; group is considered to reflect the real phylogenetic relationships of these taxa as it is also supported by morphological data. The relationships within the genus &lt;i&gt;Anthomyza&lt;/i&gt; are resolved and monophyly of its species-groups confirmed. Within the genus &lt;i&gt;Stiphrosoma&lt;/i&gt; Czerny, 1928, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fissum&lt;/i&gt; Roháček, 1996, a species of unknown relationships, was found to be most closely allied to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sabulosum&lt;/i&gt; (Haliday, 1837). Based on the above analysis a removal of the aberrant species &lt;i&gt;Paranthomyza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caricis&lt;/i&gt; Roháček, 1999 and &lt;i&gt;Anthomyza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;socculata&lt;/i&gt; (Zetterstedt, 1847) from genera to which they were formerly affiliated, is suggested.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; European Anthomyzidae; phylogeny; mitochondrial 12S+16S rRNA; Bayesian inference</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jindřich</firstname>
          <lastname>Roháček</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <lastname>Tóthová</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jaromír</firstname>
          <lastname>Vaňhara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cercyon castaneipennis &lt;/i&gt;sp. n., an overlooked species from Europe (Coleoptera: Hydrophilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cercyon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castaneipennis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is recognised as a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obsoletus&lt;/i&gt; (Gyllenhal). Apart from small differences in the morphology of the aedeagus, both species can be separated by the structure of the mentum, the shape of the antennal club and the structure and colouration of the elytra. &lt;i&gt;Cercyon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castaneipennis&lt;/i&gt; is currently known from Central Europe and the southern part of North Europe. In the Netherlands, at the western border of its range, it is considered a recent immigrant, as records before the year 2000 are lacking. A lectotype for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obsoletus&lt;/i&gt; is designated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydrophilidae; &lt;i&gt;Cercyon&lt;/i&gt;; Europe; Palaearctic Region; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Vorst</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
