<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2018.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2018</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A proposed higher taxonomy of anomodont therapsids</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A higher-level taxonomic framework for the Permo-Triassic anomodont therapsids (dicynodonts and their relatives) is presented in order to bring concordance between reconstructions of anomodont phylogeny and nomenclature. Taxonomic histories, remarks on current usage, and phylogenetic definitions are provided for twenty-two higher level (i.e., suprageneric) anomodont taxa: Anomodontia, Bidentalia, Chainosauria, Cistecephalidae, Cryptodontia, Dicynodontia, Dicynodontoidea, Emydopidae, Emydopoidea, Endothiodontia, Eumantelliidae, Geikiidae, Geikiinae, Kingoriidae, Kistecephalia, Lystrosauridae, Myosauridae, Oudenodontidae, Pylaecephalidae, Rhachiocephalidae, Therochelonia, and Venyukovioidea. Additionally, lists of diagnostic characters supporting each of these higher taxa are given, utilizing the results of several recent phylogenetic analyses of anomodont relationships.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">nomenclature; Synapsida; Dicynodontia; Permian; Triassic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">nomenclature</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kammerer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kenneth</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Angielczyk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Additions to the decapod crustacean fauna of the Hawaiian Islands, I. A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sakaila &lt;/i&gt;Manning and Holthuis, 1981 (Decapoda, Brachyura, Aethridae), with the description of a new species from the Northwestern Hawaiian Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The brachyuran crab genus &lt;i&gt;Sakaila,&lt;/i&gt; currently considered a member of the family Aethridae, is reviewed and revised. Illustrations are provided for all of the known species, and a new species, the fourth in the genus, is described based on one female from French Frigate Shoals, one male from Maro Reef, both in the Northwestern Hawaiian Islands, and a second male from Johnston Atoll. Previous species are known only from the eastern Atlantic off the west coast of Africa (S. &lt;i&gt;africana&lt;/i&gt; Manning and Holthuis, 1981) and from the far western Pacific off Japan (S. &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1963, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1963). The new species differs from its congeners mostly in the overall spination of the carapace and legs, which is more pronounced in the new species. A key to the known species is provided and the current status of each species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sakaila; Brachyura; Aethridae; Hawaii; French Frigate Shoals</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sakaila</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joel</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Scott</firstname>
          <lastname>Godwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Moffitt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-44</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Atlantic occurrence of the genus &lt;i&gt;Bellottia &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei, Bythitidae) with two new species from the Western North Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Thirteen specimens of the bythitid fish-genus &lt;i&gt;Bellottia&lt;/i&gt; have been reported from the Western North Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico. A comparison with the three known species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apoda&lt;/i&gt; Giglioli, 1883 from the East Atlantic and the Mediterranean, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger&lt;/i&gt; (Smith &amp; Radcliffe, 1913) from the Philippines and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galatheae&lt;/i&gt; Nielsen &amp; Møller, 2008 from the Solomon Sea and Philippines showed that the 13 specimens are different from all three. Furthermore, the 12 specimens from the Gulf of Mexico (B. &lt;i&gt;robusta)&lt;/i&gt; are specifically different from the specimen caught off southern Georgia (B. &lt;i&gt;cryptica)&lt;/i&gt; based on differences in body depth at origin of anal fin, presence or absence of spine on preopercular crest and number of precaudal vertebrae. The two new species appear to be associated with deep-sea coral or reef habitats and likely may have wider distributions than are apparent at present.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bythitidae; &lt;i&gt;Bellottia&lt;/i&gt;; two &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Gulf of Mexico; off southern Georgia; deep-sea corals</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bythitidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jørgen</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Steve</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ross</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cohen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A reassessment of &lt;i&gt;Cuora cyclornata &lt;/i&gt;Blanck, McCord and Le, 2006 (Testudines, Geoemydidae) and a plea for taxonomic stability</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We analyze the phylogenetic variation present in the &lt;i&gt;Cuora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trifasciata&lt;/i&gt; species complex using mitochondrial and nuclear DNA sequence data. We use this information to evaluate the recent description of &lt;i&gt;Cuora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclornata&lt;/i&gt; Blanck, McCord, and Le (2006), and reinterpret this proposed species in light of likely mitochondrial introgression. Our results indicate that the pattern of variation within the &lt;i&gt;Cuora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trifasciata&lt;/i&gt; species complex is better explained by mitochondrial introgression coupled with hybridization and/or clinal variation, than it is by the presence of a previously unrecognized species. We also use our phylogeny as a framework for discussion of additional proposed changes to generic level taxonomy in this critically imperiled clade. Our results highlight the importance of appropriate data sampling in taxonomic revisions and suggest that &lt;i&gt;Cuora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclornata&lt;/i&gt; be treated as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cuora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trifasciata.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Phillip</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Spinks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Thomson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>Bradley</middlename>
          <lastname>Shaffer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
