<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2183.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Aug. 2009</title>
    <volume>2183</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-08-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Unresolved cases of type fixation, synonymy and homonymy in harpacticoid copepod nomenclature (Crustacea: Copepoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Type fixation for each of the 601 valid genera (17 placed &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis)&lt;/i&gt; and 13 genera of doubtful identity (genera &lt;i&gt;inquirenda)&lt;/i&gt; in the Harpacticoida (Crustacea, Copepoda) has been verified. Twenty-four genus-group names published after 1930 lack the mandatory type fixation and are therefore unavailable. With the exception of &lt;i&gt;Kliopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1962 which is replaced by its senior synonym &lt;i&gt;Emertonia&lt;/i&gt; Wilson, 1932, such names are made available here by either attributing the original name to the first author(s) who explicitly fixed a type species (Psammastacus Nicholls, 1935; &lt;i&gt;Alteuthellopsis&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944; &lt;i&gt;Idyellopsis&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944; &lt;i&gt;Paralaophonte&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944; &lt;i&gt;Robertgurneya&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944; &lt;i&gt;Cladorostrata&lt;/i&gt; Shen &amp; Tai, 1963; &lt;i&gt;Micropsammis&lt;/i&gt; Mielke, 1975; and the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Rheocamptus&lt;/i&gt; Borutzky, 1948 and &lt;i&gt;Scottopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1962;) or by adopting the name taking the present authorship and date (Paranannopus Lang, 1936a; &lt;i&gt;Paraidya&lt;/i&gt; Sewell, 1940; &lt;i&gt;Apodopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1962; &lt;i&gt;Scottolana&lt;/i&gt; Por, 1967; &lt;i&gt;Barbaracletodes&lt;/i&gt; Becker, 1979; &lt;i&gt;Ameiropsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Bodin, 1979; &lt;i&gt;Chilaophonte&lt;/i&gt; Mielke, 1985; &lt;i&gt;Psammonitocrella&lt;/i&gt; Rouch, 1992; &lt;i&gt;Tectacingulum&lt;/i&gt; Harris, 1994; and the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Intermedopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1962 (corrected spelling &lt;i&gt;Intermediopsyllus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Fiersiella&lt;/i&gt; Suárez Morales &amp; Iliffe, 2005). In two cases a ruling by the International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature will be required to avoid upsetting a long-accepted name in its accustomed meaning (Halectinosoma Lang, 1944; &lt;i&gt;Heterolaophonte&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944). The recently proposed generic name &lt;i&gt;Pilocamptus&lt;/i&gt; Wells, 2007 does not satisfy the provisions of ICZN Art. 13.1 and is here made available by explicit citation of a bibliographic reference that provides a diagnosis purported to differentiate the taxon. &lt;i&gt;Rhizothrix&lt;/i&gt; Brady &amp; Robertson, 1876 is an unavailable name which was first made available by Sars (1909a). The unavailable generic name &lt;i&gt;Scottopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1962 has no potentially valid synonym and is replaced by the next oldest available name from among its subgenera, i.e. &lt;i&gt;Wellsopsyllus&lt;/i&gt; Kunz, 1981 (ICZN Art. 23.3.5). The unavailable subgeneric name &lt;i&gt;Psyllocamptus&lt;/i&gt; (Langpsyllocamptus) Kunz, 1975b is not reinstated because it denotes a taxon that is based exclusively on plesiomorphies. New replacement names have been proposed for preoccupied generic names in the harpacticoid families Canthocamptidae (Poria Lang, 1965; &lt;i&gt;Dahlakia&lt;/i&gt; Por, 1986a), Dactylopusiidae (Sewellia Lang, 1965), and Leptopontiidae (Ichnusella Cottarelli, 1971). The preoccupied generic name &lt;i&gt;Anoplosoma&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1911c (family Ameiridae) is replaced by a previously proposed, but subsequently forgotten, replacement name, &lt;i&gt;Anoplosomella&lt;/i&gt; Strand, 1929. &lt;i&gt;Nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nova&lt;/i&gt; are also suggested for &lt;i&gt;Parathalassius&lt;/i&gt; Dussart, 1986 (Calanoida: Centropagidae) and &lt;i&gt;Berea&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1963 (Cyclopoida: Chondracanthidae) which have entered into homonymy with previously established names. The junior synonym &lt;i&gt;Alteutha&lt;/i&gt; Baird, 1846b is considered valid, taking precedence as a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;protectum&lt;/i&gt; over the older names &lt;i&gt;Sterope&lt;/i&gt; Goodsir, 1845 and &lt;i&gt;Carillus&lt;/i&gt; Goodsir, 1845 (nomina &lt;i&gt;oblita).&lt;/i&gt; Similar reversal of precedence applies to the family-group names Peltidiidae Claus, 1860 and Tisbidae Stebbing, 1910 which are junior subjective synonyms of Steropinae Dana, 1854 and Scutellidiinae Claus, 1889, respectively. Since the type of &lt;i&gt;Idomene&lt;/i&gt; Philippi, 1843 is identified as a member of the Clausidiidae (Cyclopoida), the generic name &lt;i&gt;Xouthous&lt;/i&gt; Thomson, 1883 is reinstated to accommodate all remaining species currently placed in &lt;i&gt;Idomene.&lt;/i&gt; The forgotten copepod genus &lt;i&gt;Microchelonia&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1918 is placed in the family Laophontidae and considered a senior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Namakosiramia&lt;/i&gt; Ho &amp; Perkins, 1977. The family-group name Pontostratiotidae A. Scott, 1909 (type: &lt;i&gt;Pontostratiotes&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1883) is a senior subjective synonym of Cerviniopseinae Brotskaya, 1963 (type: &lt;i&gt;Cerviniopsis&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1903) and the former is consequently reinstated at the subfamilial level. The family-group name Huntemanniidae Por, 1986a (type: &lt;i&gt;Huntemannia&lt;/i&gt; Poppe, 1884) is a junior subjective synonym of Nannopinae Brady, 1880a (type: &lt;i&gt;Nannopus&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1880a) and the latter is reinstated as the valid name at family rank and with the spelling corrected to Nannopodidae. The family-name Paranannopinae Por, 1986a is a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudum&lt;/i&gt; based on an unavailable generic name and is replaced by Danielsseniinae Huys &amp; Gee in Huys &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 1996. Four orphaned taxonomic groupings created by the removal of the type species – but not of the remaining species included in a genus – require an existing (previously invalid) or new generic name. &lt;i&gt;Amphiascus&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1905a is a senior objective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Paramphiascopsis&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944 and must be restricted to the species currently included in the latter; a new genus &lt;i&gt;Sarsamphiascus&lt;/i&gt; (type: &lt;i&gt;Dactylopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; Claus, 1863) is proposed to receive all remaining &lt;i&gt;Amphiascus&lt;/i&gt; species. The new generic names &lt;i&gt;Monardius&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Glabrotelson&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. are proposed for the orphaned taxonomic groupings resulting from the removal of the types of &lt;i&gt;Teissierella&lt;/i&gt; Monard, 1935a to &lt;i&gt;Robertsonia&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1880a, and of &lt;i&gt;Hastigerella&lt;/i&gt; Nicholls, 1935 to &lt;i&gt;Arenosetella&lt;/i&gt; Wilson, 1932, respectively. &lt;i&gt;Leptomesochra&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1911b is a senior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Interleptomesochra&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1965 and must be restricted to the latter’s taxonomic concept; the previously unavailable generic name &lt;i&gt;Leptameira&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1936d is reinstated under the present authorship and date to assemble all remaining &lt;i&gt;Leptomesochra&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rony</firstname>
          <lastname>Huys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-99</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
