<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2071.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Apr. 2009</title>
    <volume>2071</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Potential cryptic speciation in Mediterranean populations of &lt;i&gt;Ophioderma&lt;/i&gt; (Echinodermata: Ophiuroidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ophioderma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda&lt;/i&gt; is a large brittlestar species, common in the Mediterranean Sea and spread across the subtropical-tropical eastern Atlantic Ocean. Recently, a morphologically similar brooding form of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda&lt;/i&gt; was discovered in the eastern Mediterranean Sea. The brooding period is restricted to late May and early June and the largest females brood over 1,000 juveniles, all of the same ontogenetic stage. Brooders differ from non-brooding &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda&lt;/i&gt; in body colour (dominated by green instead of red), gonad colour (in alcohol white instead of oliveto reddish-brown) and size (up to 17 mm disk diameter instead of 30 mm). These characters overlap between both forms though. Molecular data (mt-COI sequences) lend weak support to the existence of two separate species, but suggest that if a split occurred it is recent and both forms interbreed. Alternatively, the eastern Mediterranean populations could represent a poecilogonous subgroup of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">brooding; taxonomy; phylogeny; morphology; mt-COI</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">brooding</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sabine</firstname>
          <lastname>Stöhr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Emilie</firstname>
          <lastname>Boissin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anne</firstname>
          <lastname>Chenuil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Holotypes of ostracods of Order Podocopida from the collection of the Museum of A.V.Zhirmunsky Institute of Marine Biology FEB RAS (Vladivostok)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Museum collection of A.V. Zhimunsky Institute of Marine Biology FEB RAS contains 208 holotypes of ostracods of Order Podocopida described in 25 works of E.I. Schornikov and co-authors published within the period of 1969–2006. The list of these holotypes includes taxa of suprageneric level listed in systematic order, and taxa of lower level are listed in alphabetic order. New numbers, assigned to the holotypes instead of the previous ones as the result of reorganization of the Museum specimen collections, are supplied, as well as revised and modern names if the original ones were changed, and corresponding references.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ostracoda; Podocopida; holotypes; the Museum of IMB FEB RAS</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ostracoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Evgeny</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schornikov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olga</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tsareva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-34</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Oreophrynella &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Bufonidae) from the Pantepui region of Guyana, with notes on &lt;i&gt;O. macconnelli &lt;/i&gt;Boulenger, 1900</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oreophrynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seegobini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from 2088 m elevation on Maringma tepui in the Pakaraima Mountains of Guyana, at the Guyana-Brazil border. The new species is mainly distinguished from known congeners by small size, indistinct frontoparietal crests, prominent postorbital crests, prominent suborbital crests, well-developed webbing on hand and foot, dorsal skin minutely spiculate with scattered medium to large elevated tubercles, ventral skin anteriorly rugose with few flat granules, posteriorly tuberculate, blackish brown dorsal colour, and dark brownish orange ventral colour. Data on four specimens of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macconnelli&lt;/i&gt; collected on the southeast slope of the tepui are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oreophrynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seegobini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; endemism; Guiana Shield; taxonomy; tepuis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oreophrynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seegobini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; endemism</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-49</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana &lt;/i&gt;Bott, 1969 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Gecarcinucidae) from West Papua, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of gecarcinucid crabs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana&lt;/i&gt; Bott, 1969, are described from the islands of Waigeo and Batanta in West Papua Province, Indonesia. &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lipkei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the allied &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alba&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1980, from Papua New Guinea by having fully developed pigmented eyes, smooth carapace, smooth and distinctly gaping second major chela, and the relatively more slender male first gonopod. &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tikus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; resembles &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subconvexa&lt;/i&gt; (Roux, 1927) from Papua Province but differs by possessing indistinct and shallow epigastric lobes on the carapace, the absence of a subdistal tooth on the upper margin of the ambulatory merus of pereiopods 2-5 and a relatively stouter male first gonopod. The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana&lt;/i&gt; and its constituent species is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Gecarcinucidae; &lt;i&gt;Holthuisana&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daisy</firstname>
          <lastname>Wowor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the generic identity of &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus moratoi &lt;/i&gt;Jim &amp; Caramaschi, 1980 (Anura, Cycloramphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The generic identity of &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt; is controversial since the original description due to the presence of intermediate morphological features between the genera &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys.&lt;/i&gt; Herein we performed molecular analyses of three genes (16S, cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and Rag-1) and recovered &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt; deeply imbedded inside a clade containing only &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; species, appearing as the sister group of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concavitympanum.&lt;/i&gt; Therefore, this study formally transfers the species &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt; to the genus &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; [Proceratophrys &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt; (Jim &amp; Caramaschi 1980) comb. nov].</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt;; nomenclature; new combination; molecular systematics; 16S; cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; Rag-1</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moratoi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renata</firstname>
          <middlename>Cecília</middlename>
          <lastname>Amaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dante</firstname>
          <lastname>Pavan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>Trefaut</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
