<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2206.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Aug. 2009</title>
    <volume>2206</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-08-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Eucyclops &lt;/i&gt;Claus (Copepoda: Cyclopoida) from the Chihuahuan Desert with a redescription of &lt;i&gt;E. pseudoensifer &lt;/i&gt;Dussart</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the freshwater copepod genus &lt;i&gt;Eucyclops&lt;/i&gt; are described from two sites in the Chihuahuan Desert (CHD), which includes parts of northern Mexico and southern United States. &lt;i&gt;Eucyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuatrocienegas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished by having a short inner spiniform seta on the fifth leg, relatively short caudal rami, and a partially naked spine of the fourth endopod, among other characters. The finding of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuatrocienegas&lt;/i&gt; in Cuatro Ciénegas, an area in the CHD that is known for harbouring the highest number of endemic aquatic species in North America, suggests that these habitats could yield other endemic forms. The other new species resembles the Neotropical &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoensifer&lt;/i&gt; Dussart, 1984 but differs in having a shorter basipodal spine of the first leg, shorter outer terminal spiniform caudal seta, a different length ratio of inner/outer spines of leg 4 third endopodal segment, and a different pattern of the serra on the caudal rami. &lt;i&gt;Eucyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoensifer,&lt;/i&gt; originally collected from a high altitude lake in the Andean system of western Venezuela, is here redescribed from female and male type specimens. The description of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chihuahuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; recognizes both the subtle but consistent differences of this population and its environmental isolation in this arid region. The North American records of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoensifer&lt;/i&gt; should be revised in the light of these findings in order to determine the real distributional ranges of these species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; arid systems; new species; crustacean freshwater zooplankton</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Suárez-Morales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walsh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genera of Gymnodamaeidae (Acari: Oribatida: Plateremaeoidea) of Canada, with notes on some nomenclatorial problems</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of the North American Gymnodamaeidae is currently intractable, because (1) the adults are covered in a thick, ornamented cerotegument that provides useful characters, but that obscures the cuticle; (2) many descriptions appear to be based on newly moulted or cleared specimens and are incomplete or contain misinterpretations; and (3) there is considerable disagreement in the literature about valid genera and generic limits, leading some authors to sink some or all of the North American genera into &lt;i&gt;Gymnodamaeus&lt;/i&gt; s.l. Several nomenclatorial problems have added to the confusion. In this paper I use new diagnoses to demonstrate that seven previously described genera based on North American species can be separated from &lt;i&gt;Gymnodamaeus&lt;/i&gt; s.s. and provide a key to distinguish them. I clarify the correct publication dates for Paschoal’s genera and after consultation with the original author, propose replacements for two of these generic names that are preoccupied: &lt;i&gt;Donjohnstonella&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov. for &lt;i&gt;Johnstonella&lt;/i&gt; Paschoal and &lt;i&gt;Roynortonella&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov. for &lt;i&gt;Nortonella&lt;/i&gt; Paschoal. New Canadian provincial distribution records are provided for &lt;i&gt;Gymnodamaeus&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; Hammer (AB), &lt;i&gt;Jacotella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadricaudicula&lt;/i&gt; (Jacot) (AB, ON), &lt;i&gt;Joshuella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agrosticula&lt;/i&gt; Paschoal (AB, YK), and &lt;i&gt;Pleodamaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plokosus&lt;/i&gt; (Woolley &amp; Higgins) (AB). Finally, I discuss the similarity between the cerotegumental pustules in the Gymnodamaeidae and the epicuticular wax crystalloids on the leaves of plants such as the water lotus (Nelumbo &lt;i&gt;nucifera&lt;/i&gt; Gaertn.) and suggest that they may have a similar water repellent “Lotus-effect.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">homonym; cerotegument; Lotus-effect; epicuticular wax; &lt;i&gt;Adrodamaeus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodamaeus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nortonella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pleodamaeus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Johnstonella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Joshuella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Jacotella&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">homonym</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>Evans</middlename>
          <lastname>Walter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-44</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the first five larval stages of &lt;i&gt;Plesionika narval &lt;/i&gt;(Fabricius, 1787) (Crustacea, Decapoda, Pandalidae) obtained under laboratory conditions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first five zoeal stages of &lt;i&gt;Plesionika&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narval&lt;/i&gt; were obtained from 15 days of laboratory culture. All larval stages are described and illustrated in detail. Zoeal characters are compared with the previous described larvae of &lt;i&gt;Plesionika&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthonotus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Plesionika&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; and with undetermined zoeas of Pandalidae from plankton samples.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Plesionika&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narval&lt;/i&gt;; Pandalidae; larval development; zoea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Plesionika&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narval&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>María</middlename>
          <lastname>Landeira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <lastname>Lozano-Soldevilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>Ignacio</middlename>
          <lastname>Gonzálezgordillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-61</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crikey steveirwini &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov. from montane habitats in the Wet Tropics of northeastern Queensland, Australia (Gastropoda: Eupulmonata: Camaenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crikey&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;steveirwini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from montane habitats in the Wet Tropics of northeastern Queensland, Australia. This species is unique among the eastern Australian arboreal camaenids in both distribution (confined to montane refugia), and genital morphology (lacking a penial verge). An assessment of the phylogenetic position of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;steveirwini&lt;/i&gt; is made based on a combination of morphological features (shell and anatomy) and available molecular data. The biogeographic implications for the Australian camaenid radiation of this altitudinally restricted species are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Camaenoidea; arboreal snails; taxonomy; phylogeny; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Camaenoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <lastname>Stanisic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
