<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2123.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Jun. 2009</title>
    <volume>2123</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-06-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of helminth parasites of threatened vertebrate species from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Using available records, unpublished information retrieved from the Helminthological Collection of the Oswaldo Cruz Institute (CHIOC) and published reports, a checklist of the recorded helminth parasites of endangered vertebrates from Brazil was generated. A total of 772 records and 186 helminth species (6 Acanthocephala, 83 Nematoda, 23 Cestoda, 64 Trematoda, 10 Monogenea) in 76 host species (7 Actinopterygii, 8 Chondrichthyes, 1 Amphibia, 10 Reptilia, 22 Aves, 28 Mammalia) from Brazil were listed in the present work, including 39 undetermined helminth species and 10 new host records. This is the first compilation of the helminth parasites of threatened vertebrates in Brazil and in the Neotropics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">helminth; biodiversity; parasite; threatened vertebrate species; IUCN 2008 Red List; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">helminth</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luís</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Muniz-Pereira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabiano</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vieira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Luque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of casque-headed tree frog, genus &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; Miranda-Ribeiro (Amphibia: Anura: Hylidae), from the Atlantic Rainforest of southern Bahia, Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; is described from patches of arboreal restinga within the Atlantic Forest Biome, in a region known as Baixo Sul in southern Bahia, northeastern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arapapa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is promptly diagnosed from other &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; mainly by having small size (male snout-vent length 57.4–58.1 mm), loreal region flattened and wide, and canthus rostralis rounded and poorly elevated. The wide and flattened snout resembles that found in &lt;i&gt;Triprion&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Diaglena,&lt;/i&gt; and possibly is a parallelism (homoplasy) related to the phragmotic behavior of casque-headed tree frogs to their microhabitat usage. The decision to allocate the new species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; is discussed in detail, as the single morphological synapomorphy of the genus, the presence of a prenasal bone, is insufficient to morphologically relate the new species to &lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Triprion,&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Diaglena.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arapapa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Casque-headed tree frog; Hylinae; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aparasphenodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arapapa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Casque-headed tree frog</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bruno</firstname>
          <middlename>V. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pimenta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Napoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Célio</firstname>
          <middlename>F. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Haddad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-54</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new brevicipitid species (Brevicipitidae: Callulina) from the fragmented forests of the Taita Hills, Kenya </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species &lt;i&gt;Callulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dawida&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Taita Hills, Kenya. It is distinguished from other members of the genus on the basis of the degree of digital expansion. The species further differs from other members of the genus based on molecular sequence comparisons and on its call. The morphological variation in the new species is described, including a comparison of internal and external characters and sexual dimorphism with other species of &lt;i&gt;Callulina.&lt;/i&gt; The conservation status of the species, on the basis of its restricted distribution and land use changes in the area, is considered to be of high concern. An updated key of the species of &lt;i&gt;Callulina&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Callulina&lt;/i&gt;; Brevicipitidae; Taita Hills; Eastern Arc Mountains; Afromontane</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Callulina&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>John</middlename>
          <lastname>Measey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Sá</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Malonza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
