<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2134.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Jun. 2009</title>
    <volume>2134</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of &lt;i&gt;Dynastor &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Brassolis &lt;/i&gt;butterflies (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae): a tough nut to crack</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study examines the phylogenetic relationships among species of the butterfly genera &lt;i&gt;Dynastor&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Brassolis&lt;/i&gt; using 57 characters from adult morphology and wing coloration. We provide evidence for the monophyly of both genera. The relationships among &lt;i&gt;Dynastor&lt;/i&gt; species are well resolved, but we were unable to find informative characters that could resolve the relationships inside &lt;i&gt;Brassolis.&lt;/i&gt; We provide diagnoses for &lt;i&gt;Dynastor&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Brassolis&lt;/i&gt; and all species included in these genera, including illustrations that show geographical variation in wing color. The status of one subspecies is changed to species; &lt;i&gt;Brassolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dinizi&lt;/i&gt; d’Almeida, 1956, &lt;b&gt;NEW&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;STATUS.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brassolini; morphological homogeneity; &lt;i&gt;dinizi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brassolini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivonne</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Garzón-Orduña</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Penz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides &lt;/i&gt;Matsumura (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae, Macropsini) from Mainland China, with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; Matsumura are recorded from Mainland China. Among them, &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dilatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterodigitatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. are described as new, and &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kurentsovi&lt;/i&gt; (Anufriev) is redescribed. One new combination, &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aomians&lt;/i&gt; (Kuoh, 1981) comb. nov. (from &lt;i&gt;Oncopsis)&lt;/i&gt; is proposed and two new synonyms are revealed, the genus &lt;i&gt;Digitalis&lt;/i&gt; Liu and Zhang, 2002 (type species: &lt;i&gt;Digitalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striolatus&lt;/i&gt; Liu and Zhang) is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Digitalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striolatus&lt;/i&gt; Liu and Zhang is a new junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pediopsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aomians&lt;/i&gt; (Kuoh). Images of adults and genitalia of the four species are provided, along with a checklist of the known species of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; Macropsini; morphology; taxonomy; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wu</firstname>
          <lastname>Dai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yalin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-35</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pentaceration&lt;/i&gt;, an unusual new genus of Paramunnidae from Australia (Isopoda, Asellota)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pentaceration,&lt;/i&gt; in the janiroid asellote family Paramunnidae from the Bass Strait area in south-eastern Australia is diagnosed. The distinguishing characters of species in the new genus are 1 central and 2 lateral spines on the frontal margin of the head, elongate eyestalks, lateral spines of varying length on pereonites 2–7, and reduced width of pereonite 4 compared with 3 and 5. Descriptions are presented of the type species, &lt;i&gt;Pentaceration&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bassiana,&lt;/i&gt; and a second new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosissima.&lt;/i&gt; The new genus appears to be wide-spread around Australia and New Zealand, where several as yet undescribed species have been noted, ranging from the upper sublitoral to abyssal depth. The relationship of &lt;i&gt;Pentaceration&lt;/i&gt; to other paramunnid genera with covered coxae on all legs is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pentaceration&lt;/i&gt;; Paramunnidae; new genus; new species; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pentaceration&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <lastname>Just</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kakadudessus tomweiri&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and species of diving beetle from tropical northern Australia, based on molecular phylogenetic and morphological data (Coleoptera, Dytiscidae, Bidessini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diving beetle genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Kakadudessus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomweiri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Northern Territory (Kakadu National Park, headwaters of Mary River) and north-eastern Queensland (Cape York Peninsula) of Australia. The new species has an elongate, almost flat habitus and elytra with pale yellowish markings. The head has a cervical line between the hindmargin of the eyes and the clypeus is anteriorly bordered. Pronotum and elytra have well developed striae, the latter without sutural lines and accessory striae. The posterior part of the basal cavity of epipleura has no transverse carina, the fairly elongate and narrow prosternal process reaches the metaventrite. The latter is provided with rows of punctures at its midline and the metacoxal lines are longer than the distance between them and strongly diverging anteriorly. The parameres are bi-segmented, very thin, slender and elongate, and slightly bifid apically. The combination of all these characters separates the new species and, thus, also the new genus from all other Bidessini. Morphologically, &lt;i&gt;Kakadudessus&lt;/i&gt; resembles species of &lt;i&gt;Leiodytes&lt;/i&gt; Guignot, 1936, &lt;i&gt;Limbodessus&lt;/i&gt; Guignot, 1939 and &lt;i&gt;Uvarus&lt;/i&gt; Guignot, 1939, the parameres resemble those of species of &lt;i&gt;Allodessus&lt;/i&gt; Guignot, 1953. DNA sequence data from the mitochondrial genes cytochrome oxidase subunit I (cox1) and the large ribosomal subunit (16S rRNA), however, suggest that &lt;i&gt;Kakadudessus&lt;/i&gt; does not belong to any of the known Oriental and Australasian Bidessini genera. Most importantly, recognition of &lt;i&gt;Kakadudessus&lt;/i&gt; does not create paraphyly. All specimens were collected in small pools of shaded and intermittent streams and rivers with sandy or gravely bottom and without any vegetation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diving beetles; Dytiscidae; Bidessini; new genus; new species; classification; molecular systematics; northern Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diving beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lars</firstname>
          <lastname>Hendrich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Balke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Sabikikorius&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;uidoensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Coleoptera: Elateridae) from the Sand Dune Shore of Ui-do Island, Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species is described belonging to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Sabikikorius&lt;/i&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus&lt;/i&gt; (Sabikikorius) &lt;i&gt;uidoensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and isolated from the sand dunes of Ui-do Island, Korea. A key to the species is given with distributional information for each species of this subgenus. Sequencing data of the mitochondrial genes encoding COI (cytochrome c oxidase I) and 16S rDNA (16S ribosomal DNA) are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera; Elateridae; Agrypninae; &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus&lt;/i&gt; (Sabikikorius) &lt;i&gt;uidoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species; COI; 16S rDNA; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tae</firstname>
          <middlename>Man</middlename>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ha</firstname>
          <middlename>Sik</middlename>
          <lastname>Sim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Seunghwan</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hae</firstname>
          <middlename>Chul</middlename>
          <lastname>Park</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-06-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
