<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2072.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Apr. 2009</title>
    <volume>2072</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of Calcareous sponges (Porifera, Calcarea) from the Chilean coast </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study is part of a large international effort to inventory the markedly underestimated sponge diversity in the coastal south-eastern Pacific, and figure its biotic affinities with neighbouring faunas in the Antarctic peninsula, in the south-western Atlantic and in the tropical eastern Pacific. Collections were assembled between 2003 and 2007 from 20 Chilean localities, at depths varying from 8 to 35 m. Thirty nine specimens of calcareous sponges were collected totalling 7 species which are described here, 6 being new to science. Four species belong to Calcinea (Clathrina &lt;i&gt;antofagastensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Clathrina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fjordica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Guancha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Leucaltis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; and 3 to Calcaronea (Leucosolenia &lt;i&gt;australis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sycon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huinayense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sycettusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Calcarea; Chile; Sponges; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Calcarea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fernanda</firstname>
          <lastname>Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajdu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <lastname>Willenz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michelle</firstname>
          <lastname>Klautau</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cranial anatomy of &lt;i&gt;Jeholosaurus shangyuanensis &lt;/i&gt;(Dinosauria: Ornithischia) from the Early Cretaceous of China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A detailed description of the skull and mandible of the Chinese cerapodan ornithischian dinosaur &lt;i&gt;Jeholosaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shangyuanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Lower Cretaceous, Yixian Formation) is presented for the first time and this information is used to reassess its phylogenetic position. &lt;i&gt;Jeholosaurus&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from all other cerapodans on the basis of one autapomorphy (a row of small foramina on the nasal) and a character combination that is unique among ornithischians. Previously undescribed specimens add considerably to our knowledge of &lt;i&gt;Jeholosaurus,&lt;/i&gt; providing new insights into its anatomy and ontogeny. Revised character scores increase the resolution of phylogenetic hypotheses and provide additional support for placement of &lt;i&gt;Jeholosaurus&lt;/i&gt; within Ornithopoda.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerapoda; early Aptian; Jehol Biota; Marginocephalia; Ornithopoda; Yixian Formation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng-Lu</firstname>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-55</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus fui &lt;/i&gt;Miao, a valid bagrid species from the Yangtze River drainage, South China (Teleostei: Bagridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fui&lt;/i&gt; Miao is a valid bagrid species that can be separated from all its congeners in having 27–33 anal-fin rays. Among the species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus,&lt;/i&gt; it forms part of a group of approximately 20 species putatively characterized by having a smooth anterior margin of the pectoral-fin spine and short maxillary barbels not extending to the base of the pectoral-fin spine. &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fui,&lt;/i&gt; together with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vachelli,&lt;/i&gt; can be differentiated from all other forktailed species of this group by having no fewer than 20 branched anal-fin rays, the posterior end of the anal-fin base posterior to the vertical through the posterior end of the adipose-fin base, and anal-fin base longer than the adipose-fin base. It further differs from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; in having a gas bladder without beaded lateral and posterior margins, and from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vachelli&lt;/i&gt; in having short maxillary barbels not extending to the base of the pectoral-fin spine. &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fui&lt;/i&gt; is currently known from the main stream of the upper Yangtze River and its tributaries, the Min River, Jialing River, Tuo River, Wu River and Chishui River in Sichuan Province, Guizhou Province, and the Chongqing City. The identity and nomenclature of &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Yangtze River basin; South China; Siluriformes; Bagridae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jian-Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Cheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Andrés</middlename>
          <lastname>López</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
