<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 160KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt; </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 20KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt; </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2318.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Dec. 2009</title>
    <volume>2318</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Foreword</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pierfilippo</firstname>
          <lastname>Cerretti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franco</firstname>
          <lastname>Mason</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Minelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gianluca</firstname>
          <lastname>Nardi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Whitmore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>5-7</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Oribatid mite (Arachnida: Oribatida) coenoses from SW Sardinia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Oribatid mite communities were investigated at five sites in SW Sardinia (Carbonia-Iglesias and Medio Campidano provinces) in three representative habitat types: holm oak (Quercus &lt;i&gt;ilex)&lt;/i&gt; forest, cork oak (Quercus &lt;i&gt;suber)&lt;/i&gt; forest and pineland (Pinus &lt;i&gt;radiata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinaster).&lt;/i&gt; A total of 1,180 oribatid mite specimens, belonging to 67 different species, were extracted from soil samples. Significant differences in species diversity, abundance and Berger-Parker index of dominance were found among the different vegetation types throughout the sampling period, and non-metric multidimensional scaling (n-MDS) ordination confirmed a clear separation between the three coenoses, showing how oribatid assemblages are significantly affected by habitat evolution. The faunistic knowledge of the oribatid mites of Sardinia is rather poor, the present research represents one of the first contributions for the main Sardinian island. Besides a majority of eurytopic and widespread species representing the main part of the edaphic communities in Mediterranean landscapes, some rare and characteristic species are recorded. They are remnants of the original populations of Sardinia and the western part of the Italian peninsula, resulting from the complex tectonic events that formed the western Mediterranean basin. Among these, &lt;i&gt;Belorchestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gebennicus&lt;/i&gt; Grandjean, 1957 (Zetorchestidae), &lt;i&gt;Microppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longisetosa&lt;/i&gt; Subías &amp; Rodriguez, 1988, and &lt;i&gt;Pluritrichoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insolita&lt;/i&gt; Subías &amp; Arillo, 1989 (Oppiidae) had never been collected in Italy, single individuals of &lt;i&gt;Oxyoppioides&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Thamnacarus&lt;/i&gt; probably belong to undescribed species, while &lt;i&gt;Brachychthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirtus&lt;/i&gt; Moritz, 1976 (Brachychthoniidae), &lt;i&gt;Mongaillardia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aeoliana&lt;/i&gt; (Bernini, 1979) (Amerobelbidae), &lt;i&gt;Berniniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aeoliana&lt;/i&gt; (Bernini, 1973), &lt;i&gt;Lauroppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similifallax&lt;/i&gt; Subías &amp; Minguez, 1986, &lt;i&gt;Ramusella&lt;/i&gt; (Ramusella) &lt;i&gt;gyrata&lt;/i&gt; (Mahunka &amp; Paoletti, 1984) (Oppiidae) and &lt;i&gt;Ophidiotrichus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oglasae&lt;/i&gt; Bernini, 1975 (Oribatellidae) are new to the Sardinian fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oribatidae; soil fauna; faunistics; biogeography; population dynamics; Italy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oribatidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Massimo</firstname>
          <lastname>Migliorini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>8-37</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of terrestrial isopods (Isopoda: Oniscidea) from Sardinia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of terrestrial isopods from Sardinia are described: &lt;i&gt;Alpioniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thanit&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Trichoniscidae), &lt;i&gt;Halophiloscia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristagalli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Halophilosciidae), &lt;i&gt;Alloschizidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maymon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alloschizidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magrinii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Armadillidiidae). &lt;i&gt;Alpioniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thanit&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alloschizidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magrinii&lt;/i&gt; were collected in endogean environments, &lt;i&gt;Halophiloscia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristagalli&lt;/i&gt; on granitic beaches of small islands in the northern and western part of Sardinia, and &lt;i&gt;Alloschizidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maymon&lt;/i&gt; from a cave. The diagnostic features and the affinities of the new species are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Oniscidea; Trichoniscidae; Halophilosciidae; Armadillidiidae; new species; Italy; Sardinia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stefano</firstname>
          <lastname>Taiti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Argano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-55</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An annotated catalogue of the epigeic and cave centipedes (Chilopoda) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Published and unpublished data on the epigeic and cave centipedes of Sardinia (Italy) are summarized and critically revised in this paper. Fifty-four species are listed and discussed (1 Scutigeromorpha, 19 Lithobiomorpha, 6 Scolopendromorpha, 28 Geophilomorpha), two of which new to the island: &lt;i&gt;Lamyctes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emarginatus&lt;/i&gt; (Newport, 1844) and &lt;i&gt;Schendyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt; (Attems, 1895). Thirty-one species have been recorded in caves (1 Scutigeromorpha, 14 Lithobiomorpha, 6 Scolopendromorpha, 10 Geophilomorpha) – including the poorly known &lt;i&gt;Plutonium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zwierleini&lt;/i&gt; Cavanna, 1881 – six of which exclusive of this habitat (5 &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; spp., 1 &lt;i&gt;Cryptops&lt;/i&gt; sp.). Five species are introduced or probably introduced. General geographic distribution, chorotype, Sardinian localities and ecological notes (altitudinal ranges, habitats) are given for each species. Taxonomic notes are given for some species. &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turritanus&lt;/i&gt; Fanzago, 1881 and &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;molophai&lt;/i&gt; Restivo De Miranda, 1978, previously considered synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tricuspis&lt;/i&gt; Meinert, 1872 and &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerii&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1943, respectively, are recognized as valid species, &lt;b&gt;status&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;rev.&lt;/b&gt; The new synonymies &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domusnovae&lt;/i&gt; Restivo De Miranda, 1976 = &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lapidicola&lt;/i&gt; Meinert, 1872 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligoporus&lt;/i&gt; Latzel, 1884 = &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turritanus&lt;/i&gt; Fanzago, 1881 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fraleliae&lt;/i&gt; De Miranda Restivo, 1978 = &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turritanus&lt;/i&gt; Fanzago, 1881 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are proposed. &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turritanei&lt;/i&gt; Restivo De Miranda &lt;i&gt;i.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; in Cassola, 1982 is recognized as &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudum.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cryptops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;breviunguis&lt;/i&gt; A. Costa, 1882 is proposed as &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda&lt;/i&gt; and its identity with &lt;i&gt;Cryptops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anomalans&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844 is rejected. &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;molophai&lt;/i&gt; Restivo De Miranda, 1978 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; Silvestri, 1898 are redescribed on type or topotypical material. A lectotype for &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; Silvestri, 1898 is also designated. &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardus&lt;/i&gt; Manfredi, 1956 &lt;b&gt;status&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; formerly a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agilis&lt;/i&gt; C. L. Koch, 1847, is raised to species level; its probable affinity with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turritanus&lt;/i&gt; Fanzago, 1881 is also discussed. &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infossus&lt;/i&gt;Silvestri, 1894 (= &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahlii&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1925) is erased from the centipede fauna of Sardinia, and previous records should be referred to an unidentified species of &lt;i&gt;Lithobius&lt;/i&gt; or to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuragicus&lt;/i&gt; Zapparoli, 1997.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scutigeromorpha; Lithobiomorpha; Scolopendromorpha; Geophilomorpha; lectotype designation; new synonymies; taxonomy; distribution; catalogue; Sardinia.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scutigeromorpha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marzio</firstname>
          <lastname>Zapparoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-168</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An updated checklist of the ground beetles (Coleoptera: Carabidae) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An up-to-date checklist of the ground beetles of Sardinia and surrounding islets is presented. The presence on the island of 379 species is confirmed, while 41 are here considered of doubtful occurrence. All endemic elements are indicated and concise information is given on the Italian distribution of each species, together with the chorotype of recurrent pattern of main distribution.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Carabidae; checklist; distribution; chorotypes; endemics; Sardinia; Italian fauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Carabidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Augusto</firstname>
          <middlename>Vigna</middlename>
          <lastname>Taglianti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>169-196</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An updated catalogue of the Histeridae (Coleoptera) of Sardinia, with faunistic, zoogeographical, ecological and conservation remarks</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An updated geographical catalogue of the histerid fauna of Sardinia is given, compiling data from 74 public and private collections and records from 115 works (papers and monographs) published during the last two centuries. Seventy-four species are listed, reporting, for each one of them, collecting data (locality, date, collector/s, etc.), chorotype, Italian distribution, notes on ecology of the adults and possible additional comments. Forty-three species known from previous literature records but not included in the catalogue are listed, and the reasons for their exclusion are explained. The paper is completed by faunistic, zoogeographical, ecological and conservation remarks. The number of Sardinian species listed in the present catalogue (74) is equal to 44.8% of the known Italian fauna (165), but it is much lower than the total number of taxa reported from Sardinia in the literature (117). Of these species, only 32 have been reported by all considered works, and the oldest list and the present one share only 35 species. There are several reasons for these differences: many taxa have been excluded because they were based on misidentifications, others because they were not present in any of the examined collections; on the other hand, a few species have been added during the last 60 years, because described as new or found for the first time in Sardinia. From 1980 to the present day, the number of recorded species seems to be almost unchanged (76 in 1980, 77 in 2005 and 74 today), despite the various exclusions and additions. This may signify that the histerid fauna of Sardinia is almost completely known and that few new findings can be expected in the future. Nevertheless, 10 taxa, corresponding to 13.6% of the total, are known from a single record, specifically: &lt;i&gt;Tribalus&lt;/i&gt; (Tribalus) &lt;i&gt;minimus&lt;/i&gt; (P. Rossi), &lt;i&gt;Platysoma&lt;/i&gt; (Cylister) &lt;i&gt;elongatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatum&lt;/i&gt; (Thunberg), &lt;i&gt;Hister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicolor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicolor&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, &lt;i&gt;Merohister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ariasi&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul), &lt;i&gt;Atholus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paganettii&lt;/i&gt; (Bickhardt), &lt;i&gt;Paromalus&lt;/i&gt; (Paromalus) &lt;i&gt;filum&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, &lt;i&gt;Gnathoncus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;communis&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul), &lt;i&gt;Gnathoncus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nannetensis&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul), &lt;i&gt;Saprinus&lt;/i&gt; (Microsaprinus) &lt;i&gt;gomyi&lt;/i&gt; Secq &amp; Secq and &lt;i&gt;Exaesiopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grossipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grossipes&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul). Future research on the histerid beetles in Sardinia should focus on these species and on those no longer recovered in the last two decades. Moreover, of the 74 listed species, one—Hypocacculus (Nessus) &lt;i&gt;puncticollis&lt;/i&gt; (Küster)—was described based on Sardinian and Spanish specimens and 7—Hister &lt;i&gt;pustulosus&lt;/i&gt; Gené, &lt;i&gt;Atholus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;debeauxi&lt;/i&gt; (Moro), &lt;i&gt;Sardulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incrassatus&lt;/i&gt; Magrini &amp; Fancello, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacerensis&lt;/i&gt; Casale &amp; Marcia, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeus&lt;/i&gt; Patrizi, &lt;i&gt;Gnathoncus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerberus&lt;/i&gt; Auzat and &lt;i&gt;Hypocacculus&lt;/i&gt; (Hypocacculus) &lt;i&gt;metallescens&lt;/i&gt; (Erichson) – on Sardinian specimens, the first five being endemic or subendemic. The historical record of &lt;i&gt;Phelister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haemorrhous&lt;/i&gt; Marseul by Baudi di Selve is proved to be erroneous, and two specimens of an unidentified Neotropical &lt;i&gt;Epierus&lt;/i&gt; Erichson are still housed under this name in his collection. &lt;i&gt;Phelister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haemorrhous&lt;/i&gt; has, in fact, never been collected in Sardinia, and the provenance (“Sardinia”) of the two &lt;i&gt;Epierus&lt;/i&gt; specimens is surely erroneous. The “not Sardinian endemic” status of &lt;i&gt;Gnathoncus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerberus&lt;/i&gt; is confirmed, and new records from “Grotta di Frasassi” (Italy, Marches, Ancona) are given. The chorological analysis shows that a large part of the species (48 = 64.9%) belongs to two groups: those widespread in the Holarctic region (31 = 41.9%) and those more or less widespread in the Mediterranean basin (17 = 23.0%). However, the most striking datum is the relatively high number of endemic and subendemic species (5 = 6.8%), represented by &lt;i&gt;Hister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pustulosus&lt;/i&gt; (present also in Sicily and Corsica), &lt;i&gt;Atholus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;debeauxi&lt;/i&gt; (present also in Corsica), and &lt;i&gt;Sardulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incrassatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacerensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeus&lt;/i&gt; (present only in Sardinia). However, when the analysis is carried out on the 22 most common and widespread taxa (based on the data reported in the catalogue), the number of “Mediterranean” species [i.e. those more or less widespread in the Mediterranean basin plus &lt;i&gt;Saprinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chalcites&lt;/i&gt; (Illiger) and &lt;i&gt;Hister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pustulosus]&lt;/i&gt; is equal to the number of species widespread in the Holarctic region (9); this shows that the “Mediterranean” component of the Sardinian histerid fauna is stronger than suggested by the overall chorological analysis. The analysis of the morpho-ecological groups shows that 37 species are saprophiles (50.0%), 12 psammophiles (16.2%), 10 dendrophiles (13.5%), 4 pholeophiles (5.4%), 3 endogeans (4.1%), and 1 myrmecophile (1.3%); the remaining 7 species are the so-called “micro-histerids” (9.5%). The analysis of the dates for the last capture of each species shows that 55 species, i.e. 74.3% of the total, were last collected between 1990 and 2008. Probably, these species represent the extant and certain Sardinian histerid fauna; a number of them are rare, such as &lt;i&gt;Saprinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;godet&lt;/i&gt; (Brullé), &lt;i&gt;Atholus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;debeauxi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Merohister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ariasi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hister&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helluo&lt;/i&gt; Truqui, &lt;i&gt;Teretrius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabricii&lt;/i&gt; Mazur, &lt;i&gt;Hypocaccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pelleti&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul), etc. Moreover, the analysis shows that 6 psammophilous species, from a total of 12, were last collected between 1973 and 1987; this loss of biodiversity could be real, caused by the destruction of sandy coastal habitats following an increase in tourism in those years, or apparent, due simply to their extreme rarity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Histeridae; Sardinia; catalogue; biogeography; ecology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <lastname>Penati</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>197-280</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hydraena &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera: Hydraenidae) of the &lt;i&gt;H. evanescens &lt;/i&gt;complex from Sardinia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A morphological analysis was performed in order to clarify the taxonomic scenario within the &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evanescens&lt;/i&gt; complex (Coleoptera: Hydraenidae: Hydraeninae), including species associated with fast running waters in mountain areas of Corsica and Sardinia. The analysis was mainly focused on the specific distinction and formal description of a new species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosannae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Sulcis-Iglesiente region (SW Sardinia), morphologically distinctly separated from both the nearly parapatric &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tyrrhena&lt;/i&gt; Binaghi, 1961 (central and northern Sardinia) and the allopatric &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evanescens&lt;/i&gt; Rey, 1884 (Corsica). Two hypothetical palaeogeographical scenarios explaining the specific differentiation of the three species are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Moss beetles; &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Haenydra&lt;/i&gt; lineage; new species; Corso-Sardinia; palaeogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Moss beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paolo</firstname>
          <lastname>Audisio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessio</firstname>
          <lastname>De Biase</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <lastname>Trizzino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Emiliano</firstname>
          <lastname>Mancini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gloria</firstname>
          <lastname>Antonini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>281-289</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Cholevidae (Coleoptera) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We present a synthesis of the knowledge on the cholevid fauna of Sardinia, with an annotated checklist and an updated list of both published and unpublished collecting localities. The Cholevidae (Coleoptera, Staphylinoidea) are a group of small to medium-sized beetles, most of which are saprophagous; a significant percentage of Cholevidae are cave-dwellers, and some are highly specialized troglobitic elements. In Sardinia, twenty-five species have been recorded so far. More than half of them are endemic to the island, while some are sub-endemic (i.e. present also in Corsica or in Sicily and/or the Balearic Islands); nine species, belonging to the genera &lt;i&gt;Ovobathysciola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Patriziella,&lt;/i&gt; are specialized hypogean elements. Four more species, belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Bathysciola,&lt;/i&gt; are soil-inhabiting or cave-dwellers. The authors stress the high biogeographic and biospeleological interest of Sardinian cholevids. In particular, the colonization processes appear to be in good agreement with the current hypotheses about the origin and composition of the existing fauna of Sardinia. The hypogean species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Ovobathysciola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Patriziella&lt;/i&gt; and species of &lt;i&gt;Speonomus&lt;/i&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Batinoscelis&lt;/i&gt; are currently accepted as being related to the Baetic and Pyrenean lineages of &lt;i&gt;Anillochlamys&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Speonomus,&lt;/i&gt; respectively; therefore, they should belong to the most ancient stock of elements, originated during the Miocene drift of the Corso-Sardinian massif in the western Mediterranean. Some other endemic or sub-endemic taxa, with W-Mediterranean affinities, are probably derived from more recent colonizers as a consequence of the several connection/isolation phases which existed between Sardinia, Corsica, and other Mediterranean areas during the late Miocene (Messinian) salinity crisis, and during the Plio-Pleistocene ice-phase-related strong variations in the sea level. Finally, some widespread taxa, all epigean and winged, reached the island in more recent times, through active and passive dispersal.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Cholevidae; Sardinia; research history; taxonomy; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Achille</firstname>
          <lastname>Casale</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
          <lastname>Grafitti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leonardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Latella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>290-316</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The endogean beetle fauna of the Marganai-Oridda-Valle del Leni area (SW Sardinia), with description of seven new species of Staphylinidae Leptotyphlinae (Coleoptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty-six species of endogean beetles are recorded from the Marganai-Oridda-Valle del Leni area, belonging to six different families: Carabidae (Typhloreicheia &lt;i&gt;holdhausi&lt;/i&gt; Magrini, Fancello &amp; Casale, 2006, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilosa&lt;/i&gt; Magrini &amp; Fancello, 2007, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tanit&lt;/i&gt; Leo, Magrini &amp; Fancello, 2005), Leiodidae [Bathysciola &lt;i&gt;damryi&lt;/i&gt; (Abeille de Perrin, 1881)], Staphylinidae [Eudesis &lt;i&gt;aglena&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1882, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minima&lt;/i&gt; Binaghi, 1948, &lt;i&gt;Mayetia&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Trimium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amplipenne&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1908, &lt;i&gt;Tychobythinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentimanus&lt;/i&gt; (Reitter, 1884), &lt;i&gt;Tychus&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Pselaphostomus&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Phloeocharis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ichnusae&lt;/i&gt; Dodero, 1900, &lt;i&gt;Octavius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raymondi&lt;/i&gt; Saulcy, 1878, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; Coiffait, 1965, four new species of &lt;i&gt;Entomoculia,&lt;/i&gt; three new species of &lt;i&gt;Leptotyphlus],&lt;/i&gt; Zopheridae (Langelandia &lt;i&gt;reitteri&lt;/i&gt; Belon, 1882, &lt;i&gt;Lyreus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;septemstriatus&lt;/i&gt; Fancello &amp; Leo, 1991), Curculionidae (Torneuma sp.) and Raymondionymidae [Alaocyba &lt;i&gt;carinulata&lt;/i&gt; Perris, 1869, &lt;i&gt;Raymondiellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; (Perris, 1869)]. One species (Langelandia &lt;i&gt;reitteri)&lt;/i&gt; is W-Mediterranan, one is a Sardo-Corsican endemic (Tychobythinus &lt;i&gt;dentimanus),&lt;/i&gt; the remaining 24 species are all Sardinian endemics and 16 of these are strictly localized within the study area or restricted to SW Sardinia. The following species of Staphylinidae Leptotyphlinae are described: &lt;i&gt;Entomoculia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villascemae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carbonaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shardana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melonii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leptotyphlus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nardii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minator&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villacidrinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; all are easily distinguishable from their congeners by the structure of the male copulatory organ and female genital armature. The morphology of the copulatory organ in the newly described &lt;i&gt;Leptotyphlus&lt;/i&gt; species indicates that the classical subgeneric categories used in &lt;i&gt;Leptotyphlus&lt;/i&gt; are probably based on characters not reflecting a natural subdivision of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; endogean beetles; Carabidae; Leiodidae; Staphylinidae; Zopheridae; Curculionidae; Raymondionymidae; new species; &lt;i&gt;Entomoculia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leptotyphlus&lt;/i&gt;; SW Sardinia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luca</firstname>
          <lastname>Fancello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carles</firstname>
          <lastname>Hernando</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Piero</firstname>
          <lastname>Leo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>317-338</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Dasytidae (Coleoptera) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The study of over 10,000 specimens of Dasytidae from about 35 collections has led to the conclusion that 8 genera and 32 species and subspecies of this family, all actually observed by the author, occur in Sardinia. This number is believed to be rather close to completion. A further 30 species, reported in the past as occurring on the island, are discussed and have been removed from the list. Identification keys based on external characters only are proposed for genera and species. However, for difficult groups and where confusion may arise, drawings of aedeagi are supplied. An annoted cataloguefollows with, for each species, synonymies, bibliography, a list of sampling localities with last year of collection, notes, and chorotype. A zoogeographical analysis shows that the Sardinian Dasytidae conform to a Central Mediterranean type, with rather strong North African influences and with a high presence of strict endemics (11 species), higher than in Corsica (7 species). &lt;i&gt;Danacea&lt;/i&gt; (Allodanacaea) is no doubt the most interesting group with 7 taxa, none of which are spread all over Sardinia and 2 of which—D. (A.) &lt;i&gt;gorditana&lt;/i&gt; Liberti and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;nympha&lt;/i&gt; Liberti—only occur in a tiny area in the Nurra region. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Dasytes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doderoi&lt;/i&gt; Pic and &lt;i&gt;Aplocnemus&lt;/i&gt; (Diplambe) &lt;i&gt;januaventi&lt;/i&gt; Liberti, both strict Sardinian endemics, are very rare and poorly known: the first is only known on two female specimens, both collected in the Gennargentu area many years ago; the second seems in a “safer” situation because several specimens have been collected recently. Trap samples (mainly Malaise) from the Marganai and Montimannu region-owned forests (SW Sardinia, respectively Carbonia-Iglesias and Medio Campidano provinces), are also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Melyridae; Prionoceridae; Acanthocnemidae; &lt;i&gt;Dasytes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Danacea&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aplocnemus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Psilothrix&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dolichosoma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Divales&lt;/i&gt;; Italy; Corsica; Tyrrhenian; identification keys</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Melyridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gianfranco</firstname>
          <lastname>Liberti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>339-385</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Meligethes &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera: Nitidulidae: Meligethinae) of the &lt;i&gt;M. lugubris &lt;/i&gt;complex from Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A combined morphological and bionomical analysis was performed to clarify the position of a problematic species of the &lt;i&gt;Meligethes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lugubris&lt;/i&gt; group from Sardinia and Corsica (Coleoptera, Nitidulidae, Meligethinae). This species-group is represented by a dozen anthophagous species associated with Lamiaceae, and distributed from North Africa to Japan. The analysis was mainly focused on the specific distinction and formal description of a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foddaii&lt;/i&gt; Audisio, De Biase &amp; Trizzino &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Sardinia and Corsica. The species is morphologically scarcely distinguishable from the allopatric &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lugubris&lt;/i&gt; Sturm and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gagathinus&lt;/i&gt; Erichson (both widespread in southern Europe). An identification key to Euro-Mediterranean members of the &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lugubris&lt;/i&gt; complex is provided. Combined morphological, ecological, phenological, and preliminary molecular data are presented to support the distinction of the new species. The palaeogeographical scenario explaining the likely Plio-Pleistocene differentiation of the three species, which are all associated with the related Lamiaceae genera &lt;i&gt;Mentha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Thymus,&lt;/i&gt; is also briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pollen beetles; &lt;i&gt;Meligethes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Corso-Sardinia; palaeogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pollen beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paolo</firstname>
          <lastname>Audisio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessio</firstname>
          <lastname>De Biase</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <lastname>Trizzino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Emiliano</firstname>
          <lastname>Mancini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gloria</firstname>
          <lastname>Antonini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>386-393</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on some Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) from the Mediterranean Region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scymnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incisus&lt;/i&gt; H. Lindberg, 1931 &lt;b&gt;resurrected&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;name&lt;/b&gt; is a valid species, not a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Nephus&lt;/i&gt; (Nephus) &lt;i&gt;peyerimhoffi&lt;/i&gt; (Sicard, 1923). &lt;i&gt;Nephus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bucciarellii&lt;/i&gt; Canepari &amp; Tedeschi, 1977 is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; (N.) &lt;i&gt;ulbrichi&lt;/i&gt; Fürsch, 1977 and synonymized with &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; (N.) &lt;i&gt;schatzmayri&lt;/i&gt; Canepari &amp; Tedeschi, 1977 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hyperaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inexpectata&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1959 &lt;b&gt;resurrected&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;name&lt;/b&gt; is a valid species, not a synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concolor&lt;/i&gt; Suffrian, 1843. Four species are newly recorded from Sardinia: &lt;i&gt;Diomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubidus&lt;/i&gt; (Motshulsky, 1837), &lt;i&gt;Scymnus&lt;/i&gt; (Scymnus) &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; (Gyllenhal, 1827), &lt;i&gt;Hyperaspis&lt;/i&gt; (Hyperaspis) &lt;i&gt;duvergeri&lt;/i&gt; Fürsch, 1985 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (H.) &lt;i&gt;inexpectata&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1959.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Coccinellidae; Sardinia; Spain; Canary Islands; new synonyms; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Canepari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>394-399</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Observations on some Tenebrionidae (Coleoptera) from Sardinia, with description of three new &lt;i&gt;Asida&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new taxa, endemic of Sardinia, are described in the genus &lt;i&gt;Asida&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1802: &lt;i&gt;Asida&lt;/i&gt; (Asida) &lt;i&gt;dryas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Capoterra, Gutturu Mannu), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Asida) &lt;i&gt;anachoreta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Gonnosfanadiga, Punta Cammedda), and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Asida) &lt;i&gt;solieri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caroli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;ssp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Morgongiori, Is Benas). Additional systematic, distributional and ecological data are provided for some Tenebrionidae occurring in Sardinia. The following synonymy is established: &lt;i&gt;Stenosis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticollis&lt;/i&gt; (Reiche, 1861) = &lt;i&gt;Stenosis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticollis&lt;/i&gt; ssp. &lt;i&gt;elongatissima&lt;/i&gt; Koch, 1940 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tentyria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; Gené, 1836 is reinstated as a valid species, well differentiated from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramburi&lt;/i&gt; Solier, 1835. Furthermore, &lt;i&gt;Tentyria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; is split into three subspecies: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; ssp. &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; Gené, 1836, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; ssp. &lt;i&gt;floresii&lt;/i&gt; Gené, 1836 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosa&lt;/i&gt; ssp. &lt;i&gt;cassolai&lt;/i&gt; Ardoin, 1973. The latter is transferred from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramburi.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramburi&lt;/i&gt; is transferred from the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Tentyria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;str.&lt;/i&gt; to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Subtentyrina.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Tenebrionidae; &lt;i&gt;Asida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Stenosis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tentyria&lt;/i&gt;; nomenclature; new taxa; new synonymy; new records; Sardinia; Italy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Piero</firstname>
          <lastname>Leo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>400-420</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on some Curculionoidea (Coleoptera: Anthribidae, Apionidae, Curculionidae) from Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Torneuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curtulum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vastum&lt;/i&gt; Stüben, 2007 (Curculionidae) is raised to species level (stat. &lt;b&gt;rev.).&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Choragus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurolineatus&lt;/i&gt; Abeille de Perrin, 1893, &lt;i&gt;Melanopsacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grenieri&lt;/i&gt; (C. Brisout, 1867) (Anthribidae), &lt;i&gt;Hemitrichapion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavidum&lt;/i&gt; (Germar, 1817), &lt;i&gt;Holotrichapion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbirostre&lt;/i&gt; (Hoffmann, 1952) (Apionidae), &lt;i&gt;Ceutorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;resedae&lt;/i&gt; (Marsham, 1802), &lt;i&gt;Tychius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cupriferoides&lt;/i&gt; (Ragusa, 1922) and &lt;i&gt;Orchestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythropus&lt;/i&gt; (Germar, 1821) (Curculionidae) are newly recorded from Sardinia. &lt;i&gt;Melanopsacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grenieri&lt;/i&gt; is newly recorded from Sicily, and its association with the pyrenomycete fungus &lt;i&gt;Hypoxylon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediterraneum&lt;/i&gt; is newly reported.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Apionidae; Anthribidae; Curculionidae; Sardinia; Sicily; faunistics; &lt;i&gt;Torneuma&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Apionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Enzo</firstname>
          <lastname>Colonnelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
          <lastname>Osella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>421-426</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Bibionidae (Diptera) of Sardinia, with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The occurrence of eight species of Bibionidae is reported from Sardinia, mainly based upon recent collections made in the south-western part of the island. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Dilophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bispinosus&lt;/i&gt; Lundström, 1913 and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humeralis&lt;/i&gt; Zetterstedt, 1850, are new records for Sardinia, while two species are described as new to science: &lt;i&gt;Bibio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardocyrneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (from Sardinia and Corsica) and &lt;i&gt;Dilophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (from Sardinia). The presence on the island of a ninth species, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoratus&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen, 1804), is considered as dubious. Finally, the following synonymy is proposed: &lt;i&gt;Bibio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hortulanus&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1758) = &lt;i&gt;Bibio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siculus&lt;/i&gt; Loew, 1846 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;rev.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Bibionidae; Italy; Sardinia; Corsica; faunistics; new species; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Haenni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>427-439</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Scatopsidae (Diptera) of Sardinia, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eleven species of the family Scatopsidae are reported from Sardinia, 10 of which for the first time, from collections made in the Marganai area (Carbonia-Iglesias province) and some additional material. &lt;i&gt;Swammerdamella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinigera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; closely related to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pediculata&lt;/i&gt; (Duda, 1928), is described and figured. The state of knowledge of the Sardinian fauna and its affinities are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Scatopsidae; Italy; Sardinia; faunistics; new species; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Haenni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>440-449</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The fungus gnats (Diptera: Bolitophilidae, Keroplatidae, Mycetophilidae) of Sardinia, with description of six new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The fungus gnat fauna of Sardinia is reviewed and data presented for all species recorded. Altogether one species of Bolitophilidae, 16 species of Keroplatidae and 105 species of Mycetophilidae are recognised as occurring in Sardinia. As the bolitophilid and two of the mycetophilid species are represented only by females and are not determined to species level, the total confirmed Sardinian list stands at 119 species. Four species of Keroplatidae and 19 species of Mycetophilidae are new to the total Italian fauna, whereas three species of Keroplatidae and 32 species of Mycetophilidae are newly recorded for the island of Sardinia. Six species are described as new to science: two Keroplatidae (Urytalpa &lt;i&gt;juliae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Macrocera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuragica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and four Mycetophilidae (Boletina &lt;i&gt;ichnusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Trichonta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sandalyon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sciophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;benjaminbottomi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sciophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;immodesta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; The new synonymy &lt;i&gt;Zygomyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valida&lt;/i&gt; Winnertz, 1863 = &lt;i&gt;Zygomyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; Strobl, 1895 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is established. &lt;i&gt;Macrocera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicillata&lt;/i&gt; Costa, 1857 is tentatively considered as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phalerata&lt;/i&gt; Meigen, 1818. Label data are provided for 5 and 17 species recorded without further detail in the Fauna Europaea online database, respectively from Italian mainland and Sicily; one species, &lt;i&gt;Mycetophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alea&lt;/i&gt; Laffoon, 1965 is newly recorded for Sicily. Three species based onunconfirmed 19 th century records cited by Hellrigl from South Tyrol should be deleted from the Italian list: &lt;i&gt;Exechiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indecisa&lt;/i&gt; (Walker, 1856), &lt;i&gt;Mycetophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;signata&lt;/i&gt; Meigen, 1830 and &lt;i&gt;Mycomya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;storai&lt;/i&gt; Väisänen, 1979.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bolitophilidae; distribution; fungus gnats; Italy (mainland); Keroplatidae; Mycetophilidae; new records; new species; Sardinia; Sicily; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bolitophilidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chandler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>450-506</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the soldier flies (Diptera: Stratiomyidae) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">All published records on Stratiomyidae from Sardinia were critically evaluated and extensive, recently collected material (more than 500 specimens) was identified. The present review of the soldier flies from Sardinia includes 27 species. &lt;i&gt;Nemotelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niloticus&lt;/i&gt; Olivier, 1811 is newly recorded from Europe and Italy, and &lt;i&gt;Lasiopa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudovillosa&lt;/i&gt; Rozkošný, 1983 and &lt;i&gt;Zabrachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenella&lt;/i&gt; (Jaennicke, 1866) are newly recorded from Sardinia. &lt;i&gt;Nemotelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachystomus&lt;/i&gt; Loew, 1846 and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; Costa, 1884 are proposed as new synonyms of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notatus&lt;/i&gt; Zetterstedt, 1842. &lt;i&gt;Beris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hyaliniventris&lt;/i&gt; Costa, 1857, the types of which could not be found, is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Chorisops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibialis&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen, 1820) and declared as species &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis.&lt;/i&gt; Brief comments are made on the zoogeography of Sardinian soldier flies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Stratiomyidae; Sardinia; new synonyms; new records; faunistics; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Franco</firstname>
          <lastname>Mason</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudolf</firstname>
          <lastname>RozkoNý</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Hauser</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>507-530</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics of the Euro-Mediterranean &lt;i&gt;Empis &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Kritempis&lt;/i&gt;) (Diptera: Empididae: Empidinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Euro-Mediterranean subgenus &lt;i&gt;Kritempis&lt;/i&gt; Collin of &lt;i&gt;Empis&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus is here redefined on the basis of three synapomorphies, namely (1) hypandrium reduced to its lateral arms, (2) presence of a posteroventral group of spine-like setae on the female mid tibia at base, (3) anal vein faint, incomplete. This subgenus includes eight species: &lt;i&gt;Empis&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;algira&lt;/i&gt; Macquart, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;livida&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;macquarti&lt;/i&gt; Becker, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;macropalpa&lt;/i&gt; Egger, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;nigrimana&lt;/i&gt; Becker, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;sardoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;sibillina&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;taffertensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A detailed diagnosis of the group as well as a key to all known species is provided. All species are described or redescribed, exclusive of the well-known &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;livida.&lt;/i&gt; The holotype of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;algira&lt;/i&gt; is identified and a lectotype designated for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;macquarti,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(K.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macropalpa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;sibillina.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Empis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoffmannseggii&lt;/i&gt; Loew is moved from the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Kritempis&lt;/i&gt; to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Coptophlebia&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi. The subgenus is restricted to the Mediterranean basin exclusive of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (K.) &lt;i&gt;livida&lt;/i&gt; which is widely distributed in Europe and Algeria where the species is newly recorded.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; Diptera; Empididae; Empidinae; &lt;i&gt;Empis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Kritempis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; monophyly; EuroMediterranean distribution; Sardinia; Morocco</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christophe</firstname>
          <lastname>Daugeron</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>531-544</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of Chloropidae (Diptera) from southern Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During a recent survey of arthropod diversity in several localities of southern Sardinia, three new species of Chloropidae (Diptera) were discovered: &lt;i&gt;Aphanotrigonum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lanceolatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dicraeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardous&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The first is close to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hastatum&lt;/i&gt; Dely-Draskovits from Afghanistan; the second is placed in subgenus &lt;i&gt;Oedesiella&lt;/i&gt; Becker; the third is compared to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornuta&lt;/i&gt; (Fallén, 1820) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufifrons&lt;/i&gt; Duda, 1932.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chloropidae; Italy; Sardinia; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emilia</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nartshuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>545-551</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and re-definition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Melanophora &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Rhinophoridae), with description of a new species from Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A cladistic analysis of the genus &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; Meigen, 1803 (type-species: &lt;i&gt;Musca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grossificationis&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 [= &lt;i&gt;Musca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roralis&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758]) is presented and the generic delimitation is critically redefined. The nominal genusgroup taxon &lt;i&gt;Bequaertiana&lt;/i&gt; Curran, 1929 (type-species: &lt;i&gt;Bequaertiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argyriventris&lt;/i&gt; Curran, 1929) is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; Meigen &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The following new combinations are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argyriventris&lt;/i&gt; (Curran, 1929) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;basilewskyi&lt;/i&gt; (Peris, 1957) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from SW Sardinia is described, illustrated and compared with the other known species of the genus. The male of &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asetosa&lt;/i&gt; Kugler, 1978 is described for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;basilewskyi&lt;/i&gt; (Peris, 1957) is recorded from Kenya for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bequaertiana&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny; systematics; Sardinia; new species; new combinations</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Melanophora&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pierfilippo</firstname>
          <lastname>Cerretti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Pape</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>552-565</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Heteronychia&lt;/i&gt;) (Diptera: Sarcophagidae) of Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An account is given of the species of &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; Meigen, 1826 subgenus &lt;i&gt;Heteronychia&lt;/i&gt; Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 known from the island of Sardinia (Italy). Most of the nearly 1,400 specimens examined were collected in the SW part of the island during 2003–2006 as part of a project investigating the arthropod diversity of the Monti Marganai and Montimannu areas (respectively Carbonia-Iglesias and Medio Campidano provinces). The study resulted in the finding of eight species of &lt;i&gt;Heteronychia,&lt;/i&gt; six of which are recorded from Sardinia for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) &lt;i&gt;penicillata&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve, 1907, previously mentioned in the literature, is excluded from the fauna of the island. &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) &lt;i&gt;thirionae&lt;/i&gt; (Lehrer, 1976) is recorded for the first time from Europe and North Africa (Algeria). One species, &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) &lt;i&gt;gabrielei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from various sites in the limestone massif of Marganai, is described as new. Previously unpublished records from other Italian regions and from other countries (Algeria, Canary Islands, Greece) are also given for several species. &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) &lt;i&gt;schnabli&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve, 1911 is recognized as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (H.) &lt;i&gt;consanguinea&lt;/i&gt; Rondani, 1860 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The possible synanthropy of &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) &lt;i&gt;pandellei&lt;/i&gt; (Rohdendorf, 1937) is briefly discussed. A key to males and females of all known Sardinian and Corsican species of &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; (Heteronychia) is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Heteronychia&lt;/i&gt;; Sardinia; Corsica; new species; new synonymy; new records; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Whitmore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>566-588</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichrysis baratzsensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Hymenoptera: Chrysididae) from Sardinia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichrysis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baratzsensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Lago Baratz (Sassari province, Sardinia), is described and compared with all other Palaearctic congeners. A key for the identification of Mediterranean &lt;i&gt;Trichrysis&lt;/i&gt; species is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hymenoptera; Chrysididae; new species; Sardinia; identification key; type material</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hymenoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Franco</firstname>
          <lastname>Strumia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>589-595</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Index </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pierfilippo</firstname>
          <lastname>Cerretti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franco</firstname>
          <lastname>Mason</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Minelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gianluca</firstname>
          <lastname>Nardi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Whitmore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>596-602</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
