<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2011.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2011</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on the genus &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia &lt;/i&gt;Navás, 1907, with the descriptions of five new species from the Solomon Islands, a revised key to the species and notes on its geographic distribution (Phasmatodea: Anareolatae: Phasmatidae &lt;i&gt;s. l.&lt;/i&gt;: Stephanacridini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; Navás, 1907 (type-species: &lt;i&gt;Taeniosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanchezi&lt;/i&gt; Bolívar, 1897) is currently known only from the Philippine Islands and Taiwan, but here shown to extend eastwards as far as to the Solomon Islands, Northern New Guinea and even Fiji. A taxonomic review of the genus, and updated keys to the species are presented. The type-species of &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; Navás, 1907, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanchezi&lt;/i&gt; (Bolívar, 1897) from Luzon, Philippines is shown to have been misinterpreted by previous authors. This has resulted in the description of the here revealed junior synonym &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; Zompro &amp; Eusebio, 2000 (n. &lt;b&gt;syn.).&lt;/b&gt; A survey of the intraspecific variation of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanchezi&lt;/i&gt; (Bolívar, 1897) is provided along with illustrations of the holotype. &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australe&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1933) from the Solomon Islands is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;godeffroyi&lt;/i&gt; (Redtenbacher, 1908) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; from Micronesia and shown to be a distinct and valid species (rev. &lt;b&gt;stat.).&lt;/b&gt; Both species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Phasmotaenia&lt;/i&gt; Navás, 1907. Examination of the paratypes of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australe&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1933) has revealed these to represent two different species distinct from the holotype, one of which is described as new herein (P. &lt;i&gt;guentheri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.).&lt;/b&gt; The male of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australe&lt;/i&gt; is</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hennemann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oskar</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Epexochus &lt;/i&gt;Reitter, with description of three new species (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Lixinae: Cleonini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Epexochus&lt;/i&gt; Reitter is revised, its morphological characters are defined and the differences from the most closely related genera, &lt;i&gt;Leucochromus&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky and &lt;i&gt;Eurycleonus&lt;/i&gt; Bedel, are outlined. All the populations of &lt;i&gt;Epexochus&lt;/i&gt; from Kazakhstan and north-western China (Xinjiang) are referred to a single species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lehmanni&lt;/i&gt; (Ménétries). The status of &lt;i&gt;Exochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latus&lt;/i&gt; Chevrolat is discussed and its name is formally synonymised with &lt;i&gt;lehmanni.&lt;/i&gt; According to Art. 45.6.4.1 of the ICZN (1999), the name &lt;i&gt;lehmanni&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;consobrinus&lt;/i&gt; Faust, originally proposed for a colour variant and misidentified by Ter-Minasyan, is deemed to be subspecific and thus a synonym of &lt;i&gt;lehmanni.&lt;/i&gt; Three new species are described in the genus: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;korotyaevi&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. (type locality: southern Tajikistan, Shaar-tuz region), characterised by the pronotum curved towards the elytra and by slender, lanceolate scales; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;voriseki&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. (type locality: central Uzbekistan, Gazli), characterised by small size, only slightly convex elytra and long hair-like setae, and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mongolicus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. (type locality: western Mongolia, Kobdoskij Aimak), characterised by large size, convex elytra with flat intervals and an elongate lamella of the aedeagus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; weevils; morphological analysis; new species; central Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Massimo</firstname>
          <lastname>Meregalli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <lastname>Talamelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
