<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2227.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2227</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics of the &lt;i&gt;Carlia &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;fusca &lt;/i&gt;complex (Reptilia: Scincidae) from northern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Using a combination of mitochondrial and nuclear genetic markers, karyotypes and morphology, we examine the taxonomy of the Australo-papuan scincid lizard &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;‘fusca’&lt;/i&gt; complex in northern Australia, all of which had been assigned previously to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes,&lt;/i&gt; shows substantial variation in Y chromosome morphology between populations, indeed more than is seen between other species of &lt;i&gt;Carlia.&lt;/i&gt; Analyses of the molecular genetic data and morphology demonstrate that populations with different Y chromosomes are two different species and also lead to the recognition of a third species from the Torres Strait. We herein define each of these species, for which previously described names can be applied.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lizard; Scincidae; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; mitochondrial DNA; chromosome; allozyme; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lizard</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnellan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Couper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Saint</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wheaton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-31</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Freshwater leeches (Annelida: Clitellata: Hirudinida) of the Czech Republic (Central Europe): check-list, new records, and remarks on species distributions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Freshwater leeches (Annelida: Clitellata: Hirudinida) of the Czech Republic were studied on the basis of recent literature, information in selected databases, and results of recent surveys conducted by the authors. The objectives of this study were to summarize recent taxonomic information, and to update the check-list of leeches using records collected during an eleven-year study (1998 through 2008). Altogether, twenty-four species representing 12 genera and five families are reported for the Czech Republic, including the first reports of &lt;i&gt;Piscicola&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;haranti&lt;/i&gt; Jarry, 1960 and &lt;i&gt;Dina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctata&lt;/i&gt; Johansson, 1927 for the country. A detailed description of the distributions of rare species and characterization of localities from which they are reported are presented. Plausible modes of dispersal and propagation of species in Central Europe are discussed. According to recent records, leech species are divided into three groups: indigenous species with stable and strong populations (12 species), indigenous species with weak populations known from a limited number of localities (9 species), and species only recently recorded in the Czech Republic (3 species). For scarce or rare species, a category of threat in the Czech Republic according to the International Union for Conservation of Nature is recommended. Most of threatened species are inhabitants of lowland wetlands and lowland larger rivers—habitats that are negatively impacted, often catastrophically, by human activities throughout Central Europe. The protection of suitable habitats is the most effective way to protect extant populations of endangered leech species. Six species of leeches are recommended for permanent addition to the Red list of threatened species in the Czech Republic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Annelida; Clitellata; Hirudinida; leeches; Glossiphoniidae; Piscicolidae; Haemopidae; Hirudinidae; Erpobdellidae; Czech Republic; IUCN; Red List; habitat; distribution; &lt;i&gt;Piscicola&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;haranti&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctata&lt;/i&gt;; first record</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Annelida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jana</firstname>
          <lastname>Schenková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jan</firstname>
          <lastname>Sychra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimír</firstname>
          <lastname>KoEl</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nela</firstname>
          <lastname>Kubová</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jakub</firstname>
          <lastname>Horecký</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Teratohyla &lt;/i&gt;Taylor (Amphibia: Athesphatanura: Centrolenidae) from north-western Ecuador</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of Glassfrog of the family Centrolenidae. This new taxon, &lt;i&gt;Terarohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sornozai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is diagnosed by having a protruding snout in lateral profile, uniform green dorsal colouration in life, concealed prepollex, extensive webbing between the outer fingers, fully webbed toes, and small body size. It inhabits the Non-Seasonal Evergreen Foothill and Lowland forests in the provinces of Esmeraldas, Imbabura, and Pichincha, north-western Ecuador.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Centrolenidae; new species; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Teratohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sornozai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Ecuador</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Centrolenidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cisneros-Heredia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mario</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yánez-Muñoz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>Mauricio</middlename>
          <lastname>Ortegaandrade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new hermit crab (Decapoda: Anomura: Paguroidea: Paguridae) from the eastern North Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new intertidal species of the hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Pagurus,&lt;/i&gt; recently discovered on the Olympic Peninsula of Washington, is described and illustrated. This species, &lt;i&gt;Pagurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holmi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is compared and contrasted to other regional shallowwater species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Anomura; Paguroidea; Paguridae; &lt;i&gt;Pagurus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; North Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ngan</firstname>
          <middlename>Kee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patsy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclaughli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
