<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2243.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2243</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Vitzthumia&lt;/i&gt;: a taxonomic and nomenclatural conundrum of genera (Acari: Mesostigmata: Dermanyssina), with description of four species of &lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, 1911, of uncertain prior placement in the superfamilies Ascoidea or Dermanyssoidea, is redescribed, based on reexamination of type and other material of the type-species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;percicola&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, and of material representing &lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;livshitsi&lt;/i&gt; (Eidelberg) &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination&lt;/b&gt; and two new species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiduricola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kazemii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nataliae&lt;/i&gt; (Eidelberg) &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anystipalpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ukrainicus&lt;/i&gt; (Sklyar) &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination&lt;/b&gt; are determined to be junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;percicola&lt;/i&gt; Berlese and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;livshitsi&lt;/i&gt; (Eidelberg), respectively, &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonymies.&lt;/b&gt; The genus is known thus far only from adult females phoretic under the elytra of carabid beetles and the tegmina of labidurid earwigs in Eurasia. The relationships between it and the closely related &lt;i&gt;Antennoseius&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, 1916 and &lt;i&gt;Vitzthumia&lt;/i&gt; Thor, 1930, are reviewed, and the options for the family level placement of these genera are reconsidered. Attention is given to some gnathosomatic attributes that are commonly overlooked in description of species of these closely related genera. Phoresy and the role of adult female morphs in the life history of these mites, as well as the extraordinary phoretic association of one species with earwigs are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ascoidea; Dermanyssoidea; polymorphism; phoresy; carabid beetles; labidurid earwigs</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ascoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Evert</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lindquist</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moraza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-39</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Paraleptamphopidae (Crustacea Amphipoda) in the burrow of &lt;i&gt;Virilastacus rucapihuelensis &lt;/i&gt;(Parastacidae&lt;i&gt;) &lt;/i&gt;and surrounding peat bogs. &lt;i&gt;Rudolphia macrodactylus &lt;/i&gt;n. gen., n. sp. from southern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of a chilean Paraleptamphopidae is described. &lt;i&gt;Rudolphia&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. shares eleven characters with the family diagnosis &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Bousfield, 1983. The diagnosis of the new genus is: A1 and A2 long; A1 equal to length of body, A1 inner flagellum scale shaped, calceoli gammarid-type in males only; Mx1 asymmetrical; Gn1 propodus mittenlike, palmar index = 1.81; Gn2 carpus longer than Gn1, palmar index = 2.39; coxal gills: P2–5 and 7 bilobate, P6 ovoid; dactyls of pereopods very long; Pleopods multiarticulate, Pl 2 sexually dimorphic; Uropods birami, rami uniarticulate, Ur1 and Ur2 exopodites scarcely shorter than endopodites, Ur1 peduncle longer than rami, Ur2 resembling Ur1 but much shorter, Ur3 subequal in length to Ur2, Ur3 peduncle shorter than rami, rami acuminated of equal length, with pairs of a bifid and a plumose setae; Telson cleft halfway. &lt;i&gt;Rudolphia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is the first discovery of Paraleptamphopidae sp. out of New Zealand. A cladistic analysis allows us support that Paraleptamphopidae clade was differentiated before the New ZealandSouth America separation (80–85 mya).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Pholeteran; Phylogeny; Biogeography; Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Rudolphia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grosso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcela</firstname>
          <lastname>Peralta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the presence of &lt;i&gt;Anchistioides willeyi &lt;/i&gt;(Borradaile, 1899) (Decapoda: Caridea: Anchistioididae) in the Red Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-56</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new arboreal species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Deh Akro-II Wetlands Complex, Sindh, Pakistan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A distinctive new thin-toed gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dehakroense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Deh Akro-II Wetlands Complex, Nawabshah, Sindh, bringing the number of species of this genus in Pakistan to nine. The major diagnostic characters of the new species include the presence of 7–9 very narrow, V-shaped, dark brown, transverse dorsal bands on the body from the nape to the level of the vent, four precloacal pores in males, absence of femoral pores, 21–25 rows of ventral scales across midbody, 92–102 scales along ventral midline of body, and presence of paired subcaudal scales under the post-pygal portion of the tail. The species is a desert form and has thus far been found only in sandy areas of this wetlands complex at mean elevations of about 10 m. Strictly nocturnal, it inhabits old-growth trees of &lt;i&gt;Prosopis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cineraria&lt;/i&gt; (Jand/Kandi) and feeds mainly on a variety of insects.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; new species; description; Desert Wetlands Complex; Pakistan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rafaqat</firstname>
          <lastname>Masroor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">ErratumNG, N. K. &amp; MCLAUGHLI, P. A. (2009) A new hermit crab (Decapoda: Anomura: Paguroidea: Paguridae) from the eastern North Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2227, 6368.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
