<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2077.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Apr. 2009</title>
    <volume>2077</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-04-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An evaluation of the genus &lt;i&gt;Kincaidiana &lt;/i&gt;Altman, 1936, with the designation of &lt;i&gt;Altmanella &lt;/i&gt;n. gen. (Annelida, Clitellata, Lumbriculidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of morphological characters for the western Nearctic genus &lt;i&gt;Kincaidiana&lt;/i&gt; indicated that the two described species should be assigned to separate genera. &lt;i&gt;Kincaidiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freidris&lt;/i&gt; Cook was transferred to a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Altmanella.&lt;/i&gt; New material resembling &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freidris&lt;/i&gt; was obtained from many sites throughout western North America. Morphology of the male reproductive structures varied among populations, and the most distinctive morphological differences were accounted for by splitting the taxon into two species, which roughly corresponded to large scale regional patterns. Typical &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freidris&lt;/i&gt; occurred in several Pacific Coast drainages. &lt;i&gt;Altmanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;idahoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; mostly associated with the Snake River drainage, was distinguished from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freidris&lt;/i&gt; by shorter and less muscular atria and penial structures. A second new lumbriculid species with the same basic arrangement of reproductive organs was collected in southeastern North America, and was provisionally assigned to &lt;i&gt;Altmanella.&lt;/i&gt; However, in contrast to the petiolate atria and large penial structures of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freidris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;idahoensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Altmanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lenati&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has tubular atria and simple male porophores.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clitellata; Oligochaeta; Lumbriculidae; Kincaidiana; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clitellata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steven.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new Parastenocarididae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida) from India: &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris muvattupuzha &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. from a river and &lt;i&gt;P. kotumsarensis &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. from a cave</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">To date, 11 harpacticoid species from the family Parastenocarididae are known to occur on the Indian subcontinent. Of these, ten species belong to the genus &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; Kessler, 1913, and one to the genus &lt;i&gt;Kinnecaris&lt;/i&gt; Jakobi, 1972. Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris,&lt;/i&gt; viz. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muvattupuzha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kotumsarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated herein from India and their taxonomic position within the genus &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; discussed. &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muvattupuzha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was found in the hyporheic zone of the River Muvattupuzha in the State of Kerala, southwestern India. Having a unique set of morphological characters, this new species does not perfectly fit into any of the known &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; species-groups; it is treated as &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; It stands out in the genus, &lt;i&gt;inter&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alia,&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of a distinct unguiform process at the inner distal corner of each caudal ramus in both sexes and a club-shaped, distally spinulose leg 4 endopod in the male. &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kotumsarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described based on specimens collected from Kotumsar Cave in the State of Chhattisgarh, central India. This species shares features with the &lt;i&gt;brevipes-group&lt;/i&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; (i.e. similar endopodal complex of the male leg 4) and the recently redefined genus &lt;i&gt;Kinnecaris&lt;/i&gt; (i.e. presence of the triangular platelike fifth legs, which are similar in both sexes, and paired ventrolateral integumental windows on the antepenultimate and penultimate urosomites). Hence, for the time being, this species, like the preceding one, is also treated as &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kotumsarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is the first cavernicolous parastenocaridid from India and, on a broader geographical scale, from southern Asia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hyporheos; cavernicole; taxonomy; Crustacea; &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hyporheos</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yenumula</firstname>
          <middlename>Ranga</middlename>
          <lastname>Reddy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danielle</firstname>
          <lastname>Defaye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-55</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Aponema &lt;/i&gt;Jensen, 1978 (Nematoda: Microlaimidae) with description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; Jensen, 1978 is discussed. An emended diagnosis and identification keys at species level are provided. Two &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; species – &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decramerae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mnazi&lt;/i&gt; are transferred from the genus &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Microlaimus&lt;/i&gt; because of the presence of two testes. One known &lt;i&gt;Microlaimus&lt;/i&gt; species, &lt;i&gt;Microlaimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanus&lt;/i&gt; Blome, 1982, is transferred from the genus &lt;i&gt;Microlaimus&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; because of the presence of a single testis in males. Three new &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; species are described. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is characterized by a small body, smooth or slightly transversely striated cuticle, amphids with rod-like protruding corpus gelatum, almost round pharyngeal bulb and presence of three papilliform precloacal supplements in males. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nympha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanum&lt;/i&gt; but differs from the former by the position of amphidial fovea (at about 1.5 head diameters from anterior end &lt;i&gt;vs&lt;/i&gt; less than 0.7 head diameters from anterior in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nympha)&lt;/i&gt; and from the latter by the presence of a gubernaculum, a protruding corpus gelatum from the amphidial fovea and by the shorter tail (c = 8.2–11.3 &lt;i&gt;vs&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; = 5.8–7.8). &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutissima&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is characterized by a very small slender body, transversely striated cuticle, roundish amphidial fovea, spherical pharyngeal bulb, presence of short somatic setae, large spermatozoa, and a weakly developed copulatory apparatus without gubernaculum. It differs from the other &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; species by the small body size (0.20–0.43 mm). It mostly resembles &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathyalis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. but differs by smaller size, slightly striated cuticle and absence of a gubernaculum. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;westindicum&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is characterized by a larger body, annulated cuticle, discernible dorsal tooth, pyriform pharyngeal bulb and conical tail. It differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanum&lt;/i&gt; (Blome, 1982) by longer body size and structure of buccal cavity. All &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt; species described in this paper are characterized by monorchic males without gubernacular apophyses, females with two outstretched ovaries and a conical tail.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; Microlaimidae; &lt;i&gt;Aponema&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shota</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kovalyev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miljutina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
