<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2203.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Aug. 2009</title>
    <volume>2203</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ichnotaxonomic revision of &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt;, a mammalian ichnogenus from the Middle Jurassic La Matilde Formation, Santa Cruz province, Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The ichnological assemblage from the Estancia Laguna Manantiales, from the Middle Jurassic La Matilde Formation, Santa Cruz province, Argentina, is exceptional both in diversity and abundance. It is composed of mammal, dinosaur, invertebrate, and root traces. The most significant and abundant specimens are those assigned to the ichnogenus &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt; Casamiquela, 1961. This ichnogenus is revised and an emendation of its diagnosis is suggested. The inclusion of all the known specimens to the type ichnospecies, &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; Casamiquela, 1961, is challenged and some specimens are placed in a new ichnospecies, &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manantialensis&lt;/i&gt; isp. nov. Similar tracks from other ichnological localities worldwide were previously referred to &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus,&lt;/i&gt; but only &lt;i&gt;Eopentapodiscus&lt;/i&gt; (Ellenberger, 1970), from South Africa is considered as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus.&lt;/i&gt; The ichnotaxobases used to classify tracks with mammalian affinities at ichnogeneric and ichnospecific levels are evaluated and re-assessed ichnotaxonomic criteria are proposed. Different criteria used to distinguish mammalian imprints from non-mammalian tracks are commented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt;; ichnotaxonomy; mammal tracks; Jurassic; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ameghinichnus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Silvina</firstname>
          <lastname>De Valais</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of larval Erythraeinae (Acari: Prostigmata: Erythraeidae) from Ukraine and the taxonomic state of &lt;i&gt;Zhangiella&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Makolia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crimeaensis&lt;/i&gt; Saboori, Khaustov &amp; Hakimitabar &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Erythraeidae) is described and illustrated from larvae ectoparasitic on &lt;i&gt;Lasius&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) from Ukraine. A key to world genera of Erythraeinae (larva) is presented and the genus &lt;i&gt;Zhangiella&lt;/i&gt; Saboori, Cobanoglu &amp; Bayram is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Curteria&lt;/i&gt; Southcott.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">larva; ectoparasite; mite; &lt;i&gt;Lasius&lt;/i&gt;; Formicidae; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">larva</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alireza</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandr</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Khaustov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masoud</firstname>
          <lastname>Hakimitabar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hamidreza</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajiqanbar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-30</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological variation and systematics of &lt;i&gt;Dipsas catesbyi &lt;/i&gt;(Sentzen, 1796) and &lt;i&gt;Dipsas pavonina &lt;/i&gt;Schlegel, 1837 (Serpentes: Dipsadinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; includes approximately 32 species, distributed from Mexico to South America (Brazil, Argentina, Paraguay, Bolivia and Peru). High variability in color pattern and scalation has made it difficult to define limits among &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; species and to interpret patterns of geographic variation. We analyzed 14 meristic and 18 morphometric characters of 483 specimens of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catesbyi&lt;/i&gt; and 129 specimens of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavonina,&lt;/i&gt; as well as their color pattern, coloration, hemipenis, cephalic glands and geographic distribution. We describe variation in meristic and morphometric characters and incorporate new characters into revised diagnoses. The results indicate a greater morphological similarity between &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catesbyi&lt;/i&gt; and species of &lt;i&gt;Sibynomorphus&lt;/i&gt; than with the other species of &lt;i&gt;Dipsas.&lt;/i&gt; More morphological studies should be done to evaluate current phylogenetic proposals for relationships within the tribe Dipsadini.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catesbyi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavonina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dipsadinae&lt;/i&gt;; hemipenes; variation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catesbyi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Caroline</middlename>
          <lastname>De Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lúcia</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Costa Prudente</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of tonguefish (Pleuronectiformes: Cynoglossidae) from Taiwanese waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; new species, described from nine specimens captured in deep waters off Taiwan, is distinguished from congeners by the following combination of characters: predominant 1–2–2–2–2 pattern of interdigitation of dorsal pterygiophores and neural spines, 14 caudal-fin rays, 92–94 dorsal-fin rays, 79–82 anal-fin rays, 9 abdominal and 50–51 total vertebrae, 5 hypurals, deep body (28.6–35.1 % SL), small scales (102–108 scales in longitudinal series, 45–48 scales in transverse row), blackish-brown ocular-side opercle, bluish-black blind-side opercle, uniformly reddish-brown to dark-brown ocular-side background pigmentation with some specimens also having 5–7 mostly complete crossbands, and uniformly white to light-yellow blind side with dense patches of blackish-brown chromatophores predominantly covering pterygiophore regions of the dorsal and anal fins. &lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; were retrieved from commercial catches of fishing trawlers landed at three regional fish ports operating in deep waters off northeastern and southwestern Taiwan. The only information associated with these specimens is the general region of capture based on where fishing trawlers operate. Data on relative abundance, depth of capture, geographic distribution, and microhabitat conditions where this species is captured are unavailable at this time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt;; flatfish; deep waters; systematics; Pepperdot tonguefish</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Symphurus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mao-Ying</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Munroe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the ant spider genus &lt;i&gt;Suffasia &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae: Zodariidae) from the Western Ghats, India with a key to the species of the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Suffasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;keralaensis,&lt;/i&gt; a new species in the spider family Zodariidae from the Western Ghats in India is described. It can be diagnosed from other members of the genus by oval spermathecae in the female and by the presence of three cymbial pits and long curved embolus with pointed tip of the male palp. A diagnostic key to both male and female species so far reported of the genus &lt;i&gt;Suffasia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spider taxonomy; biodiversity hot spot; Zodariinae; &lt;i&gt;Suffasia&lt;/i&gt; genitalia; new taxa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spider taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ambalaparambil</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sudhikumar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudy</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocqué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pothalil</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sebastian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Vitreorana oyampiensis &lt;/i&gt;(Anura, Centrolenidae) in Central Amazonia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Menin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Albertina</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Domingos</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-08-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
