<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2008.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Feb. 2009</title>
    <volume>2008</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic identification and color descriptions of early life-history stages of Belizean &lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Astrapogon &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Apogonidae) with Comments on identification of adult &lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Astrapogon&lt;/i&gt; are represented in the Caribbean by six species (P. &lt;i&gt;conklini,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pigmentaria,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xenus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alutus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stellatus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puncticulatus).&lt;/i&gt; Species identification of larvae and juveniles is problematic because characters used to distinguish adults (e.g., patterns of pigmentation and numbers of gill rakers) are absent, incomplete, or difficult to discern in the young stages. Neighbor-joining trees derived from mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase 1 sequences (DNA Barcoding) were used to match early life stages and adults. Subsequent comparative analysis of preserved voucher specimens from which the DNA was extracted or digital color photographs of those specimens taken prior to preservation yielded sufficient information to separate all early life-history stages of Belizean &lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Astrapogon&lt;/i&gt; and provided additional information for field identification of adult &lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx.&lt;/i&gt; Patterns of chromatophores in fresh material, combined with patterns of melanophores, provide the easiest means of separating the life-history stages of &lt;i&gt;Phaeoptyx.&lt;/i&gt; Larvae of &lt;i&gt;Astrapogon&lt;/i&gt; species are morphologically very similar, and some differences in pigmentation detected among them may reflect different stages of development. Continued implementation of the DNA Barcoding methods and field protocol outlined herein should prove valuable in accurately identifying much more of the ichthyoplankton fauna of the Caribbean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">DNA Barcoding; fish larvae; chromatophores; Belize</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">DNA Barcoding</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carole</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Baldwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julie</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mounts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lee</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Weigt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the flathead genus &lt;i&gt;Onigocia &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Platycephalidae) collected from the Coral and Tasman Seas</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of platycephalid, &lt;i&gt;Onigocia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrimalis,&lt;/i&gt; is described on the basis of specimens collected from the Chesterfield Islands (Coral Sea) and Norfolk Ridge (Tasman Sea), at depths of 111–330 m. &lt;i&gt;Onigocia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrimalis&lt;/i&gt; differs from the six congeners of the genus in having 12–13 (usually 12) second dorsal-fin rays, 12 anal-fin rays, 21–25 pectoral-fin rays, 8 branched caudal-fin rays, anterior 2–4 scales of the lateral line with a spine, and a single preocular spine, and in lacking gill rakers on the upper arch, ocular and interopercular flaps, and distinct antrorse lachrymal spines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Onigocia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrimalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Platycephalidae; Coral Sea; Tasman Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Onigocia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrimalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Platycephalidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hisashi</firstname>
          <lastname>Imamura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leslie</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Knapp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-28</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Further specimens and phylogenetic position of the recently described leaf turtle species &lt;i&gt;Cyclemys gemeli &lt;/i&gt;(Testudines: Geoemydidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe external morphology and habitat of ten specimens of &lt;i&gt;Cyclemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli,&lt;/i&gt; a recently discovered leaf turtle species from north-eastern India, previously known only from its incomplete holotype and photos of a live female. Further, we assess the phylogenetic position of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli&lt;/i&gt; using sequence data of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene as well as of three nuclear DNA fragments (C-mos, Rag2 genes, intron 1 of R35 gene) and confirm its genetic distinctiveness. Mitochondrial data strongly suggest a sister group relationship of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca,&lt;/i&gt; another species occurring in Myanmar. According to our new records, the Naga Hills and the Arakan Mts could constitute the geographical divide between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca.&lt;/i&gt; Morphologically, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli&lt;/i&gt; resembles other dark-bellied &lt;i&gt;Cyclemys&lt;/i&gt; species and determination by external morphology alone is quite difficult.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">India; Myanmar; &lt;i&gt;Cyclemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cyclemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemeli&lt;/i&gt;; molecular phylogenetics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">India</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Praschag</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hundsdörfer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Uwe</firstname>
          <lastname>Fritz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-37</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of lizard genus &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus &lt;/i&gt;Spix, 1825 (Squamata: Gekkota: Phyllodactylidae) from Serra do Sincorá, northeastern Brazil, and the status of &lt;i&gt;G&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi &lt;/i&gt;Vanzolini, 2005</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of gekkonid lizard genus &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Spix, 1825 is described on the basis of material collected in the “campos rupestres” (open rocky communities) of Mucugê municipality, northeastern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vanzolinii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from its congeners in the number of transverse and longitudinal rows of dorsal tubercles and color pattern. It is thought to be closer to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guttulatus&lt;/i&gt; which also occurs and is restricted to the rocky communities from highland open areas in the Espinhaço mountain range. The discovery leads to a reevaluation of the taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi&lt;/i&gt; Vanzolini, 2005, which is here considered a synonym of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amarali&lt;/i&gt; Barbour, 1925.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; Gekkota; Phyllodactylidae; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vanzolinii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; New species; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amarali;&lt;/i&gt; Synonymy; Meadow fields; Serra do Sincorá; Mucugê municipality; Northeastern Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata; Gekkota; Phyllodactylidae; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vanzolinii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; New species; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amarali;&lt;/i&gt; Synonymy; Meadow fields; Serra do Sincorá; Mucugê municipality; Northeastern Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <lastname>Cassimiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-52</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pareas &lt;/i&gt;(Serpentes: Colubridae: Pareatinae) from the Gaoligong Mountains, southwestern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; Wagler, 1830 (Serpentes: Colubridae: Pareatinae) is described from Gaoligong Mountains, Yunnan province, southwestern China. The new species is distinguished from congeners in the following combination of traits: preoculars 1/1; subocular and postocular fused into a single crescent-shaped scale; anterior temporals 1, posterior 2–3; 15 dorsal rows on whole body, 9 median rows feebly keeled (invisible on neck); vertebral scales slightly enlarged; ventrals 175; subcaudals 76 (excluding terminal spine), all divided; a big black oval patch on the back of head; two round black spots on each side of the face.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigriceps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; snakes; systematics; taxonomy; Yunnan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigriceps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; snakes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Keji</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xuejian</firstname>
          <lastname>Deng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new brooding feather star of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dorometra &lt;/i&gt;(Echinodermata: Crinoidea: Comatulida: Antedonidae) from the Ryukyu Islands, southwestern Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new comatulid of the family Antedonidae, &lt;i&gt;Dorometra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sesokonis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described from coral reefs of the Ryukyu Islands, southwestern Japan. The new species is extremely small with ten short arms and a unique pinnulation in which some proximal pinnules are absent or poorly developed in most specimens. Additionally, cirrals and brachials of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sesokonis&lt;/i&gt; are elongated and partly colorless. The combination of these morphological characters makes the new species appear like juvenile specimens, regardless of sexual maturity. This species also has remarkable reproductive habits, exhibiting both external brooding and hermaphroditism.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Comatulid; &lt;i&gt;Dorometra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sesokonis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; external brooding; hermaphroditism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Comatulid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masami</firstname>
          <lastname>Obuchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ichizo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kogo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yoshihisa</firstname>
          <lastname>Fujita</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-02-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
