<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2222.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Sep. 2009</title>
    <volume>2222</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barrosasaurus casamiquelai &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov., a new titanosaur (Dinosauria, Sauropoda) from the Anacleto Formation (Late Cretaceous: early Campanian) of Sierra Barrosa (Neuquén, Argentina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new Late Cretaceous titanosaurian sauropod from the Sierra Barrosa locality (Anacleto Formation, Late Cretaceous, early Campanian) of Neuquén Province, Argentina, &lt;i&gt;Barrosasaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;casamiquelai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described. The holotype of this species consists of three large and incomplete, although well-preserved, dorsal vertebrae (one probably the third, the next the seventh or eighth, and the last the ninth or tenth). The arrangement of neural arch laminae in the dorsal vertebrae of this titanosaur differs from that present in other genera in the following ways: the spinoprezygapophyseal laminae are well developed in the third vertebra, and relictual in the seventh or eighth vertebra; two spinodiapophyseal laminae are present in the seventh or eighth and in the ninth or tenth vertebrae, the anterior spinodiapophyseal lamina being more strongly developed than the posterior spinodiapophyseal lamina in the ninth or tenth vertebra. These characters, among others, allow the recognition of this individual as a new species of Titanosauria, which increases knowledge of the diversity of titanosaurs in the Late Cretaceous of Patagonia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sauropoda; Titanosauria; new species; Sierra Barrosa; Neuquén; Patagonia; Argentina; Upper Cretaceous; Anacleto Formation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sauropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leonardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Salgado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodolfo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The geographic distribution of echiurans in the Atlantic Ocean (Phylum Echiura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This report provides a checklist of the echiurans from the Atlantic Ocean and maps their distribution. Investigations on the taxonomy of this group since the publication of the monograph by Stephen and Edmonds (1972) on the phyla Sipuncula and Echiura have yielded two new genera, 12 new species and 13 new records. Currently the echiuran fauna of the Atlantic comprises three families, 25 genera and 63 species. The family Bonelliidae contains 35 species in 18 genera; the Echiuridae is represented by six genera and 27 species, and the Urechidae by a single species &lt;i&gt;Urechis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; (Müller). This study shows that the Atlantic has a relatively high species diversity, comprising about 38% of the known world fauna. Bonelliids alone comprise about 56% of the echiuran fauna of the Atlantic. An analysis of distribution is given in relation to general biogeographic regions and faunistic provinces. Dichotomous keys for the identification of genera and species of echiurans from the Atlantic is provided. The North Temperate component is the richest and most diverse, making up about 68% of the Atlantic echiuran fauna; 25 species have been recorded from within the tropics; and the South Temperate component is poorly represented, with only about 19% of the total fauna. The cosmopolitan component is also poorly represented, with only four species, so far, known. Thirteen species of echiurans are provisionally considered to be endemic to the Atlantic. Members of the Echiuridae are usually shallow-water inhabitants of intertidal and subtidal zones while bonelliids exhibit a higher species richness on deeper bottoms of all oceans, mostly at depths of 1000–6000 m in the Atlantic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geographic distribution; Echiura; Atlantic Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geographic distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ramlall</firstname>
          <lastname>Biseswar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis &lt;/i&gt;(Serpentes: Colubridae) from the Cerrado of Bolivia, with comments on &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis scalaris &lt;/i&gt;in Bolivia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis&lt;/i&gt; from the Chiquitano Region in the eastern lowlands of Bolivia. The new species can be identified as member of the genus &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis&lt;/i&gt; by its vertebral morphology. The new species differs from the other two species of &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis&lt;/i&gt; in its unique, uniform dorsal color pattern. It further differs from &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scalaris&lt;/i&gt; by having two prefrontals and a narrow septum within each neural spine and perpendicular to its long axis. For &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scalaris&lt;/i&gt; we present new records from Bolivia, including the highest altitudinal record for the species and genus (Serranía Beu in the Pilón Lajas Reserve, Department of La Paz, 1500 m).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chiquitano Region; Department of Santa Cruz; Reptilia; San Sebastián; Snakes; Squamata; &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;werdingorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chiquitano Region; Department of Santa Cruz; Reptilia; San Sebastián; Snakes; Squamata; &lt;i&gt;Xenopholis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;werdingorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Jansen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lucindo</firstname>
          <middlename>Gonzales</middlename>
          <lastname>Álvarez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gunther</firstname>
          <lastname>Köhler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-45</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Alacran &lt;/i&gt;(Scorpiones: Typhlochactidae) from a cave in Oaxaca, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alacran&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chamuco&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a new eyeless, troglobitic scorpion from Te Cimutaa, Valle Nacional, is described. This is the second known species in the genus; sharing with &lt;i&gt;Alacran&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tartarus&lt;/i&gt; a very similar trichobothrial pattern and the lack of “petite” trichobothria—both unique characters in the family Typhlochactidae. The new species differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tartarus&lt;/i&gt; in the pedipalp finger dentition and the relative size of the telson. The two cave systems in Oaxaca where the two species of &lt;i&gt;Alacran&lt;/i&gt; occur are approximately 75 kilometers apart.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scorpion; troglobite; eyeless; Typhlochactidae; Alacraninae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scorpion</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Francke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-56</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Metrarabdotos &lt;/i&gt;(Bryozoa, Ascophora) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Worldwide there are approximately 40 species of &lt;i&gt;Metrarabdotos,&lt;/i&gt; only six of which are extant. Among the living species, three were previously recorded from the Brazilian coast: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unguiculatum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosum,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gulo,&lt;/i&gt; collected from Bahia and Espírito Santo States. There are no records of fossil species of &lt;i&gt;Metrarabdotos&lt;/i&gt; from Brazil. This study reports two living &lt;i&gt;Metrarabdotos&lt;/i&gt; species, collected from three states in Brazil―Sergipe, Bahia and Espírito Santo. One of the species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sergipensis,&lt;/i&gt; is new to science. Its morphological features, such as extreme tuberculation of the zooidal frontal shield, add appreciably to the range of morphological disparity known in the genus.&lt;b&gt;Key-words:&lt;/b&gt; Brazil, Bryozoa, Metrarabdotosidae, new species, Southwestern Atlantic, taxonomy</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Flávia</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Laís</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carmen</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gumarães</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-65</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of the Brazilian torrent frog &lt;i&gt;Hylodes heyeri &lt;/i&gt;(Anura; Hylodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>R. N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lingnau</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Toledo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
