<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2304.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Dec. 2009</title>
    <volume>2304</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mysidae (Mysida) of New Zealand; a checklist, identification key to species and an overview of material in New Zealand collections</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Mysida are small, mostly marine crustaceans that are an important element of food webs, specifically as prey for several commercially important fish species. Taking their ecological and economical importance into account, relatively little attention is attributed to these organisms, and they are often neglected in biodiversity surveys and studies. To draw attention to these animals and stimulate research in New Zealand, we summarize information available for New Zealand Mysidae. We present a checklist of the 17 species recorded in New Zealand waters as well as a preliminary identification key to species based on the existing literature. We also provide an overview of mysid material available in collections in New Zealand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New Zealand; Mysidae; mysids; Mysidacea; checklist; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New Zealand</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Blom</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new family and genus of calanoid copepods (Crustacea) from the abyss of the Atlantic Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kyphocalanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from female specimens collected at abyssal depths above the sea bed in the Atlantic Ocean. Although the new genus shares the presence of sensory setae on maxilla and maxilliped with other Bradfordian families of the superfamily Clausocalanoidea, it does not fit the diagnosis of any of these families. The family Kyphocalanidae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is established for the genus and 4 species are identified, although we only had enough suitable material to name one of them: &lt;i&gt;Kyphocalanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Kyphocalanidae is defined by the following apomorphies: maxillule supplied with 3 setae on praecoxal arthrite; maxilla endopod has 8 thick worm-like sensory setae distinctly longer than sclerotized setae of maxilla endites, and the maxilliped shows a 1, 2, 0 setal armament with only worm-like sensory elements of the three praecoxal endites respectively. Segmentation and setation of the swimming legs of the new genus are typical of Clausocalanoidea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Calanoida; &lt;i&gt;Kyphocalanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; deep benthopelagic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Markhaseva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Knud</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Re-description of the type series of &lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides viviparus &lt;/i&gt;(Bufonidae), with a taxonomic reassessment</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The type series of &lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viviparus&lt;/i&gt; (Tornier, 1905) from the southern Tanzanian highlands has been rediscovered in the Museum für Naturkunde, Berlin. A re-description is given and a lectotype designated. Available topotypic material is included in our assessment of morphological variation in this population. With clarification of the species’ identity, nomenclatural confusions can be addressed. We reject the designation of an earlier neotype, and also of records attributed to the species north and east of the Southern Highlands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt;; viviparous bufonid; Tanzanian highlands; Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Poynton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tim</firstname>
          <middlename>R. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davenport</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark-Oliver</firstname>
          <lastname>Rödel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the taxonomy and distribution of &lt;i&gt;Plagiotaphrus &lt;/i&gt;Attems 1914 (Diplopoda, Spirostreptida, Spirostreptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Plagiotaphrus&lt;/i&gt; is a monophyletic genus which formerly included three species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcifer&lt;/i&gt; Attems 1914 (the type species), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;improvisus&lt;/i&gt; (Attems 1934) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longius&lt;/i&gt; Attems 1928. &lt;i&gt;Plagiotaphrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longius&lt;/i&gt; is a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubium&lt;/i&gt; and is here excluded from the genus. A key to the species based on gonopod morphology is also presented. The distribution of &lt;i&gt;Plagiotaphrus&lt;/i&gt; is disjunct. Given that several localities in Africa have not been surveyed it is likely that &lt;i&gt;Plagiotaphrus&lt;/i&gt; species occur in more localities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">savanna; millipedes; gonopod; conservation; southern Africa; central Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">savanna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tarombera</firstname>
          <lastname>Mwabvu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michelle</firstname>
          <lastname>Hamer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Slotow</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Barraclough</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The generic allocation of &lt;i&gt;Hyla antoniiochoai &lt;/i&gt;De la Riva &amp; Chaparro, 2005 (Anura), with description of its advertisement call and ecology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The description of the frog “Hyla” &lt;i&gt;antoniiochoai&lt;/i&gt; is based on a subadult female and a juvenile collected in 2005 near Esperanza, Kosñipata Valley, &lt;i&gt;Región&lt;/i&gt; (formerly &lt;i&gt;Departamento)&lt;/i&gt; Cusco, southeastern Peru. The species was assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; (Hylidae) but could not be assigned to any species group within this genus. According to the original description, typical characters include the absence of webbing in hands, and vestigial webbing between Toes III and IV. In 2009, we collected additional specimens including adults of both sexes from the type locality. To our surprise these specimens show characters, such as a closed brood pouch, that are typical of &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; (Hemiphractidae). Furthermore, our analysis of the advertisement call supports its relation with &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca.&lt;/i&gt; Consequently, we assign &lt;i&gt;“Hyla”&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antoniiochoai&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca,&lt;/i&gt; compare it with its congeners, and improve the species diagnosis and description. &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antoniiochoai&lt;/i&gt; lives in epiphytic bromeliads in the cloud forest and montane scrub between 2700 and 3300 m in Manu National Park. The new specimens were found inside bromeliads approximately 6–8 from the ground. It shares with the central Peruvian &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zeugocystis,&lt;/i&gt; and the Venezuelan &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walkeri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;williamsonii&lt;/i&gt; a lateral, paired brood pouch (instead of the single, dorsomedian pouch found in most &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; &lt;i&gt;Gastrotheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antoniiochoai&lt;/i&gt;; Hemiphractidae; marsupial frog; new combination; vocalization</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Catenazzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edgar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-12-04</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
