<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2246.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Oct. 2009</title>
    <volume>2246</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus &lt;/i&gt;(Reptilia: Squamata: Scincidae) from the Great Sandy Desert and Pilbara Coast, Western Australia and reassignment of eight species from &lt;i&gt;Glaphyromorphus &lt;/i&gt;to &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The concept of the skink lizard genus &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus&lt;/i&gt; Greer, 1979 is expanded to include eleven species [antoniorum, &lt;i&gt;brongersmai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;butlerorum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;douglasi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emigrans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciolatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;isolepis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richardsonii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;musivus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;pardalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;timorensis],&lt;/i&gt; eight of which [antoniorum, &lt;i&gt;brongersmai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;butlerorum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;douglasi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emigrans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;isolepis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pardalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;timorensis]&lt;/i&gt; (comb. nov.) previously belonged to &lt;i&gt;Glaphyromorphus&lt;/i&gt; Wells &amp; Wellington, 1983. This decision is based on the results of three recent studies, which indicated that ‘Glaphyromorphus’ was a polyphyletic assemblage representing a morphotype within Australian sphenomorphine skinks. In addition, we describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus&lt;/i&gt; based on morphological and molecular genetic evidence. The new species is distributed in coastal areas of the Pilbara region, Dampierland and the Great Sandy Desert in northwestern Western Australia. &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;musivus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from regional congeners by possessing a characteristic dorsal pattern comprising numerous whitish and dark spots which align to form a diffuse reticulum, a pale vertebral stripe, more slender body and smaller body size, 52–62 paravertebral scales, scales along top of the fourth toe with oblique sutures on basal quarter to third of digit, subdigital lamellae of fourth toe undivided and feebly keeled and 10–15 plantar scales. The description of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;musivus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; brings the number of species of Australian &lt;i&gt;Eremiascincus&lt;/i&gt; to seven.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lacertilia; Lygosominae; taxonomy; mitochondrial DNA; &lt;i&gt;cytochrome&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lacertilia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <lastname>Mecke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Doughty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnellan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of karst dwelling &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis &lt;/i&gt;Strauch 1887 (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Sarawak, Borneo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of karst dwelling &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; is described from western Sarawak, Malaysia on the island of Borneo. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paripari&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is presumably endemic to the karst outcroppings which extend approximately 4.2 km between Gua Angin and Gua Pari-pari in the district of Bau. It is the only species of Southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; with a median, subcaudal row of bead-like scales and whose adult males have a bright yellow head and a bright yellow regenerated tail. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paripari&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs markedly from the other three species of Bornean &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in aspects of size, squamation, and coloration and its presence underscores the potential unrealized diversity of this genus in Borneo as compared to Peninsular Malaysia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;paripari&lt;/i&gt;; Borneo; karst; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chan</firstname>
          <middlename>Kin</middlename>
          <lastname>Onn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-31</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An essay on precision in morphometric measurements in anurans: inter-individual, intra-individual and temporal comparisons</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Morphometric comparisons among specimens continue being an important tool for biological and taxonomical studies and are indispensable for the description of new species. However, there are few works that have been done to compare the precision of the measurements that different investigators take in live or preserved animals with different body sizes and time of preservation. Herein we evaluate statistically this information. The results indicate that there are significant differences among the measurements taken by different people (inter-individual comparisons), but not within each of them (intra-individual comparisons). Also, there are temporal differences in the morphometric measurements among living animals, freshly preserved specimens and specimens after five months of preservation. These results demonstrate that morphometric measurements must be made by just one person and that for any morphometric analysis it is important to keep in mind the preservation time differences of the animals in the museums.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Frogs; morphological measures; repeatability; Manova; discriminant analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Frogs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <middlename>Hernando</middlename>
          <lastname>Bernal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jairo</firstname>
          <middlename>Alfonso</middlename>
          <lastname>Clavijo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-44</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of the spider family Symphytognathidae in Europe and description of &lt;i&gt;Anapistula ataecina &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Araneae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The spider family Symphytognathidae has never been recorded from Europe, being mostly present in tropical regions. Different collecting trips to a cave system in Portugal revealed several specimens of a new species of Symphytognathidae here described, &lt;i&gt;Anapistula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ataecina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; This is one of the smallest spiders described to date. The species is almost exclusively known from the Frade Cave System in Portugal which is partly endangered by limestone quarries. No males were found to date despite many collecting trips to the caves during more than three years. Parthenogenesis could therefore be responsible for the species reproduction. Its web, with a sheet-like structure, seems atypical for the family and for the genus. Details on the eggsacs and spinneret morphology are also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneoidea; cave; endangered species; morphology; new species; parthenogenesis; Portugal; spider; spinnerets; troglobite</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Cardoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nikolaj</firstname>
          <lastname>Scharff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Making biodiversity discovery more efficient: An exploratory test using Mexican birds</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent studies have explored the possible utility of ecological niche modeling as a tool for species discovery, with promising initial results, but no detailed test has as-yet evaluated the success or failure rates of the method. We use a comprehensive distributional summary for the birds of Mexico to develop a test, in which well-known and broadlydistributed species are used to predict the distributional areas of poorly-known congener species. The results indicated that all of the ‘unknown’ species chosen for testing were predicted significantly better than random expectations by the ecological characteristics of at least one well-known congener species. These results bode well for broader applications of using biodiversity informatics tools to guide species discovery, but further testing and development of protocols is still needed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">ecological niche models; model predictivity; species discovery; distribution; Aves</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">ecological niche models</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>Townsend</middlename>
          <lastname>Peterson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adolfo</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Navarro-Sigüenza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-66</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Podargus brachypterus &lt;/i&gt;vs. &lt;i&gt;macrorhynchus&lt;/i&gt;: misuse of Article 32.5.1.1 of the Code</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <lastname>Schodde</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
