<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2035.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Mar. 2009</title>
    <volume>2035</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-03-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revisions of Australian ground-hunting spiders: IV. The spider subfamily Diaprograptinae subfam. nov. (Araneomorphae: Miturgidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The newly recognised Diaprograptinae includes the Australian &lt;i&gt;Diaprograpta&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1909, &lt;i&gt;Eupograpta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., &lt;i&gt;Mituliodon&lt;/i&gt; Raven &amp; Stumkat, 2003, &lt;i&gt;Mitzoruga&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., &lt;i&gt;Nuliodon&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., and the New Zealand &lt;i&gt;Zealoctenus&lt;/i&gt; Forster &amp; Wilton, 1973. All genera are unique in the Miturgidae &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strict.&lt;/i&gt; in the possession of claw tufts, and more equivocally, in the apical segment of the posterior lateral spinnerets, which in Diaprograptinae is not as strongly elongated as in &lt;i&gt;Miturga.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Diaprograpta&lt;/i&gt; includes the type species, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striola&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1909 from Western Australia, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirsti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from South Australia, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alfredgodfreyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Victoria, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peterandrewsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from western Queensland and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abrahamsae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from southeast Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Eupograpta&lt;/i&gt; includes &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kottae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; sympatric with &lt;i&gt;Diaprograpta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anhat&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from western Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Mitzoruga&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. is described to accommodate &lt;i&gt;Uliodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoreus&lt;/i&gt; (Hogg, 1896), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elapines&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from xeric regions of Australia. The genus presents a character combination which challenges the boundary between the Miturgidae Simon, 1886 and Zoridae F. O. P.-Cambridge, 1893. &lt;i&gt;Nuliodon&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. includes only &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fishburni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from eastern Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Zoridae; taxonomy; Australia; biodiversity; biogeography; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Zoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Raven</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tantulocarid genus &lt;i&gt;Arcticotantalus &lt;/i&gt;removed from Basipodellidae into Deoterthridae (Crustacea: Maxillopoda) after the description of a new species from Greenland, with first live photographs and an overview of the class</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Tantulocarida was found off the coast of Disko Island, West Greenland. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Arcticotantulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kristenseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is exclusively found on an as yet undescribed species of &lt;i&gt;Bradya&lt;/i&gt; Boeck, 1873 (Copepoda, Harpacticoida) caught at depths of 200 m off the coast in muddy sediments. A total of 44 individuals were found, and 38 were examined by use of LM and SEM; these represented different stages of the life cycle: tantulus larvae, developing males, parthenogenetic females, and what may be only the third record of a developing sexual female. &lt;i&gt;Arcticotantulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kristenseni&lt;/i&gt; is tentatively placed in Deoterthridae based on the mode of formation of the male trunk sac, the pattern of ornamentation on the tergites and cephalic shield, and the number of setae on the thoracopods and caudal rami. It is suggested that the genus &lt;i&gt;Arcticotantulus&lt;/i&gt; Kornev, Tchesunov &amp; Rybnikov, 2004 is removed from Basipodellidae and placed in Deothertridae instead, in accordance with the mode of trunk sac development in males and the absence in the latter family of a cephalic rostrum. Various internal anatomical features were examined, including the tubular structures inside the head of the tantulus larvae. The first live photographs of any species of Tantulocarida are presented. This is also the first report on Tantulocarida from West Greenland.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Deoterthridae; parasite; ectoparasitic crustacean; Harpacticoida; parthenogenetic; &lt;i&gt;Bradya&lt;/i&gt;; sexual female tantulocarid</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Deoterthridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steen</firstname>
          <middlename>Wilhelm</middlename>
          <lastname>Knudsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maja</firstname>
          <lastname>Kirkegaard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jørgen</firstname>
          <lastname>Olesen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
