<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2033.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Mar. 2009</title>
    <volume>2033</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of the &lt;i&gt;longulus&lt;/i&gt;-group of &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus &lt;/i&gt;Clairville, 1806 from north-eastern Turkey (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artvinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cagrankaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lundbergi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sivrikaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toledoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae) are described from north-eastern Turkey. All five species belong to the &lt;i&gt;longulus-group&lt;/i&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; Clairville, 1806. They are externally very similar and only the males can be distinguished with certainty by the shape of their aedeagi. These are figured for all five new species, together with the female genitalia of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cagrankaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; The males of the species have the proand mesotarsi provided with sucker cups, what is demonstrated for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cagrankaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; by some SEM photos. The DNA of this species was also studied; the results suggest a close relationship with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dobrogeanus&lt;/i&gt; Ieniştea, 1962, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gueorguievi&lt;/i&gt; Wewalka, 1975, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kraatzii&lt;/i&gt; Schaum, 1868, and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sardomontanus&lt;/i&gt; Pederzani, Rocchi &amp; Schizzerotto, 2004. The present data indicate an allopatric distribution for the new species, each occurring in a rather restricted area. Except &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artvinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; they have been found on the northern slope of the Doğu Karadeniz Dağlari, a mountain range south of the coast of the Black Sea. The number of Turkish Dytiscidae is raised to about 145 species and that of the endemic taxa to 23. The total number of the members of the &lt;i&gt;longulus-group&lt;/i&gt; increases from 18 to 23 species. Finally, some new records are presented for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erzurumensis&lt;/i&gt; Erman &amp; Fery, 2000.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;longulus-group&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new records; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <lastname>Fery</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ömer</firstname>
          <middlename>Köksal</middlename>
          <lastname>Erman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of &lt;i&gt;Episothalma &lt;/i&gt;Swinhoe, 1893, with descriptions of two new species and one new genus (Lepidoptera, Geometridae, Geometrinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Episothalma&lt;/i&gt; Swinhoe is reviewed, and two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;irrobustaria,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Thailand, and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuspidata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Hainan Province, China. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellata&lt;/i&gt; Swinhoe is excluded from &lt;i&gt;Episothalma&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudepisothalma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is erected based on this species. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellata.&lt;/i&gt; Descriptions and diagnoses for both genera are given. All the known species are redescribed, and variations in the male genitalia of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustaria&lt;/i&gt; (Guenée) are described and figured. Illustrations of adults and genitalia are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geometrinae; &lt;i&gt;Episothalma&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Pseudepisothalma&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geometrinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dayong</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xuejian</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hongxiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>13-25</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Goniaspis &lt;/i&gt;Duda (Diptera: Chloropidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Goniaspis&lt;/i&gt; Duda is revised. The genus includes ten species: &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;equalis&lt;/i&gt; (Williston) (type locality: Saint Vincent); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Saint Lucia); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lurida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Blue Creek, Belize); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscurata&lt;/i&gt; Duda (type locality: San José, Costa Rica); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: San José, Costa Rica); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubra&lt;/i&gt; (Becker) (type species of genus, type locality: Sierra san Lorenzo, Colombia); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scutellaris&lt;/i&gt; (Williston) (type locality: Saint Vincent); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subaequalis&lt;/i&gt; (Malloch) (type locality: Montserrat, Trinidad); &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncata&lt;/i&gt; (Malloch) (type locality: Trece Aguas, Guatemala); and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;versicolor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: La Paz, Bolivia). The identity of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruana&lt;/i&gt; Duda cannot be determined and it is considered a &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda.&lt;/i&gt; All recognized species are described and illustrated, and a key to species is included. &lt;i&gt;Goniaspis&lt;/i&gt; has been assigned to the &lt;i&gt;Hippelates&lt;/i&gt; genus group (or tribe Hippelatini) in previous higher classifications of the Chloropidae, based primarily on the possession of a strong, ventral, hind-tibial spur. However, this character state is subject to frequent homoplasy in the Chloropidae, and multiple morphological character states suggest that &lt;i&gt;Goniaspis&lt;/i&gt; may be more closely related to the genus &lt;i&gt;Elachiptera&lt;/i&gt; Macquart.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chloropidae; Neotropical; &lt;i&gt;Goniaspis&lt;/i&gt;; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julia</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mlynarek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Terry</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wheeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Analysis of the geographical distribution of &lt;i&gt;Psammolestes &lt;/i&gt;Bergroth (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Reduviidae: Triatominae) in South America, with new records of &lt;i&gt;Psammolestes tertius &lt;/i&gt;Lent &amp; Jurberg</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Psammolestes&lt;/i&gt; is comprised of three recognized Rhodniini species: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreodes,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tertius.&lt;/i&gt; The geographical distribution of these triatomines in South America was analyzed using ecological niche modeling. Additionally, temperature, precipitation, and altitude limits for these species were estimated. The genetic algorithm for rule-set production (GARP) was applied to predict their geographical distribution. The models used were able to predict, with high probabilities, the occurrence of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tertius&lt;/i&gt; in open woodlands of South America (mainly Cerrado and Caatinga ecoregions), making it the &lt;i&gt;Psammolestes&lt;/i&gt; species with the widest distribution. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri&lt;/i&gt; presented a discontinuous potential distribution covering the Venezuelan Llanos and southeastern/southwestern fringes of Amazonia. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreodes&lt;/i&gt; presented the southernmost area of distribution, occurring mainly in the Argentinean Chaco. The models also support potential areas of co-occurrence for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tertius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreodes&lt;/i&gt; in southwestern Brazil. Clear ecological niche differences were observed for the three species: while &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri&lt;/i&gt; occurred in warm and humid areas, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreodes&lt;/i&gt; occupied the driest and coldest areas. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tertius&lt;/i&gt; presented intermediate climatological limits and occurred in the highest altitudes. Although climatic factors may determine the triatomine distribution, biotic factors, such as the association with thornbirds (Phacellodomus), may also influence the geographical distribution of &lt;i&gt;Psammolestes&lt;/i&gt; species. Finally, this study confirms the usefulness of ecological niche modeling as a tool for studies on biogeographical aspects of triatomines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Triatomine; Rhodniini; GARP; predictive maps; Furnariidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Triatomine</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <lastname>Gurgel-Gonçalves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Reinalda</firstname>
          <middlename>Bandeira</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Australotarsius&lt;/i&gt;a new genus of the rove beetle tribe Staphylinini from Australia (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylininae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Australotarsius&lt;/i&gt; Solodovnikov &amp; Newton, &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a new genus of rove beetles of the tribe Staphylinini, endemic to Australia, is described and compared to other Staphylinini. It includes two new species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; Solodovnikov &amp; Newton, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Queensland and New South Wales, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tasmanicus&lt;/i&gt; Solodovnikov &amp; Newton, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Tasmania. The systematic position of &lt;i&gt;Australotarsius&lt;/i&gt; within Staphylinini needs further investigation in the context of a broad-scale phylogenetic study of this large tribe. Preliminarily this new genus is thought to be a member of the lineage of Staphylinini which includes genera &lt;i&gt;Anchocerus&lt;/i&gt; Fauvel, 1905, &lt;i&gt;Acylophorus&lt;/i&gt; Nordmann, 1837, &lt;i&gt;Anaquedius&lt;/i&gt; Casey, 1915, &lt;i&gt;Hemiquedius&lt;/i&gt; Casey, 1915 and possibly &lt;i&gt;Euryporus&lt;/i&gt; Erichson, 1839, all of which are current members of the subtribe Quediina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Quediina; systematics; new species; eastern Australia; Tasmania</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Quediina</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexey</firstname>
          <lastname>Solodovnikov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfred</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Newton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chelobasis &lt;/i&gt;Gray, 1832 (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Cassidinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Chelobasis&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1832 is reviewed. Four species are recognized. A key to the species is presented. The literature is summarized and each species is illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chelobasis&lt;/i&gt;; Chrysomelidae; Cassidinae; key to species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chelobasis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Staines</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
