<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2286.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Nov. 2009</title>
    <volume>2286</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the knowledge of the Staphylinus-complex (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylinini) of China. Part 21. The genus &lt;i&gt;Ocypus &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1819, subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus &lt;/i&gt;Mulsant &amp; Rey, 1876. Section 4</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The paper deals with the species of the &lt;i&gt;picipennis-&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;fuscatus-lineages&lt;/i&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt; Mulsant &amp; Rey, 1876 of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1819, known to occur at present on the territory of the People’s Republic of China, in the Russian Far East, and in Japan. Eight species are treated, all previously described: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1793), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helleni&lt;/i&gt; (J. Müller, 1926), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aenescens&lt;/i&gt; Eppelsheim, 1889, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inexspectatus&lt;/i&gt; Eppelsheim, 1887, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shiretokensis&lt;/i&gt; Hayashi, 2008, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graeseri&lt;/i&gt; Eppelsheim, 1887, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscatus&lt;/i&gt; (Gravenhorst, 1802) and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigroaeneus&lt;/i&gt; Sharp, 1889. Based on the study of the type material, the following new synonymies are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Staphylinus&lt;/i&gt; (Pseudocypus) &lt;i&gt;rambouseki&lt;/i&gt; J. Müller, 1925 and &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscatoides&lt;/i&gt; Coiffait, 1964 are placed in synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; (Pseudocypus) &lt;i&gt;graeseri&lt;/i&gt; Eppelsheim, 1887. &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eppelsheimi&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1887 is transfered to the genus &lt;i&gt;Miobdelus&lt;/i&gt; Sharp, 1889 (comb. nov.); &lt;i&gt;Miobdelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montivagus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2001 becomes a junior objective synonym of it (syn. nov.). Lectotypes are designated for &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helleni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rambouseki,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigroaeneus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eppelsheimi.&lt;/i&gt; Neotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graeseri&lt;/i&gt; Eppelsheim, 1887. Each species is described, illustrated and all available distributional and bionomic data are given. A key to the species of the &lt;i&gt;picipennis-&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;fuscatus-lineages&lt;/i&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus,&lt;/i&gt; that occur in People’s Republic of China, in the Russian Far East, and in Japan, is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Staphylininae; &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt;; subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic; mainland China; Russian Far East; Japan; taxonomy; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ale</firstname>
          <lastname>Smetana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Asian &lt;i&gt;Hydroscapha&lt;/i&gt;, with comments on male-female association of co-occuring species (Coleoptera, Myxophaga, Hydroscaphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four syntopically co-occuring species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hydroscapha&lt;/i&gt; LeConte, 1874 are recorded at three adjacent hygropetric localities in the Indian state of Meghalaya (Khasi Hills). Association of males with conspecific females was recognized as a crucial problem for the taxonomic treatment of these taxa. Antennal morphology and abundance data of all collected morphotypes and their presence/absence at each locality were used for this association; most of these data are, however, shown as insufficient for a reliable association due to intraspecific variability (in the case of antennal morphology) or incomplete knowledge of seasonal dynamics (in the case of relative abundance of males versus females). Utilizing male characters separately from those of females is suggested as a possible solution. Following this approach, updated identification keys for males and females of Asian &lt;i&gt;Hydroscapha&lt;/i&gt; and tables summarizing useful diagnostic characters are provided. Disadvantages of this approach are also discussed. The examined samples include two species described as new (Hydroscapha &lt;i&gt;khasiorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rajani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.)&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; Löbl, 1994, which is recorded in India for the first time. A fourth species currently represented by one specimen only is left unidentified.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myxophaga; Hydroscaphidae; &lt;i&gt;Hydroscapha&lt;/i&gt;; sexual dimorphism; morphology; hygropetric habitats; identification key; new species; Oriental Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myxophaga</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Fikáček</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hana</firstname>
          <lastname>Ípková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-48</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Philothalpus &lt;/i&gt;Kraatz from Peru (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae, Xanthopygina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Philothalpus&lt;/i&gt; Kraatz, 1857 are described from Peru, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;juanecoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Cusco) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucieae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Junin). Photographs and drawings of the diagnostic characters are provided. Both species are included in the key to &lt;i&gt;Philothalpus&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Staphylinidae; &lt;i&gt;Philothalpus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; identification key; Neotropical region; rove beetles; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Staphylinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Angelico</firstname>
          <lastname>Asenjo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cibele</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ribeiro-Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Synopsis of &lt;i&gt;Lytopsenella &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer (Hymenoptera: Bethylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lytopsenella&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1905, is a Bethylinae genus with two species and is hitherto restricted to southern Chile. The genus is recognized by having the marginal cell in the fore wing closed and elongate. The goal of this study is to summarize the taxonomic knowledge of the species. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;herbsti&lt;/i&gt; (Kieffer, 1904) and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testaceicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Kieffer, 1910) are revised and illustrated. Additional taxonomic variations are added and geographic distributions are broadened. &lt;i&gt;Lytopsenella&lt;/i&gt; is recorded from Argentina for the first time. A key for both species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hymenoptera; Bethylidae; &lt;i&gt;Lytopsenella&lt;/i&gt;; Taxonomy; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hymenoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Celso</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-64</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the final instar nymph of &lt;i&gt;Homeoura nepos &lt;/i&gt;(Selys, 1876) (Odonata: Coenagrionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kenneth</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tennessen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
