<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2247.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Oct. 2009</title>
    <volume>2247</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-10-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The status of the amphibian nomina created by Merrem (1820) and Ritgen (1828)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In a poorly known work, Ritgen (1828) published an unconventional taxonomy and nomenclature of amphibians and reptiles. This work was an expansion of the taxonomic system of Merrem (1820) for these animals. After a survey of the nomenclatural status of the few supraspecific nomina used in Merrem (1820) for amphibians, in the current sense of this term, we ascertain the nomenclatural status of all the nomina created by Ritgen (1828) for genera and higher taxa including these animals. We designate nucleospecies (type-species) for his five new generic nomina, which results in making them invalid junior synonyms of nomina currently considered valid. Among the 21 nomina which he created for higher amphibian taxa, two prove to be the valid senior synonyms, following the Rules suggested by Dubois (2006a), of nomina used by Frost &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2006), and the same is true for two other such nomina created earlier by Merrem (1820). This example shows how these Rules allow to stabilize automatically and objectively the higher nomenclature in zoology, without recourse to interpretations, “opinion” or use of the “principle of authority”, which currently predominates in this field.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Merrem; Ritgen; amphibians; higher taxa nomenclature; Rules; “principle of authority”; synonymy; &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia&lt;/i&gt;; first-reviser action</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Merrem</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annemarie</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new, large species of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis &lt;/i&gt;Méhelÿ 1904 (Anura: Microhylidae) from the Iquitos region, Amazonian Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Microhylidae) from lowland rainforests in the western Amazon basin of Peru (near Iquitos, Departamento de Loreto). The species differs from congeners in the Amazon basin by its large size (it is the largest known &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; species), bright yellow iris, a grey dorsum with reddish blotches posteriorly and on limbs, and a creamy white venter with bold dark mottling with pale centers. The new species also differs from two other sympatric &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; species at 12S–16S mitochondrial DNA (6.1% and 11.9% sequence divergence between the new species and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventrimaculata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bassleri,&lt;/i&gt; respectively). A comparison of the new species with other microhylids found in the western Amazon basin is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; new species; terrestrial frog; Peru; mitochondrial DNA; Microhylidae; &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devriesi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura; new species; terrestrial frog; Peru; mitochondrial DNA; Microhylidae; &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devriesi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Chris</middlename>
          <lastname>Funk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cannatella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-50</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Catalogue of type specimens of invertebrates in the collection of the Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amazônia, Manaus, Brazil. V. Arachnida: Araneae, Opiliones and Scorpiones</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A catalogue of type specimens of Araneae, Opiliones and Scorpiones deposited in the Invertebrate Collection of the Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amazônia (INPA), Manaus, Brazil, is presented. There are 52 holotypes and 99 lots of paratypes for 68 species of Araneae; 6 holotypes and 18 lots of paratypes for 7 species of Opiliones; and 19 holotypes and 20 lots of paratypes for 19 species of Scorpiones.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazon region; Arthropod; type material; INPA; zoological collection; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazon region</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Regiane</firstname>
          <lastname>Saturnino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lúcia</middlename>
          <lastname>Tourinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Clarissa</firstname>
          <middlename>Salette</middlename>
          <lastname>De Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renner</firstname>
          <middlename>L. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Baptista</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Célio</firstname>
          <lastname>Magalhães</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">ErratumLicciano, M. Giangrande, A. and Gambi, M. C. (2009) A new genus of Sabellidae (Annelida, Polychaeta) from Antartica, with discussion of relationships among plesiomorphic genera within Sabellinae. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2226, 28-42.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
