<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2289.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Nov. 2009</title>
    <volume>2289</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the pontoniine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Rapipontonia &lt;/i&gt;Marin, 2007 (Decapoda: Caridea: Palaemonidae), with the description of a new species from the Indo-West Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of hydroid-associated pontoniine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Rapipontonia&lt;/i&gt; Marin, 2007 is presented. The genus is characterized by a highly specific prehensile mechanism of the ambulatory pereiopods that allows clinging to their hosts. A new species is described from Vietnam and Indonesia distinguished from the most similar species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paragalene&lt;/i&gt; Marin, 2007, by longer rostrum, longer carpus of the minor second pereiopod in females and the number of unpaired spines on the distoventral margin of propodus of the ambulatory pereiopods. A new record of &lt;i&gt;Rapipontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galene&lt;/i&gt; (Holthuis, 1951) from Hawaii significantly extends the known range of the species. A revised key for the identification of all species of the genus is given. Based on morphology of mature females and distribution of individuals per hosts observed in Vietnam, a sex-role reversal mechanism is suggested for the first time within the subfamily.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Rapipontonia&lt;/i&gt;; hydroid-associated; new records; new species; sexual dimorphism; sex-role reversal</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Botryllid species (Tunicata, Ascidiacea) from the Mediterranean coast of Israel, with some considerations on the systematics of Botryllinae </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Several botryllid colonies of the genus &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; from the Mediterranean coast of Israel are analysed. Three species are described: &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leachii,&lt;/i&gt; which differs because of its smaller size, from specimens collected from other European seas and is considered a case of dwarfism due to the particular hydrological conditions of the study area; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anceps,&lt;/i&gt; a species originally described from the Indo-Pacific region, which probably migrated from the Red Sea; and &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;israeliense,&lt;/i&gt; a new species. The distinction between the genera &lt;i&gt;Botryllus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; is discussed, and the original Milne-Edwards diagnosis based on differences in the structure of the system is recognised as still valid. Lastly, the diagnostic features usually employed in specific taxonomic determinations of Botryllinae are analysed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; ascidians; &lt;i&gt;Botryllus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;israeliense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Israel Mediterranean Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Riccardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Brunetti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-32</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Aphanodactylidae, a new family of thoracotreme crabs (Crustacea: Brachyura) symbiotic with polychaete worms</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The pea crabs of the family Pinnotheridae De Haan, 1833, have traditionally been recognised on the basis of their simplified external morphology, modified third maxillipeds, and general habit of living in association with invertebrate hosts, usually bivalve molluscs. Recent morphological and molecular studies of Pinnotheridae show that it is not a natural group as traditionally conceived. The subfamily Asthenognathinae Stimpson, 1858, actually belongs in the Varunidae H. Milne Edwards, 1853, and the subfamily Tritodynamiinae Števčić, 2005, is part of the Macrophthalmidae Dana, 1851. However, several ‘pinnotherid’ genera that are superficially similar to asthenognathines and allied to &lt;i&gt;Aphanodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Tesch, 1918, appear to form a discrete group, but lack the chief synapomorphy of Pinnotheridae, namely, the highly modified maxilliped 3. Moreover, &lt;i&gt;Aphanodactylus&lt;/i&gt; and allies do not share synapomorphies with of any presently recognised thoracotreme family. A new family, Aphanodactylidae, is therefore established for &lt;i&gt;Aphanodactylus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gandoa&lt;/i&gt; Kammerer, 2006, &lt;i&gt;Uruma&lt;/i&gt; Naruse, Fujita &amp; Ng, 2009, and a new genus and species described herein, &lt;i&gt;Gustavus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mecognathus.&lt;/i&gt; Aphanodactylids (where known) are symbiotic with terebellid polychaete worms and share short, stout, ambulatory legs with one or more spines lining the flexor margins of the ischiomeri of at least some of the ambulatory legs; a row of distal flexor spines on the ambulatory propodi opposing a claw-like dactylus; very short ambulatory dactyli that are less than half the respective propodus length; and marked sexual dimorphism in which the female is distinctly wider than the male. The phylogenetic position of Aphanodactylidae remains to be determined but the morphology of the third maxillipeds and the position of the male gonopore suggests that it may belong in the Pinnotheroidea, to which it is tentatively assigned. Each genus of the Aphanodactylidae is diagnosed and illustrated, and a key to the genera provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Brachyura; Thoracotremata; Pinnotheroidea; Aphanodactylidae; Pinnotheridae; symbiosis; Polychaeta; Terebellidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-47</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of the Neotropical spider genus &lt;i&gt;Enna&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae, Lycosoidea, Trechaleidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Currently, 24 species are known for the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Enna&lt;/i&gt; O. Pickard-Cambridge, from North, Central and South America, of which six are known from Brazil. In this study four new species are described and illustrated based on female specimens from the Southeastern and Southern Brazilian states of Minas Gerais, São Paulo, Rio de Janeiro and Paraná. &lt;i&gt;Enna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trivittata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;segredo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meridionalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caparao&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from all known species by the general shape of the epigynum. New records in Brazil are presented for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;braslandia&lt;/i&gt; Silva, Lise &amp; Carico and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;redundans&lt;/i&gt; (Platnick).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; new species; distribution; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Estevam</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Cruz</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arno</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-54</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Nannosquilla &lt;/i&gt;(Stomatopoda: Nannosquillidae) from the Western Atlantic Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Nannosquillidae contains thirteen genera, one of which is &lt;i&gt;Nannosquilla,&lt;/i&gt; composed of twenty-five species. The genus is distributed on both sides of the American continent, but contains no amphi-American species, and only one species in Indonesia. During surveys conducted in the Potiguar Basin, Rio Grande do Norte state/BR, a new species, &lt;i&gt;Nannosquilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;potiguara,&lt;/i&gt; was found. The new species is similar to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmitti,&lt;/i&gt; sharing the characters of seven intermediary fixed teeth in the posterior margin of telson on both side of the submedians movable tooth, and the inner spine on the uropodal protopod being longer than the outer. The two species differ in the number of teeth of the raptorial claw, in the morphology of rostral plate, and in the median projection of telson. From the Brazilian coast only one other species, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dacostai,&lt;/i&gt; has previously been recorded. It is similar to new species in the subpentagonal rostral plate and the inner spine of uropodal protopod being longest, but &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;potiguara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differ by a larger number of teeth on the dactylus of the raptorial claw and by fixed teeth on each side of the submedian movable teeth at telson. A key to the Atlantic species of &lt;i&gt;Nannosquilla&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lysiosquilloidea; new taxa; Potiguar Basin; Rio Grande do Norte; Northeast; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lysiosquilloidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Débora</firstname>
          <middlename>Lucatelli</middlename>
          <lastname>De Albuquerque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petrônio</firstname>
          <middlename>Alves</middlename>
          <lastname>Coelho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-60</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comments on the snake-eel genus &lt;i&gt;Xyrias &lt;/i&gt;(Anguilliformes: Ophichthidae) with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Comments on the snake-eel genus &lt;i&gt;Xyrias&lt;/i&gt; (Anguilliformes: Ophichthidae) with the description of a new species. &lt;i&gt;Xyrias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chioui,&lt;/i&gt; a new robust snake-eel species, subfamily Ophichthinae, is described on the basis of a specimen caught at 60–70 m depth on a benthic longline off Changbin, Taitung County, eastern Taiwan. It is distinguished from its congeners by having fewer vertebrae (126), 3 postorbital cephalic pores, and biserial rather than multiserial mandibular dentition. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Xyrias&lt;/i&gt; is provided. Additional records of &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;revulsus&lt;/i&gt; from the Arafura Sea and off New South Wales, Australia, extend its depth range from a few to 300 meters. The generic diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Xyrias&lt;/i&gt; is expanded such that the maxillary dentition ranges from a biserial to a multiserial condition.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ophichthidae; &lt;i&gt;Xyrias&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ophichthidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccosker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wei-Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-67</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">ErratumNg, H. H. &amp; Hadiaty, R. K. (2009) &lt;i&gt;Ompok brevirictus&lt;/i&gt;, a new catfish (Teleostei: Siluridae) from Sumatra. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2232, 5060.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
