<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2068.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Apr. 2009</title>
    <volume>2068</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-04-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the current knowledge of the systematics of Onchidiidae (Mollusca: Gastropoda: Pulmonata) with a checklist of nominal species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Because Onchidiidae (Mollusca: Gastropoda: Pulmonata) has been understudied since the last experts were active more than 70 years ago, systematics of this taxon is in a state of confusion: The nomenclatural status of most species names is unknown; the current supra-specific classification, largely based on Labbé’s work, has not been revised since the 1930s and needs to be re-evaluated through a modern, phylogenetic approach. A checklist of all 143 species names available in Onchidiidae is provided, as a first step towards a systematic revision. In addition, type material information (all existing types were examined by the author), type locality, and comments on the current taxonomic status and classification are provided for each species name. Present state of knowledge of the higher-level systematics of Onchidiidae is also briefly reviewed. Species diversity based on traditional generic taxa is presented. Finally, type localities are listed by region, worldwide, and interesting questions of biogeography are mentioned.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Alpha taxonomy; biodiversity; nomenclature; systematic revision</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Alpha taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Benoît</firstname>
          <lastname>Dayrat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Helobdella &lt;/i&gt;Blanchard 1896 (Hirudinida: Rhynchobdellida: Glossiphoniidae) from Taiwan, with a checklist of hirudinea fauna of the island</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this study, two new species of &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; leeches, &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;octatestisaca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melananus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and a newly recorded species, &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;europaea,&lt;/i&gt; are reported. Morphological characters and DNA barcode analysis were used to identify the three new species. The differences between these species and other morphologically congeneric species were also compared. In addition, the potential ecological impact of these species was discussed and a checklist of the hirudinea fauna in Taiwan, including eight species in Family Glossiphoniidae, four in Hirudinidae, two in Haemopidae, two in Haemadipsidae, and two in Salifidae, was provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;octatestisaca&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melananus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;europaea&lt;/i&gt;; DNA barcode; taxonomy; invasive species; Hirudinea; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;octatestisaca&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yi-Te</firstname>
          <lastname>Lai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chih-Han</firstname>
          <lastname>Chang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jiun-Hong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-46</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new &lt;i&gt;Tegenaria &lt;/i&gt;species (Araneae: Agelenidae) from Portugal</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genera complex &lt;i&gt;Tegenaria/Malthonica&lt;/i&gt; is a problematic spider group of the family Agelenidae. Besides taxonomical problems, new European species are described on a regular basis. Here two species from Portugal, &lt;i&gt;Tegenaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrientosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tegenaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incognita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; are described. Both species show a significant similarity to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bucculenta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feminea&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montigena,&lt;/i&gt; a species group restricted to the Iberian Peninsula. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrientosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; can be separated by the pyramidal shaped ventral branch of the conductor, the shape and arrangement of the RTA and the proportion of the bulblength to the cymbium-length, the run and shortness of the copulatory ducts with the diverticulae originating laterally and the irregularly sclerotized egg-shaped spermathecae, which are touching each other anteriorly. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incognita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; can be separated by the very broad lateral branch and the almost completely hidden lateroventral branch of the RTA, the shape of the conductor with the terminal end pointing towards posterior, the inwards directed epigynal teeth, the run and shortness of the copulatory ducts with the anteriorly originating diverticulae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Iberian Peninsula; Malthonica; new species; Spain; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Iberian Peninsula</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Angelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Bolzern</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luís</firstname>
          <lastname>Crespo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Cardoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Polygordiidae (Polychaeta) from the Australian region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The interstitial polychaete family Polygordiidae is recorded from Australia for the first time, based on two new species: &lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arafura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from continental shelf depths in the Arafura Sea, northern Australia, and &lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiarama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the continental shelf and slope off southeastern Australia. &lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiarama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; found at slope depths up to 1650 m, is the deepest record to date for the family, which has previously been recorded from intertidal habitats, shallow coastal waters and continental shelf depths.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arafura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiarama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Australia; continental shelf; continental slope</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arafura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polygordius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiarama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Australia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lynda</firstname>
          <lastname>Avery</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patricia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robin</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-04-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
