<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2275.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Oct. 2009</title>
    <volume>2275</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2009</year>
    <date_published>2009-10-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species of the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Aquilaspio &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Prionospio &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Spionidae: &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt;) from the southern coast of Turkey (Levantine Sea, eastern Mediterranean), with description of a new species and two new reports for the Mediterranean fauna</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study deals with species of the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (Aquilaspio) and &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (Prionospio) collected from various habitats and depths along the southern coast of Turkey in September and October 2005. The examination of a large collection of material revealed 10 species, of which one species, &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (P.) &lt;i&gt;ergeni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is new to science; two species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (P.) &lt;i&gt;depauperata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;krusadensis,&lt;/i&gt; are new to the Mediterranean fauna; and one species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;sexoculata,&lt;/i&gt; is new to the Turkish marine fauna. &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (P.) &lt;i&gt;ergeni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all other &lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; species in having three pairs of pinnate branchiae between chaetigers 2 and 4 and one pair of apinnate branchiae on chaetiger 5. Four species―P. (P.) &lt;i&gt;saccifera,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;sexoculata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (P.) &lt;i&gt;depauperata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;krusadensis―are&lt;/i&gt; aliens. The former two species could have been introduced to the Mediterranean from the Red Sea through the Suez Canal (Lessepsian migrants) and the others from the Pacific or Indian Oceans via ballast water of ships. The morphological, ecological, and distributional features of these species are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (Prionospio) &lt;i&gt;ergeni&lt;/i&gt;; Lessepsian; eastern Mediterranean Sea; Mediterranean coast of Turkey; alien species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Prionospio&lt;/i&gt; (Prionospio) &lt;i&gt;ergeni&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ertan</firstname>
          <lastname>Dagli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Melih</firstname>
          <middlename>Ertan</middlename>
          <lastname>Çinar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An annotated checklist of Echinodermata of Montenegro (the south Adriatic Sea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Published literature on the echinoderms of Montenegro (the south Adriatic Sea) is still very scarce. As a baseline for future studies that will enhance the knowledge of this fauna, we have compiled a checklist combining the existing published data with original data from a recent research. The checklist of the echinoderm fauna of the Montenegrin part of the south Adriatic Sea includes 57 species, grouped into 39 genera and 30 families, of which one crinoid (Crinoidea), 18 asteroids (Asteroidea), 9 ophiuroids (Ophiuroidea), 15 echinoids (Echinoidea), and 14 holothurians (Holothuroidea), which makes 56.4% of the species recorded so far in the Adriatic Sea, and 37.0% of the current total number of Mediterranean echinoderms. Ten recorded species are Mediterranean endemics, and two are Mediterranean subendemics. Six species are new for the fauna of Montenegro.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Echinoderms; checklist; new records; Adriatic Sea; Montenegro</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Echinoderms</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Slavica</firstname>
          <lastname>KaĆelan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sreten</firstname>
          <lastname>Mandić</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivica</firstname>
          <lastname>Radović</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jasmina</firstname>
          <lastname>Krpo-Ćetković</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-40</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ancistrus &lt;/i&gt;Kner, 1854 (Siluriformes: Loricariidae) from the Rio Iguaçu basin, Paraná State, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Rio Iguaçu basin, a tributary to the left bank of the Rio Paraná, is characterized by high endemism of fish species. Several specimens of &lt;i&gt;Ancistrus,&lt;/i&gt; family Loricariidae, were recently caught in that river and they were attributed to three new species that are described herein. They can be diagnosed from their congeners by having short maxillary barbels which are not free from the lower lip, by lacking pre-anal fin plate and also by morphometric and meristic traits. Comments on the geographic distribution of those species and congeners are also provided, in addition to a key to the species from the Río de La Plata and coastal basins from southern Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ancistrini; armored catfish; endemism; Neotropical fishes; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ancistrini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <middlename>Gasparetto</middlename>
          <lastname>Bifi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>Simone</middlename>
          <lastname>Pavanelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cláudio</firstname>
          <middlename>Henrique</middlename>
          <lastname>Zawadzki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-59</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius microps &lt;/i&gt;Thulin, 1928 and &lt;i&gt;H. pallidus &lt;/i&gt;Thulin, 1911 (Eutardigrada: Hypsibiidae) based on the type material from the Thulin collection</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microps&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus,&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed based on the type material from the Thulin collection. Those two species are very similar to each other and in the past their identification was based mostly on external claw morphology (identifications were very often doubtful and subjective). In this study we describe further differences between these two species. Apart from the claw morphology, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microps&lt;/i&gt; by: a larger body size, a wider buccal tube, longer placoids and placoid row and a longer pharynx. These two species differ also from other species attributed to the &lt;i&gt;dujardini&lt;/i&gt; group by having granular rather than rod-shaped macroplacoids and by the absence of a constriction in the first macroplacoid.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microps&lt;/i&gt; Thulin; 1928; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidus&lt;/i&gt; Thulin; 1911; &lt;i&gt;dujardini&lt;/i&gt; group; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Łukasz</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaczmarek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Łukasz</firstname>
          <lastname>Michalczyk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2009-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
