<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1572.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1572</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the characters of Centrolenidae (Amphibia: Anura: Athesphatanura), with comments on its taxonomy and the description of new taxa of glassfrogs</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Anurans of the family Centrolenidae are a diverse clade of arboreal frogs distributed across tropical America. Knowledge of their taxonomy, systematics, ecology, behavior, morphology, and other evolutionary aspects of their biology is deficient. Relationships among centrolenid species remain largely unresolved, with no satisfactory phylogenetic hypothesis, and none of the current genera has compelling evidence of monophyly. Further, understanding the phylogeny of glassfrogs is constrained by species-level taxonomic problems, including incorrect description of characters, incomplete analyses of intraspecific variation, and lack of appreciation of species diversity. Herein, we define and analyze the 23 characters that are useful, in combination, in diagnosing centrolenid species, and thereby provide a reference for the use of future workers. We propose revised classifications for the parietal and visceral peritoneal pigmentation, liver form and coloration of its associated hepatic peritoneum, nuptial excrescences, and hand ornamentation. We comment on the generic and species-level taxonomy of Centrolenidae, proposing the recognition of a new genus and describing a new species from Ecuador. We treat &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellifera&lt;/i&gt; Boulenger as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prosoblepon&lt;/i&gt; (Boettger), &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cardiacalyptum&lt;/i&gt; McCranie &amp; Wilson as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chirripoi&lt;/i&gt; (Taylor), and &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crybetes&lt;/i&gt; McCranie and Wilson as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colymbiphyllum&lt;/i&gt; (Taylor). We also present an annotated list of the species of glassfrogs from the Republic of Ecuador with some distributional remarks.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Centrolenidae; diagnostic characters; variation; peritoneal coloration; nuptial excrescences; taxonomy; synonyms; &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nymphargus&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Nymphargus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laurae&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Centrolenidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cisneros-Heredia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roy</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdiarmid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-82</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1571.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1571</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Skeletomusculature of Scelionidae (Hymenoptera: Platygastroidea): head and mesosoma</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The skeletomusculature of the head and mesosoma of the parasitoid wasp family Scelionidae is reviewed. Representatives of 27 scelionid genera are examined together with 13 non-scelionid taxa for comparison. Terms employed for other groups of Hymenoptera are reviewed, and a consensus terminology is proposed. External characters are redescribed and correlated with corresponding apodemes, muscles and putative exocrine gland openings; their phylogenetic importance is discussed. 229 skeletal structures were termed and defined, from which 84 are newly established or redefined. 67 muscles of the head and mesosoma are examined and homologized with those present in other Hymenoptera taxa. The presence of the cranio-antennal muscle, an extrinsic antennal muscle originating from the head capsule, is unique for Scelionidae. The dorsally bent epistomal sulcus and the corresponding internal epistomal ridge extend to the anterior margin of the oral foramen, the clypeo-pleurostomal line is absent and the tentorium is fused with the pleurostomal condyle. The frontal ledge is present in those scelionid genera having the anterior mandibular articulation located on the lateral margin of the oral foramen. The ledge corresponds to the site of origin of the mandibular abductor muscle, which is displaced from the genal area to the top of the frons. The protractor of the pharyngeal plate originates dorsally of the antennal foramen in Scelionidae. All scelionid genera have a postgenal bridge developed between the oral and occipital foramina. The propleural arm is reduced, muscles originating from the propleural arm in other Hymenoptera are situated on other propectal structures in Scelionidae. The profurcal bridge is absent. The first flexor of the fore wing originates from the posteroventral part of the pronotum in Scelionidae and Vanhorniidae, whereas the muscle originatesfrom the mesopleuron in all other Hymenoptera. The netrion apodeme anteriorly limits the site of origin of the first flexor of the fore wing. Three types of netrion are described on the basis of the relative position of the netrion apodeme and the posterior pronotal inflection. The occlusor muscle apodeme is absent in basal Scelionidae, the fan-shaped muscle originates from the pronotum. In &lt;i&gt;Nixonia&lt;/i&gt; the muscle originates posterior to the netrion apodeme. The skaphion apodeme crosses the site of origin of the longitudinal flight muscle. The lateral and dorsal axillar surfaces and the axillar carina are defined and described for the first time in Platygastroidea. The retractor of the mesoscutum is reported in Scelionidae and the variability of the muscle and corresponding skeletal structures within the family is described. The term sternaulus is redefined on the basis of the site of origin of the mesopleuro-mesobasalare muscle. The term speculum is adopted from Ichneumonidae and Cynipoidea taxonomy on the basis of the site of origin of the mesopleuro-mesofurcal muscle. The remnants of the mesopleural ridge, sulcus and mesopleural arm and pit and the putative border between the mesepisternum and mesepimeron is discussed. The mesopleural depressor of the mesotrochanter sensu Gibson 1985 originates from the anterior extension of the mesofurca and therefore the muscle is redefined and referred to in the present study as the lateral mesofurco-mesotrochanteral muscle. In &lt;i&gt;Nixonia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sparasion,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Idris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Gryon&lt;/i&gt; both the lateral and median mesofurco-mesotrochanteral muscles are present. The lateral mesofurco-mesotrochanteral muscle is present in Platygastridae. The second flexor of the hind wing at least partly originates from the posteriorly delimited area of the mesopectus in Scelionidae similarly to some other Proctotrupomorpha and Chalcidoidea. The serial homology of this area and the netrion is discussed. The possible serial homology of the medially elevated area of the metanotum and mesoscutellum and the usage of the term metascutellum in Apocrita is discussed with the descriptions of correlated internal structures. The anterior metanotal wing process is located on the independent humeral sclerite in Scelionidae, similar to other Apocrita except Cynipoidea. The metanotal depressor of the metatrochanter originates from the humeral sclerite in Scelionidae as well as in some other Proctotrupoidea. The metapleuron is extended secondarily dorsally of the metapleural ridge and corresponding metapleural sulcus in Scelionidae. In Telenominae, Gryonini and Baeini the metafurca is located posteriorly on the metadiscrimenal lamella.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scelionidae; morphology; terminology; comparative anatomy; skeletomusculature; parasitoid wasps</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scelionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Istvan</firstname>
          <lastname>Miko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lars</firstname>
          <lastname>Vilhelmsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Norman</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Johnson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lubomir</firstname>
          <lastname>Masner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zsolt</firstname>
          <lastname>Penzes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-78</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1570.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1570</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on the Australian stick insects (Phasmida), including a checklist of species and bibliography</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Australian phasmid fauna has been revised prior to publication of a field guide by the same authors. Six new genera are described: &lt;i&gt;Austrosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Cornicandovia&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Davidrentzia&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Micropodacanthus&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Paratropidoderus&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch and &lt;i&gt;Spinosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock. Sixteen new species from various parts of Australia are described and figured: &lt;i&gt;Candovia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robinsoni&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Rhamphosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palumensis&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Scionecra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;milledgei&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicerci&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;garradungensis&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larryi&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lewisensis&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rentzi&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whitei&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Spinosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doddi&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock [all Necrosciinae], &lt;i&gt;Pachymorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch [Pachymorphinae], &lt;i&gt;Davidrentzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valida&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch [Platycraninae], &lt;i&gt;Micropodacanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mouldsi&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Micropodacanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sztrakai&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, &lt;i&gt;Paratropidoderus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosus&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch and &lt;i&gt;Podacanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;keyi&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch [Tropidoderinae]. A number of new combinations are proposed, new synonyms and incorrect synonymy corrected following detailed examination of type and other material: 1. (Lonchodinae): &lt;i&gt;Austrocarausius&lt;/i&gt; Brock, 2000: &lt;i&gt;Carausius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macerrimus&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1907 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Austrocarausius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigropunctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Kirby, 1896). &lt;i&gt;Denhama&lt;/i&gt; Werner, 1912: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;austrocarinata&lt;/i&gt; (Otte &amp; Brock, 2005), &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longiceps&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner, 1907), &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striata&lt;/i&gt; (Sjöstedt, 1918) and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutrachelia&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) are transferred from &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875, the latter species also removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coenosa&lt;/i&gt; (Gray, 1833). &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; (Sjöstedt, 1918), a former &lt;i&gt;Marcenia&lt;/i&gt; species, is also transferred. &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 (= &lt;i&gt;Marcenia&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918 syn. n.): &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caurus&lt;/i&gt; (Tepper, 1905) comb. n. transferred from &lt;i&gt;Lonchodes&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835 (three new synonyms also reported for this species: &lt;i&gt;Bacillus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peristhenellus&lt;/i&gt; Tepper, 1905, &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunctatrix&lt;/i&gt; (Sjöstedt, 1918) and &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrogranulosus&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918). &lt;i&gt;Marcenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frenchi&lt;/i&gt; (Wood-Mason, 1877) is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculatus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875. 2. (Necrosciinae): &lt;i&gt;Austrosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Brock &amp; Hasenpusch, gen. n.: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carterus&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) comb. n., transferred from &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1893 (= &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filiformis&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 syn. n.). &lt;i&gt;Candovia&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Hyrtacus,&lt;/i&gt; along with the type species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coenosa.&lt;/i&gt; This has resulted in all former Australian species placed in &lt;i&gt;Parasipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 being transferred to &lt;i&gt;Candovia&lt;/i&gt; i.e. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aberrata&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner, 1907) comb. n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulata&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner, 1907) comb. n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosa&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner, 1907) comb. n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallida&lt;/i&gt; (Sjöstedt, 1918), comb. n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spurcata&lt;/i&gt; (Brunner, 1907) comb. n. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strumosa&lt;/i&gt; (Redtenbacher, 1908) comb. n. In addition, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evoneobertii&lt;/i&gt; (Zompro &amp; Adis, 2001) comb. n. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peridromes&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) comb. n. (including its new synonyms &lt;i&gt;Clitarchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1907, &lt;i&gt;Bacunculus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tener&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1907 and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cercatus&lt;/i&gt; (Redtenbacher, 1908)) are transferred from &lt;i&gt;Echetlus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875. &lt;i&gt;Cornicandovia&lt;/i&gt; Hasenpusch &amp; Brock gen n.: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australica&lt;/i&gt; (Redtenbacher, 1908) comb. n. &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1893: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bella&lt;/i&gt; (Tepper, 1905) comb. n. (new synonym &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovabdita&lt;/i&gt; Rentz &amp; John, 1987) is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Necroscia&lt;/i&gt; Serville, 1838, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caeca&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918 rev. stat., is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carterus&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859). &lt;i&gt;Rhamphosipyloidea&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908: &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandica&lt;/i&gt; (Sjöstedt, 1918) comb. n. is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Sipyloidea,&lt;/i&gt; also removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;carterus.&lt;/i&gt; 3. (Pachymorphinae): &lt;i&gt;Pachymorpha&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pasithoe&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplicipes&lt;/i&gt; Serville, 1838. 4. (Eurycanthinae). &lt;i&gt;Eurycantha&lt;/i&gt; Boisduval, 1835: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sifia&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calcarata&lt;/i&gt; Lucas, 1870. 5. (Phasmatinae): &lt;i&gt;Vetilia&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835, resulting in the transfer of these species to &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enceladus&lt;/i&gt; (Gray, 1835) comb. n. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thoon&lt;/i&gt; (Stål, 1875) comb. n. &lt;i&gt;Vetilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ligia&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuelfingi&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paula&lt;/i&gt; (Tepper, 1905) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aliena&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 are new synonyms of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nubilosa&lt;/i&gt; Tepper, 1905. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caprella&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) comb. n. is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Ctenomorpha&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1833. &lt;i&gt;Anchiale&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 (= &lt;i&gt;Ctenomorphodes&lt;/i&gt; Karny, 1923 syn. n.), resulting in the transfer of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;briareus&lt;/i&gt; (Gray, 1834) comb. n. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessulata&lt;/i&gt; (Gray, 1835) which is renamed &lt;i&gt;Anchiale&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;austrotessulata&lt;/i&gt; name nov., as &lt;i&gt;tessulata&lt;/i&gt; Gray is preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;Anchiale&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessulata&lt;/i&gt; (Goeze, 1778). &lt;i&gt;Austroclonistria&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Arphax&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875, as &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrulataa&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908) is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Arphax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolomedes&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859). &lt;i&gt;Ctenomorpha&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1833: &lt;i&gt;Paractenomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrotegmus&lt;/i&gt; (Tepper, 1887) is confirmed as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Ctenomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginipennis&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1833. &lt;i&gt;Hermarchus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polynesicus&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insignis&lt;/i&gt; (Kaup, 1871). &lt;i&gt;Paronchestus&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1908: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornutus&lt;/i&gt; (Tepper, 1905) comb. n. is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Acrophylla&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835 and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pasimachus&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) from &lt;i&gt;Onchestus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875. 6. (Platycraninae): &lt;i&gt;Megacrania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batesii&lt;/i&gt; (Kirby, 1896) is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Megacrania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alpheus&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859). 7. (Tropidoderinae): &lt;i&gt;Didymuria&lt;/i&gt; Kirby 1904: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virginea&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875 is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;violescens&lt;/i&gt; (Leach, 1814). &lt;i&gt;Lysicles&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1877: &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;periphanes&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood, 1859) comb. n. is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Echetlus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1875. &lt;i&gt;Tropidoderus&lt;/i&gt; Gray 1835: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;michaelseni&lt;/i&gt; Werner, 1912 is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;childrenii&lt;/i&gt; (Gray, 1833). 8. (Xeroderinae): &lt;i&gt;Cooktownia&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918 becomes a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Xeroderus&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1835, as &lt;i&gt;Cooktownia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plana&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918 is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Xeroderus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kirbii&lt;/i&gt; Gray, &lt;i&gt;1835.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jack</firstname>
          <lastname>Hasenpusch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-84</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1569.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1569</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the longicorn beetle genus &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus &lt;/i&gt;Hope 1833 (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae: Cerambycinae: Uracanthini) from Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A thorough taxonomic revision of the Australian &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; is provided, including a redefinition of the scope of the genus, descriptions and illustrations of new and previously known species, and a key to all species. The revised Australian &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; includes 39 species, eight of which are established as new to science: &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudogigas&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicoloratus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perthensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctulatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadristriolatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bistriolatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. Six new synonyms are proposed (senior synonyms last): &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multilineatus&lt;/i&gt; McKeown with &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventralis&lt;/i&gt; Lea, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentiapicalis&lt;/i&gt; McKeown with &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus&lt;/i&gt; Lea, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginellus&lt;/i&gt; Hope and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt; Lea (not Aurivillius) with &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bivitta&lt;/i&gt; Newman, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscostriatus&lt;/i&gt; McKeown with &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lateroalbus&lt;/i&gt; Lea, and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daviumbus&lt;/i&gt; Gressitt with &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; Lea. Dorsal views of all species are presented as photographs, terminalia of both sexes illustrated, and distributions mapped. The larvae of this genus are borers of at least 31 genera of trees and parasitic plants in 15 families (Asteraceae, Betulaceae, Casuarinaceae, Cupressaceae, Fabaceae, Loranthaceae, Myrtaceae, Pittosporaceae, Proteaceae, Rhamnaceae, Rosaceae, Rutaceae, Sapindaceae, Sterculiaceae, and Xanthorrhoeaceae), including some economically important crops such as citrus, lychee (or litchi), peach, plum, and apricot. Several species are important pests of orchards. &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt; adults visit flowers of various tree species and are attracted to the light.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerambycidae; Cerambycinae; &lt;i&gt;Uracanthus&lt;/i&gt;; Australia; revision</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerambycidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Duangrat</firstname>
          <lastname>Thongphak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Qiao</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-139</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1568.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1568</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An annotated checklist and keys to the species of Copepoda Harpacticoida (Crustacea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A checklist of the approximately 4300 species of Copepoda Harpacticoida is presented. It is prepared according to the opinions of the latest revisers and adopts the phylogenetic system of Seifried (2003). The opportunity is taken to formally propose replacement names for preoccupied taxa (p. 14). Comments are provided on other taxonomic issues. A dichotomous key to families is followed by tabular keys to species within each family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Harpacticoida; checklist; identification keys</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>B. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wells</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-872</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1567.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1567</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Micronoctuidae (Lepidoptera: Noctuoidea). Part 1, Taxonomy of the Pollexinae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the first part of a series of papers on the recently described family Micronoctuidae Fibiger, 2005. Part 1 includes the description of a new subfamily (Pollexinae), two new genera (Disca and &lt;i&gt;Pollex),&lt;/i&gt; two new subgenera (Bilobiana and &lt;i&gt;Proma),&lt;/i&gt; and 72 new species. One new combination is stated. Two previously described species are redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Micronoctuidae; taxonomy; new subfamily; new genera; new subgenera; new species; new combination</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Micronoctuidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Fibiger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-116</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1566.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1566</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1814 (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Ampithoidae) with descriptions of seventeen new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; is the largest and the most complex of the ampithoid amphipod genera. The species of this genus have been recorded globally. This study reviews the Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Amphithoe,&lt;/i&gt; increasing the known Australian fauna from three to 20 species, and provides a key and diagnoses to Australian species. The 17 new species are &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cookana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eremitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geographe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hyalos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meganae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;merimbula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ningaloo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parakava&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peronana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudongana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roly&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotunda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulladulla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ampithoidae; Australia; Amphipoda; taxonomy; new species; &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ampithoidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rachael</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-95</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1565.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1565</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ostracoda (Myodocopa) from Anchialine Caves and Ocean Blue Holes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eleven stygobitic myodocopid ostracodes (two new–Danielopolina &lt;i&gt;palmeri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Spelaeoecia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hox)&lt;/i&gt; in the Order Halocyprida are reported from anchialine waters in 11 inland blue holes in Bahamas. One stygobitic halocyprid ostracode is reported from two localities in Bermuda, and one from a cave in Mexico. A new subfamily, Spelaeoeciinae, is proposed to contain the genus &lt;i&gt;Spelaeoecia,&lt;/i&gt; and the subfamily Deeveyinae is elevated to family status. Two new species of cladocopid ostracode (Pseudopolycope &lt;i&gt;helix&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pontopolycope&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;storthynx),&lt;/i&gt; are described from a cave in Mexico and an oceanic blue hole in the Bahamas. Nine species of myodocopid ostracodes (four new—Rutiderma &lt;i&gt;flex,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eusarsiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;syrinx,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eusarsiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fax,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Synasterope&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matrix)&lt;/i&gt; in the Suborder Myodocopina and one species in the Suborder Halocypridina are reported from ocean blue holes in the Bahamas. This is the first report of a halocyprid living in both an inland and ocean blue hole in the Bahamas. The sarsiellid genus &lt;i&gt;Dantya&lt;/i&gt; Kornicker &amp; Cohen 1978 is reported for the first time in the Bahamas, but the single juvenile specimen is left in open nomenclature as &lt;i&gt;Dantya&lt;/i&gt; sp. A. The development of &lt;i&gt;Deeveya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bransoni&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Eusarsiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;syrinx&lt;/i&gt; is described in detail. With the exception of one species of &lt;i&gt;Danielopolina&lt;/i&gt; from deep waters of the South Atlantic, all other species of &lt;i&gt;Danielopolina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Spelaeoecia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Deeveya&lt;/i&gt; have been previously found only in inland, anchialine caves. The discovery of &lt;i&gt;Deeveya&lt;/i&gt; inhabiting deeper, hydrologically-isolated waters in ocean blue holes, which are otherwise comparable to classical anchialine environments, has raised questions concerning the geographic limits to the anchialine habitat and its supposed reliance on terrestrial inputs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Halocyprida; Myodocopida; Ostracoda; anchialine caves; blue holes; Bahamas; Mexico; Bermuda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Halocyprida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kornicker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Iliffe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Harrison-Nelson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-151</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1564.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1564</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Annotated checklist of the rotifers (Phylum Rotifera), with notes on nomenclature, taxonomy and distribution</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Phylum Rotifera comprises about 2030 known species classified in three main groups, the marine Seisonida (3 species), the Monogononta (1570 species) and the unique, exclusively parthenogenetic Bdelloidea with 461 clonal species. Here I present an annotated checklist of the taxon, giving the global distribution of the valid species. This checklist contains over 3,000 available names at the genusand species-group level, including valid names and a non-comprehensive list of synonyms. A number of taxonomic and nomenclatural suggestions following from the review is presented. Suggestions include several new synonyms and two &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nova:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dissotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kostei&lt;/i&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Dissotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeata&lt;/i&gt; Koste, 1996 non Ehrenberg, 1838 (stat. &lt;i&gt;nov.,&lt;/i&gt; ex. &lt;i&gt;Dissotrocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hertzogi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeata)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lepadella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zigzag&lt;/i&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Lepadella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bractea&lt;/i&gt; Myers, 1934 non (Ehrenberg, 1838). This contribution also describes features of an on-line, global names database of the Rotifera, on which this checklist is based.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">biodiversity; biogeography; Rotifera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">biodiversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Segers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-104</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1563.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1563</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Identifying species of &lt;i&gt;Bythinella&lt;/i&gt; (Caenogastropoda: Rissooidea): A plea for an integrative approach</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Bythinella&lt;/i&gt; comprises many species throughout Europe, but species delimitation, traditionally based on shell morphology and genital anatomy, is often a matter of debate. Out of an ongoing large-scale project on the phylogeny of the genus, we analyzed the relationships of species occurring in the south Austrian province Carinthia and in neighboring Slovenia as a model for similar cases of systematic and taxonomic ambiguity. Our analyses based on sequence data of a fragment of COI comprising 638 bp, morphological and anatomical investigations confirmed the presence of three species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca&lt;/i&gt; (Gallenstein, 1848), &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robiciana&lt;/i&gt; (Clessin, 1890) and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angelitae&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov. for &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca&lt;/i&gt; (Frauenfeld, 1857). The latter, while genetically distinct, is morphologically and anatomically cryptic in that it can only be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca&lt;/i&gt; by the denticulation of the radular marginal teeth. &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robiciana,&lt;/i&gt; on the other hand, is morphologically well defined, but genetically not separable from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca,&lt;/i&gt; its stem species. Thus, taxonomy in &lt;i&gt;Bythinella&lt;/i&gt; has to be based on the integration of morphology, anatomy and genetics. Our phylogenetic analyses suggest that &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opaca&lt;/i&gt; has colonized Carinthia, which has largely been covered by glaciers during the last ice age, along two routes, one from the south and a second one from the southeast.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bythinella&lt;/i&gt;; Carinthia; cryptic species; DNA-barcoding; DNA-taxonomy; paraphyly; post-glacial colonization; punctuated equilibrium; Slovenia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bythinella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Haase</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Mildner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two species in the alpheid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1814, with remarks on &lt;i&gt;A. amazone&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951 (Decapoda, Caridea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the alpheid genus &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1814 are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sydneyensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described on the basis of several specimens collected near Sydney, New South Wales, Australia. This species is closely related to the polymorphic &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phyllocheles&lt;/i&gt; Banner &amp; Banner, 1983 known only from La Réunion in the southwestern Indian Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ivoiriensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described on the basis of a single specimen collected off Ivory Coast, West Africa. This species appears to be most closely related to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amazone&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951 from the tropical eastern Atlantic and the Mediterranean Sea. The morphological variability of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amazone&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phyllocheles,&lt;/i&gt; including polymorphism of the chelipeds, are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Alpheidae; &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Australia; West Africa; cheliped polymorphism; variability</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Alpheidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The shocking pink dragon millipede, &lt;i&gt;Desmoxytes purpurosea&lt;/i&gt;, a colourful new species from Thailand (Diplopoda: Polydesmida: Paradoxosomatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A shocking pink, very spiny new species of “dragon millipede”, &lt;i&gt;Desmoxytes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurosea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Thailand, Uthaithani province. Its behaviour suggests that its colouration is aposematic, like that of some bright red congeners. Relations of the new species to congeners are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; aposematic; Uthaithani province</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Henrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Enghoff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chirasak</firstname>
          <lastname>Sutcharit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Somsak</firstname>
          <lastname>Panha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-36</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new sphyrapodid species (Crustacea: Tanaidacea: Apseudomorpha) from southwestern Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Kudinopasternakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balanorostrata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudosphyrapus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quintolongus&lt;/i&gt; are described from Japan. &lt;i&gt;Kudinopasternakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balanorostrata&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by an acorn-shaped rostrum. It most closely resembles &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siegi&lt;/i&gt; (Viskup &amp; Heard, 1989), but can be distinguished by the shape of the rostrum, the number of setae on article 2 of the mandibular palp, and the setation on the outer lobe of the fixed endite of the maxilla. &lt;i&gt;Pseudosphyrapus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quintolongus&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by an unusually large lateral process on pleonite 5, which distinguishes it from all other species in the genus. Keys to species of &lt;i&gt;Kudinopasternakia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudosphyrapus&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Sphyrapodidae; &lt;i&gt;Kudinopasternakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balanorostrata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudosphyrapus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quintolongus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Keiichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kakui</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kajihara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shunsuke</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mawatari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-54</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the family Cyclocoelidae Stossich, 1902 with the proposal of two new subfamilies and the description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Morishitium &lt;/i&gt;Witenberg, 1928 from the common snipe, &lt;i&gt;Gallinago gallinago&lt;/i&gt;, from Texas, U.S.A.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on the definition of 6 basic body types in the group, the family Cyclocoelidae is revised with the erection of Skrjabinocoelinae n. subf. and Szidatitreminae n. subf., and the resurrection of the subfamily Hyptiasminae. Subfamily keys and keys to genera that accommodate the original 3 subfamilies (Cyclocoelinae, Ophthalmophaginae, and Haematotrephinae), the 3 additional subfamilies proposed, the 6 body types used in the revision, and the recently described genus &lt;i&gt;Selfcoelum&lt;/i&gt; are provided. &lt;i&gt;Morishitium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texanense&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from the common snipe, &lt;i&gt;Gallinago&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gallinago,&lt;/i&gt; in Texas, U.S.A., the genus &lt;i&gt;Neoallopyge&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Allopyge,&lt;/i&gt; and the genus &lt;i&gt;Neohyptiasmus&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Morishitium.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curlew; Cyclocoelidae; Cyclocoelinae; &lt;i&gt;Gallinago&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gallinago&lt;/i&gt;; Haematotrephinae; Hyptiasminae; key; &lt;i&gt;Morishitium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texanense&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Neoallopyge&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neohyptiasmus&lt;/i&gt;; Ophthalmophaginae; revision; Scolopacidae; Skrjabinocoelinae n. subf.; snipe; Szidatitreminae n. subf.; Texas; U.S.A.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curlew</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Norman</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dronen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1562.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1562</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the Chinese &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; Marshall (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Entiminae) with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Chinese species of the highland weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; (Marshall, 1916) are revised. One new species, &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiggyobensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described from Jiggyob, Tibet, China. A total of 26 &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; species are recorded from China. A key to &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; and its related genera, a key to all Chinese &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; species, and a diagnosis of each species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curculionidae; Entiminae; Key; &lt;i&gt;Hyperomias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiggyobensis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Tibet; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curculionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alonso-Zarazaga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Runzhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera karatolosi &lt;/i&gt;sp.n. and &lt;i&gt;E. mirzayani&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. (Orthoptera, Tettigoniidae), two new bushcrickets from Greece and Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karatolosi&lt;/i&gt; Mofidi-Neyestanak &amp; Quicke from Greece and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirzayani&lt;/i&gt; Mofidi-Neyestanak &amp; Quicke from Iran, two new species of bushcrickets (Orthoptera, Tettigoniidae: Platycleidini), are described and distinguished from closely related species based on morphology. Species relationships within &lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera&lt;/i&gt; Maran are discussed and some species are given new assignments. A simplified illustrated identification key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera&lt;/i&gt; is provided to accommodate the new species. They are being described since they have been used to generate DNA sequence data that will be published elsewhere as part of a phylogenetic study of the tribe Platycleidini.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera&lt;/i&gt;; Platycleidini; new species; description; morphology; Mediterranean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupholidoptera&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohsen</firstname>
          <lastname>Mofidi-Neyestanak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Donald</firstname>
          <middlename>L. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Quicke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stipesoculus&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of micropterous Mezirinae (Hemiptera: Aradidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new micropterous aradid, &lt;i&gt;Stipesoculus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;productus&lt;/i&gt; Bai, Wu &amp; Cai, gen. &amp; sp. nov., from China, is described. A key to related genera is given and the diagnostic morphological features of new genus are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Aradidae; Mezirinae; &lt;i&gt;Stipesoculus&lt;/i&gt;; China; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiaoshuan</firstname>
          <lastname>Bai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhiyi</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wanzhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-61</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of new genus and species of Ochlerini from Central America (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae: Discocephalinae)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described for &lt;i&gt;Stalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trisinuatus&lt;/i&gt; Rolston; the external genitalia of the latter are redescribed; and a new species is described from Costa Rica, &lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rolstoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trisinuatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rolstoni&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Stalius&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parastalius&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Viviana</firstname>
          <middlename>Cauduro</middlename>
          <lastname>Matesco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jocelia</firstname>
          <lastname>Grazia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>Alexandre</middlename>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1561.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1561</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Insects found in birds' nests from Argentina. Part I: a bibliographical review, with taxonomical corrections, comments and a hypothetical mechanism of transmission of cimicid bugs</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A bibliographical review of the insects found in birds’ nests from Argentina is herein presented. The bird species are cited as they were originally recorded in the respective publications, but their nomenclature is updated. For each kind of nest, the data are ordered in the following manner: by insect order, family, subfamily and species (references, without locality) and by province: locality with specimens when stated (reference with locality data). Comments on nomenclature and some corrections are included under the respective notes. Three items that have received most attention were the hematophagous Reduviidae: Triatominae, Cimicidae, and the larvae of &lt;i&gt;Philornis&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Muscidae). Identifications of other insects are scarce, and were explicitly mentioned in only three short works, and in an anecdotal manner in other papers. In general, insects found in birds’ nests may be grouped by ecological guilds (predators, hematophagous parasitoids, detritivores, phytophagous and some predator insect hibernants, and inquilines), permanency (temporal and permanent residents) inside the nests, and according to their direct relationship to the birds. A transmission mechanism is hypothesized for the hematophagous bugs of the family Cimicidae based upon data on birds that nidificate in nests of other birds. Some new records are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Insects; birds’ nests; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Insects</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paola</firstname>
          <lastname>Turienzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Osvaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>Di</middlename>
          <lastname>Iorio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of the genera &lt;i&gt;Acerentulus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Brasilidia&lt;/i&gt; (Protura: Acerentomidae) from China, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Acerentulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Brasilidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jilinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Jilin Province, northeastern China, are described and illustrated in the present paper. All specimens are deposited in Shanghai Entomological Museum (SEM), Institute of Plant Physiology &amp; Ecology, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Protura; Acerentomidae; &lt;i&gt;Acerentulus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Brasilidia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Protura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-61</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new Species of &lt;i&gt;Tricorythodes &lt;/i&gt;Ulmer (Ephemeroptera: Leptohyphidae) from Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">At present 17 species of &lt;i&gt;Tricorythodes&lt;/i&gt; Ulmer are known from South America. Two new species are described here from Colombia: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uniandinus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from nymphs and imagines of both sexes, and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capuccinorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from males and females imagines. A brief diagnosis and illustrations to distinguish both species from the other of the genus are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Leptohyphidae; Neotropic; mayfly; Taxonomy; Colombia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Leptohyphidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Emmerich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1560.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1560</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some New Zealand Polyclads (Platyhelminthes, Polycladida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight species of poyclads from New Zealand are presented. Five species were already known to science, and are redescribed. Four of these species have been previously reported from New Zealand, the fifth, &lt;i&gt;Echinoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celerrima,&lt;/i&gt; is new to New Zealand. Two are new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chromoplana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chromoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sirena&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;Chromoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaikouris&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. One species belongs to a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Aotearoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ballantinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. n. sp. All new species and the new genus are described and discussed. The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Postenterogonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orbicularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Notoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suteri&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Notoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Leptostylochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; is reviewed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polycladida; Acotylea; Cotylea; New Zealand; species descriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polycladida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus australis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., a new Mandarin dogfish (Squaliformes: Squalidae) from the south-west Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Mandarin dogfish, &lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on specimens from southeastern Australia. Australian populations were previously considered to be conspecific with &lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbifer&lt;/i&gt; from the western North Pacific and Indonesia, but recent investigations revealed that the two forms differ in morphology and in the structure of the CO1 gene. &lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; has a smaller eye, shorter dorsal-caudal space, and smaller pectoral fins and dorsal fins and spines. These species are clearly separable from the only other congener, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asper,&lt;/i&gt; and all other members of the family Squalidae, by the possession of a greatly produced barbel on their anterior nasal flap. The new species occurs in temperate waters of eastern Australia, and possibly New Zealand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Squalidae; Australia; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cirrhigaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>White</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Last</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stevens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new and distinctive species of the hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Catapaguropsis&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Paguridae) from the South China Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diagnosis of the recently described hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Catapaguropsis&lt;/i&gt; Lemaitre &amp; McLaughlin, 2006 is emended to accommodate a second distinctive new species, &lt;i&gt;Catapaguropsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., which does not exhibit the sexual dimorphism described for the type species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandica&lt;/i&gt; Lemaitre &amp; McLaughlin, 2006. &lt;i&gt;Catapaguropsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is characterized by the marked reduction, in both sexes, of the posterior portions of the pleons, uropods, and telsons that are encased by cnidarians. In addition to the description and illustrations, this new species is compared and contrasted with species of other pagurid genera that occupy atypical carcinoecia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Paguridae; emended &lt;i&gt;Catapaguropsis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; unique carcinoecia; South China Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patsy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclaughlin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <lastname>Lemaitre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-41</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oligosarcus perdido&lt;/i&gt; (Characiformes, Characidae), a new species of freshwater fish from Serra da Bodoquena, upper Rio Paraguai basin, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oligosarcus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perdido,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of freshwater fish from Serra da Bodoquena, upper Rio Paraguai basin, Brazil, is described. The new species is distinguished from congeners by the number of lateral-line scales, number of scales around the caudal peduncle, and osteological characters. The osteology of this new species is also documented by stereomicroscopic photography of cleared and stained specimens. Ecological notes based on direct observation by scuba diving in the field are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; freshwater fishes; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcel</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cavallaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Otavio</firstname>
          <lastname>Froehlich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new ground dweller &lt;i&gt;Mesabolivar&lt;/i&gt; Gonzalez-Sponga, 1998 (Araneae: Pholcidae) from Blumenau, Santa Catarina, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new ground dwelling pholcid species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mesabolivar&lt;/i&gt; from Blumenau, Santa Catarina, Brazil, are described: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huberi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudilapsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;embapua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pholcidae; &lt;i&gt;Mesabolivar&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical region; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pholcidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ewerton</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Machado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brescovit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Francisco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-61</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Tagulis mystacinus &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae: Thomisidae) from Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tagulis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mystacinus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1895 from Sri Lanka is redescribed based on a pair of newly collected male and female specimens. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mystacinus&lt;/i&gt; may be separated from other thomisids by the presence of very peculiar leaf-shaped macrosetae immediately posterior to anterior and posterior lateral eyes. They also may be separated by details of their genitalia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Bominae; Crab spiders; Sri Lanka; Tagulini; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Suresh</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Benjamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ziyard</firstname>
          <lastname>Jalee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1559.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1559</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the Capsalinae (Monogenea: Capsalidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Capsalinae Baird, 1853 (Monogenea: Capsalidae) is revised based on a thorough review of original descriptions and examination of type museum material, where available, to validate species. A total of 262 type and voucher specimens was studied representing apparently 42 of the 60 currently described capsaline species. A combination of characters that should be independent of variation due to specimen preparation techniques was chosen to discriminate species. These characters include the presence/absence of papillae on the ventral surface of the haptor, the presence/absence and the morphology of haptoral accessory sclerites and the presence/absence of dorsomarginal body sclerites and their morphology and distribution. We consider that only 36 of the 60 nominal capsaline species are valid. We could find no support for &lt;i&gt;Caballerocotyla&lt;/i&gt; Price, 1960 and therefore we synonymise it with &lt;i&gt;Capsala&lt;/i&gt; Bosc, 1811. Under the current concept we recognise 22 species of &lt;i&gt;Capsala,&lt;/i&gt; 7 species of &lt;i&gt;Capsaloides&lt;/i&gt; Price, 1938, 3 species of &lt;i&gt;Nasicola&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1968 and 4 species of &lt;i&gt;Tristoma&lt;/i&gt; Cuvier, 1817. The following &lt;i&gt;Capsala&lt;/i&gt; species are considered valid: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albsmithi&lt;/i&gt; (Dollfus, 1962) n. comb.; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biparasitica&lt;/i&gt; (Goto, 1894) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caballeroi&lt;/i&gt; Winter, 1955; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foliacea&lt;/i&gt; (Goto, 1894) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gouri&lt;/i&gt; Chauhan, 1951; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gregalis&lt;/i&gt; (Wagner &amp; Carter, 1967) n. comb.; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interrupta&lt;/i&gt; (Monticelli, 1891) Johnston, 1929; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katsuwoni&lt;/i&gt; (Ishii, 1936) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; (Verrill, 1875) Johnston, 1929; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maccallumi&lt;/i&gt; Price, 1939; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magronum&lt;/i&gt; (Ishii, 1936) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manteri&lt;/i&gt; Price, 1951; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manteriaffinis&lt;/i&gt; (Mamaev, 1968) n. comb.; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinierei&lt;/i&gt; Bosc, 1811; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notosinense&lt;/i&gt; (Mamaev, 1968) n. comb.; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nozawae&lt;/i&gt; (Goto, 1894) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;onchidiocotyle&lt;/i&gt; (Setti, 1899) Johnston, 1929; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovalis&lt;/i&gt; (Goto, 1894) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paucispinosa&lt;/i&gt; (Mamaev, 1968) n. comb.; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pelamydis&lt;/i&gt; (Taschenberg, 1878) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;poeyi&lt;/i&gt; (Pérez-Vigueras, 1935) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pricei&lt;/i&gt; Hildago-Escalente, 1950. We consider the following &lt;i&gt;Capsaloides&lt;/i&gt; species valid: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornutus&lt;/i&gt; (Verrill, 1875) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristatus&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1968; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoffmannae&lt;/i&gt; Lamothe-Argumedo, 1996; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnaspinosus&lt;/i&gt; Price, 1939; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nairagi&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1968; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perugiai&lt;/i&gt; (Setti, 1898) Price, 1938; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinuatus&lt;/i&gt; (Goto, 1894) Price, 1938. The following &lt;i&gt;Nasicola&lt;/i&gt; species are deemed valid: &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; Kohn, Baptista-Farias, Santos &amp; Gibson, 2004; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hogansi&lt;/i&gt; Wheeler &amp; Beverley-Burton, 1987; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klawei&lt;/i&gt; Stunkard, 1962. Presently, we consider the following &lt;i&gt;Tristoma&lt;/i&gt; species valid: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adcoccineum&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1968; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adintegrum&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1968; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coccineum&lt;/i&gt; Cuvier, 1817; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;integrum&lt;/i&gt; Diesing, 1850. A list of new and re-established synonyms is provided. The status of each species is discussed in detail and a key to all capsaline species that we consider valid is presented. The following 5 capsaline species are considered to be &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirendae:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Caballerocotyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phillippina&lt;/i&gt; Velasquez, 1982; &lt;i&gt;Capsala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacotyle&lt;/i&gt; (Linstow, 1906) Johnston, 1929; &lt;i&gt;Tristoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuhrmanni&lt;/i&gt; Guiart, 1938; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levinsenii&lt;/i&gt; Monticelli, 1891; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uncinatum&lt;/i&gt; Monticelli, 1889. The importance of careful character selection to discriminate between capsaline species and the need for studies of live parasites to obtain additional characters based on reproductive structures is addressed. Hostspecificity in the Capsalinae is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Monogenea; Capsalidae; Capsalinae; &lt;i&gt;Caballerocotyla&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Capsala&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Capsaloides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nasicola&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tristoma&lt;/i&gt;; Istiophoridae; Molidae; Scombridae; Xiphiidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Monogenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leslie</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chisholm</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whittington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and morphogenesis of &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocrassum&lt;/i&gt; Wang and Nie, 1935, with redefinition of &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt; Sterki, 1878 (Protista: Ciliophora: Stichotrichia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A population of the rare species &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocrassum&lt;/i&gt; Wang and Nie, 1935, was discovered from a lagoon in the northern region of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, and its morphology was investigated through protargol-impregnation, scanning electron microscopy and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo&lt;/i&gt; observations. Morphogenetic events of cell division and physiological reorganization were described for the first time to this species. It was found that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocrassum&lt;/i&gt; has the ventral cirral rows organized in the same manner as &lt;i&gt;Pseudouroleptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudatus&lt;/i&gt; Hemberger, 1985. However two independent primordia VI, one for the proter and other for the opisthe, are generated intrakinetally from the rightmost ventral cirral row. In addition, dorsal kineties replicate entirely “de novo” and do not fragment. Based on the data obtained, the genus &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt; was redefined and the species currently assigned to it were classified into five groups according to current knowledge on their ciliature and the combination &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lentum&lt;/i&gt; (Biernacka, 1963) nov. comb. is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphisiellidae; Brazil; Ciliate; Spirofilidae; &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphisiellidae; Brazil; Ciliate; Spirofilidae; &lt;i&gt;Strongylidium&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thiago</firstname>
          <lastname>Da Silva Paiva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Inacio</firstname>
          <middlename>Domingos</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva-Neto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia gutui&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Apseudomorph Tanaidacean (Crustacea: Malacostraca: Peracarida) from the Australian northwest continental shelf</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gutui,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from specimens collected in depths of 78–83 m from the Northwest Continental Shelf of Australia. Of the four previously known species of &lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia&lt;/i&gt; Guţu, 1989, &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gutui&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deltoides&lt;/i&gt; (K. H. Barnard, 1914) and &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomassini&lt;/i&gt; Guţu, 1989 by having the outer flagella of the antennule with fewer than 9 articles and its distinctive armature on anterodorsal region of the carapace. It can be separated from &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alinati&lt;/i&gt; Guţu, 1989 and &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bajau&lt;/i&gt; Bamber and Sheader, 2005 by a combination of characters, including (1) a spatulate rostrum fringed with 20 or more blunt marginal teeth interspersed with 5–8 small plumose setae; (2) distinct ridges or tubercles on the carapace, (3) a well-developed, expanded lateral lobe on article 1 of the antenna (absent in &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bajau),&lt;/i&gt; and (4) 3–5 blunt spines (instead of 1 or 2) on the anterior margin of the basis of pereopod 2. A key to the five nominal species now comprising the genus &lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia&lt;/i&gt; is presented. &lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gutui&lt;/i&gt; represents the first record of its genus from Australian waters and the second for the genus in the eastern Indian Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Metapseudidae; &lt;i&gt;Julmarichardia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; NW Australian shelf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rebecca</firstname>
          <middlename>Kirk</middlename>
          <lastname>Ritger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1558.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1558</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of sympatric New Zealand&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;species of &lt;i&gt;Platynereis&lt;/i&gt;, with description of three new species additional to &lt;i&gt;P. australis&lt;/i&gt; (Schmarda) (Annelida: Polychaeta: Nereididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Metamorphosed, sexually mature &lt;i&gt;Platynereis&lt;/i&gt; adults captured swimming nearshore at night off the New Zealand coast had major morphological differences that indicated four similar sympatric species existed, where previously only &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; had been known. Simultaneous reproductive swarming of all taxa was possible at a locality. The three hitherto cryptic species are described as &lt;i&gt;Platynereis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahanga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kau&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karaka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov..&lt;/b&gt; Paragnath arrangement and chaetal morphology are near identical in all four species. Homogomph notopodial falcigers, which are distinctive in shape in some &lt;i&gt;Platynereis,&lt;/i&gt; are lacking in adults of this group of species. Pigmentation pattern differences and other minor variations are present in life in atokous (unmetamorphosed) benthic forms, but museum specimen atokes cannot be unambiguously separated into species by morphology. Heteronereid (metamorphosed) natatory forms of the four New Zealand species are distinct in several characters, including morphology of sperm papillae groups in males, and number of pre-natatory anterior segments in both sexes. Differences in size, habitat, peak spawning season, interbreeding, and juvenile development are noted. Morphology and biology are discussed in relation to other &lt;i&gt;Platynereis.&lt;/i&gt; Presence of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; group species beyond the continental shelf seas adjoining the three main islands is now undetermined except for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; at Chatham Islands, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahanga&lt;/i&gt; at the subantarctic Auckland and Campbell Islands, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karaka&lt;/i&gt; at Wanganella Bank; all prior reports of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; outside the New Zealand region need re-evaluation from specimens.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polychaeta; &lt;i&gt;Platynereis&lt;/i&gt;; heteronereid; Nereididae; taxonomy; cryptic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polychaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Geoffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Read</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A remarkable new species of &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; showing sexual dimorphism, with the transfer of &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Piassagera&lt;/i&gt; to the Hernandariinae (Opiliones, Gonyleptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1927 (Gonyleptidae: Hernandariinae), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Rio de Janeiro state, southeastern Brazil. It presents sexual dimorphism in leg IV, contrasting remarkably with the type species of the hitherto monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; and the closest genera (Piassagera Roewer, 1928 and &lt;i&gt;Pseudotrogulus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1932), which were all thought to have lost this dimorphism. The presence of sexual dimorphism in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt; implies a complex scenario of loss or reversal of this character. New records are given of type species of genus, &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrenus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1913, for which a lectotype is designated. New diagnoses are provided for Hernandariinae and &lt;i&gt;Multumbo.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Piassagera&lt;/i&gt; are transferred from the Gonyleptinae to the Hernandariinae.Uma nova espécie de &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1927, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; é descrita do estado do Rio de Janeiro. Ela apresenta dimorfismo sexual na perna IV, condição em notável contraste com a espécie-tipo do até então gênero monotípico &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; e com os gêneros mais relacionados, &lt;i&gt;Piassagera&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1928 e &lt;i&gt;Pseudotrogulus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1932, nos quais esse dimorfismo era considerado como perdido. A presença de dimorfismo sexual em &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt; sugere um complexo cenário de perda ou reversão desse dimorfismo. Também foram incluídos novos registros da espécie-tipo do gênero, &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrenus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1913, e um lectótipo é designado. Novas diagnoses para &lt;i&gt;Hernandariinae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; são apresentadas. &lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; e &lt;i&gt;Piassagera&lt;/i&gt; são aqui transferidos de Gonyleptinae para Hernandariinae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt;; armature of leg IV; Laniatores; Gonyleptinae; Atlantic Rain Forest; areas of endemism; Serra dos Órgãos</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Multumbo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorphicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcio</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dasilva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-37</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Establishment of the Vultocinidae, a new family for an unusual new genus and new species of Indo-West Pacific crab (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Goneplacoidea), with comments on the taxonomy of the Goneplacidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new family, Vultocinidae, is established for an unusual new genus and new species of crab (Crustacea: Brachyura: Goneplacoidea) here described from relatively deep waters in the central Philippines and Vanuatu. Although &lt;i&gt;Vultocinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anfractus,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, new species, superficially resembles pilumnid genera like &lt;i&gt;Lophoplax&lt;/i&gt; and pseudoziid genera like &lt;i&gt;Planopilumnus&lt;/i&gt; in its deeply sculptured carapace and leg surfaces, its male abdomen and gonopods appear to affiiliate it with the Goneplacidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; instead. However, its suite of many unusual characters requires the recognition of a new family for &lt;i&gt;Vultocinus.&lt;/i&gt; Comparisons of the Vultocinidae with the Goneplacidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; suggests that the subfamily Mathildellinae, presently regarded as a subfamily, should be recognised as a full family; and two other problematic constituent genera, &lt;i&gt;Progeryon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Conleyus,&lt;/i&gt; are also referred to their respective families in the Goneplacoidea. The genus &lt;i&gt;Paragalene&lt;/i&gt; is also referred to the Progeryonidae. The extent of the sterno-abdominal cavity along the thoracic sternites, structure of the posterior thoracic sternites, position of the press button of the male abdominal locking mechanism and form of the first four male abdominal segment as characters in the taxonomy of the Goneplacoidea is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Goneplacoidea; Goneplacidae; new family; new genus; new species; Philippine Islands; Vanuatu</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marivene</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Manuel-Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1557.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1557</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus pachydermus&lt;/i&gt;, and description of two new (extinct?) species of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; from Ecuador (Anura: Bufonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachydermus&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed on the basis of the retraced holotype and recently collected specimens. Comparisons with the holotype confirmed that this species occurs neither in Pacific Colombia, nor in the northeastern Cordillera of Ecuador, as proposed by previous authors. It occurs in the northwestern Andes of Peru and adjacent Ecuador. Populations from the Cordillera Oriental in northern Ecuador (some of them previously allocated to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachydermus)&lt;/i&gt; are described as a new species, which is distinguished from other &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; by size, coloration, and by having white digital pads that contrast with adjacent black phalanges. In addition, a population of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; from the Andes of southwestern Ecuador, previously included in the &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bomolochos&lt;/i&gt; complex, and having an aqua blue iris is described as a new species. We include osteological data of both new species. Predictions of numbers of species of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; to be discovered and described, as well as of numbers for Ecuadorian amphibian diversity, indicates that these faunas are yet largely undescribed. Because recent records of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachydermus&lt;/i&gt; and the two new species are lacking despite search efforts, we assume that they are possibly extinct, similar to many other Andean &lt;i&gt;Atelopus.&lt;/i&gt; Thus, we categorize these species either aspossibly extinct or, applying IUCN Red List criteria, as Critically Endangered. Current evidence suggests that amphibian extinctions in the Ecuadorian and Peruvian Andes have been more drastic than previously recognized.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Bufonidae; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;onorei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bomolochos;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petersi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachydermus;&lt;/i&gt; Ecuador; Extinction; Morphology; New species; Osteology; Peru; Systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura; Bufonidae; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;onorei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bomolochos;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petersi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachydermus;&lt;/i&gt; Ecuador; Extinction; Morphology; New species; Osteology; Peru; Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coloma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <lastname>Lotters</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duellman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfonso</firstname>
          <lastname>Miranda-Leiva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Benthic decapod crustaceans (Crustacea: Decapoda) of Cubagua Island, Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The crustacean decapod fauna of Cubagua Island in the Caribbean Sea, Venezuela, an island much affected by coastal upweling, was surveyed. A total of 178 species from 41 families were recorded, of which 56 species were new records for the island; eigth genera and six species were new records for Venezuela. Most species had previously been recorded from the the Caribbean province, 19.7% were endemic for the province, 64.1% had affinities to the Brazilian province, 57.3% to the Texan and Carolinian provinces and 45.5% showed continuous distributions across the provinces but showing less endemism and more affinities with Brazilian province than the general trends of distributions of decapods in the Caribbean. It appears that upwelling processes around the island hinders the development of the typical Caribbean marine ecosystems. The proximity with the northern limit of the Brazilian province also affects the biodiversity of the island.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caribbean Sea; Crustacea; Decapoda; upwelling; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caribbean Sea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Hernandez-Avila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfredo</firstname>
          <lastname>Gomez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Lira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lee</firstname>
          <lastname>Galindo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-45</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Archimonocelis&lt;/i&gt; Meixner, 1938 (Proseriata, Archimonocelididae) from southern Apulia (Italy)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A survey of the composition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Archimonocelis&lt;/i&gt; Meixner, 1938 in southern Apulia (Italy) revealed the presence of four species, three of which are new. &lt;i&gt;Archimonocelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scopulicola&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. has a straight stylet, provided with a girdle of 18 copulatory spines, and a chromosome set with n=10. In both &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cygnicollis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parastaresoi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., an accessory glandular organ, provided with spines, is present. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cygnicollis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is provided with a unique double-walled stylet. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parastaresoi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is similar to the western Mediterranean &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staresoi&lt;/i&gt; Martens &amp; Curini-Galletti, 1993; size and shape of accessory spines are the main discriminating features between the two species. In addition, numerous specimens of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carmelitana&lt;/i&gt; Martens &amp; Curini-Galletti, 1993 were found. A comprehensive discussion of the new species is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; marine biodiversity; meiofauna; Mediterranean; &lt;i&gt;Archimonocelis&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <lastname>Curini-Galletti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Valentina</firstname>
          <lastname>Delogu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paolo</firstname>
          <lastname>Campus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <lastname>Casu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caenotropus schizodon,&lt;/i&gt; a new chilodontid fish from the Rio Tapajos drainage, Brazil (Ostariophysi: Characiformes: Chilodontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caenotropus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schizodon,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Rio Tapajós, Rio Amazonas drainage. The new species is readily distinguished from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labyrinthicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mestomorgmatos&lt;/i&gt; by its bifid premaxillary teeth. &lt;i&gt;Caenotropus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schizodon&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculosus&lt;/i&gt; by its lack of teeth on the lower jaw, the dusky distal portions of the anterior dorsal-fin rays but without a distinct patch of dark pigmentation, and the possession of 28-30 lateral-line scales &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; 27 rarely 28. The hypothesis of a sister-species relationship of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schizodon&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labyrinthicus&lt;/i&gt; is supported by three synapomorphies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Neotropical region; Brazil; fish</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <lastname>Scharcansky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Alberto Santos</middlename>
          <lastname>De Lucena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lack of secondary sexual characters in a male of &lt;i&gt;Tsingymantis antitra&lt;/i&gt; confirms its position as most basal mantelline frog lineage</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Achille</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Raselimanana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <lastname>Glaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1556.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1556</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the hover wasp genus &lt;i&gt;Eustenogaster&lt;/i&gt; van der Vecht (Insecta: Hymenoptera; Vespidae, Stenogastrinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision is given for the stenogastrine genus &lt;i&gt;Eustenogaster&lt;/i&gt; van der Vecht, 1969, which is distributed from India to Southeast Asia and southern China. A total of 15 species, including three new species (E. &lt;i&gt;fumipennis&lt;/i&gt; Saito, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latebricola&lt;/i&gt; Saito, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinicauda&lt;/i&gt; Saito, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; are recognized in the genus. A key to species, descriptions of the new species, and notes on taxonomic status, morphological characters and distribution records of the previously described taxa are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Vespidae; Stenogastrinae; &lt;i&gt;Eustenogaster&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; distribution; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Vespidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Saito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun-Ichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kojima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;flagria &lt;/i&gt;group of &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt; Mohrig (Diptera, Sciaridae) in a biodiversity hot spot: nine new sympatric species from Kambaiti, Myanmar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flagria&lt;/i&gt; group is defined for the species bearing two or more mesial megasetae arising from a common basal body on the gonostylus. Nine new species are described from Kambaiti, Myanmar (Burma): &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acamptochaeta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicuspis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filigera,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flabellata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foveolata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigas,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligonema&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rima.&lt;/i&gt; Three additional new species were seen in the material from Kambaiti but were left unnamed because of the poor condition of the specimens. The total number of named sympatric &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt; species in Kambaiti is now 18.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sciaridae; &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Myanmar</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sciaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heikki</firstname>
          <lastname>Hippa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pekka</firstname>
          <lastname>Vilkamaa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Papua New Guinea genus &lt;i&gt;Elemacoris&lt;/i&gt; Miller (Hemiptera: Reduviidae: Harpactorinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of the Papua New Guinea genus &lt;i&gt;Elemacoris&lt;/i&gt; in the reduviid subfamily Harpactorinae are revised. Two species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt; Miller, 1958 and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doesburgi&lt;/i&gt; Zhao, Constant &amp; Cai, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described or redescribed, illustrated, and keyed. The diagnostic characters of the genus are modified. The type specimens of the new species are preserved in the Royal Belgian Institute of Natural Sciences.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Harpactorinae; &lt;i&gt;Elemacoris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Papua New Guinea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jerome</firstname>
          <lastname>Constant</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wanzhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a New Species of &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium &lt;/i&gt;Saussure (Hymenoptera, Vespidae, Eumeninae) from Taiwan with a Catalogue of the &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium &lt;/i&gt;Species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new eumenine species, &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taiwanum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Taiwan is described. Based on the examination of holotype, the subspecies &lt;i&gt;multifascitum&lt;/i&gt; Giordani Soika 1986 of &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxum&lt;/i&gt; is actually a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatum&lt;/i&gt; (Smith), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A catalogue of the nine species of &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium&lt;/i&gt; Saussure is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New species; &lt;i&gt;Pararrhynchium&lt;/i&gt;; Catalogue</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kim</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeong</firstname>
          <lastname>Kyu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Seiki</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamane</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1555.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1555</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the Neotropical spider genus &lt;i&gt;Oligoxystre &lt;/i&gt;Vellard 1924 (Theraphosidae, Ischnocolinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Oligoxystre&lt;/i&gt; Vellard 1924 is revised. &lt;i&gt;Pseudoligoxystre&lt;/i&gt; Vol 2001 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Oligoxystre&lt;/i&gt; and its typespecies, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bolivianum&lt;/i&gt; Vol 2001, is considered valid. The type-specimen of &lt;i&gt;Oligoxystre&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auratum&lt;/i&gt; Vellard 1924, type-species by original designation, is considered lost. No additional material matching the original description was found and therefore the species is diagnosed from the original description. Four new species, all from Brazil, are also described: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caatinga,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dominguense,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tucuruiense,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufoniger.&lt;/i&gt; Data on natural history of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bolivianum&lt;/i&gt; from field and captivity observations are presented. The genus &lt;i&gt;Cenobiopelma&lt;/i&gt; Mello-Leitão &amp; Arlé 1934 ) is based upon &lt;i&gt;Cenobiopelma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mimeticum&lt;/i&gt; Mello-Leitão &amp; Arlé 1934 for which no type was ever designated and hence both are considered nomina nuda.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Mygalomorphae; Ischnocolinae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudoligoxystre&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cenobiopelma&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Paulo Leite</middlename>
          <lastname>Guadanucci</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Aromobatidae: Allobatinae) exhibiting a novel reproductive behaviour</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Mabura Hill Forest Reserve, central Guyana, South America. The new species is distinguished from congeneric species by cryptic colouration, very small size, first finger longer than second, third finger not distinctly swollen in males, absence of lateral fringes on fingers and toes, complete lateral black band present, diffuse pale dorsolateral stripe present, diffuse, pale, partial oblique lateral stripe present, pale ventrolateral stripe present, throat in adult males pale, and unique advertisement call and reproductive behaviour. The new species occasionally deposits tadpoles in leptodactylid foam nests, which constitutes the first case of interspecific brood parasitism in frogs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spumaponens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Anura; Aromobatidae; Guyana; Mabura Hill Forest Reserve; reproductive behaviour</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spumaponens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Raffael</firstname>
          <lastname>Ernst</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-38</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new, toxic species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Dendrobatidae: Colostethinae) from the Cordillera Central of Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; is described from cloud forest in the Cordillera Central of Colombia at approximately 2100–2500 m above sea level. It is a riparian species not known to occur more than a few meters from the water’s edge. Specimens were collected in grassy vegetation and on and beneath rocks along streams and pools, in both primary forest and in or at the edge of forest clearings. Most specimens were collected during the day, but several were observed to be active at night. The new species differs from other species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; in lacking pale oblique lateral and ventrolateral stripes, possessing a pale dorsolateral stripe, lacking or having at most rudimentary toe webbing, and possessing a marbled or reticulated ventral color pattern. Adult males of the new species possess a swollen third finger and a gray or black throat. In life, the new species possesses bright lemonor golden-yellow flash marks on the axilla, groin, belly, and concealed surfaces of the thigh and shank, and bluish-white ventral coloration, and it exudes a milky secretion from the skin. The aqueous extract of the skin is toxic, but additional samples are required to determine the nature of the toxic compound(s).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; systematics; Amphibia; Dendrobatoidea; South America; cloud forest; alkaloid; toxicity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Taran</firstname>
          <lastname>Grant</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery of &lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt; Huys &amp; Gee, 1993 (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Pseudotachidiidae) with description of a new species from the Antarctic deep sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species diversity of Copepoda Harpacticoida in the deep sea of the Angola Basin (DIVA I expedition with RV &lt;i&gt;Meteor)&lt;/i&gt; and in the Weddell Sea (ANDEEP II expedition with RV &lt;i&gt;Polarstern)&lt;/i&gt; have been investigated. From the obtained multicorer samples two female specimens of &lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt; Huys &amp; Gee, 1993 were collected. The only specimen known before was described as &lt;i&gt;Psammis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longifurca&lt;/i&gt; by Bodin in 1968 from the northern Atlantic. In the present paper a new species &lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polaris&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from the Antarctic Weddell Sea is described. The monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt; within the Paranannopinae Por, 1986 can be confirmed by several new autapomorphies whereas the relation to other paranannopid taxa must remain open for the moment. The new findings implicate a widespread distribution of &lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt; from the northern to the southern Atlantic and even to the southern polar regions. Up to now all individuals that have been found occur exclusively at deep-sea sites and in very low abundances.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; systematics; distribution; deep sea; southern Atlantic; Weddell Sea; Copepoda Harpacticoida; deep sea meiofauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathypsammis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elke</firstname>
          <lastname>Willen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maximilian</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1554.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1554</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes malletei&lt;/i&gt; (Isoptera: Rhinotermitidae): a valid Nearctic subterranean termite from Eastern North America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt; Holmgren in North America has been in need of revision for years, but because of morphological ambiguity, traditional morphological identification of &lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt; species has always been difficult and unreliable. Analysis of termites, applying non-morphological genetic comparisons of mitochondrial DNA from numerous populations across North America, has implicated new species which are presently under investigation. Applying the 16S rRNA gene with biometric, cuticular hydrocarbons, and ethological data, a cryptic species of Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt; has been identified from Delaware, Georgia, Maryland, North Carolina, and South Carolina and determined to constitute a valid species with an apparently Atlantic distribution. Epicuticular hydrocarbon analysis showing the presence of rare triunsaturated alkenes, and a total absence of methyl branched alkanes also support this cryptic group as a distinct species. The name for this species is &lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malletei,&lt;/i&gt; previously described, but not generally accepted by termite experts in the United States. Comparisons from a 403 bp region of the mtDNA 16S rRNA gene was used to discriminate known &lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt; species from North America: The eastern subterranean termite &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavipes&lt;/i&gt; (Kollar), dark southern subterranean termite &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virginicus&lt;/i&gt; (Banks), light southern subterranean termite &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hageni&lt;/i&gt; Banks, arid subterranean termite &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibialis&lt;/i&gt; Banks, and western subterranean termite &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hesperus&lt;/i&gt; Banks. When compared to this new species, both maximum parsimony and maximum likelihood support their genetic isolation from sympatric populations of known species and eliminate either exotic Palearctic introductions or western Nearctic involvement.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt;; Rhinotermitidae; Nearctic; mtDNA; cuticular hydrocarbon</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Reticulitermes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Austin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.-G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bagneres</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Szalanski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Scheffrahn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heintschel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Messenger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Clement</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Holarctic genus &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; Strobl (Diptera: Mycetophilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of fungus gnats (Diptera: Mycetophilidae), &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miloi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lisae&lt;/i&gt; spp. nov., are described and figured from California. &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distincta&lt;/i&gt; Fisher is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Tetragoneura&lt;/i&gt; Winnertz and a replacement name, &lt;i&gt;Tetragoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fisherae&lt;/i&gt; Kerr, nom. nov., is given for this species. A diagnosis and description of the genus &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; Strobl is presented and includes a key to species of the genus. The relationship of species within the genus &lt;i&gt;Novakia&lt;/i&gt; is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; &lt;i&gt;Tetragoneura&lt;/i&gt;; fungus gnats; new species; California</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kerr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-40</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myrciariamyia admirabilis&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of gall midge (Diptera, Cecidomyiidae) associated with &lt;i&gt;Erythroxylum suberosum &lt;/i&gt;(Erythroxylaceae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myrciariamyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;admirabilis&lt;/i&gt; Maia, a new species of Cecidomyiidae (Diptera) that induces leaf galls on &lt;i&gt;Erythroxylum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suberosum&lt;/i&gt; A.St.-Hil. (Erythroxylaceae) is described and illustrated (larva, pupa, male, female and gall) based on material from Minas Gerais, Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myrciariamyia&lt;/i&gt;; Cecidomyiidae; Diptera; Erythroxylaceae; galls</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myrciariamyia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Valeria</firstname>
          <middlename>Cid</middlename>
          <lastname>Maia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>Wilson</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and surface structure of eggs and first instar larvae of &lt;i&gt;Croce schmidti&lt;/i&gt; (Navas, 1927) (Neuroptera: Nemopteridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology of eggs and first instar larvae of &lt;i&gt;Croce&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; (Navás, 1927) is described and figured for the first time using light and scanning electron microscopy. The females were collected from Derik, Mardin Province, Turkey and maintained in the laboratory. The eggs are elongate and cylindrical with rounded ends and bear a small terminal micropylar knob. Except for the adhesive materials, the chorion surface is smooth. The newly emerged larva of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by a slightly quadrangular head and short prothorax and has prominent pale dark brown color markings on the metatergites. The body is covered with short brown setae, which include macrotrichia and dolichasters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Egg; larvae; scanning electron microscope</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Egg</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ali</firstname>
          <lastname>Satar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zekiye</firstname>
          <lastname>Suludere</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Selami</firstname>
          <lastname>Candan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Savas</firstname>
          <lastname>Canbulat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-55</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of the Genus &lt;i&gt;Amphinemura&lt;/i&gt; (Plecoptera: Nemouridae) from Yunnan, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species, &lt;i&gt;Amphinemura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auriculata&lt;/i&gt; Du &amp; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dispositspina&lt;/i&gt; Du &amp; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamatmicroda&lt;/i&gt; Du &amp; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latifollicula&lt;/i&gt; Du &amp; Wang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Yunnan province, China are described in this paper.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plecoptera; Nemouridae; &lt;i&gt;Amphinemura&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plecoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yu-Zhou</firstname>
          <lastname>Du</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhi-Jie</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hesperempis&lt;/i&gt; Melander (Diptera: Empididae) from Siberia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Igor</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shamshev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-65</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The status of &lt;i&gt;Clinocera rufipes&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi, a new junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Clinocera nigra&lt;/i&gt; Meigen (Diptera: Empididae: Clinocerinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bradley</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinclair</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1553.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1553</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Stomatopod and decapod crustaceans from Camamu Bay, state of Bahia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Camamu Bay, located on the central coast of the state of Bahia, Brazil (13°47’ to 14°10’S), is the third-largest Brazilian bay. It is included in a zone that perhaps constitutes the last unexplored frontier on the Brazilian coast, situated between Todos os Santos Bay in Bahia, and the city of Vitória in Espírito Santo. Moreover, this zone coincides with an area of remarkable zoogeographical interest, the transition zone between the Brazilian and Paulista provinces. Camamu Bay contains a wide diversity of marine environments such as sandy beaches, rocky substrata, and mangroves, and it is still in a good state of preservation compared to other large Brazilian bays. The objective of this study was to survey the fauna of Crustacea (orders Stomatopoda and Decapoda) in Camamu Bay. The material analyzed was collected by trawling from July 2003 to September 2005. Voucher specimens were deposited in the collections of the Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz and the Universidade Estadual do Sudoeste da Bahia, located in the cities of Ilhéus and Jequié (state of Bahia, Brazil), respectively. A total of 93 species, belonging to 35 families, was collected. The order Stomatopoda was represented by 3 families and 4 species; the order Decapoda was represented by 31 families and 89 species. The most important family in terms of number of species was Alpheidae, with 11 species. Of the total number of species, 88 are recorded from Camamu Bay for the first time, while 10 species are cited from the state of Bahia for the first time. The southern geographical distributional limits in the western Atlantic for the caridean &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pandionis&lt;/i&gt; and the brachyurans &lt;i&gt;Macrocoeloma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevigatum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Elamena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gordonae&lt;/i&gt; are extended.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">crustaceans; diversity; estuaries; Camamu Bay; Bahia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">crustaceans</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>Oliveira</middlename>
          <lastname>De Almeida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Cecilia</middlename>
          <lastname>Guerrazzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petronio</firstname>
          <middlename>Alves</middlename>
          <lastname>Coelho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Ixodes&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Ixodidae) of Mexico: parasite-host and host-parasite checklists</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Parasite-host and host-parasite checklists are provided for all species of &lt;i&gt;Ixodes&lt;/i&gt; known from Mexico; host and locality data are from specimens housed in the Colección Nacional de Ácaros, Instituto de Biología, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, and from literature. Six &lt;i&gt;Ixodes&lt;/i&gt; species (I. &lt;i&gt;brunneus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conepati,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eadsi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guatemalensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texanus)&lt;/i&gt; are newly recorded from Mexico; in addition, 17 new locality records are presented for eight species (I. &lt;i&gt;affinis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luciae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubidus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scapularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinipalpis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tancitarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;woodi),&lt;/i&gt; and eight new host records are given for five species (I. &lt;i&gt;affinis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubidus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinipalpis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tancitarius).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ixodidae; &lt;i&gt;Ixodes&lt;/i&gt;; Mexico; checklists; hosts; distribution.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ixodidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carmen</firstname>
          <lastname>Guzman-Cornejo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Robbins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tila</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Perez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhantos&lt;/i&gt; (Siluriformes: Loricariidae), a new species from southern Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhantos&lt;/i&gt; is described for a uniquely pigmented species of loricariid catfish from the upper Río Orinoco of Amazonas, Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhantos&lt;/i&gt; can be separated from all other &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; except &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micromaculatus&lt;/i&gt; by having its head and dorsal and lateral surfaces of body densely covered in very small spots (greater than 15 spots on the first plate in the dorsal series of specimens less than 100 mm SL vs. less than 10; greater than 30 spots in specimens greater than 100 mm SL vs. less than 15). The new species is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micromaculatus&lt;/i&gt; by having round spots (vs. longitudinally oval) that are unordered (vs. in longitudinal lines), by having well-developed keels on the lateral plates (vs. keels weak), by the presence of a ridge on the pterotic that is contiguous with the supraorbital ridge (vs. pterotic ridge absent), and by having the abdomen fully plated (vs. partially plated or naked).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazonas; Catfish; Hypostominae; &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micromaculatus&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropics; Siluriformes; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazonas</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Armbruster</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leigh</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tansey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nathan</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lujan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-20</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1552.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1552</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; Shull (Insecta, Thysanoptera, Thripidae) and three related genera in Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; and related genera in Japan were studied, and the following four genera and eight species recorded: &lt;i&gt;Anascirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okinawanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Drepanothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reuteri&lt;/i&gt; Uzel, &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; Hood, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katsura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machili&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Parascirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fagaceae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; The male of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reuteri&lt;/i&gt; is recorded from Japan for the first time. Ten genera are recognized in the &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; genus group, and relationships between these are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thysanoptera; Thripidae; &lt;i&gt;Anascirtothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Drepanothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Parascirtothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Scirtothrips&lt;/i&gt; genus group; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thysanoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masami</firstname>
          <lastname>Masumoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuji</firstname>
          <lastname>Okajima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A checklist of Turkish Neuroptera with annotating on provincial distributions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A checklist of Turkish Neuroptera is presented. The list is based on an examination of relevant literature and personal investigations carried out between 1997 and 2007. 193 species and 6 subspecies are currently recognized as occurring in Turkey.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Checklist; Neuroptera; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Checklist</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Savas</firstname>
          <lastname>Canbulat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-52</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Claustropyga &lt;/i&gt;Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig (Diptera, Sciaridae) with the description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The following new species are described from Canada: &lt;i&gt;Claustropyga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirifica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Quebec and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spicea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triloba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Yukon. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aperta&lt;/i&gt; Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig, previously known from Europe, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplicis&lt;/i&gt; Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig, previously known from Ontario, are recorded from Vancouver Island, British Columbia. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auriculata&lt;/i&gt; Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig, previously known from the Palaearctic region and from Alaska, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusidens&lt;/i&gt; Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig, previously known from Europe, are recorded from the Yukon. The diagnostic characters of all the Nearctic species are discussed. In addition to the above-mentioned species, the Nearctic fauna of &lt;i&gt;Claustropyga&lt;/i&gt; includes &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthostyla&lt;/i&gt; (Tuomikoski), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elizabethae&lt;/i&gt; Hippa, Vilkamaa &amp; Mohrig and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcorticis&lt;/i&gt; (Mohrig &amp; Krivosheina). A key to the known species of &lt;i&gt;Claustropyga&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sciaridae; &lt;i&gt;Claustropyga&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; Nearctic region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sciaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pekka</firstname>
          <lastname>Vilkamaa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Heikki</firstname>
          <lastname>Hippa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1551.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1551</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Calommata&lt;/i&gt; (Atypidae) and new spider species (Araneae) from Israel</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The extraordinary finding in Israel of &lt;i&gt;Calommata,&lt;/i&gt; a unique mygalomorph atypid, is reviewed. Another new find out of range concerns the cybaeid genus &lt;i&gt;Paracedicus,&lt;/i&gt; represented in Israel by two new species: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baram&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geshur.&lt;/i&gt; Pitfall trapping yielded several new species disclosing among others populations inhabiting the sands of the southern Arava Valley of &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elifaz&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Cerbalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aravaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; that resemble very closely psammophilous species living in the Haluza sands of the Negev. The unknown males of &lt;i&gt;Ozyptila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavigera&lt;/i&gt; (O.P.-Cambridge, 1872), &lt;i&gt;Tmarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hazevensis&lt;/i&gt; Levy, 1973, and &lt;i&gt;Ebo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eremus&lt;/i&gt; Levy, 1999 are described. In addition the following new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Zoropsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaleri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zodarion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geshur,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;odem,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hahnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carmelita,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ozyptila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedotmikha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Xysticus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sansan,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Theridion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zekharya,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Singa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ammophila&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neoscona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lotan.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spider fauna; new species; Israel</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spider fauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gershom</firstname>
          <lastname>Levy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the systematics of western North Pacific angel sharks, genus &lt;i&gt;Squatina&lt;/i&gt;, with redescriptions of &lt;i&gt;Squatina formosa&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;S. japonica&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;S. nebulosa&lt;/i&gt; (Chondrichthyes: Squatiniformes, Squatinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Squatinids are quite distinct from other shark-like fishes, but individual species are difficult to differentiate. Four of the 16 known, valid squatinid species occur in the western North Pacific (WNP). Differences among the WNP species complex have traditionally relied upon the nasal barbel shape, interorbital and interspiracle distances, ocellus patterns, number of dermal folds about the mouth, and the presence of midback thorns. Unfortunately, many of these characters are difficult to distinguish, hindering identification of individuals. Using WNP squatinid specimens and photographs, both from field expeditions and museums, we confirm the validity of four species in the area. Additionally, we correct mistakes made in the literature on &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosa&lt;/i&gt; type material, clarify differences in the particularly challenging distinction between &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nebulosa,&lt;/i&gt; and provide the basis for a revised dichotomous key for the region that includes all four known valid WNP squatinid species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squatinidae; angel sharks; redescription; Japan; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squatinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walsh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ebert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-47</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of branchipodid fairy shrimp (Crustacea: Branchiopoda: Anostraca) from Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new anostracan genus with two new species in the family Branchipodidae is described from the Murray Darling basin, Australia. This is the first record of the family from Australia. Males of &lt;i&gt;Australobranchipus&lt;/i&gt; typically have long and elaborate frontal appendages comparable to those in the branchipodid genera &lt;i&gt;Branchipus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pumilibranchipus.&lt;/i&gt; Females have a compact brood pouch like other branchipodid genera. Two new species in this genus are described (A. &lt;i&gt;parooensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilgaiphila).&lt;/i&gt; Along with recent additions in &lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Parartemia,&lt;/i&gt; and confirmation of the presence of &lt;i&gt;Streptocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; these new findings change the concept of low diversity among higher anostracan taxa in Australia. &lt;i&gt;Australobranchipus&lt;/i&gt; is also remarkable for having the shortest known life cycle of any Australian anostracans. In the type locality, which typically holds water for only two to six weeks in occasional years, and when cultured, it matures within a week and dies within two weeks, allowing these species to avoid competition with other anostracans.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Australobranchipus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Australobranchipus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parooensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Australobranchipus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilgaiphila&lt;/i&gt;; biogeography; life cycle</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>Christopher</middlename>
          <lastname>Rogers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>V</middlename>
          <lastname>Timms</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Merlijn</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luc</firstname>
          <lastname>Brendonck</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of oppioid mites from Turkey (Acari: Oribatida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new oppioid oribatid mites, &lt;i&gt;Moritzoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicarinata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yozgatensis&lt;/i&gt; ssp. nov. of the family Oppiidae and &lt;i&gt;Cosmogneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ozkani&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. of the family Autognetidae are described from Turkey, using specimens collected in Yozgat Pine Grove National Park.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oppioidea; Oppiidae; Autognetidae; Yozgat Pine Grove National Park; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oppioidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ayse</firstname>
          <lastname>Toluk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nusret</firstname>
          <lastname>Ayyildiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Subias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1550.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1550</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phytoseiid mites of the subtribe Amblyseiina (Acari: Phytoseiidae: Amblyseiini) from sub-Saharan Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the fifth publication in a series to determine the phytoseiid mites of sub-Saharan Africa. Thirty-one phytoseiid species of the subtribe Amblyseiina are reported in this paper. They refer to all species of this subtribe known to occur in sub-Saharan Africa. Ten of these species are described for the first time, 15 species are redescribed and 6 are not evaluated in this study. Most of those species were collected in cassava habitat in tropical Africa and in other habitats in South Africa. A key is included to help in the separation of these species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Mesostigmata; Phytoseiidae; Amblyseiini; predator; cassava; taxonomy; sub-Saharan Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ignace</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zannou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gilberto</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Moraes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eddie</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ueckermann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anibal</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yaninek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rachid</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-47</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genitives of species and subspecies nomina derived from personal names should not be emended</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Article 31 of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; allows to form a species or subspecies from a personal name, using a nomen in the genitive case. Some zoologists have construed this rule as meaning that such nomina should always end in &lt;i&gt;-i&lt;/i&gt; if dedicated to a man, in &lt;i&gt;-ae&lt;/i&gt; if dedicated to a woman, in &lt;i&gt;-arum&lt;/i&gt; to several women and in &lt;i&gt;-orum&lt;/i&gt; to several persons including at least one man. They therefore proposed emendations to those nomina which they considered ill-formed under this interpretation. A detailed analysis shows that the latter is wrong, and that the original spelling (including its ending) of any new nomen based on a personal name should not be modified (except possibly in a few very rare cases). New spellings proposed by some authors for the reasons above are unjustified emendations, with their own authors and dates. Some problems related to homonymy in nomina based on personal names are also discussed. In conclusion, I propose a rewording of a few Articles of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; to remedy some of the ambiguities pointed to by this analysis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; nomenclature; spelling; personal name; gender; genitive; stem; ending; emendation; homonymy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1549.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1549</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new percid fishes (Percidae: &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt;) from the Mobile Basin drainage of Alabama, Georgia, and Tennessee</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; are described from upland drainages of the Mobile Basin. Two of the three species are narrowly distributed: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kusha,&lt;/i&gt; the Bridled Darter, is currently known only from the Conasauga River drainage in Georgia and Tennessee and Etowah River drainage in Georgia, both tributaries of the Coosa River, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sipsi,&lt;/i&gt; the Bankhead Darter, which is restricted to tributaries of Sipsey Fork of the Black Warrior River in northwestern Alabama. The third species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smithvanizi,&lt;/i&gt; the Muscadine Darter, occurs above the Fall Line in the Tallapoosa River drainage in eastern Alabama and western Georgia. In a molecular analysis using mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; sequence data, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kusha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smithvanizi&lt;/i&gt; were recovered as sister species, while &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sipsi&lt;/i&gt; was recovered in a clade consisting of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurolineata&lt;/i&gt; (P. &lt;i&gt;sciera&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sipsi).&lt;/i&gt; Two of the three species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kusha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sipsi,&lt;/i&gt; are considered to be imperiled species and are in need of conservation actions to prevent their extinction. Description of these three darters increases the number of described species of &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; to 44. Sixteen are known to occur in the Mobile Basin, including nine that are endemic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Percidae; &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kusha&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sipsi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smithvanizi&lt;/i&gt;; darter; new species; taxonomy; conservation; Alabama; Georgia; Tennessee; Mobile Basin</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Percidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Neely</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walsh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Noel</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Burkhead</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hypselodoris jacksoni&lt;/i&gt;, a new species from the south-western Pacific Ocean (Nudibranchia: Chromodorididae), with a discussion on intraspecific variation in mantle glands in &lt;i&gt;Chromodoris willani&lt;/i&gt; Rudman, 1982</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hypselodoris&lt;/i&gt; (Chromodorididae) is described from the subtropical and temperate south-western Pacific Ocean (eastern Australia, Lord Howe Island, Norfolk Island). The colouration of &lt;i&gt;Hypselodoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jacksoni&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is distinctive, though highly variable intraspecifically. &lt;i&gt;Hypselodoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jacksoni&lt;/i&gt; belongs to the Indo-Pacific &lt;i&gt;Hypselodoris&lt;/i&gt; clade (for which the key synapomorphy is a minute receptaculum seminis) and, based on comparisons of internal and external morphology, appears to belong to a subclade characterised by an elevated branchial sheath, probably most closely related to &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krakotoa&lt;/i&gt; Gosliner &amp; Johnson, 1999, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidi&lt;/i&gt; Gosliner &amp; Johnson, 1999 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regina&lt;/i&gt; Ev. &amp; Er. Marcus, 1970. Intraspecific variation in the arrangement of mantle glands in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jacksoni&lt;/i&gt; prompted a preand post-fixation comparison of mantle glands in another chromodorid, &lt;i&gt;Chromodoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;willani&lt;/i&gt; Rudman, 1982. These results indicate these structures can vary significantly within a population (and thus species), and it is likely that too much emphasis has been placed on mantle glands for separating species in the recent literature.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mantle glands; nudibranch; Opisthobranchia; Gastropoda; Mollusca</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mantle glands</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nerida</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Willan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-42</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On a new genus and species of euryplacid crab (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Goneplacoidea) from the Philippines</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of euryplacid crab (Brachyura, Goneplacoidea) is described from the Philippines. It superficially resembles species of &lt;i&gt;Carcinoplax&lt;/i&gt; H. Milne Edwards, 1852 (Goneplacidae) but the structure of the sternum, abdomen, and gonopods show that it is a euryplacid. Comparisons are made with &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; De Haan, 1835.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Euryplacidae; Goneplacidae; new genus; new species; Philippines</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Castro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halecium arcticum &lt;/i&gt;(Cnidaria: Hydrozoa), a new species of hydroid from Spitsbergen</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt; is described and figured. The new species was found among the kelp forest-associated fauna collected during the Polish diving expedition to Hornsund (Spitsbergen, Svalbard Archipelago) in 2003. The relationships with several closely-related &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt; species are discussed.Key words: Benthic hydroid, new species, &lt;i&gt;Halecium,&lt;/i&gt; Svalbard, Arctic</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marta</firstname>
          <lastname>Ronowicz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Schuchert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis, 1952 (Digenea: Gyliauchenidae Fukui, 1929), including the redescription of &lt;i&gt;I. vogelsangi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis, 1952&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent studies on the Gyliauchenidae Fukui, 1929 have lead to our reinterpretation of the morphology of the group. Here we emend the generic diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis, 1952 to reflect current understanding of the morphology of the digestive system and male terminal genitalia. We redescribe the type-, and only, species, &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vogelsangi&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis, 1952, based on our examinations of paratype material from the intestine of &lt;i&gt;Prionurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; Gill, 1862, caught in Pacific waters off Mexico. Specimens of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vogelsangi&lt;/i&gt; are distinctive because of their massive bodies, and &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished among the Gyliauchenidae by the position of the cirrus-sac entirely posterior to the caeca, the possession of a post-testicular ovary and the coiling of the uterus between the diagonal testes. The ventral sucker of &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; is close to the posterior extremity of the body, supporting placement of the genus within the Gyliaucheninae Fukui, 1929. Here we recognise &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; as a monotypic genus within the Gyliauchenidae, which is restricted to acanthurid fishes in the Eastern Pacific Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vogelsangi&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis; 1952; &lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis; 1952; Gyliauchenidae; Digenea; &lt;i&gt;Prionurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; Gill; 1862; Acanthuridae; East Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ichthyotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vogelsangi&lt;/i&gt; Caballero &amp; Bravo-Hollis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kathryn</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1548.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1548</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Porcellanidae (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura) from New Caledonia and the Loyalty Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Thirty-one species of the family Porcellanidae are reported on the basis of rich material recently collected from New Caledonia and the Loyalty Islands. They include two species of &lt;i&gt;Aliaporcellana&lt;/i&gt; Nakasone &amp; Miyake, 1971, one of &lt;i&gt;Capilliporcellana&lt;/i&gt; Haig, 1978, two of &lt;i&gt;Enosteoides&lt;/i&gt; Johnson, 1970, one of &lt;i&gt;Heteropolyonyx&lt;/i&gt; Osawa, 2001, four of &lt;i&gt;Lissoporcellana&lt;/i&gt; Haig, 1978, two of &lt;i&gt;Pachycheles&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, 11 species of &lt;i&gt;Petrolisthes&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, one of &lt;i&gt;Pisidia&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1820, six of &lt;i&gt;Polyonyx&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, and one of &lt;i&gt;Porcellana&lt;/i&gt; Lamarck, 1801. Two species, one each of &lt;i&gt;Lissoporcellana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Polyonyx,&lt;/i&gt; are new to science and are herein described and illustrated. Some records greatly extend the previously known distribution ranges of their species. A neotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Polyonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biunguiculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Dana, 1852), of which the type specimen is apparently lost, in order to fix its identity. A key to all the Indo-West Pacific porcellanid genera is provided. For the genera recorded from New Caledonia and the Loyalty Islands, keys to species known from whole the Indo-West Pacific or presently from the islands are also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Anomura; Porcellanidae; new species; New Caledonia; Loyalty Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masayuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Osawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-49</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala primordialis&lt;/i&gt; (Douthitt) complex (Cestoda: Anoplocephalidae) in voles and squirrels</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study redescribes &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primordialis&lt;/i&gt; (Douthitt) in the red squirrel, &lt;i&gt;Tamiasciurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hudsonicus,&lt;/i&gt; describes two new, related species of &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; Lühe from &lt;i&gt;Microtus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Myodes&lt;/i&gt; (syn. &lt;i&gt;Clethrionomys)&lt;/i&gt; voles, and summarizes the patterns of their host specificity and geographic distribution, particularly in Alaska and adjacent regions in Canada and north-eastern Siberia. &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nearctica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alaskensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are shown to be slightly, but consistently differentiated host-specific parasites of &lt;i&gt;Myodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rutilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Myodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gapperi,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Microtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miurus,&lt;/i&gt; respectively. The related &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; sp. from &lt;i&gt;Microtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oeconomus&lt;/i&gt; is also suspected to be specifically distinct, but the available material does not allow a description of a new species. &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primordialis-like&lt;/i&gt; cestodes occur widely in rodents in North America, ranging from California to Labrador and Alaska, but also in north-eastern Siberia. The specific identity of the few Eurasian specimens could not, however, be confirmed. &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primordialis-like&lt;/i&gt; species seem to be rare in all host species and regions, maximum prevalences being 8%, 3%, 6.5% and 5% for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primordialis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nearctica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alaskensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; sp., respectively.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">tapeworms; Anoplocephalinae; &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alaskensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nearctica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paranoplocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primordialis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tamiasciurus&lt;/i&gt;; Sciuridae; &lt;i&gt;Microtus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Clethrionomys&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Myodes&lt;/i&gt;; Cricetidae; Arvicolinae; Alaska</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">tapeworms</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Voitto</firstname>
          <lastname>Haukisalmi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Heikki</firstname>
          <lastname>Henttonen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1547.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1547</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biogeographic area relationships in Venezuela: A Parsimony analysis of Culicidae-Phytotelmata distribution in National Parks</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study represents the first attempt to understand the current distribution and evolutionary history of Culicidae in Venezuela and adjacent areas using cladistic methods. We studied the association between immature mosquitoes and their aquatic habitats in plants (phytotelmata) in 16 protected natural areas of Venezuela. A total of 68 mosquito species was collected from 47 host-plant species. Parsimony Analysis of Endemicity using localities and mosquito species was used to find the most parsimonious cladograms depicting the biogeographic relationships. Varying degrees of mosquito-plant associations were observed, with the greatest specificity existing at the genus and subgenus levels. Implicit enumeration algorithms obtained one parsimonious tree (L=101 steps) with four well-supported groups named "Amazonas" (southern Venezuela), “Bolivar” (southeastern Venezuela), "Los Andes Cordillera” and "Coastal Cordillera" (northern Caribbean mountain range). These results support the hypothesis that the Guayana Shield was an ancestral center of speciation, followed by the Andean Region, whereas the mosquito fauna from the Central Cordillera was derived from the latter.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anophelinae; Bromeliaceae; cladistics; Culicini; Diptera; endemism; Historical biogeography; mosquitoes; Sabethini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anophelinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan-Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Navarro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <lastname>Liria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hermes</firstname>
          <lastname>Pinango</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Barrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Euglossa &lt;/i&gt;Latreille (Hymenoptera: Apidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Euglossella)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jacquelynae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from Central Brazil, &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solangeae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from coastal southeastern Brazil, and &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Euglossa)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sovietica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from the western Brazilian Amazon, are described as new species. &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solangeae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is believed to belong to the &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stellfeldi&lt;/i&gt; Moure species group—a discussion on the placement of this group is also presented – and &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sovietica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is treated as a member of &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurea&lt;/i&gt; Friese species group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Apini; &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jacquelynae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solangeae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sovietica&lt;/i&gt;; Euglossina; new species; Neotropics; orchid bees; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Apini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andre</firstname>
          <lastname>Nemesio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-31</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Coelana &lt;/i&gt;Kramer, 1964 (Hemiptera, Cicadellidae, Neocoelidiinae) and taxonomic notes on the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Coelana&lt;/i&gt; Kramer [= &lt;i&gt;Coelidiana&lt;/i&gt; subgenus &lt;i&gt;Coelana&lt;/i&gt; DeLong &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudum]&lt;/i&gt; is revised and its two species, &lt;i&gt;Coelana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modesta&lt;/i&gt; (Baker) and &lt;i&gt;Coelana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;drakei&lt;/i&gt; Kramer are redescribed. &lt;i&gt;Coelana&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from other genera of Neocoelidiinae by the presence of a small black spot at the apex of the crown and male genitalia with an inflated pygofer, longer than subgenital plates, with a large ventral hook and laterally with a long suture, extending from the ventral margin to near the dorsal margin. The species are redescribed and illustrated, their geographical distribution is given, and a lectotype for &lt;i&gt;Neocoelidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modesta&lt;/i&gt; Baker is designated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; geographical distribution; lectotype; leafhoppers; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Paula</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques-Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodney</firstname>
          <middlename>Ramiro</middlename>
          <lastname>Cavichioli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-42</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tyranniphilopterus polioptilus&lt;/i&gt; new species (Phthiraptera: Ischnocera: Philopteridae) parasitic on the Masked Gnatcatcher, &lt;i&gt;Polioptila dumicola&lt;/i&gt; (Passeriformes, Polioptilidae) in Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tyranniphilopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polioptilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated from specimens collected off &lt;i&gt;Polioptila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumicola&lt;/i&gt; (Vieillot, 1816) from two localities in the coastal area NE of Buenos Aires Province, Argentina. Morphologically the new species is similar to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;titicacae&lt;/i&gt; (Eichler &amp; Freund, 1956) and several other undescribed species from the Tyrannidae, differing from all of them by proportions of the head and dorsal anterior plate, most body measurements, number of dorsal and ventral setae in both sexes, and number and arrangements of vulvar setae in females. Descriptions of the male, female, the three nymphal instars and the egg are also included. A list is presented of all known species of &lt;i&gt;Tyranniphilopterus,&lt;/i&gt; arranged by host taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">egg morphology; oviposition sites; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">egg morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Armando</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cicchino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Synochoneura&lt;/i&gt; Obraztsov, with the description of a new species from China (Lepidoptera: Tortricidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synochoneura&lt;/i&gt; is a small genus restricted to China. The genus is reviewed, and one new species is described: &lt;i&gt;Synochoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; The female of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tapaishani&lt;/i&gt; (Caradja) is reported for the first time. Images of adults, male genitalia, and female genitalia are provided, along with a key to the known species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Tortricidae; &lt;i&gt;Synochoneura&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xinpu</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Houhun</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the Chinese endemic delphacid genus &lt;i&gt;Neuterthron&lt;/i&gt; Ding (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha) from Yunnan and Shaanxi Provinces</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the Chinese endemic delphacid genus &lt;i&gt;Neuterthron&lt;/i&gt; Ding are described: &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platynotum&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (S.W. China: Yunnan), and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatulum&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (N.W. China: Shaanxi). A key is presented to all species of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Delphacidae; Taxonomy; Auchenorrhyncha; &lt;i&gt;Neuterthron&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Delphacidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dao-Zheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Qin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of Phlaeobinae from China (Orthoptera: Acrididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiang-Chu</firstname>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong</firstname>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1546.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1546</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery and revision of &lt;i&gt;Foenobethylus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1913 (Hymenoptera, Bethylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The bethylid genus &lt;i&gt;Foenobethylus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1913, unstudied for almost a century, is redescribed and assigned to the subfamily Pristocerinae based on a preliminary phylogenetic assessment. Four new species: &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bidentatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Brunei), &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Malaysia), &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emiliacasellae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Thailand), and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomascokeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Malaysia) are described, based on males only, as females remain unrecognised in this genus. All specimens are deposited in the Department of Entomology, the Natural History Museum, London, U.K. The type species &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer (Philippines), although unrepresented by any traceable specimen, can be distinguished from these species based on the original description. A key to the five known species of &lt;i&gt;Foenobethylus&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pristocerinae; Foenobethylus; Southeast Asia; taxonomy; phylogeny; 28S rDNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pristocerinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gergely</firstname>
          <lastname>Varkonyi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Polaszek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of four species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Brachinus&lt;/i&gt; Weber (Coleoptera: Caraboidea: Brachinidae) from the Philippines</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species diversity of the bombardier beetles is poorly known in Asia except Japan. In the present paper, species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Brachinus&lt;/i&gt; Weber of the Philippines are dealt with. Among the four species reported in the Philippines, two species are described as new to science: &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;philippinensis&lt;/i&gt; Tian &amp; Deuve, &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solidipalpis&lt;/i&gt; Tian &amp; Deuve, &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species.&lt;/b&gt; Redescriptions are given for the two known species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luzonicus&lt;/i&gt; Chaudoir and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piceus&lt;/i&gt; Chaudoir. A key to all Philippine species of &lt;i&gt;Brachinus&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Caraboidea; Brachinidae; &lt;i&gt;Brachinus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; the Philippines</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mingyi</firstname>
          <lastname>Tian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thierry</firstname>
          <lastname>Deuve</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-22</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudokuzicus&lt;/i&gt; Gorochov, 1993 (Orthoptera: Tettigoniidae: Meconematidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A key to species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudokuzicus&lt;/i&gt; Gorochov, 1993 is presented. Generic diagnosis are presented. One subgenus and three species are described as new: &lt;i&gt;Similkuzicus&lt;/i&gt; subgen. nov., &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(P.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(P.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acinacus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;P.(S.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadridentatus&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov.. The type specimens are deposited in Museum of Hebei University, Baoding.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudokuzicus&lt;/i&gt;; Meconematinae; Tettigoniidae; review.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudokuzicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fu-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shi</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shao-Li</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mao</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yan-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chang</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ammophila nancy&lt;/i&gt; Menke, a new species in the &lt;i&gt;pruinosa&lt;/i&gt; complex (Hymenoptera: Sphecidae: Ammophilinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ammophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nancy&lt;/i&gt; new species (Hymenoptera, Sphecidae), is described from Arizona, California, Nevada, New Mexico, Texas and Mexico (Sonora and Baja California). The new species is a member of the &lt;i&gt;pruinosa&lt;/i&gt; complex which also contains &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; Menke, 1964, and &lt;i&gt;pruinosa&lt;/i&gt; Cresson, 1865. A key is provided for the identification of the three species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New species; &lt;i&gt;Ammophila&lt;/i&gt;; Sphecidae; &lt;i&gt;pruinosa&lt;/i&gt; complex; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt;; Arizona</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arnold</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-38</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Erotylidae and Endomychidae (Coleoptera: Cucujoidea) of the Maritime Provinces of Canada: New records, zoogeography, and observations on beetle-fungi relationships and forest health</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Erotylidae and Endomychidae of the Maritime Provinces are surveyed. Fifteen species are now known from the region, fourteen in Nova Scotia, seven in New Brunswick, and four on Prince Edward Island. Thirteen new provincial records (seven from Nova Scotia, three from New Brunswick, and three from Prince Edward Island) are reported. Four erotylids, &lt;i&gt;Dacne&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrimaculata&lt;/i&gt; (Say), &lt;i&gt;Triplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dissimulator&lt;/i&gt; (Crotch), &lt;i&gt;Triplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavicollis&lt;/i&gt; Lacordaire, &lt;i&gt;Triplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macra&lt;/i&gt; LeConte; and two endomychids, &lt;i&gt;Rhanidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicolor&lt;/i&gt; (Ziegler) and &lt;i&gt;Lycoperdina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferruginea&lt;/i&gt; LeConte, are newly recorded in the Maritime Provinces as a whole. New records of the rare endomychid, &lt;i&gt;Hadromychus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chandleri&lt;/i&gt; Bousquet &amp; Leschen, are reported. The fauna is examined in a regional zoogeographic context, paying particular attention to the insular faunas of Cape Breton and Prince Edward Islands. Attention is also drawn to the number of species that have been very rarely collected. This apparent scarcity may be related to the long history of forest management in the region, in particular the effects of intensive forestry on the communities of forest fungi on which these species feed and depend. Attention is drawn to the importance of ongoing research to monitor their populations and assess how these species may be employed as indicators of the overall health forest ecosystems.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Erotylidae; Endomychidae; Dacninae; Tritominae; Merophysiinae; Endomychinae; Stenotarsinae; Epipocinae; Lycoperdininae; Mycetaeinae; fungus beetles; forest Coleoptera; saproxylic fauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Majka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Pythamus&lt;/i&gt; Melichar (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Evacanthinae) in the Indian subcontinent</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pythamus&lt;/i&gt; Melichar (type species: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dealbatus&lt;/i&gt; Melichar) is redefined. The genus &lt;i&gt;Dussana&lt;/i&gt; Distant (type species: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quaerenda&lt;/i&gt; Distant) is treated as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pythamus.&lt;/i&gt; Three new species, &lt;i&gt;Pythamus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biramosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (India: Karnataka), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bispinosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (India: Tamil Nadu, Kerala) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (India: Tamil Nadu) in addition to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dealbatus&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Dussana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quaerenda&lt;/i&gt; is treated as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dealbatus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dussana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;assamensis&lt;/i&gt; Ramakrishnan is transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Onukia.&lt;/i&gt; A key to species of &lt;i&gt;Pythamus&lt;/i&gt; is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homoptera; Auchenorrhyncha; morphology; distribution; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Viraktamath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Webb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-61</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ptiliola flammifera&lt;/i&gt; (MIynarski) reinstated as a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;P. kunzei&lt;/i&gt; (Heer) (Coleoptera: Ptiliidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ptiliola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flammifera&lt;/i&gt; (Młynarski) is recognised as a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kunzei&lt;/i&gt; (Heer). Apart from differences in the structure of the aedeagus, both species can be separated by the pronotal surface and the apical fringe of the elytra. The male of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flammifera&lt;/i&gt; carries a distinct tuft of hairs on the metaventrite, absent in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kunzei.&lt;/i&gt; Currently, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flammifera&lt;/i&gt; is only known from Poland and the Netherlands. A key for the identification of all three Palaearctic &lt;i&gt;Ptiliola&lt;/i&gt; species is presented. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Trichopteryx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kunzei&lt;/i&gt; Heer, 1841.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ptiliidae; featherwing beetle; &lt;i&gt;Ptiliola&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic region; identification key; lectotype designation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ptiliidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Vorst</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1545.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1545</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological variation and sexual dimorphism in the California skate, &lt;i&gt;Raja inornata&lt;/i&gt; Jordan and Gilbert, 1881 from the Gulf of California, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Knowledge of taxonomy, systematics and life histories of the skates that inhabit the Gulf of California is scarce. Five species have been documented in the Sea of Cortez: &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cortezensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;equatorialis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inornata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhina&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;velezi.&lt;/i&gt; The California skate (R. &lt;i&gt;inornata)&lt;/i&gt; is the most abundant species caught as by-catch during the hake trawl fishery in the Gulf. Intraspecific variation in the external morphology of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inornata&lt;/i&gt; from the northern Gulf of California, México is described on the basis of 24 proportional morphometric variables from 45 males (227–525 mm total length TL) and 52 females (226-690 mm TL). Males and females had 9 and 14 proportional dimensions respectively that were isometric with total length (TL). Regression slope and elevation analysis revealed that 9 relationships between TL and morphometric variables were sexually dimorphic. A stepwise discriminant function separated three groups of skates (females and males of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inornata&lt;/i&gt; and males of &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cortezensis)&lt;/i&gt; and was able to correctly classify 97%, 100% and 100% of the original grouped cases, respectively. The variables that best discriminated between species and sexes were preorbital length, preoral length, distance between fifth gill openings, maximum distance between pelvic fins, and distance from cloaca to anterior caudal fin. The study also revealed that several of the meristic characters examined showed considerable variation and, therefore, should be used with caution in taxonomic studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">morphometrics; allometry; sexual dimorphism; &lt;i&gt;Raja;&lt;/i&gt; Rajiformes; Gulf of California</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">morphometrics; allometry; sexual dimorphism; &lt;i&gt;Raja;&lt;/i&gt; Rajiformes; Gulf of California</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Leonardo Castillo</middlename>
          <lastname>Geniz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <middlename>Sosa</middlename>
          <lastname>Nishizaki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>Carlos Perez</middlename>
          <lastname>Jimenez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Neoscirula &lt;/i&gt;(Prostigmata: Cunaxidae) from a Tropical dry forest in Jalisco, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of cunaxid mites are described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Neoscirula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aliciae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neoscirula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baloghi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neoscirula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoffmannae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from a tropical dry forest at Chamela Biological Station, Jalisco, Mexico. A key for the species of &lt;i&gt;Neoscirula&lt;/i&gt; of the world is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bdelloidea; taxonomy; predatory mites; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bdelloidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Blanca</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mejia-Recamier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Palacios-Vargas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-31</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the brachylepadomorph cirripede genus &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt;, including the first record of an Early Cretaceous species from the Russian Far East*</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">To date, twelve species have been assigned to the brachylepadomorph cirripede genus &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt; Withers, 1914, some of them on the basis of very limited material. The current status of all these taxa is briefly reviewed. Added are notes on a small collection of isolated capitular valves from middle Albian (Lower Cretaceous) strata in the lower reaches of the Amur River (Vassinskaja protoka, Khabarovsk region); this constitutes the first record of &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt; from the Russian Far East (North Pacific Province). It is noted that species of &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt; are almost exclusively European in distribution; notable exceptions are &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;articulata&lt;/i&gt; (?lower Aptian; Alexander Island, Antarctica), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt; (unspecified Upper Cretaceous, Kuzna-chaj, Azerbaijan; here considered to be a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubium),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; nov. sp. (upper Paleocene; Turgay Strait, northwestern Kazakhstan), and the present lot which appears to be closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rigida&lt;/i&gt; from the lower Albianmiddle (?upper) Cenomanian of Europe (England, France). In the absence of other valves (terga, rostra and imbricating plates), for now we refer to this lot as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;rigida,&lt;/i&gt; and consider it a vicariant species, awaiting the discovery of additional material. In the literature, it has been pointed out that amongst associated faunal elements (in particular, ammonoids and buchiid/inoceramid bivalves) at Vassinskaja protoka and nearby sections along the Amur River, there are species which are closely related to European taxa, and their occurrence appears best explained by vicariance biogeography. The absence of &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt; in younger strata in the Russian Far East suggests that no subsequent radiation took place, but collection failure cannot be ruled out either in view of the vastness of the area and the generally small size of cirripede valves.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cirripedia; Brachylepadomorpha; Brachylepadidae; &lt;i&gt;Pycnolepas&lt;/i&gt;; revision; Russia; Lower Cretaceous</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cirripedia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jagt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tatiana</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zonova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jagt-Yazykova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-47</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; (Siluriformes: Trichomycteridae) from the Andean Cordillera of Peru with comments on relationships within the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megantoni,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from several localities on the Andes of Perú at 1,360 to 2,200 m elevation. The new species differs from all congeners in the possession of autapomorphic characters: ventral interopercle with thickened integument and a reduced foramen in the frontal-supraoccipital. It is further distinguished by the following combination of characteristics: the tip of the pelvic fin when depressed does not reach the anus, the presence of a premaxilla rectangle, the first dorsal fin pterygiophore insertion at or posterior to vertebra 19 to 21, the supraorbital canal with pore 3, the outer tooth row with conic teeth, the head muscles not hypertrophied, the first pectoral fin ray prolonged as thin short filament, the possession of 17 pairs of ribs on each side, and 37 to 40 vertebrae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichomycterinae; South America; catfish; Perú; Andean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichomycterinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>Quispe</middlename>
          <lastname>Chuquihuamani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Otiothops&lt;/i&gt; MacLeay (Araneae: Palpimanidae) from Caxiuana National Forest, Para Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of spiders of the genus &lt;i&gt;Otiothops,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nov.&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puraquequara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nov.&lt;/i&gt; (family Palpimanidae) are described from Caxiuanã National Forest, Portel/Melgaço, Pará, Brazil. The specimens were collected during structured inventories and natural history remarks are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazonia; Neotropical region; taxonomy; Haplogynae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazonia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brescovit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonaldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Augusto P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barreiros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Jose Augusto Pereira Barreiros (1977-2007)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonaldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1544.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1544</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of the tribe Paromalini Reitter (Coleoptera: Histeridae, Dendrophilinae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper reviews the tribe Paromalini Reitter (Coleoptera, Histeridae) of China. Five new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Carcinops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penatii&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Sichuan, &lt;i&gt;Platylomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inflexus&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Eulomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosus&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhou, n. sp. from Hainan, &lt;i&gt;Paromalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutangulus&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Yunnan, and &lt;i&gt;Paromalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetanus&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Xizang. The genus &lt;i&gt;Diplostix&lt;/i&gt; Bickhardt and nine species of this and other genera are recorded for the first time in China. They are &lt;i&gt;Diplostix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vicaria&lt;/i&gt; (Cooman, 1935), &lt;i&gt;Pachylomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deficiens&lt;/i&gt; Cooman, 1933, &lt;i&gt;Platylomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;submetallicus&lt;/i&gt; (Lewis, 1892), &lt;i&gt;Platylomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonkinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Cooman, 1937), &lt;i&gt;Eulomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amplipes&lt;/i&gt; Cooman, 1937, &lt;i&gt;Eulomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pupulus&lt;/i&gt; Cooman, 1937, &lt;i&gt;Eulomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seitzi&lt;/i&gt; Cooman, 1941, &lt;i&gt;Eulomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermicipygus&lt;/i&gt; Cooman, 1937, &lt;i&gt;Paromalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parallelepipedus&lt;/i&gt; (Herbst, 1792). According to our study, the Chinese fauna of the tribe Paromalini is now comprised of six genera and twenty-seven species. Keys to these genera and species are presented. The taxonomic position of &lt;i&gt;Pachylomalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deficiens&lt;/i&gt; Cooman is discussed. All the type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, the Chinese Academy of Sciences.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Histeridae; Paromalini; new species; new records; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ye-Jun</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Zhang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on &lt;i&gt;Falsocis&lt;/i&gt; Pic (Coleoptera: Tenebrionoidea: Ciidae), with the description of an endangered Brazilian species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Falsocis&lt;/i&gt; Pic is redescribed based on &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opacus&lt;/i&gt; Pic and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; an endangered Brazilian species. A key to males of the species of &lt;i&gt;Falsocis&lt;/i&gt; is provided, together with a description of the external morphology of adults and of the morphology of male genitalia of both species. In addition, the female genitalia of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described. &lt;i&gt;Falsocis&lt;/i&gt; is included in the tribe Ciini, and its relationship with &lt;i&gt;Acanthocis&lt;/i&gt; Miyatake and other Ciidae genera is discussed. &lt;i&gt;Falsocis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is known from only three Atlantic Forest remnants, all surrounded by urban areas, pastures or agriculture, and is probably one of the most endangered Brazilian ciids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Beetle; Neotropical; Ciinae; Ciini; Atlantic Forest; Conservation Biology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Beetle</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cristiano</firstname>
          <lastname>Lopes-Andrade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The study on Antennal Sensilla of eight Acrididae species (Orthoptera: Acridoidea) in Northeast China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The types, numbers and distributions of antennal sensilla were studied in both male and female adults of eight Acrididae species in Northeast China using scanning electron microscope (SEM). Totally, there were thirteen types of sensilla found on the antennae. They were identified as trichoid sensilla (I, II), chaetic sensilla (I, II), basiconic sensilla (I, II, III, IV, V), cavity sensilla, coeloconic sensilla, boehm's bristles and paddle-shaped sensilla. The types of antennal sensilla in each Acrididae species ranged from nine to twelve. Each of the species had the same types of antennal sensilla in male and female, and males had more abundant basiconic sensilla, chaetic sensilla, coeloconic sensilla, cavity sensilla than females. &lt;i&gt;Acrida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinerca&lt;/i&gt; had the largest total numbers of sensilla, and &lt;i&gt;Euthystria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lueifemora&lt;/i&gt; had the fewest. Boehm's bristles had a concentration in the base of the pedicel. Paddle-shaped sensilla had a concentration in the base of the scape. There were significant differences in the distribution of the other eleven types of sensilla.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acrididae; antenna; sensilla; scanning electron microscopy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acrididae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Na</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bing-Zhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miao</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1543.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1543</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Monogeneans of the malabar grouper &lt;i&gt;Epinephelus malabaricus&lt;/i&gt; (Perciformes, Serranidae) off New Caledonia, with a description of six new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; (Monogenea: Diplectanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eleven species were differentiated among more than 300 monogeneans collected on the gills of two wild malabar groupers, &lt;i&gt;Epinephelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malabaricus,&lt;/i&gt; caught in the lagoon of New Caledonia, South Pacific. Diplectanids included seven species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1958, which were differentiated mainly on the basis of morphology of the sclerotised vagina. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manifestus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was the most abundant species (65–80% of the diplectanids); all other species were rare. It is characterised by morphology of its vagina, in general shape of a question mark. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malabaricus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maternus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; both have a vagina with two spherical chambers, and are differentiated on the basis of measurements of these chambers. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manipulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has an elongate vagina with a long primary chamber. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marcellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a long vagina with two bends. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a long vagina with a straight primary canal and the two chambers united in a common sclerotised part. Two specimens were provisorily attributed to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;shenzhenensis&lt;/i&gt; Yang, Zeng &amp; Gibson, 2005. &lt;i&gt;Diplectanum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a funnel-shaped male copulatory organ. Two species of &lt;i&gt;Haliotrema&lt;/i&gt; (Ancyrocephal-idae) and &lt;i&gt;Pseudomegalocotyla&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Capsalidae) are mentioned but not described. The presence of 11 species of monogeneans in this fish, after a previous published record of 12 species in &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus,&lt;/i&gt; provides additional argument for existence of a very rich fauna of monogeneans in groupers, and an impressive parasite biodiversity in coral reef fish in general. Lists are given for other parasites of the malabar grouper, including monogeneans, digeneans, cestodes and nematodes, including new records from New Caledonia; more than 40 parasite species have been recorded in the literature. The malabar grouper is a major fish for aquaculture in South East Asia and a precise description of its parasites is needed for identification of potential threats to farmed fish.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Monogenea; Diplectanidae; Serranidae; Parasite lists; New Caledonia; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manifestus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malabaricus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maternus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manipulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marcellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Diplectanum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhabdosynochus&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;shenzhenensis&lt;/i&gt;; Ancyrocephalidae; &lt;i&gt;Haliotrema&lt;/i&gt; spp.; Capsalidae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudomegalocotyla&lt;/i&gt; sp.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Monogenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Lou</firstname>
          <lastname>Justine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aude</firstname>
          <lastname>Sigura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new cryptogonimid genera &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. and &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. (Digenea: Cryptogonimidae) from tropical Indo-West Pacific Haemulidae (Perciformes)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A survey of the parasites of Indo-West Pacific Haemulidae revealed the presence of three new cryptogonimid (Digenea: Cryptogonimidae) species warranting two new genera, &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littlewoodi&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicolla&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from the intestine and pyloric caeca of &lt;i&gt;Plectorhinchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbosus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marjoriae&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., n. sp. from the intestine and pyloric caeca of &lt;i&gt;Diagramma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiosum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albovittatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbosus&lt;/i&gt; from Heron and Lizard Islands off the Great Barrier Reef, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. is distinguished from all other cryptogonimid genera by the combination of an elongate body, funnel-shaped oral sucker, relatively small number of large oral spines, highly lobed ovary, opposite to slightly oblique testes, uterine loops that are restricted to the hindbody and extend well posterior to the testes and vitelline follicles that may extend from the ovary into the forebody, but do not extend anterior to the intestinal bifurcation. &lt;i&gt;Pseudallacanthochasmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plectorhynchi&lt;/i&gt; Mamaev, 1970 is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plectorhyncha&lt;/i&gt; (Mamaev, 1970) n. comb. based on morphological and ecological (host preference) characteristics. &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. is distinguished from all other cryptogonimid genera by the combination of a lanceolate body, relatively small number of large oral spines, prepharynx that is much longer than the oesophagus, tandem testes, uterine loops that are extensive in the hindbody and extend well posterior to the testes and vitelline follicles that extend from the ovary to the pharynx. Morphological analysis of the three species described here was augmented with DNA sequence analyses utilizing data from the large subunit (LSU) and the internal transcribed spacers (ITS) 1 and 2, and 5.8S nuclear ribosomal DNA. Sequence data from the LSU and ITS (encompassing the ITS1, 5.8S and ITS2) of the taxa examined here were aligned with those reported for other cryptogonimids, &lt;i&gt;Caulanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomasi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Latuterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tkachi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neometadena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovata,&lt;/i&gt; four representative species of &lt;i&gt;Retrovarium&lt;/i&gt; and an undescribed species of &lt;i&gt;Siphoderina,&lt;/i&gt; for comparative purposes and to explore levels of interspecific and intergeneric variation among these taxa. Minimum evolution analysis was conducted on a combined (LSU and ITS) dataset to explore relationships among these genera. Despite their superficial morphological and host preference similarities, species of &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema&lt;/i&gt; were genetically distant from each other. Interspecific and intergeneric variation among the species described here is similar to that reported for other cryptogonimids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cryptogonimidae; &lt;i&gt;Beluesca&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Chelediadema&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Caulanus&lt;/i&gt;; Haemulidae; Digenea; &lt;i&gt;Diagramma&lt;/i&gt;; internal transcribed spacers; ITS; Indo-West Pacific; Great Barrier Reef; &lt;i&gt;Latuterus&lt;/i&gt;; LSU; Lutjanidae; &lt;i&gt;Plectorhinchus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Siphoderina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Retrovarium.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cryptogonimidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terrence</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Speleonectes emersoni&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;a new species of Remipedia (Crustacea) from the Dominican Republic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Remipedia (Crustacea), &lt;i&gt;Speleonectes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emersoni,&lt;/i&gt; is described from two anchialine caves in the Dominican Republic. It represents the first record of remipedes for the island of Hispaniola. &lt;i&gt;Speleonectes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emersoni&lt;/i&gt; is a comparatively small-sized remipede. It can be distinguished from other species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Speleonectes&lt;/i&gt; by a combination of features that include: 1) a relatively large antennal exopod, 2) frontal filaments with subapically inserted medial processes extending over the tip of the main filament, 3) an arc-shaped horseshoe-type claw with 7–10 small denticles, and 4) an anal segment that is longer than wide with caudal rami nearly as long as the anal segment.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Remipedia; Speleonectidae; anchialine caves; Dominican Republic; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dorte</firstname>
          <lastname>Lorentzen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <lastname>Koenemann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Iliffe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1542.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1542</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Anillinus &lt;/i&gt;Casey (Carabidae: Trechinae: Bembidiini) from Great Smoky Mountains National Park, U.S.A. and phylogeography of the &lt;i&gt;A. langdoni&lt;/i&gt; species group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Anillinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langdoni–species&lt;/i&gt; group is characterized and two new species are described, &lt;i&gt;Anillinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cieglerae&lt;/i&gt; Sokolov and Carlton &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillus&lt;/i&gt; Sokolov and Carlton &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; both from Great Smoky Mountains National Park. The &lt;i&gt;langdoni–group&lt;/i&gt; includes four species at present, three apparently endemic to the Great Smoky Mountains and adjacent mountains of western North Carolina/Tennessee, and a fourth from South Mountains of middle North Carolina. They are distinguished mainly using characters of the male genitalia and to a lesser extent, differences in shapes of female spermathecae. Phylogenetic analyses based on aedeagal morphology and COI gene sequences yielded conflicting results, with the later providing a phylogeny that was more parsimonious with expectations based on geographic distributions. Speciation within the group may derive from ecological constraints and altitudinal fluctuations of habitat corridors during past climate changes combined with the impact of local watersheds as fine scale isolating mechanisms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Adephaga; Carabidae; &lt;i&gt;Anillinus&lt;/i&gt;; South Appalachians; new species; taxonomy; identification key; COI gene sequences; phylogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Igor</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sokolov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuliya</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sokolova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carlton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on the Canacidae (Diptera), subfamily Apetaeninae. I. &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus enderleini&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;nomen novum&lt;/i&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Listriomastax litorea&lt;/i&gt; Enderlein, 1909, with remarks on the chaetotaxy, morphology, and habitats of the Apetaeninae from the Kerguelen Biogeographical Province</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A thorough examination of the chaetotaxy and morphology of the subantarctic Apetaeninae &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litoralis&lt;/i&gt; Eaton, 1875 and &lt;i&gt;Listriomastax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litorea&lt;/i&gt; Enderlein, 1909 has corroborated the early generic synonymy proposed by Hennig (1971). Thus, the latter genus is re-considered as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; Eaton, 1875. Accordingly, &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litoreus&lt;/i&gt; (Enderlein, 1909), &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;preoccupatum&lt;/i&gt; by &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoreus&lt;/i&gt; (Hutton, 1902), changes its specific epithet by designation of the new name &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enderleini&lt;/i&gt; [nomen &lt;i&gt;novum].&lt;/i&gt; New remarks and observations on the range of chaetotactic variation as well as on the female abdomen morphology are given. Further, distributional and ecological records from the literature are summarized. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; from the Kerguelen Biogeographical Province is also proposed. The presumed validity of &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watsoni&lt;/i&gt; Hardy, 1962 from Macquarie Island is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt;; Kerguelen Biogeographical Province; &lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enderleini&lt;/i&gt; [nomen &lt;i&gt;novum]&lt;/i&gt;; chaetotaxy; morphology; ecology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apetaenus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lorenzo</firstname>
          <lastname>Munari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-34</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Corrections in the status and rank of names used to denote varietal forms of mosquitoes (Diptera: Culicidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The status and rank of mosquito varietal names listed in &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Catalog&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mosquitoes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;World&lt;/i&gt; are reviewed. Names proposed or adopted for existent varieties are deemed to be subspecific or infrasubspecific under provisions of the &lt;i&gt;International&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zoological&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nomenclature&lt;/i&gt; that regulate the rank of species-group names that follow binomina. Type data and taxonomic information are provided for each taxon.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Culicidae; mosquitoes; varieties; subspecies; infrasubspecies; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Culicidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralph</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Harbach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Theresa</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Howard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemiandrus&lt;/i&gt; (Orthoptera: Anostostomatidae) from Fiordland National Park, New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemiandrus&lt;/i&gt; are described from alpine habitat in the Sinbad Gully of Fiordland National Park, New Zealand. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superba&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is the largest known member of the genus, and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitaweta&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is perhaps the most brilliantly colored. Fiordland is a major centre of diversity for &lt;i&gt;Hemiandrus;&lt;/i&gt; a photographic overview and key to the species recorded from the Park are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anostostomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Hemiandrus;&lt;/i&gt; ground weta; new species; Sinbad Gully; Fiordland; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anostostomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Hemiandrus;&lt;/i&gt; ground weta; new species; Sinbad Gully; Fiordland; New Zealand</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tony</firstname>
          <lastname>Jewell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Panorpa&lt;/i&gt; (Mecoptera: Panorpidae) from Shaanxi, China with notes on their biology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of scorpionflies, &lt;i&gt;Panorpa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;byersi&lt;/i&gt; Hua et Huang and &lt;i&gt;Panorpa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicornis&lt;/i&gt; Hua et Li, from Shaanxi Province, China, are described and illustrated. Their male genitalia were observed under scanning electron microscopy. Their biology is briefly noticed with larval stage obtained through rearing. The type specimens are preserved in the Entomological Museum, Northwest A &amp; F University.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mecoptera; Panorpidae; &lt;i&gt;Panorpa&lt;/i&gt;; scorpionfly; new species; biology; Shaanxi; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mecoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xue</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Baozhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Hua</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lijun</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pengying</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Replacement name for a homonymous dragonfly generic name (Odonata)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gunther</firstname>
          <lastname>Fleck</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Janira</firstname>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1541.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1541</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediagnoses of the milliped genera &lt;i&gt;Pseudojulus&lt;/i&gt; Bollman, 1887, and &lt;i&gt;Arvechambus&lt;/i&gt; Causey, 1963, in the southeastern USA; description of &lt;i&gt;P. mississippiensis&lt;/i&gt;, n. sp. and proposal of the subtribe Pseudojulina (Julida: Parajulidae: Parajulinae: Aniulini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Pseudojulina &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subtribe,&lt;/b&gt; featuring lateral lobes on the 8 th sternum in males, is proposed for the milliped genera &lt;i&gt;Pseudojulus&lt;/i&gt; Bollman, 1887, &lt;i&gt;Arvechambus&lt;/i&gt; Causey, 1963, and &lt;i&gt;Arvechamboides&lt;/i&gt; Shelley, 2007 (Julida: Parajulidae: Parajulinae: Aniulini). The coordinate, nominate taxon, &lt;b&gt;Aniulina&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;stat.,&lt;/b&gt; is necessitated for other aniulinine genera, and "Southern &lt;b&gt;Clade"&lt;/b&gt; is proposed to replace "Aniulina" as the unofficial name for the tribal lineage comprising Aniulini + Gosiulini + Nesoressini + Parajulini. New accounts &amp; diagnoses, consistent with the new taxon, are presented for &lt;i&gt;Pseudojulus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Arvechambus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Arvechamboides,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mississippiensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., from Grenada County, Mississippi, is described. A variant displaying features of 3 species — &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paynei&lt;/i&gt; (Hoffman, 1992) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carolinensis&lt;/i&gt; &amp; &lt;i&gt;coastalis,&lt;/i&gt; both by Shelley, 2004 — is characterized as is a gynandromorph of &lt;i&gt;Arvechambus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hummi&lt;/i&gt; Causey, 1963, that possesses malformed gonopods &amp; cyphopods. Nomenclatural alterations appear necessary among family-group taxa in the Parajulidae; existing tribes may warrant elevation to subfamilies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudojulus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Arvechambus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Arvechamboides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mississippiensis&lt;/i&gt;; Pseudojulina; Aniulina; gynandromorph; southeastern US</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudojulus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rowland</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shelley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Tropocyclops&lt;/i&gt; (Copepoda, Cyclopidae) from Lake Matano, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Tropocyclops,&lt;/i&gt; from the subfamily Eucyclopinae (Cyclopoida, Cyclopidae) is described on the basis of specimens recently collected from the deep waters of the ancient Lake Matano, Indonesia. &lt;i&gt;Tropocyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matanoensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is distinguished from other species in the genus by the armature of P5 (with one seta and one spine) and the absence of lateral hairs on the somite bearing it, the antenna with only one seta on the antero-distal corner, the special shape of the seminal receptacle in female, and several other characters detailed in this study. A discussion of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tropocyclops&lt;/i&gt; and the morphological characteristics of its representatives is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Cyclopoida; Sulawesi; taxonomy; new species; &lt;i&gt;Tropocyclops&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danielle</firstname>
          <lastname>Defaye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-29</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new dwarf forest toad (Amphibia: Bufonidae:&lt;i&gt; Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt;) from the Ukaguru Mountains, Tanzania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt; from the Ukaguru Mountains, Eastern Arc Mountains Tanzania, is described. The new species is diagnosed by the presence of large prominent spines with keratinized tips, positioned on the dorsum, head and limbs. In addition, the combination of the following characters presence of large tympanum and annulum, foot longer than tibia, the lack of parotoid glands and advertisement call features, allow this species to be distinguished from all other species in the genus. The new species adds to our understanding of the relatively undersampled and poorly understood, amphibian fauna of the Ukaguru Mountains.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt;; Ukaguru Mountains; Eastern Arc; Biodiversity hotspot; Tanzania</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nectophrynoides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michele</firstname>
          <lastname>Menegon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sebastiano</firstname>
          <lastname>Salvidio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wilirk</firstname>
          <lastname>Ngalason</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-40</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genitive of species-group scientific names formed from personal names</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">To avoid confusion with citations of a generic name and its author, the &lt;i&gt;International&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zoological&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nomenclature&lt;/i&gt; encourages specific names based on personal names to be instigated in the genitive case. The Latin genitive suffix also indicates the gender and singular or plural state of the modified proper noun. Some zoologists have interpreted Article 31 as stipulating that these latter should always correspond with the gender and singular or plural state of the person or persons commemorated. They believe the original spelling is justifiably emended if, in their view, the author or authors have employed the incorrect suffix. We contend that the gender and singular or plural state of a noun so employed is part of its etymology and unregulated by the Code. The author's selection of suffix should be respected and the original spelling preserved. We offer a rewording of Article 31 to remedy this ambiguity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Code; emendation; genitive; gender; nomenclature; personal name; sex; species; spelling; suffix; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Code</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Douglas</firstname>
          <lastname>Brandon-Jones</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duckworth</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulina</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jenkins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rylands</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Esteban</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sarmiento</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus santanderensis:&lt;/i&gt; A new species of troglomorphic catfish (Siluriformes, Trichomycteridae) from Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santanderensis,&lt;/i&gt; described as a new species of troglomorphic catfish, was collected from the cave “El Puente” located in the upper Lebrija River basin of the Santander Department of northeast Colombia. The new species has light-red pigmentation, a first pectoral ray as long as the pectoral fin, and variable reduction in eye size. A comparative analysis with other troglomorphic species from South America and epigean species from northern Colombia is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Catfish; Trichomycteridae; Troglomorphic; Colombia; Siluriformes; Caves</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Catfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cesar</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Castellanos-Morales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-55</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on millipedes of the family Julidae (Diplopoda, Julida) from Altai, Siberia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sibiriulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;altaicus&lt;/i&gt; Guli…ka, 1972 is redescribed based upon topotype material. The species &lt;i&gt;Megaphyllum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sjaelandicum&lt;/i&gt; (Meinert, 1868) is recorded in the fauna of Siberia for the first time. Remarks are provided for the two species encountered and &lt;i&gt;Sibiriulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multinicus&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova, 2001, including notes on the variation of two latter species. All three species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sibiriulus&lt;/i&gt; Guli…ka, 1963 are keyed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diplopoda; Julida; &lt;i&gt;Sibiriulus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Megaphyllum&lt;/i&gt;; redescription; new record; variation; key; Russia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diplopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pavel</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nefediev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julia</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nefedieva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-63</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An index to new species of Nematoda in &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt; from 2003 to 2006</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">From 2003 to 2006, 17 papers describing 39 new species were published in &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt; by 38 authors from 13 countries. A bibliographic analysis of these papers and a list of the new taxa of Nematoda are presented in this paper.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; bibliography; index; taxonomy; literature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zeng</firstname>
          <middlename>Qi</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1540.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Aug. 2007</title>
    <volume>1540</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of Australian &lt;i&gt;Cymadusa&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Ampithoidae) with descriptions of eight new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cymadusa&lt;/i&gt; is a large genus of large bodied, predominantly tropical ampithoid amphipods. Prior to this paper 22 species were recognised in &lt;i&gt;Cymadusa&lt;/i&gt; of which four were known from Australia. Eight new species are described from Australia, increasing the known Australian species to 12. The new species described herein are: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chuawe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heronensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiigurru&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pemptos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thagaay&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; , &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tishana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wistari&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flindersi&lt;/i&gt; Stebbing, 1888 is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;Cymdusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setosa&lt;/i&gt; (Haswell, 1879). Diagnoses and a key to the Australian species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ampithoidae; Australia; Amphipoda; taxonomy; new species; &lt;i&gt;Cymadusa.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ampithoidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rachael</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Amazonian &lt;i&gt;Cryptocellus&lt;/i&gt; Westwood (Arachnida, Ricinulei)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cryptocellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;icamiabas&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from an adult male from Amazonas state, Brazil. The new species is a member of the Amazonian &lt;i&gt;foedus&lt;/i&gt; group, and is closest to &lt;i&gt;Cryptocellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abaporu&lt;/i&gt; Bonaldo &amp; Pinto-da-Rocha, 2003, &lt;i&gt;Cryptocellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;becki&lt;/i&gt; Platnick, 1977, and &lt;i&gt;Cryptocellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simonis&lt;/i&gt; Hansen &amp; Sorensen, 1904. The distribution pattern and morphology of the &lt;i&gt;foedus&lt;/i&gt; group are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropics; Brazilian Amazonia; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;foedus&lt;/i&gt; group; Ricinulei</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lucia</middlename>
          <lastname>Tourinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Clarissa</firstname>
          <middlename>Salette</middlename>
          <lastname>De Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus minutus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Hylidae) of the Guiana Shield: using DNA barcodes to assess identity and diversity</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Herein we discuss the geographic structure of genetic variation of the widely distributed lesser treefrog (Dendropsophus &lt;i&gt;minutus)&lt;/i&gt; from the Guianas in a preliminary examination of the status of Guianan populations referred to this taxon. Current sampling is insufficient to determine the status of all lineages of this complex within South America, but our results do indicate the presence of cryptic species within this relatively small portion of the ‘species’ range. Our findings reveal a geographic discontinuity of genetic structure within this region that appears to be correlated with elevation. We also present evidence that supports previous assertions that the conventional DNA barcode locus (COI) is not suitable for amphibians.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt;; DNA barcoding; Guiana Shield</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendropsophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Monty</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hawkins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jack</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brice</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Noonan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Second International Symposium of Integrative Zoology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <lastname>Buckeridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-08-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
