<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1436.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1436</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acalyptris &lt;/i&gt;Meyrick: revision of the &lt;i&gt;platani &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;staticis &lt;/i&gt;groups in Europe and the Mediterranean (Lepidoptera: Nepticulidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The European and Mediterranean species of the &lt;i&gt;Acalyptris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platani&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staticis&lt;/i&gt; groups are revised, with respectively four and six species. Three new species are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pistaciae&lt;/i&gt; Van Nieukerken &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (from Greece, Cyprus and Turkey, on &lt;i&gt;Pistacia)&lt;/i&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;platani&lt;/i&gt; group, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limoniastri&lt;/i&gt; Van Nieukerken &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (from Algeria and Tunisia, associated with &lt;i&gt;Limoniastrum)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lesbia&lt;/i&gt; Van Nieukerken &amp; Hull &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (from Greece: Lesvos, on &lt;i&gt;Limonium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gmelini)&lt;/i&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;staticis&lt;/i&gt; group. Lectotypes are selected for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minimella&lt;/i&gt; (Rebel, 1924) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staticis&lt;/i&gt; (Walsingham, 1908). The European species of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platani&lt;/i&gt; group are leafminers on Anacardiaceae, Platanaceae and Loranthaceae, the species of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staticis&lt;/i&gt; group feed on Plumbaginaceae, except &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrenaica&lt;/i&gt; A. &amp; Z. Laštůvka, for which the host is unknown, but likely to belong to another family. Immatures are described for five species, final instar larvae and pupal exuviae for all species in the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platani&lt;/i&gt; group and for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lesbia.&lt;/i&gt; Larvae and pupae of the latter species differ markedly from the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platani&lt;/i&gt; group. Recorded parasitoids are listed. CO1 barcodes are provided for seven species. The groups are phylogenetically not very close; the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Acalyptris&lt;/i&gt; and the phylogeny on the basis of CO1 (mt-DNA) sequences are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; new species; phylogeny; larval morphology; pupal morphology; hostplants; Anacardiaceae; Platanaceae; Loranthaceae; Plumbaginaceae; CO1; DNA-barcodes; Palaearctic; Hymenoptera; Eulophidae; Braconidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy; new species; phylogeny; larval morphology; pupal morphology; hostplants; Anacardiaceae; Platanaceae; Loranthaceae; Plumbaginaceae; CO1; DNA-barcodes; Palaearctic; Hymenoptera; Eulophidae; Braconidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Erik</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Nieukerken</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hainanaella lutea &lt;/i&gt;gen. and sp. nov., a new genus and species of delphacid planthopper (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of Chinese Delphacidae (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha), &lt;i&gt;Hainanaella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; with one new species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated. The new genus is assigned to the tribe Delphacini &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Asche (1985, 1990), and subtribe Numatina based on the definition of Emeljanov (1993).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Delphacidae; Delphacini; Taxonomy; Auchenorrhyncha; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Delphacidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dao-Zheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Qin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ya-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Caryanda jiuyishana &lt;/i&gt;Fu &amp; Zheng, 2000 (Orthoptera: Acrididae: Oxyinae: Oxyini) with proposal of a new synomym</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caryanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiuyishana&lt;/i&gt; Fu &amp; Zheng is redescribed with proposal of &lt;i&gt;Caryanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhengi&lt;/i&gt; Fu &amp; Sun as a new junior synonym of the species as a result of reexamination of their type specimens and a series of specimens from the type localities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caryanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiuyishana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Caryanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhengi&lt;/i&gt;; new synonym; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caryanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jiuyishana&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jianhua</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peng</firstname>
          <lastname>Fu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuan</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic study of the genus &lt;i&gt;Zema &lt;/i&gt;Fennah (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha: Tropiduchidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Hemiptera: Fulgoroidea: Tropiduchidae) is described and illustrated from Yunnan, southwestern China. This represents the second known species of &lt;i&gt;Zema.&lt;/i&gt; The type species, &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gressitti&lt;/i&gt; Fennah, unrecorded since its 1956 description, is redescribed and illustrated and a revised generic description provided. New distributional records for &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gressitti&lt;/i&gt; are given for Nepal and China (Yunnan, Xizang).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zema&lt;/i&gt;; Tropiduchidae; new species; new distribution records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zema&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rong-Rong</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ai-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Liang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1435.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1435</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological characterization of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus elenae &lt;/i&gt;tadpoles (Anura: Leptodactylidae: &lt;i&gt;L. fuscus &lt;/i&gt;group), from central Paraguay</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper we characterize the morphology of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elenae&lt;/i&gt; tadpoles (L. &lt;i&gt;fuscus&lt;/i&gt; group) from central Paraguay, considering external morphology, oral disc, buccopharyngeal cavity, skeleton and musculature (N = 17; Gosner Stage 36–37; Central, Paraguay). Specimens were fixed with 10% formaline and were prepared according to a classic staining protocol. These larvae show external traits similar to those of other taxa within the group, such as an ovoid and depressed body, left spiracle, ventromedial vent tube, and marginal papillae interrupted in a wide rostral gap. Distinctive features are the rounded snout, the distally wide and rounded tail, the labial tooth formula 2(2)/3(1), lateral constrictions absent, and the large internal marginal papillae, intercalated every two or four small external marginal papillae. Inside the buccopharyngeal cavity, traits shared with related species are the prenarial ridge, the transversal nares, two pairs of infralabial papillae, the medial ones joined at their bases, four lingual papillae, and dorsal and ventral vela with secretory epithelium. Skeletal configuration is constant within the genus, with common character states such as the quadripartite suprarostral cartilage, quadratoorbital commissure and larval crista parotica present, larval otic process absent, ceratobranchials fused to the hypobranchial plates, anterior branchial process, and basihyal absent. &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elenae&lt;/i&gt; and other &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscus&lt;/i&gt; group species resemble taxa from the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentadactylus&lt;/i&gt; group, due to the configuration of the branchial process, the articular process of the palatoquadrate, the suspensorium, and the trabecular horns; this can be observed in the chondrocranium and hyobranchial skeleton morphospaces for 22 species of the genus. Finally, muscular features are also maintained at intra-genus level, with common traits such as m. mandibulolabialis superior absent, mm. diaphragmatopraecordialis, interhyoideus posterior and hyoangularis medialis present, m. subarcualis rectus I with 3 slips, and m. subarcualis rectus II–IV inserted on ceratobranchial III. Further analyses on intraspecific variation and descriptions of related larvae are needed to improve the knowledge about this diverse genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elenae;&lt;/i&gt; tadpole; external morphology; buccopharyngeal cavity; chondrocranium; hyobranchial skeleton; musculature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elenae;&lt;/i&gt; tadpole; external morphology; buccopharyngeal cavity; chondrocranium; hyobranchial skeleton; musculature</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Florencia Vera</middlename>
          <lastname>Candioti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Brusquetti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Flavia</firstname>
          <lastname>Netto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Arthropoda: Pycnogonida) from the Great Barrier Reef and discussion on the &lt;i&gt;A. tenuicorpus&lt;/i&gt;-complex</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of sea spider is described from the Great Barrier Reef, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perissoporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;n.sp.&lt;/i&gt; is in a species complex of extremely slender and tenuous forms that have serrated heel spines and are known to inhabit IndoWest Pacific coral reefs. The new species is characterized by the multiple cement gland pores on femora of males. Otherwise the species is very similar to, and probably closely related to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuicorpus.&lt;/i&gt; The species boundaries within the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuicorpus&lt;/i&gt; complex are difficult to discern and are not clearly defined, especially for females. Other character sets seem necessary to indicate affinities and distribution patterns of the &lt;i&gt;tenuicorpus&lt;/i&gt; complex.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sea spiders; &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; coral reefs; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sea spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claudia</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arango</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franz</firstname>
          <lastname>Krapp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-24</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of vent associated &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Galatheidae) from the Western Pacific, with notes on its genetic identification</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myojinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; herein described and illustrated from Myojin Knoll and Northwest Eifuku Seamount in the Western Pacific, is the tenth species of &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; known to be associated with active hydrothermal vents. It resembles &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;starmer&lt;/i&gt; Baba &amp; de Saint Laurent, 1992 in general ornamentation and spination of the body but differs in the erectness of the eyespine and form of the telson plates. Information on genetic identification using mitochondrial sequences (COI) is provided. Distributions of the vent associated &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; in the Western Pacific and the habitat of the new species are briefly described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anomura; Galatheidae; &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt;; Hydrothermal vent; Myojin Knoll; Eifuku Seamount</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anomura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sherine</firstname>
          <middlename>Sonia</middlename>
          <lastname>Cubelio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shinji</firstname>
          <lastname>Tsuchida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michel</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hendrickx</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ryusuke</firstname>
          <lastname>Kado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Seiichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Watanabe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-36</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery of the sea cucumber &lt;i&gt;"Toxodora" pacifica &lt;/i&gt;Ohshima, 1915 (Echinodermata: Holothuroidea: Apodida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The apodous holothurian species originally described by Ohshima (1915) as &lt;i&gt;Toxodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; has been rediscovered, and its known geographic range extended from Suruga Bay, Japan to the western side of the Yellow Sea, China. As the genus name &lt;i&gt;Toxodora&lt;/i&gt; is no longer available, a new genus name, &lt;i&gt;Neotoxodora&lt;/i&gt; Liao, Pawson, and Wei, is proposed. The type material of &lt;i&gt;Neotoxodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; is lost, and a Neotype is named for this species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Toxodora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neotoxodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt;; Holothuroidea; Apodida; Yellow Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Toxodora&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yulin</firstname>
          <lastname>Liao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pawson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-40</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Halacarid mites (Acari: Halacaridae) from Esperance (Western Australia), description of two new &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus &lt;/i&gt;species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticeps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described. The two species are from the southern coast of Western Australia, from Esperance. &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticeps&lt;/i&gt; has a long, slender gnathosoma, the rostrum is about as long as the gnathosomal base, major parts of the dorsal and ventral plates are punctate, the hardly delimited porose areolae have a similar ornamentation, the epimeral pores are enlarged. In &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvulus&lt;/i&gt; the slender rostrum is almost twice as long as the gnathosomal base, the dorsal and ventral plates are almost smooth except for the sharply delimited areolae with rosette pores. &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaurus&lt;/i&gt; Bartsch, 1999 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australensis&lt;/i&gt; (Lohmann, 1909), which are new records in the Esperance fauna, are also characterized by an elongate gnathosoma, but are not closely related with any of the two new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Australia; south-western coast; Halacaroidea; &lt;i&gt;Copidognathus&lt;/i&gt;; new records; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Australia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ilse</firstname>
          <lastname>Bartsch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-49</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new rock dwelling frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (Amphibia: Leptodactylidae) from Eastern Cuba, with comments on other species with similar habits</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (subgenus &lt;i&gt;Euhyas)&lt;/i&gt; is described from the limestone region at the north slope of the Sierra Maestra, Eastern Cuba. It is a large, rock dwelling species with enlarged digital discs and mottled dorsum. It closely resembles &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bresslerae,&lt;/i&gt; differing from it by a combination of external characters, chromosome patterns, and vocalization. Comparisons are also made with &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ricordii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acmonis,&lt;/i&gt; and some other Cuban members of the genus that share similar habits.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euhyas&lt;/i&gt;; Cuba; new species; rock/cave ecomorph</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <lastname>Cadiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nils</firstname>
          <lastname>Navarro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1434.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1434</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Intraspecific variation of the caudal fin skeleton in &lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum bicirrhosum&lt;/i&gt; Cuvier 1829 (Teleostei: Osteoglossomorpha: Osteoglossidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The caudal fin skeleton has been regarded as a major source of characters used in the evaluation of teleostean interrelationships. Despite the increasing number of papers drawing attention to the variability observed within species when large samples are considered, intraspecific variation of this complex remains poorly known for many teleostean groups, and comparative anatomical studies still often rely on a small number of specimens. Within the Osteoglossomorpha, there are few studies concerning instraspecific variation patterns, and many aspects of both the anatomy and homology of the caudal fin skeleton elements are controversial (e.g. epurals &lt;i&gt;versus&lt;/i&gt; uroneurals; number of hypurals compounding the “hypural fan”). Given this perspective, we examined the caudal skeleton of 84 specimens of the neotropical osteoglossid fish &lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicirrhosum,&lt;/i&gt; and described and quantified its morphological variation. We determined that the number of neural spines on the preural centra and hypural fusion patterns showed the greatest variation. Despite the widespread distribution of this taxon, the observed variation appears to be geographically independent, and occurs randomly within populations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt;; caudal skeleton; intraspecific variation; Osteoglossidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>E. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca acanthurum &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Nematoda: Cosmocercidae) in &lt;i&gt;Pseudoeurycea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leprosa &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Chiropterotriton orculus &lt;/i&gt;from the Transmexican Volcanic Belt, Central Mexico&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;with a checklist of the helminth parasites of plethodontid salamanders</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Plethodontid salamanders represent a group of amphibians that show a great evolutionary diversification in México, however no study of their helminth parasites had been conducted thus far. In this paper, we describe &lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Nematoda: Cosmocercidae) from the intestine of the plethodontid salamanders &lt;i&gt;Pseudoeurycea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leprosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chiropterotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orculus&lt;/i&gt; from Llano Grande and Texcalyacac, Estado de México, in Central México. &lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is easily distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca&lt;/i&gt; in that females possess a uniquely spined tail, a character no seen in congeners. In addition, we compiled all the information of helminth parasites of plethodontid salamanders, and we present it in the form of a checklist of both parasite-host, and host-parasite. A brief analysis of the helminth parasite species composition is presented regarding life-history and development characteristics of plethodontids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Helminths; Plethodontidae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudoeurycea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leprosa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Chiropterotriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orculus&lt;/i&gt;; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cosmocerca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Helminths</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Falcon-Ordaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Windfield-Perez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mendoza-Garfias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Parra-Olea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.-P.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Leon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-49</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella &lt;/i&gt;(Annelida: Sabellidae: Sabellinae) from Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; Fitzhugh &amp; Rouse, 1999 are described from eastern Australia. &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hutchingsae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; was found from preserved coral rock debris collected in 1977 on the outer Barrier Reef near Lizard Island, Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fitzhughi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; was found alive in burrows in and among spirorbin serpulid tubes on intertidal rocks in Tasmania in 1996. Both species were found in mucoid tubes, and brood their young in a manner similar to the only other described species of &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterouncinata&lt;/i&gt; Fitzhugh &amp; Rouse, 1999. &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hutchingsae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is exceptional as it possesses a type of thoracic neurochaetal uncinus different from the other two species, and which is similar to the notochaetal acicular “palmate hook” seen in &lt;i&gt;Caobangia.&lt;/i&gt; Descriptions of both species are given, and the diagnosis for &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; is emended. Larval and chaetal morphology and relationships among of the three known &lt;i&gt;Terebrasabella&lt;/i&gt; spp. are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">polychaete; bioerosion; burrow; hermaphrodite</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">polychaete</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <lastname>Murray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Greg</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rouse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1433.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1433</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Palaearctic species of &lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer, 1900 (Hymenoptera: Aulacidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Palaearctic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1900 are revised and illustrated for the first time. Twenty-one valid species are recognized. Two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edoardoi&lt;/i&gt; Turrisi, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Crete Island and Greece, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paglianoi&lt;/i&gt; Turrisi, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Morocco and Tunisia. Four new synonymies are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Aulacus&lt;/i&gt; (Pristaula- &lt;i&gt;cus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holtzi&lt;/i&gt; Schulz, 1906 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressus&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola, 1808) (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.);&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arozarenae&lt;/i&gt; Ortega &amp; Baez, 1985 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galitae&lt;/i&gt; (Gribodo, 1879) (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.);&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Aulacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sibiricola&lt;/i&gt; Semenow, 1892 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbator&lt;/i&gt; (Thunberg, 1822) (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.);&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holzschuhi&lt;/i&gt; Madl, 1990 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gloriator&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1804) (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; The following synonymies are confirmed on the basis of the study of type material: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscuripennis&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1841 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressus&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola, 1808); &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1900 and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;immaculatus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1904 = &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galitae&lt;/i&gt; (Gribodo, 1879). Three &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri&lt;/i&gt; Tournier, 1911, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plurimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; Tournier, 1911, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversostriatus&lt;/i&gt; Tournier, 1911, previously assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Aulacus,&lt;/i&gt; are all synonyms of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressus&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola, 1808) (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; The previously unknown male of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boninensis&lt;/i&gt; Konishi, 1990 is described. Lectotypes and paralectotypes of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comptipennis&lt;/i&gt; Enderlein, 1912, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;immaculatus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1904, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arozarenae&lt;/i&gt; Ortega &amp; Baez, 1985 are designated. A key to species and distributional maps are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic Region; systematic revision; new species; distribution; biology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
          <middlename>Fabrizio</middlename>
          <lastname>Turrisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-76</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1432.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1432</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Parabradya &lt;/i&gt;Lang, 1944 (Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Ectinosomatidae) from the abyssal plain of the Angola Basin</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;samsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from deep-sea samples collected from the Angola Basin during the DIVA-1 campaign in July 2000. &lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;samsoni&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from its congeners by: its bigger size, the ornamentation of the body, the cuticula (except for that of the cephalic shield and the genital field) is covered with spinules, the multipinnate setae of A1, A2, mouthparts, P1–P5 and caudal rami, and the position of the innermost seta of P5, which is not directly situated at the inner distal corner, but displaced towards the outer edge. Full generic rank is assigned to both &lt;i&gt;Bradya&lt;/i&gt; Boeck, 1873 and &lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944. With &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;samsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt; includes five species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt;; species description; taxonomy; deep sea; scanning electron microscopy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parabradya&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sybille</firstname>
          <lastname>Seifried</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christoph</firstname>
          <lastname>Plum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maximilian</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A basal phylogenetic placement for the salticid spider &lt;i&gt;Eupoa&lt;/i&gt;, with descriptions of two new species (Araneae: Salticidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The southeast Asian genus &lt;i&gt;Eupoa&lt;/i&gt; includes small salticid spiders with unusual palpi. Two new species of the genus are described. Two morphological characters (presence of a median apophysis in the male palp and of a tarsal claw in the female palp) suggest it is excluded from the main clade of salticids (the Salticoida). Sequences of nuclear and mitochondrial gene regions (28S, 18S, 16S–ND1, CO1), analyzed by parsimony and Bayesian methods, agree that &lt;i&gt;Eupoa&lt;/i&gt; is a basal (non-salticoid) salticid, but fail to find a clear placement. &lt;i&gt;Eupoa&lt;/i&gt; may represent a deep-branching lineage long separate from the lyssomanines, spartaeines, and other basal groups.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Salticidae; &lt;i&gt;Eupoa&lt;/i&gt;; lapsiines; Spartaeinae; Lyssomaninae; Hisponinae; jumping spider; basal groups; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wayne</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>X.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Melissa</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bodner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-33</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stictodora cablei &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Digenea: Heterophyidae) from the royal tern, &lt;i&gt;Sterna maxima &lt;/i&gt;(Laridae: Sterninae) from Puerto Rico and the Brazos County area of the Texas Gulf coast, U.S.A., with a list of other endohelminths recovered in Texas</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During a study of the endohelminths of wading birds from the Texas Gulf coast, 3 immature specimens of &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; (Heterophyidae) representing the same species that had previously been identified as &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthotrema&lt;/i&gt; from the royal tern, &lt;i&gt;Sterna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maxima,&lt;/i&gt; in Puerto Rico by Raymond M. Cable, Robert S. Connor, and Jan W. Balling in 1960 were recovered from a royal tern, collected from the Bryan Utility Lake, Bryan, Texas. An additional 17 slides (14 whole mounts and 3 slides of sections) of this species that had been collected from this same bird host in Puerto Rico by Dr. Raymond M. Cable were examined from the holdings of the Harold W. Manter Laboratory of Parasitology, University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. This species of &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; has the characteristic of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Galactosomoides&lt;/i&gt; and does not conform to the original description of &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; (=Acanthotrema) &lt;i&gt;acanthotrema&lt;/i&gt; from the royal tern in Brazil, and it is therefore described as &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cablei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. The new species can be distinguished from all the other species in the genus by its unique acetabulogenital complex in which the acetabulum is highly modified with a small pad-like structure at its base surrounded by 3 papilliform arms extending sinistrally from it, whose outer edges fuse with the wall of the acetabulogenital sac, supporting the walls of the sac and the genital opening, and where the acetabulogenital sac contains a second, larger pad-like structure (the gonotyl described by Raymond M. Cable, Robert S. Conner, and Jan W. Balling in 1960) that extends from the left wall of the sac. Eleven other endohelminths were found in royal terns from Texas, U.S.A.: 3 cestodes, &lt;i&gt;Angularella&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Dilepididae), an unknown genus and species of Dilepididae, and an unidentified immature cestode; 1 nematode, &lt;i&gt;Contracaecum&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Anisakidae); and 7 trematodes, &lt;i&gt;Cardiocephaloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brandesii&lt;/i&gt; (Strigeidae), &lt;i&gt;Cercarioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cochleariformis&lt;/i&gt; (Heterophyidae), &lt;i&gt;Mesostephanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fajardensis&lt;/i&gt; (Cyathocotylidae), &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andersoni&lt;/i&gt; (Philophthalmidae), &lt;i&gt;Parorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthus&lt;/i&gt; (Philophthalmidae), &lt;i&gt;Stephanoprora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conciliata&lt;/i&gt; (Echinostomatidae), and &lt;i&gt;Stephanoprora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt; (Echinostomatidae). &lt;i&gt;Angularella&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Contracaecum&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fajardensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conciliata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cochleariformis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthus&lt;/i&gt; represent new host records. A checklist of parasites previously reported from the royal tern is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Angularella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Beaverostomum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cardiocephaloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brandesii;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cercarioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cochleariformis;&lt;/i&gt; Cestoda; &lt;i&gt;Contracaecum;&lt;/i&gt; Digenea; Dilepididae; Gulf of Mexico; &lt;i&gt;Mesostephanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fajardensis;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andersoni;&lt;/i&gt; Nematoda; &lt;i&gt;Parorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthus;&lt;/i&gt; Puerto Rico; royal tern; &lt;i&gt;Stephanoprora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conciliata;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stephanoprora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sterna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maxima;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; (Acanthotrema) &lt;i&gt;acanthotrema;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stictodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cablei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; Stictodorinae; Texas; Trematoda; U.S.A.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Angularella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dronen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Blend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gardner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jimenez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Halisarca &lt;/i&gt;(Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from the Sea of Okhotsk, North Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of sponge without skeleton, &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;korotkovae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Sea of Okhotsk. It differs from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; by its different ecological conditions, as well as by its morphology and histology. The new species is characterized by its fulvous colour and by its big nucleolated, eosinophilic microgranular cells (18.7×9.5 to 10.8×7.1 µm) concentrated mainly in the ectosomal part of sponge in aggregates up to 40 µm in diameter.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Porifera; &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Sea of Okhotsk; NW Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ereskovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the generic status of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes jackhintoni &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, 2006, with a new key to the genus &lt;i&gt;Laomenes &lt;/i&gt;Clark (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1431.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1431</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the species of &lt;i&gt;Hydraena &lt;/i&gt;Kugelann (Coleoptera: Hydraenidae) from Palawan and Busuanga, with descriptions of eleven new species, and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Hydraena &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Hydraenopsis&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;scabra &lt;/i&gt;d'Orchymont, 1925</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt; Kugelann from the Philippine Islands of Palawan and Busuanga are revised. Eleven new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;busuanga&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;castanescens&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;claudia&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;hosiwergi&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;jojoorculloi&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;kodadai&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;manguao&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;nielshaggei&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;palawanensis&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;pseudopalawanensis&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;zetteli&lt;/i&gt; Freitag &amp; Jäch, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt; (Hydraenopsis) &lt;i&gt;scabra&lt;/i&gt; d’Orchymont, 1925 is redescribed and its distribution in the Philippines documented. A key to the &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt; species of Palawan and Busuanga is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydraenidae; &lt;i&gt;Hydraena&lt;/i&gt;; Palawan; Busuanga; Philippines; South-East Asia; taxonomy; water beetles</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Freitag</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manfred</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sipunculans of the Caribbean coast of Venezuela and Curacao</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">All sipunculan species currently known to occur on the Caribbean coast of Venezuela and Curaçao are reviewed. Included are species previously reported in the primary literature and those collected by Cutler (EBC) in 1987/1988 and Hernández-Ávila (IHA) in 2003/2004. Nineteen species of sipunculans belonging to eleven genera are known from this region. Most specious is the genus &lt;i&gt;Aspidosiphon&lt;/i&gt; with seven species and the genus &lt;i&gt;Phascolosoma&lt;/i&gt; with three species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sipuncula; faunal list; Caribbean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sipuncula</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dean</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hernandez-Avila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cutler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-54</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lamnatibia&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of the &lt;i&gt;Polysphincta &lt;/i&gt;group of genera from Colombia (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae; Pimplinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of the &lt;i&gt;Polysphincta&lt;/i&gt; group of genera (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae; Pimplinae), &lt;i&gt;Lamnatibia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andina&lt;/i&gt; Palacio &amp; Sääksjärvi, is described from the cloudforests of the Colombian Andes. The new genus can be easily separated from other genera of the &lt;i&gt;Polysphincta&lt;/i&gt; group by the specialized shape of the fore and middle femora, the presence of a thin, longitudinal ridge in the inner face of the fore and middle tibiae, and the combined absence of occipital and epicnemial carinae. The new genus’s potential affinities with other genera of the &lt;i&gt;Polysphincta&lt;/i&gt; group and its distribution are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Colombia; Hymenoptera; Ichneumonidae; &lt;i&gt;Lamnatibia&lt;/i&gt;; neotropics; new genus; new species; Pimplinae; phylogeny; South America; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Colombia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Edgard</firstname>
          <lastname>Palacio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ilari</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Saaksjarvi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Varpu</firstname>
          <lastname>Vahtera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-63</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on some Western Palaearctic Xantholinini (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae). 181° contribution to the knowledge of the Staphylinidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Milichilinus&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1908, described as a subgenus of &lt;i&gt;Xantholinus&lt;/i&gt; Dejean, 1821, is elevated to the status of genus on the basis of some external characters and an aedeagus with large parameres. The genus currently includes &lt;i&gt;Milichilinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorus&lt;/i&gt; (Erichson, 1839), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Milichilinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meybohmi&lt;/i&gt; (Assing, 2006), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lepidophallus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulatus&lt;/i&gt; Bordoni, 2004 is recorded as new from Bulgaria. The following replacement names are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Echdysia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Edulia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Emathidis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for the preoccupied &lt;i&gt;Elgonia&lt;/i&gt; Bordoni, 2001, &lt;i&gt;Lepta&lt;/i&gt; Bordoni, 2002 and &lt;i&gt;Cibyra&lt;/i&gt; Bordoni, 2002, respectively. The holotype of &lt;i&gt;Lepidophallus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicatellatus&lt;/i&gt; Bordoni, 2005 is preserved in Schülke collection in Berlin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Xantholinini; &lt;i&gt;Milichilinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lepidophallus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Elgonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lepta&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cibyra&lt;/i&gt;; replacement names</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arnaldo</firstname>
          <lastname>Bordoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1430.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1430</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics of the Palaearctic and Oriental lizard tribe Lacertini (Squamata: Lacertidae: Lacertinae), with descriptions of eight new genera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">DNA sequence indicates the Lacertidae contain two subfamilies, Gallotiinae and Lacertinae, the latter comprising two monophyletic tribes, the Eremiadini of Africa and arid southwest and central Asia, and the Lacertini of Europe, northwest Africa and southwest and east Asia. Relationships within the 108 species of Lacertini are explored using mtDNA (291 bp cytochrome b; 329 bp 12S rRNA for 59 nominal species, and reanalysis of the data of Harris &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 1998, and Fu 2000). The morphology of the tribe is reviewed and 64 of its characters (equivalent to 83 binary ones) also used to assess relationships. The Lacertini are assigned to 19 monophyletic units of 1 to 27 species, recognised here as the following genera (contents are indicated in brackets): &lt;i&gt;Algyroides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anatololacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;danfordi&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Apathya&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;cappadocica&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Archaeolacerta&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;bedriagae),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dalmatolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;oxycephala),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Darevskia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saxicola&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Dinarolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;mosorensis),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hellenolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;graeca),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Iranolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;brandtii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zagrosica),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lacerta&lt;/i&gt; s. str. (sand and green lizards, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agilis&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Parvilacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fraasii),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Phoenicolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (L. &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; group), &lt;i&gt;Podarcis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(wall&lt;/i&gt; lizards), &lt;i&gt;Scelarcis&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;perspicillata),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Takydromus&lt;/i&gt; (Asian grass lizards), &lt;i&gt;Teira&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;dugesii),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Timon&lt;/i&gt; (ocellated lizards, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepida&lt;/i&gt; group) and &lt;i&gt;Zootoca&lt;/i&gt; (L. &lt;i&gt;vivipara).&lt;/i&gt; Both mtDNA and morphology indicate that &lt;i&gt;Lacerta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Timon&lt;/i&gt; are sister taxa, and DNA suggests further possible relationships among genera (Fig. 1, p. 6). Neither DNA nor morphology indicates that the archaeolacertas (sometimes formalised as &lt;i&gt;Archaeolacerta&lt;/i&gt; sens. lat.) form a clade. Instead, they are representatives of an ecomorph associated with living on rock exposures and using the narrow crevices that these contain. The Lacertidae probably arose in the European area, with the Gallotiinae later reaching Northwest Africa and the Canary Islands, and the ancestor of the Eremiadini invading Africa in the mid-Miocene. The Lacertini spread through much of their present European range and diversified, perhaps largely by repeated vicariance, around 12–16 My ago, producing the ancestors of the present mainly small-bodied genera, which then underwent often modest speciation. Three units spread more widely: the &lt;i&gt;Lacerta-Timon&lt;/i&gt; clade of large-bodied lizards probably dispersed earliest, followed by &lt;i&gt;Algyroides&lt;/i&gt; and then &lt;i&gt;Podarcis.&lt;/i&gt; Overall, European Lacertidae show a pattern of repeated spread, often accompanied by restriction of previous groups. Expansion of Lacertini may have displaced earlier lacertid lineages from all or much of Europe; while spread of &lt;i&gt;Podarcis&lt;/i&gt; may have restricted many other genera of Lacertini. The earlier expansion of the &lt;i&gt;Lacerta-Timon&lt;/i&gt; clade probably did not have this effect, as difference in adult body size restricted competitive interaction with other forms. Several invasions of more distant areas also occurred: of East Asia by &lt;i&gt;Takydromus&lt;/i&gt; over 10 My ago, and more recently of northwest Africa by &lt;i&gt;Podarcis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scelarcis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Timon,&lt;/i&gt; and Madeira by &lt;i&gt;Teira.&lt;/i&gt; Relationships within the Eremiadini estimated from both mtDNA, and nDNA differ considerably from those based on morphology. They indicate relatively mesic forms may have diversified widely across Africa and given rise to at least three independent invasions of arid habitats. MtDNA also indicates that &lt;i&gt;Lacerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andreanskyi&lt;/i&gt; belongs in the Eremiadini and may occupy a basal position there. It is assigned to a further new genus, &lt;i&gt;Atlantolacerta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Lacertini; Eremiadini; Lacertidae; systematics; phylogeny; evolution; mitochondrial DNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>Nicholas</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Arribas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Salvador</firstname>
          <lastname>Carranza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-86</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1429.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1429</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the shovel-nosed lobsters of the genus &lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Decapoda: Scyllaridae), with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The shovel-nosed lobster genus &lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1815, long considered to contain only &lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt; (Lund, 1793), is revised and five species recognised. &lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indicus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1815, which had been relegated to the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis,&lt;/i&gt; is reinstated and a lectotype designated. Three new species &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australiensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parindicus&lt;/i&gt; are diagnosed. Specimens of &lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt; were collected from various locations throughout the Indo-West Pacific Oceans. Samples were analysed using a concordance approach involving three techniques: morphometrics/morphology, starch gel isozyme electrophoresis, and mitochondrial DNA sequencing of 16S and COI genes. All three investigations supported the recognition of five species. Despite significant genetic divergence, several sympatric species are morphologically similar and identification can be difficult; a key using a combination of live colour patterns and morphometric ratios is presented as an aid to species discrimination.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt;; shovel-nosed lobster; Indo-West Pacific; new species; DNA; 16S; COI; electophoresis; allozyme; morphometrics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thenus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Burton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of seven new species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Diptacus &lt;/i&gt;Keifer (Acari: Eriophyoidea: Diptilomiopidae: Diptilomiopinae) from northwestern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; Keifer from northwestern China are described: &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abelis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Abelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biflora&lt;/i&gt; Turcz. (Caprifoliaceae); &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhouzhisis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Carpinus&lt;/i&gt; sp. L. (Betulaceae); &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maddenis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Maddenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypoleuca&lt;/i&gt; Koehne (Rosaceae); &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wenisis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Viburnum&lt;/i&gt; sp. L. (Caprifoliaceae); &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrulatis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Photinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrulata&lt;/i&gt; Lindl. (Rosaceae); &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mercuriasis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Mercurialis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leiocarpa&lt;/i&gt; Sieb. et Zucc. (Euphorbiaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Diptacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorbusis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Sorbus&lt;/i&gt; sp. L. (Rosaceae). All species described here are vagrant on the undersurface of host leaves.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; leaf vagrants; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zi-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yue</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first zoea of &lt;i&gt;Inachus aguiarii&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Inachus communissimus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Ergasticus clouei&lt;/i&gt; (Decapoda, Brachyura, Majoidea) with implications for the systematics of the family Inachidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first zoeal stages of the inachid crabs &lt;i&gt;Inachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aguiarii&lt;/i&gt; de Brito Capello, 1876, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;communissimus&lt;/i&gt; Rizza, 1839 and &lt;i&gt;Ergasticus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clouei&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1882, are described and illustrated from laboratory-hatched material obtained from ovigerous females collected in the western Mediterranean. The morphologies of the first zoeae were compared with the corresponding stage of other known species in the family Inachidae. The zoeae of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aguiarii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;communissimus&lt;/i&gt; are very similar to those described in other species of the genus, especially &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thoracicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsettensis.&lt;/i&gt; The zoeae of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aguiarii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;communissimus&lt;/i&gt; differ from each other in the number of setae on the ventral margin of the carapace. The first zoea of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clouei,&lt;/i&gt; however, does not share the zoeal characters common to other Inachidae. Therefore, does not completely fit into the characteristics of the family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; Majoidea; Inachidae; zoea; morphology; &lt;i&gt;Inachus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ergasticus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pere</firstname>
          <lastname>Abello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1428.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1428</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Annotated catalogue of the Pompilidae (Hymenoptera) of Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This work represents the first catalogue of the Australian pompilid fauna since the Australian catalogue of Hymenoptera by Froggatt (1892) and the world catalogue of Pompilidae by Dalla Torre (1897). The catalogue follows the subfamily arrangement suggested by Pitts &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2006) and lists four subfamilies, 45 genera and 256 species. Three species and two genera which have exclusively extralimital distributions are included only because of their occurrence in the Australian literature. At the generic level the catalogue lists the original description of the valid generic name and any synonyms, plus literature that refers to Australian material or literature that may be of interest to Australian workers. At the specific and subspecific level the catalogue lists the original description plus any subsequent literature dealing with that taxon. Two new combinations are recorded, though both require further confirmation. One species remains unplaced to subfamily.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Catalogue; Pompilidae; Australia; Hymenoptera; spider wasps</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Catalogue</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Elliott</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-83</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1427.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1427</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic analysis of the genera of endemic Hawaiian sap beetles (Coleoptera: Nitidulidae) based on morphology with redescription and key to the genera of endemic Hawaiian Nitidulidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The endemic Hawaiian sap beetles were originally placed in 13 genera in 1908; &lt;i&gt;Apetasimus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Apetinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtostolus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eunitidula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eupetinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gonioryctus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Goniothorax,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nesapterus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nesopeplus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nesopetinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Notopeplus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Orthostolus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Apetasimus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtostolus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eunitidula,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Notopeplus&lt;/i&gt; were described for single species, with additional species later described for &lt;i&gt;Apetasimus&lt;/i&gt; and three undescribed species known for &lt;i&gt;Eunitidula&lt;/i&gt; from Oahu, Molokai, and West Maui. &lt;i&gt;Nesopeplus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nesopetinus&lt;/i&gt; have been previously shown to be junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Prosopeus.&lt;/i&gt; The monophyly of the genera is tested using morphological characters, primarily of the male copulatory sac, in a parsimony framework. The results provide the rationale for reducing the number of endemic genera to six; &lt;i&gt;Apetasimus&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Cyrtostolus&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Orthostolus&lt;/i&gt; in part), &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Notopeplus),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eupetinus&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Apetinus),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gonioryctus&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Eunitidula&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Goniothorax&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Nesapterus),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Orthostolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.s.,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Prosopeus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Brachypeplus&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis,&lt;/i&gt; a species endemic to Guam, was placed in the formerly Hawaiian endemic &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus&lt;/i&gt; in 1962. Examination of the types of all species of &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus&lt;/i&gt; shows no direct connection between &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; and the Hawaiian taxa comprising the remainder of &lt;i&gt;Cillaeopeplus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Brachypeplus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; is placed &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis&lt;/i&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Brachypeplus&lt;/i&gt; herein. The position of the endemic Hawaiian sap beetles within the nit-idulid subfamily Cillaeinae is surveyed using exemplar species from 22 of 27 genera placed in Cillaeinae. Undescribed species from eastern Polynesia allied with &lt;i&gt;Brachypeplus&lt;/i&gt; subgenus &lt;i&gt;Selis&lt;/i&gt; are proposed as the closest relatives of the Hawaiian endemic sap beetles based on internal and external morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hawaii; phylogeny; brachyptery; brachypterous; wing reduction</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hawaii</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Curtis</firstname>
          <lastname>Ewing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species and additional records of &lt;i&gt;Lesteva &lt;/i&gt;Latreille, 1797 from the mountains of South Siberia (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Omaliinae: Anthophagini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Lesteva&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1797 are described from South Siberia: &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dabanensis&lt;/i&gt; Shavrin, Shilenkov &amp; Anistschenko, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Khamar-Daban and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barguzinica&lt;/i&gt; Shavrin, Shilenkov &amp; Anistschenko, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from the Barguzin mountain ranges. Habitus, mouthparts and genitalia are illustrated. New collecting records are provided for &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brathinoides&lt;/i&gt; Zerche, 2000 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sajanensis&lt;/i&gt; Zerche, 2000. A key to &lt;i&gt;Lesteva&lt;/i&gt; species known from South Siberia is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Omaliinae; Palaearctic; South Siberia; taxonomy; distribution; &lt;i&gt;Lesteva&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new records; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexey</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shavrin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Viktor</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shilenkov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Anistschenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-47</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two Pseudoliodine genera &lt;i&gt;Dermatohomoeus &lt;/i&gt;Hlisnikovsky and &lt;i&gt;Pseudcolenis&lt;/i&gt; Reitter (Coleoptera: Leiodidae: Leiodinae) in Korea, with a description of &lt;i&gt;Pseudcolenis hoshinai &lt;/i&gt;new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic study of two Korean pseudoliodine genera, &lt;i&gt;Dermatohomoeus&lt;/i&gt; Hlisnikovský and &lt;i&gt;Pseudcolenis&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, is presented. Two genera and three species are recognized. One new species (Pseudcolenis &lt;i&gt;hoshinai&lt;/i&gt; Park &amp; Ahn) is described. &lt;i&gt;Dermatohomoeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrenus&lt;/i&gt; (Hisamatsu) is reported for the first time in the Korean peninsula. &lt;i&gt;Pseudcolenis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hilleri&lt;/i&gt; Reitter is new to South Korea. A key for the genera and species, description of the new species, and illustrations of diagnostic characters are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera; Leiodidae; Leiodinae; Pseudoliodini; &lt;i&gt;Dermatohomoeus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pseudcolenis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sun-Jae</firstname>
          <lastname>Park</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kee-Jeong</firstname>
          <lastname>Ahn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic analysis of the Neotropical social wasps of the genus &lt;i&gt;Angiopolybia&lt;/i&gt; Araujo, 1946 (Hymenoptera, Vespidae, Epiponini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A morphological cladistic analysis of the Neotropical swarm-founding genus &lt;i&gt;Angiopolybia&lt;/i&gt; Araujo is presented. A single cladogram resulted from the analysis, with the following ingroup topology: (A. &lt;i&gt;pallens&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zischkai)&lt;/i&gt; + (A. &lt;i&gt;paraensis&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obidensis).&lt;/i&gt; The monophyly of the genus is supported by four synapomorphies. A new identification key is presented for the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Vespidae; Epiponini; &lt;i&gt;Angiopolybia&lt;/i&gt;; Phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Vespidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Andena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Noll</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carpenter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-64</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The ant genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudaphomomyrmex &lt;/i&gt;Wheeler, 1920 a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Tapinoma &lt;/i&gt;Foerster, 1850</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Brian.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fisher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barry</firstname>
          <lastname>Bolton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1426.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1426</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The identity of the Javan Krait, &lt;i&gt;Bungarus javanicus &lt;/i&gt;Kopstein, 1932 (Squamata: Elapidae): evidence from mitochondrial and nuclear DNA sequence analyses and morphology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Javan Krait (Bungarus &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; Kopstein, 1932) was described on the basis of a single specimen that had been discovered subsequent to its delivery of lethal bites to two sleeping people in a rice field hut. Until 1936, only two additional specimens were found in the vicinity of the type locality near Cirebon on the north coast of West Java province, Indonesia. The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; has remained doubtful due to its great similarity to the common and widely distributed Malayan Krait (Bungarus &lt;i&gt;candidus),&lt;/i&gt; from which it was distinguished only by its black (vs. black-andwhite banded) colouration. We rediscovered &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; near its type locality in 1993 and obtained substantial series of black kraits in West and Central Java provinces in 1996 and 1998. We provide a detailed redescription of the type specimen and the two other specimens of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; available to Kopstein. We then use nucleotide sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene to estimate relationships among 27 black and black-and-white banded kraits from Java and Bali. In addition, we use exon-primed intron-crossing primers to analyze a sequence segment of the alpha-bungarotoxin (A31) gene from ten black and black-and-white banded kraits from these islands. Four mitochondrial haplotypes were identified which exhibited minimal sequence divergence and no correlation to colouration. In particular, both external phenotypes were found in the same genealogical lineage near Indramayu, where black kraits and black-and-white banded &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus&lt;/i&gt; occur in syntopy. Neither the nucleotide sequence of intron 2 nor partial exon 2 and 3 sequences of the alphabungarotoxin (A31) gene exhibited variation within the sample from Java and Bali. Intron 2 sequence divergence between the Javan kraits and the closely related &lt;i&gt;Bungarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicinctus&lt;/i&gt; is 1.1%. Morphological examination of specimens of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus&lt;/i&gt; from Java revealed no differences beyond colouration. The combined evidence identifies the locally strong populations of black kraits in Java as conspecific with local &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus.&lt;/i&gt; Their regional dichromatism includes two fundamentally different patterns for predator avoidance, and is interpreted as the result of increased genetic fixation of mutations in one or several instable genes (which can cause similar pattern abnormalities in various species of &lt;i&gt;Bungarus),&lt;/i&gt; in the course of the colonization of the alluvial plains of northern Java. These plains are of very recent origin and likely offered selective pressures different from those in older parts of the island, rendering both black and black-and-white banded phenotypes successful in predator avoidance.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reptilia; Squamata; Elapidae; &lt;i&gt;Bungarus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bungarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bungarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bungarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicinctus&lt;/i&gt;; alpha-bungarotoxin; Bali; biogeography; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; ecomorph; genetic differentiation; Indonesia; intron; Java; mitochondrial DNA; molecular taxonomy; morphological characters; nuclear DNA; snake; Southeast Asia; venomous</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reptilia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulrich</firstname>
          <lastname>Kuch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dietrich</firstname>
          <lastname>Mebs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Seven new species of &lt;i&gt;Grania &lt;/i&gt;(Annelida: Clitellata: Enchytraeidae) from New Caledonia, South Pacific Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In meiofauna of the intertidal and subtidal zones (to 20 m depth) of New Caledonia seven species of the marine enchytraeid genus &lt;i&gt;Grania&lt;/i&gt; were found, all of which were previously undescribed: &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novacaledonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinctura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galbina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fustata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fiscellata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; On the basis of morphology, these new species seem to have a phylogenetic affinity to congeners in Australia and possibly Antarctica, although little is known about the enchytraeid fauna of the surrounding areas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Grania&lt;/i&gt;; Enchytraeidae; New Caledonia; meiofauna; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Grania&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pierre</firstname>
          <lastname>De Wit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christer</firstname>
          <lastname>Erseus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Holorchis castex &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Digenea: Lepocreadiidae) from the painted sweet-lips &lt;i&gt;Diagramma pictum &lt;/i&gt;(Thunberg, 1792) (Perciformes: Haemulidae) from New Caledonia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Holorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the haemulid fish &lt;i&gt;Diagramma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pictum&lt;/i&gt; off New Caledonia. It is easily distinguished from all other species in the genus in that the vitellarium reaches well into the forebody. Its relationships with members of the genera &lt;i&gt;Pseudaephnidiogenes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Aephnidiogenes&lt;/i&gt; are also discussed. The monorchiid &lt;i&gt;Lasiotocus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plectorhynchi&lt;/i&gt; is reported from the same host.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Lepocreadiidae; &lt;i&gt;Holorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Haemulidae; &lt;i&gt;Diagramma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pictum&lt;/i&gt;; New Caledonia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodney</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean-Lou</firstname>
          <lastname>Justine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Solenysa &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1894 (Araneae: Linyphiidae) from Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Solenysa&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1894 from Japan are described, &lt;i&gt;i.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;e.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Solenysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reflexilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Solenysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;partibilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The differences of the genitalic structures between both new species and related species are studied.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; genitalia; morphology; variation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lihong</firstname>
          <lastname>Tu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hirotsugu</firstname>
          <lastname>Ono</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Disella &lt;/i&gt;(Eriophyidae: Nothopodinae: Nothopodini) from South China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt; from the Lao Mountains and Tongling Great Canyon, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, China are described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biaristatume&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Huodendron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biaristatum&lt;/i&gt; (Styracaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baisensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Caesalpinia&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Fabaceae). Both species described here are vagrant on the undersurface of host leaves. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt; from China is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;in&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;in&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;China&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;in&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Disella&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;in&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;China&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.-W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.-G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Corrections to species names recently placed in &lt;i&gt;Kinyongia &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Nadzikambia&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Chamaeleonidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Colin</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tilbury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Krystal</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tolley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Branch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1425.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1425</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic relationships of &lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides &lt;/i&gt;(Anyphaenidae) spiders from the southeastern coast of New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; construct silk retreats in rock crevices of the marine spray zone, a harsh and unusual habitat for spiders. This study expands the distribution records of three morphological species of &lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; found on the eastern and southern coasts of New Zealand’s South Island and uses mitochondrial DNA to examine their relationships and characterize their dispersal capabilities. Both 16S and ND1 sequences distinguish &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pletus&lt;/i&gt; found on the northeastern coast from a complex of two southern species comprised of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt; from the mainland and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picunus&lt;/i&gt; from Stewart Island. Neither 16S DNA nor ND1 protein separates these southern species. However, ND1 parsimony and likelihood analyses place 10 of 11 Stewart Island specimens in a clade of low support that nests deeply within &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus.&lt;/i&gt; A nested haplotype analysis characterizes &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picunus&lt;/i&gt; populations as having restricted gene flow/dispersal but with some long distance dispersal. Genetic distances between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pletus&lt;/i&gt; and the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus-A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picunus&lt;/i&gt; complex indicate a Pliocene origin, whereas distances between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picunus&lt;/i&gt; suggest a Pleistocene divergence.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picunus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pletus&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial DNA; nested haplotype analysis; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amaurobioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Opell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Berger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bous</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Manning</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-10</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of Australian crab spider &lt;i&gt;Diaea pulleinei &lt;/i&gt;Rainbow, 1915 (Araneae: Thomisidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species richness of described crab spiders (Family Thomisidae) in Australia is low. Altogether 123 species of the family are known from this continent. One of the most abundantly represented genera of crab spiders in Australia is &lt;i&gt;Diaea&lt;/i&gt; (31 recognized species). This paper revises knowledge of one species of this genus, &lt;i&gt;Diaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulleinei&lt;/i&gt; Rainbow, 1915, supplementing its description with the hitherto unknown female.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulleinei&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; redescription; description; male; female</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulleinei&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Szymkowiak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>11-20</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ambanus &lt;/i&gt;Ovtchinnikov, 1999 from China (Araneae: Amaurobiidae: Coelotinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ambanus&lt;/i&gt; Ovtchinnikov, 1999 (Araneae: Amaurobiidae: Coelotinae) from Mt. Changbai of Northeast China are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudonariceus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triangulatus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trisaccatus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. The study showed that all three new &lt;i&gt;Ambanus&lt;/i&gt; species have five to six trichobothria on the retrolateral cymbium, similar to some Coelotinae from the Himalayan region. &lt;i&gt;Draconarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kayasanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Paik, 1972) comb. nov. is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Ambanus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ambanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nariceus&lt;/i&gt; (Zhu &amp; Wang, 1994) comb. nov. from &lt;i&gt;Coelotes.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spiders; Northeast China; taxonomy; trichobothrium; new combination</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Da-Xiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-28</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new taxa in the Eriophyidae (Acari, Prostigmata) from the Brazilian fauna</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aceria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from leaf erineum galls of &lt;i&gt;Heteropteris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aceroides&lt;/i&gt; Griseb, and &lt;i&gt;Epitrimerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edsilvai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; a vagrant specis from leaves of &lt;i&gt;Nectandra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megapotamica&lt;/i&gt; (Spreng.) Mez. are described from female and male specimens, from the State of Sao Paulo, Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Eriophyidae; Eriophyoidea; taxonomy; Brazil; plant feeding; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>H. W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Flechtmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-33</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cotylegaleatidae, a new family of Ploima (Rotifera: Monogononta), for &lt;i&gt;Cotylegaleata perplexa &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov., from freshwater benthos of Belgium</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new monotypic rotifer family, Cotylegaleatidae, is proposed for &lt;i&gt;Cotylegaleata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perplexa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; collected from benthos of an artificial small freshwater lake in Belgium. The new family belongs to the subclass Monogononta, order Ploima. Its distinctive characters include: a hollow cup-shaped structure (sucker ?) surrounding the mouth opening, a non-retractile head shield, a distal foot pseudosegment with two toes and two ventro-lateral spurs, a J-shaped vitellarium, and characteristic specialized virgate trophi with stiletto-shaped epipharyngeal elements.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rotifera; Monogononta; Cotylegaleatidae fam. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Cotylegaleata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perplexa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Lepadellidae; Belgium</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rotifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Willem</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Smet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-43</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Gobiidae) from the Mexican coast of the Gulf of Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of gobies (Teleostei: Gobiidae) were recently discovered off the coast of Veracruz, Mexico in the southwestern Gulf of Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jarocho&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be diagnosed from other species in the genus by the disjunct yellow lateral stripe restricted to the head and caudal fin base, the yellow medial stripe on the snout, and the black ovoid to rectangular spot at the base of the caudal fin, immediately ventral to the yellow dash. This species forms shoals in the water column close to rock and coral reefs, feeding presumably on zooplankton, a trait shared by only one other species in the genus. &lt;i&gt;Elacatinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;redimiculus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be diagnosed from other species in the genus by the distinct reddish orange blotches or broken bands on the head and 13 reddish orange to dark brown stripes between the pectoral and caudal fins. Both species are currently known only from the southwestern Gulf of Mexico from reefs within the Veracruz Marine Park off the coast of Veracruz, Mexico.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gulf of Mexico; Atlantic Ocean; reef fish; new species; goby</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gulf of Mexico</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lad</firstname>
          <lastname>Akins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new side-necked turtle (Pleurodira, Pelomedusoides) from the Santana Formation (Early Cretaceous), Araripe Basin, Northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The fossil fauna of turtles from the Santana Formation, Araripe Basin, Early Cretaceous from Northeastern Brazil, includes, to exception of the &lt;i&gt;Santanachelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaffneyi&lt;/i&gt; (Cryptodira, Protostegidae), only pelurodiran taxa. A new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Caririemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;violetae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Pleurodira, Pelomedusoides), from the Romualdo Member, upper section of the Santana Formation, is described here. &lt;i&gt;Caririemys&lt;/i&gt; is based on one specimen consisting of a carapace, several vertebrae, a right femur and a right pelvis. &lt;i&gt;Caririemys&lt;/i&gt; differs of the other pleurodirans from the Santana Formation by the following combination of characters: oval and moderately domed carapace; complete neural series reaching the suprapygal; and neural plate 8 shows an extensive contact with costal 7 and 8. This new taxon enhances the turtle diversity of the Santana Formation, which is presently the most diverse deposit of Mesozoic Testudines in the country.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Santana Formation; Romualdo Member; Early Cretaceous; Testudines; Pleurodira</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Santana Formation; Romualdo Member; Early Cretaceous; Testudines; Pleurodira</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>Ribeiro</middlename>
          <lastname>De Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>Wilhelm Armin</middlename>
          <lastname>Kellner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-61</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from western Papua New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">I describe a new gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratus,&lt;/i&gt; from the Star Mts. of the western extreme of Papua New Guinea. The new species differs from all Papuan congeners in having a row of enlarged, dentate tubercles extending the length of each lateral skin fold. Further differences with the other species of Papuan &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; are identified and serve to highlight the uniqueness of the new species. I speculate that relationships of the new species may lie closest to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loriae&lt;/i&gt; Boulenger among named forms, but numerous additional species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; remain to be described from New Guinea and this suggestion can only be considered tentative.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">lizard; gecko; Star Mountains; Tabubil; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">lizard</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fred</firstname>
          <lastname>Kraus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1424.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1424</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the tropical/temperate amphipod genus &lt;i&gt;Dulichiella &lt;/i&gt;Stout, 1912, and the description of a new Atlantic genus &lt;i&gt;Verdeia &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Melitidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The melitid amphipod genus &lt;i&gt;Dulichiella&lt;/i&gt; Stout, 1912, is revised. Based on examination of type material or new material from near type localities, we redescribe &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anisochir&lt;/i&gt; (Krøyer, 1845) from Brazil, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;appendiculata&lt;/i&gt; (Say, 1818) from the south-eastern United States, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; (Haswell, 1879) from eastern Australia, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cotesi&lt;/i&gt; (Giles, 1890) from the Andaman Islands, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuvettensis&lt;/i&gt; Appadoo &amp; Myers, 2005 from Mauritius, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fresnelii&lt;/i&gt; (Audouin, 1826) from the Red Sea, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; Lowry &amp; Springthorpe, 2005 from Australasia and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; Stout, 1912 from California. Based on published illustrations and new material we describe six new species: &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guinea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from western Africa; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lecroyae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the south-eastern United States; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oahu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Hawaii; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from south-eastern Mexico; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomioka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Japan and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tulear&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Madagascar. The new genus &lt;i&gt;Verdeia&lt;/i&gt; is described for two established species, &lt;i&gt;Melita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandimana&lt;/i&gt; Chevreux, 1908 from the Cape Verde Islands and &lt;i&gt;Melita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subchelata&lt;/i&gt; Schellenberg, 1925 from Namibia. We provide a key to the world species of these genera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Melitidae; &lt;i&gt;Dulichiella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Verdeia&lt;/i&gt;; new genera; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Springthorpe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1423.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1423</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">DNA Barcoding: Mixed results for big-headed flies (Diptera: Pipunculidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sequence data from 658 base pairs of mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase I (cox1) were analysed for 28 described species of Pipunculidae (Diptera) in an effort to test the concept of DNA Barcoding on this family. Two recently revised but distantly related pipunculid lineages with presumed different evolutionary histories were used for the test (Clistoabdom- &lt;i&gt;inalis&lt;/i&gt; Skevington, 2001 and &lt;i&gt;Nephrocerus&lt;/i&gt; Zetterstedt, 1838). An effort was made to test the concept using sister taxa and morphologically similar sibling species swarms in these two genera. Morphological species concepts for &lt;i&gt;Clistoabdominalis&lt;/i&gt; taxa were either supported by &lt;i&gt;cox1&lt;/i&gt; data or found to be too broad. Most of the discordance could be accounted for after reassessing morphological characters. In these cases, the molecular data were invaluable in assisting taxonomic decision-making. The radiation of Nearctic species of &lt;i&gt;Nephrocerus&lt;/i&gt; could not be diagnosed using &lt;i&gt;cox1.&lt;/i&gt; The ability of &lt;i&gt;cox1&lt;/i&gt; to recover phylogenetic signal was also tested on &lt;i&gt;Clistoabdominalis.&lt;/i&gt; Morphological data for &lt;i&gt;Clistoabdominalis&lt;/i&gt; were combined with the molecular data set. The pipunculid phylogeny from molecular data closely resembles the published phylogeny based on morphology. Partitioned Bremer support is used to localize areas of conflict between the datasets.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pipunculidae; Diptera; DNA Barcoding; phylogeny; mitochondrial rDNA; &lt;i&gt;cox1&lt;/i&gt; gene; COI; molecular systematics; morphology; total evidence</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pipunculidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Skevington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <middlename>Kehlmaier And Gunilla</middlename>
          <lastname>Stahls</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Criotettix &lt;/i&gt;Bolivar (Orthoptera: Scelimenidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A total of nineteen species of &lt;i&gt;Criotettix&lt;/i&gt; Bolivar occurring in China were systematically researched in this paper. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Criotettix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longinota&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Criotettix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripennis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. are described as new to science. Synonymy, distribution and a key to species are presented. The type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi’an, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Scelimenidae; &lt;i&gt;Criotettix&lt;/i&gt;; review; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shizhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Wei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhemin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weian</firstname>
          <lastname>Deng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-49</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Isoneuromyia &lt;/i&gt;from China (Diptera: Keroplatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Isoneuromyia&lt;/i&gt; Brunetti are described from China: &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinica&lt;/i&gt; Xu, Cao et Evenhuis, n. sp; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;completa&lt;/i&gt; Xu, Cao et Evenhuis, n. sp; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singulus&lt;/i&gt; Xu, Cao et Evenhuis, n. sp; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wolongensis&lt;/i&gt; Xu, Cao et Evenhuis, n. sp. Another species, &lt;i&gt;I.semirufa&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen) is newly recorded from Zhejiang province in China. A key to Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Isoneuromyia&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Keroplatidae; &lt;i&gt;Isoneuromyia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Keroplatidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Huachao</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Cao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Neal</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Evenhuis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zuji</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic status of the bees from French Guiana described by Jules Dominique (Hymenoptera: Apidae, Megachilidae, Halictidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laus</firstname>
          <lastname>Rasmussen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gilles</firstname>
          <lastname>Mahe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ismael</firstname>
          <middlename>Alejandro</middlename>
          <lastname>Hinojosa-Diaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Arpedium &lt;/i&gt;from Kyrgyzstan (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae, Omaliinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Assing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-66</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Almunisna &lt;/i&gt;Dworakowska (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae: Typhlocybini): a genus newly recorded from China with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;males&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Almunisna&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;males&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Almunisna&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1422.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1422</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematic review of the neotropical shovelnose catfish genus &lt;i&gt;Sorubim &lt;/i&gt;Cuvier (Siluriformes: Pimelodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Sorubim&lt;/i&gt; Cuvier, 1829, and two species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lima&lt;/i&gt; (Bloch &amp; Schneider 1801) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trigonocephalus&lt;/i&gt; MirandaRibeiro, 1920, are redescribed based on the examination of type material and about 400 non-type specimens from ichthyological collections in Europe and North and South America. The five species of the genus are, in addition to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lima&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trigonocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; Littmann, Burr, Schmidt and Isern 2001, found in the Essequibo, Orinoco, and Amazon basins; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuspicaudus&lt;/i&gt; Littmann, Burr and Nass 2000, occurring in the Sinu, Cauca, and Magdalena rivers of Colombia and the Lago Maracaibo basin of Colombia and Venezuela; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maniradii&lt;/i&gt; Littmann, Burr and Buitrago-Suarez 2001, known from the upper and middle Amazon basin. &lt;i&gt;Sorubim&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lima&lt;/i&gt; is the widest-ranging species, occurring in most of the major drainage basins of South America. &lt;i&gt;Sorubim&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trigonocephalus&lt;/i&gt; is extremely rare in natural history collections and is currently known from only two major tributaries of the Amazon basin. Three species (S. &lt;i&gt;maniradii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lima)&lt;/i&gt; occur syntopically. Species of &lt;i&gt;Sorubim&lt;/i&gt; are diagnosed on the basis of body and head shape, differences in fin ray and gill-raker numbers, mental barbel position, and degree of pigmentation of the lateral stripe. At least two of the species (S. &lt;i&gt;lima&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus)&lt;/i&gt; make up part of the ornamental fish trade and are sold for food in local fish markets in South America. A key to adults of the five species is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pimelodidae; South America; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pimelodidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Littmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of snapper (Perciformes: Lutjanidae) from Brazil, with comments on the distribution of &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus griseus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;L. apodus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Snappers of the family Lutjanidae contain several of the most important reef-fishery species in the tropical western Atlantic. Despite their importance, substantial gaps exist for both systematic and ecological information, especially for the southwestern Atlantic. Recent collecting efforts along the coast of Brazil have resulted in the discovery of many new reef-fish species, including commercially important parrotfishes (Scaridae) and grunts (Haemulidae). Based on field collecting, museum specimens, and literature records, we describe a new species of snapper, &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alexandrei,&lt;/i&gt; which is apparently endemic to the Brazilian coast. The newly settled and early juvenile life stages are also described. This species is common in many Brazilian reef and coastal estuarine systems where it has been often misidentified as the gray snapper, &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus,&lt;/i&gt; or the schoolmaster, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apodus.&lt;/i&gt; Identification of the new species cast doubt on prior distributional assumptions about the southern ranges of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apodus,&lt;/i&gt; and subsequent field and museum work confirmed that those species are not reliably recorded in Brazil. The taxonomic status of two Brazilian species previously referred to &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bodianus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aya&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Genyoroge&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canina,&lt;/i&gt; is reviewed to determine the number of valid &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; species occurring in Brazil. Twelve species of &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; are now recognized in the western Atlantic, eight of which occur in Brazil (one endemic). A key for the identification of all western Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; species and their known distributional ranges is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alexandrei&lt;/i&gt; new species; snappers; biogeography; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lutjanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alexandrei&lt;/i&gt; new species; snappers; biogeography; Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kenyon</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lindeman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-43</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of taipan (Elapidae: &lt;i&gt;Oxyuranus&lt;/i&gt;) from central Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Snakes in the Australo-Papuan elapid genus &lt;i&gt;Oxyuranus&lt;/i&gt; are considered to be the most venomous species in the world. A recent expedition to the central ranges of Western Australia discovered a third species, which is described here from the only known specimen. Molecular genetic analyses using mitochondrial nucleotide sequences places the new species as the sister lineage of the two described &lt;i&gt;Oxyuranus&lt;/i&gt; species, with all three species united by a long branch that also separates them from the nearest of the brown snakes species (Pseudonaja) to which the taipans are close relatives. Morphologically, the new species shares with the other &lt;i&gt;Oxyuranus&lt;/i&gt; an undivided anal scale, high midbody scale row (21) and ventral scale (250) counts, but differs in having a single primary temporal scale and fewer lower labials (six). Maximum body size and venom potency are unknown. The discovery of a third species of taipan in the remote central ranges of Australia underlines the paucity of collecting from this region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Elapidae; mitochondrial DNA; species boundary; snake; taipan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Elapidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Doughty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brad</firstname>
          <lastname>Maryan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnellan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hutchinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The auditory region of &lt;i&gt;Brachycephalus &lt;/i&gt;and its bearing on the monophyly of the genus (Anura: Brachycephalidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We surveyed the morphology of the auditory region of members of the anuran genus &lt;i&gt;Brachycephalus.&lt;/i&gt; The sample included seven of the eleven known species; in addition, &lt;i&gt;Brachycephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ephippium&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vertebralis&lt;/i&gt; were each represented by several specimens from different localities. All species lack a tympanum, tympanic annulus, stapes, and Eustachian tube. However, the operculum and the &lt;i&gt;m.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opercularis&lt;/i&gt; remain. The large operculum bears a robust process for the &lt;i&gt;m.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opercularis&lt;/i&gt; and covers most of the fenestra ovalis. The auditory apparatus of &lt;i&gt;Brachycephalus&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished by the large size and the orientation of the fenestra ovalis, which faces posterior, rather than lateral. The morphology of these structures is compared to those of other minute brachycephalid frogs considered to be close relatives of &lt;i&gt;Brachycephalus,&lt;/i&gt; and the importance of these characters as evidence of the monophyly of the genus is discussed. We also discuss the importance of other morphological features cited to support close relationships among small-sized brachycephalids, and consider the role of miniaturization in generating convergent pattern of loss of morphological features.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">digit reduction; middle ear; miniaturization; ostia pharyngea; &lt;i&gt;tympanic&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulus&lt;/i&gt;; stapes; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">digit reduction</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sebben</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1421.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1421</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the knowledge of the "Staphylinus-complex" (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylinini) of China. Part XX. The genus &lt;i&gt;Ocypus &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1819, subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus &lt;/i&gt;Mulsant &amp; Rey, 1876. Section 1</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The paper deals with the species of the &lt;i&gt;semenowi-lineage&lt;/i&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt; Mulsant &amp; Rey, 1876 of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1819, known to occur at present on the territory of the People’s Republic of China. Thirty three species are treated, of which twenty nine are described as new: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ballio,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bion,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calamis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elpenor,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glabrio,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hecato,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laelaps,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orodes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pammenes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pelias,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quiris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarpedon,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scaevola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;teuthras,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vindex,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xerxes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zetes,&lt;/i&gt; (all from Sichuan), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palamedes&lt;/i&gt; (from Sichuan: Jiuding Shan), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abaris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sadales&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgias&lt;/i&gt; (all from Gansu), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hyas&lt;/i&gt; (from Yunnan), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dryas&lt;/i&gt; (from Xinjiang), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zeuxis&lt;/i&gt; (from Hubei: Da Shennongjia range), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neocles&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinton&lt;/i&gt; (both from Shaanxi: Qinling Shan), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;menander&lt;/i&gt; (both from Shaanxi: Daba Shan). The lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semenowi&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1887. &lt;i&gt;Protocypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puer&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2005 is transferred to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt; (new combination). Each species is described, illustrated and all available distributional and bionomic data are given. A key to the Chinese species of the &lt;i&gt;semenowi-lineage&lt;/i&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Staphylininae; &lt;i&gt;Ocypus&lt;/i&gt;; subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pseudocypus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic; mainland China; taxonomy; new species; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Smetana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-72</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1420.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1420</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Echinolittorina &lt;/i&gt;Habe, 1956 (Gastropoda: Littorinidae) in the Indo-West Pacific Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogeny of the genus &lt;i&gt;Echinolittorina,&lt;/i&gt; and phylogeography of some of its members, have previously been examined using molecular data, so that species can now be defined by a combination of phylogenetic, morphological and geographical criteria. The 26 species recognized in the Indo-West Pacific biogeographical region form a monophyletic group, here defined as the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Granulilittorina&lt;/i&gt; Habe &amp; Kosuge, 1966. Morphological descriptions are provided for these 26 species, including details of shell, pigmentation of headfoot, reproductive anatomy, spermatozoa, egg capsules and radulae. Diagnoses include reference to mitochondrial gene sequences (COI). A key is based on shells, tentacle pigmentation, penial shape and geographical distribution. Seven new species are described: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marisrubri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;omanensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;austrotrochoides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marquesensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wallaceana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tricincta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;philippinensis.&lt;/i&gt; Three name changes are proposed: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malaccana&lt;/i&gt; (Philippi, 1847) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cecillei&lt;/i&gt; (Philippi, 1851) are valid names for two members of the former ‘E. &lt;i&gt;trochoides’&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biangulata&lt;/i&gt; (von Martens, 1897) replaces ‘E. &lt;i&gt;quadricincta’.&lt;/i&gt; Full synonymies are given for all taxa, and the taxonomic, evolutionary and ecological literature reviewed. Distribution maps are based on examination of 1701 samples and reliable literature records. The contrast between continental and oceanic distribution patterns is emphasized; one clade of five species and two additional species are shown to have an association with upwelling areas. All species are known (or predicted from protoconch size and oviduct anatomy) to have planktotrophic development, and rare extralimital records suggest a maximum open-water dispersal distance of 1000–2100 km. The most useful morphological characters for identification are the shell, penial shape and copulatory bursa in the pallial oviduct. Sister species can be morphologically similar, but are almost always entirely allopatric, so that distributional information is important for identification. Substantial intraspecific variation is present in the shell shape and sculpture of most species; where there is a pronounced geographical pattern this may have a genetic basis, but ecophenotypic effects are also implicated, e.g. by predictable associations in some species of strongly nodulose sculpture with limestone substrates and with dry habitats where growth rate may be slow. Morphological characters are superimposed on a molecular phylogeny to demonstrate the synapomorphies of clades. This is essentially a morphostatic radiation of largely allopatric species with little morphological differentiation; ecological divergence is limited to specialization to oceanic, continental or upwelling areas and to small differences in zonation level.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">shell sculpture; penis; radula; oceanic distribution; upwelling; morphostatic radiation; littoral fringe</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">shell sculpture</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Reid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-161</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1419.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1419</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leptogorgia &lt;/i&gt;Milne Edwards &amp; Haime, 1857 (Coelenterata: Octocorallia: Gorgoniidae)in the eastern Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of the widespread gorgoniid genus &lt;i&gt;Leptogorgia,&lt;/i&gt; which occur along the eastern Pacific, are taxonomically revised based on original type material of all species described until now and reference specimens from recent surveys and expeditions along the Pacific coast of Panama, and Costa Rica. As a result, 21 species are recognized as valid and one as dubious. Lectotypes are assigned for eight species in order to establish their taxonomic status. All the species aredescribed and illustrated. The fauna herein reported does not represent overall diversity or geographical range of each species but adds new reports. The present count is 16 species for Panama, 11 for Costa Rica, 7 for Mexico, 6 for El Salvador, 4 for Peru, 4 for Ecuador, 3 for Colombia, 2 for California, 2 for Nicaragua, and 2 for Chile.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Coelenterata; Costa Rica; eastern Pacific; gorgonian; octocoral; &lt;i&gt;Leptogorgia&lt;/i&gt;; sea fans; Panama; soft corals; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Odalisca</firstname>
          <lastname>Breedy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hector</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guzman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-90</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1418.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1418</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of catfishes, recent and fossil (Osteichthyes: Siluriformes), and catalogue of siluriform primary types</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A checklist of Recent and fossil catfishes (Order Siluriformes) is presented, summarizing taxonomic literature published through 2005. From 4624 nominal species group names and 810 genus group names, 3093 species are recognized as valid, and are distributed among 478 genera and 36 families. Distributional summaries are provided for each species, and nomenclatural synonymies, including relevant information on all name-bearing types, are included for all taxa. One new name is proposed herein: &lt;i&gt;Clariallabes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;teugelsi,&lt;/i&gt; as a replacement for &lt;i&gt;Clarias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Allabenchelys)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumerili&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibarbis&lt;/i&gt; David &amp; Poll, 1937, which is preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;Clarias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibarbis&lt;/i&gt; Worthington, 1933, but has been treated as a valid species of &lt;i&gt;Clariallabes&lt;/i&gt; by Teugels. &lt;i&gt;Acrochordonichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanogaster&lt;/i&gt; Bleeker, 1854, is designated as type species of &lt;i&gt;Acrochordonichthys&lt;/i&gt; Bleeker, 1857, inasmuch as no earlier valid designation has been found. A new genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagarius,&lt;/i&gt; is proposed for the “pseudobagarius group” of species formerly placed in &lt;i&gt;Akysis.&lt;/i&gt; The status of 228 species group names remains unresolved and 31 names based on otoliths ascribed to catfishes are listed but not placed into the checklist. The current emphasis given to catfish taxonomy at present is likely to result in a dramatic increase in the total number of valid taxa as well as major changes in the membership of some of the higher level taxa recognized here.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematognathi; taxonomy; nomenclature; biodiversity; freshwater fishes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematognathi</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carl</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferraris</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-628</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1417.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1417</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis &lt;/i&gt;Whiteaves, 1784 from the Indian and Pacific Oceans and reestablishment of the genus &lt;i&gt;Galacantha &lt;/i&gt;A. Milne-Edwards, 1880 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Galatheidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sixty-six species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; have been studied using specimens collected during numerous French expeditions carried out in the last decades in the deep-waters of the southwest Indian and southwest Pacific Oceans, between 140 and 4400 m. Twenty-five new species are described, and the diagnoses and illustrations of some relatively rare species (M. &lt;i&gt;africana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;debilis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lenzii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moresbyi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orcina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinclairi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stylirostris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wardeni)&lt;/i&gt; are provided. The reestablishment of the genus &lt;i&gt;Galacantha&lt;/i&gt; is proposed, including the descriptions/diagnoses and a key to all species. The genus contains nine species, including three new species (G. &lt;i&gt;bellis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diomedeae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quiquei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostrata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subrostrata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subspinosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachynotus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valdiviae).&lt;/i&gt; The number of species collected by station is very small (usually one species), probably related to their low densities. However, in some samples, as many as five species have been found. The highest number of species have been observed in the Banda Sea (Indonesia) and Solomon Islands. The new records of some species greatly extend the previously known distribution range of the species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Anomura; Galatheidae; &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Galacantha&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Enrique</firstname>
          <lastname>Macpherson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-135</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1416.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1416</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics of the family Ariidae (Ostariophysi, Siluriformes), with a redefinition of the genera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic &lt;i&gt;status&lt;/i&gt; of all the nominal genera of the Ariidae are reviewed and ariid genera are diagnosed by exclusive characters as well as by a combination of internal and external morphological features. The results are based on a phylogenetic analysis undertaken by the senior author (Marceniuk, 2003). The species so far recognized are taxonomically reevaluated and considered as valid, &lt;i&gt;inquirendae&lt;/i&gt; or synonyms under each diagnosed genus based on direct examination of specimens or use of diagnostic characters available in the literature. A key to identification of genera is provided based on morphological characters that can be easily recognized. In the new classification proposed, Ariidae comprises the following twenty six valid genera: &lt;i&gt;Amissidens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Arius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Aspistor,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bagre,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Batrachocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Brustiarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cathorops,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cephalocassis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cinetodus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cochlefelis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cryptarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Doiichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Galeichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Genidens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hemiarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ketengus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nedystoma,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nemapteryx,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neoarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Netuma,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Notarius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Osteogeneiosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachyula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Plicofollis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Potamarius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sciades.&lt;/i&gt; Three new genera are erected. The nominal genera &lt;i&gt;Bagre&lt;/i&gt; Oken, 1817, &lt;i&gt;Glanis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stearopterus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Breviceps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;non&lt;/i&gt; Merrem, 1820, &lt;i&gt;Felichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ailurichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mystus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;non&lt;/i&gt; Scopoli, 1777 and &lt;i&gt;Anemanotus&lt;/i&gt; are considered junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Bagre&lt;/i&gt; Cloquet, 1816. &lt;i&gt;Hexanematichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sciadeichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Selenaspis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ariopsis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Leptarius&lt;/i&gt; are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Sciades.&lt;/i&gt; The nominal genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudarius&lt;/i&gt; is an objective synonym, and &lt;i&gt;Ariodes&lt;/i&gt; a subjective synonym, of &lt;i&gt;Arius.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sciadeops&lt;/i&gt; is synonymous with &lt;i&gt;Notarius.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Catastoma&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sarcogenys&lt;/i&gt; are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Netuma.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tetranesodon&lt;/i&gt; is preliminary considered junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pachyula.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hemipimelodus&lt;/i&gt; is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cephalocassis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Septobranchus&lt;/i&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cinetodus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guiritinga&lt;/i&gt; is a new synonym of &lt;i&gt;Genidens.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ariidae; Systematics; Revision of Genera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ariidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marceniuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menezes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-126</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1415.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1415</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic notes on genera allied to&lt;i&gt; Pleurotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae, Entedoninae) with description of a new genus from the Afrotropical region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Afrotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;risbeci&lt;/i&gt; Gumovsky &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&amp;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae, Entedoninae), a parasitoid of leafminers on &lt;i&gt;Khaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senegalensis&lt;/i&gt; in Senegal and &lt;i&gt;Ochna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchra&lt;/i&gt; in South Africa, is described. The new genus belongs to the complex of genera allied to &lt;i&gt;Pleurotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt; Girault, 1913, which includes also the genera &lt;i&gt;Apleurotropis&lt;/i&gt; Girault, 1913, &lt;i&gt;Kratoysma&lt;/i&gt; Bouček, 1965, &lt;i&gt;Zaommomentedon&lt;/i&gt; Girault, 1915, &lt;i&gt;Platocharis&lt;/i&gt; Kerrich, 1969, &lt;i&gt;Schizocharis&lt;/i&gt; Kerrich, 1969, and &lt;i&gt;Parahorismenus&lt;/i&gt; Girault, 1915. The following nomenclature changes are proposed: the generic name &lt;i&gt;Atullya&lt;/i&gt; Surekha &amp; Narendran, 1988 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Pleurotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt; (syn. &lt;b&gt;nov.);&lt;/b&gt; two species are moved from &lt;i&gt;Schizocharis&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Zaommomentedon:&lt;/i&gt; Z. &lt;i&gt;milletiae&lt;/i&gt; (Kerrich, 1969) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;newbyi&lt;/i&gt; (Kerrich, 1969) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Relationships within and outside the complex, generic concepts and taxonomic values of some characters are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chalcidoidea; Eulophidae; &lt;i&gt;Afrotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pleurotroppopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Apleurotropis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Kratoysma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zaommomentedon&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Platocharis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Schizocharis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Parahorismenus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Atullya&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Khaya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senegalensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ochna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchra.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chalcidoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alex</firstname>
          <lastname>Gumovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of apterous Doryctinae (Hymenoptera: Braconidae) from Costa Rica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oroceguera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andersoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; an apterous braconid in the subfamily Doryctinae is described from Costa Rica. Portions of the diagnostic keys from Marsh (1997; 2002) are combined and updated to include this new genus. Diagnostic features are presented to distinguish it from other Doryctinae; its unusual morphology is discussed and conjecture is made on life history.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hymenoptera; Braconidae; New World; ocelli; wingless; &lt;i&gt;Oroceguera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andersoni&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hymenoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Katja</firstname>
          <lastname>Seltmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Sharkey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-21</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Toumeyella lomagundiae &lt;/i&gt;Hall and &lt;i&gt;T. obunca &lt;/i&gt;De Lotto, and their transfer to &lt;i&gt;Hallicoccus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Coccidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two African soft scale insects, &lt;i&gt;Toumeyella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lomagundiae&lt;/i&gt; Hall and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obunca&lt;/i&gt; De Lotto, are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Hallicoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The adult females of both species are redescribed, and the first-instar nymph of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lomagundiae&lt;/i&gt; is described. A revised taxonomic key to separate the adult females is provided. The affinity of &lt;i&gt;Hallicoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; with the genus &lt;i&gt;Toumeyella&lt;/i&gt; Cockerell is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Africa; Coccidae; keys; new genus scale insect; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Takumasa</firstname>
          <lastname>Kondo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-33</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new genera in the Nymphidiina (Lepidoptera: Riodinidae: Nymphidiini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new riodinid genera in the subtribe Nymphidiina (tribe Nymphidiini) are described from the lowlands of the Amazon basin. &lt;i&gt;Livendula&lt;/i&gt; Hall, n. gen., is described with &lt;i&gt;huebneri&lt;/i&gt; Butler as its type species, and the following eleven species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Livendula&lt;/i&gt; (n. combs.) from &lt;i&gt;Adelotypa&lt;/i&gt; Warren: &lt;i&gt;amasis&lt;/i&gt; Hewitson, &lt;i&gt;aminias&lt;/i&gt; Hewitson, &lt;i&gt;aristus&lt;/i&gt; Stoll, &lt;i&gt;balista&lt;/i&gt; Hewitson, &lt;i&gt;epixanthe&lt;/i&gt; Stichel, &lt;i&gt;huebneri&lt;/i&gt; Butler, &lt;i&gt;jasonhalli&lt;/i&gt; Brévignon &amp; Gallard, &lt;i&gt;leucocyana&lt;/i&gt; Geyer, &lt;i&gt;leucophaea&lt;/i&gt; Hübner, &lt;i&gt;pauxilla&lt;/i&gt; Stichel, and &lt;i&gt;violacea&lt;/i&gt; Butler. &lt;i&gt;Minotauros&lt;/i&gt; Hall, n. gen., is described with &lt;i&gt;lampros&lt;/i&gt; Bates as its type species, and the following two species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Minotauros&lt;/i&gt; (n. combs.) from &lt;i&gt;Adelotypa:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lampros&lt;/i&gt; Bates, and &lt;i&gt;charessa&lt;/i&gt; Stichel.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Adelotypa&lt;/i&gt;; Amazon; morphology; Nymphidiini; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Adelotypa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>P. W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-42</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of two new species of click-beetle (Coleoptera: Elateridae) from Turkey </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this study, two new species of click-beetles, &lt;i&gt;Ampedus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Athous&lt;/i&gt; (Orthathous) &lt;i&gt;demirsoyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from Turkey. The morphologies of these new species and their genital organs are described, photographs of each species and character details are provided, and distribution maps are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Elateridae; &lt;i&gt;Ampedus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Athous&lt;/i&gt;; Turkey; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
          <lastname>Platia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mahmut</firstname>
          <lastname>Kabalak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Osman</firstname>
          <lastname>Sert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-47</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new fossil mordellid (Coleoptera: Tenebrionoidea: Mordellidae) from the Yixian Formation of Western Liaoning Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Mirimordella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilicruralis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; in the subfamily Praemordellinae of Mordellidae, is described and illustrated based on a nearly complete fossil specimen. It is from the Yixian Formation of western Liaoning Province, NE China. The diagnosis of the subfamily Praemordellinae is emended based on this new species. Characters such as simple and linear maxillary palpi, simple claws, simple penultimate segments of fore and middle tarsi, small hind coxal plates, slender hind femora, only apical ridges on hind tibiae and tarsi, and no elongated last tergum suggest that Praemordellinae might be the precursor of modern mordellids. The resemblance between the new species and the Late Jurassic &lt;i&gt;Praemordella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martynovi&lt;/i&gt; indicates close relationships between them and with the tribe Stenaliini in the subfamily Mordellinae. The position of epicoxa and slender hind femur suggest that the new species may be more primitive than &lt;i&gt;Praemordella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martynovi&lt;/i&gt; and may indicate the age of the Yixian Formation no later than Late Jurassic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fossil; Mordellidae; new taxon; Late Jurassic; Yixian Formation; Liaoning</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fossil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wenhua</firstname>
          <lastname>Lu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dong</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new &lt;i&gt;Tachygonidius &lt;/i&gt;species from the Atlantic coast of Brazil (Coleoptera: Curculionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of &lt;i&gt;Tachygonidius&lt;/i&gt; are described from the Atlantic coast of Brazil: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluminensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Restinga da Marambaia, Rio de Janeiro) and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Boa Esperança do Sul, São Paulo). The former species develops as a leaf miner in a species of Ochnaceae. Sexual dimorphism related to the form of the declivous portion of pygidium, deeper in male and less deep in female, is reported for the first time in &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluminensis.&lt;/i&gt; A key for the four known species of &lt;i&gt;Tachygonidius&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; leaf miner; &lt;i&gt;Tachygonidius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluminensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tachygonidius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; weevil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vanin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>R. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mermudes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-64</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lathrobium &lt;/i&gt;from Kyrgyzstan (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae: Paederinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Assing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1414.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1414</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Additions to the aspidochirotid, molpadid and apodid holothuroids (Echinodermata: Holothuroidea) from the east coast of southern Africa, with descriptions of new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Collections of holothuroid echinoderms received from the Natal and South African Museums, the Universities of Cape Town and Witwatersrand and that present in the former University of Durban-Westville, contain several new species and many others that are new to the fauna of southern Africa, south of the tropic of Capricorn. A paper describing and/or recording several dendrochirotids and a dactylochirotid, from a portion of these materials originating from the east coast of southern Africa, has already been published. The current paper describes and/or reports on several new species and records of aspidochirotid, molpadid and apodid holothuroids, also from the east coast, extending from Inhaca Island, off the coast of Maputo (Mozambique), to the Port St. Johns-East London area (South Africa), the subtropical zoogeographic province. A few other species have been included if they represent juvenile material, or considered extensions of ranges (bathymetric or otherwise) of previously known species, or confirmation of a species previously recorded from a single locality in the region under consideration, or for the provision of taxonomic data that was excluded for some previous published records. Of the 30 species treated, four are new to science and seven are new records for the southern African region. The new species are &lt;i&gt;Holothuria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Lessonothuria)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Theelothuria)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duoturriforma,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.(T.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicosta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(T.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudonotablis,&lt;/i&gt; whereas the new records include &lt;i&gt;Stichopus&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;monotuberculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Quoy &amp; Gaimard), &lt;i&gt;Actinopyga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bannwarthi&lt;/i&gt; Panning, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lecanora&lt;/i&gt; (Jaeger), &lt;i&gt;Bohadschia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmorata&lt;/i&gt; (Jaeger), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Vaneyothuria)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;integra&lt;/i&gt; Koehler &amp; Vaney, &lt;i&gt;Molpadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triforia&lt;/i&gt; (Cherbonnier) and &lt;i&gt;Protankyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;autopista&lt;/i&gt; (Marenzeller).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Holothuroidea; Aspidochirotida; Molpadida; Apodida; South Africa; new species; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Holothuroidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ahmed</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Thandar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1413.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Mar. 2007</title>
    <volume>1413</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biodiversity, biogeography, and bibliography of the cicadas of Thailand (Hemiptera: Cicadoidea: Cicadidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A total of 148 species in 35 genera of cicadas is reported for Thailand. Of these, 11 species and one genus (Muda) are reported for the first time from the country. Fifteen undescribed species were discovered (to be described at a later date), in our collections and among museum holdings, thereby adding to the diversity of the known cicada fauna of Thailand. Ten other species are removed from the Thai cicada fauna. Major areas of diversity are the northwestern region of the country and peninsular Thailand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity; cicadas; Cicadidae; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Allen</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sanborn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Polly</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Phillips</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-46</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new genera of oscinelline Chloropidae (Diptera) from Costa Rica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Medeventor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described for the type species &lt;i&gt;Medeventor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nubosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Costa Rica: Monteverde). &lt;i&gt;Medeventor&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from other Oscinellinae on the basis of a large, extensively setulose body, reduced cephalic and thoracic setae, a broad but weak facial carina and broad rugose gena. It appears to be most closely related to the Old World genera &lt;i&gt;Lipara&lt;/i&gt; Meigen and &lt;i&gt;Pseudeurina&lt;/i&gt; de Meijere. &lt;i&gt;Oscinicita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described for the type species &lt;i&gt;Oscinicita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hansoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Costa Rica: San Pedro de la Tigra). &lt;i&gt;Oscinicita&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished by its minute size, reduced wing venation and structure of the gena, face and frons. Its phylogenetic placement within the family is unknown.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chloropidae; &lt;i&gt;Medeventor&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Oscinicita&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terry</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wheeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Nanexila &lt;/i&gt;Winterton &amp; Irwin and &lt;i&gt;Taenogera &lt;/i&gt;Krober from Australia (Diptera: Therevidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species are desc r ibed in eac h of the closel y related gener a &lt;i&gt;Nanexila&lt;/i&gt; Wintert on &amp; Irwin an d &lt;i&gt;Taenogera&lt;/i&gt; Kröber. &lt;i&gt;Nanexila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricauda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nanexila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jimrodmani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described. The phylogeneti c placement and diagnostic characteristics of these new species an d othe r species recently transferred t o &lt;i&gt;Nanexila&lt;/i&gt; ar e discussed . &lt;i&gt;Taenogera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Taenogera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunnea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; ar e distinctive species descr ibed f r om female specimens collected in Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Taenogera&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed in light o f these new species and a revised ke y to species presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stiletto fl y; Asiloidea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stiletto fl y</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shaun</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Winterton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-64</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Nudobius &lt;/i&gt;from China (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae: Staphylininae, Xantholinini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Volker</firstname>
          <lastname>Assing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-03-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
