<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1627.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1627</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Zyzzyzus&lt;/i&gt; Stechow, 1921 (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa: Tubulariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The hydrozoan genus &lt;i&gt;Zyzzyzus&lt;/i&gt; is revised based on reexaminations of all available type specimens and on additional material. The taxon includes four valid species: &lt;i&gt;Zyzzyzus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spongicolus&lt;/i&gt; (von Lendenfeld, 1884), from the eastern Indian and southwest Pacific oceans; the type species, &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;warreni&lt;/i&gt; Calder, 1988, from the Atlantic, western Indian, and western Pacific oceans; and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;floridanus&lt;/i&gt; Petersen, 1990 and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; Petersen, 1990, both from the northwest Atlantic. Although type specimens of &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calderi&lt;/i&gt; Petersen, 1990 could not be located, it has been assigned here to the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;warreni&lt;/i&gt; because of similarities between the two in nematocyst dimensions, in number and structure of endodermal canals, and in external morphology of the hydrocaulus and hydrorhiza. A sixth nominal species (Corymorpha &lt;i&gt;iyoensis&lt;/i&gt; Yamada, 1958) has on one occasion been assigned to the genus, but detailed studies of the type material are needed to resolve its taxonomic affinities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; revision; Capitata; Tubulariidae; &lt;i&gt;Zyzzyzus&lt;/i&gt;; cnidome</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>J. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alvaro</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Migotto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A large new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Bufonidae) from Cerrado of Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new toad, &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerradensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described, including its tadpole and the advertisement call. The new species occupies Cerrado habitats in the Brazilian states of Piauí, Bahia, Goiás, Minas Gerais, and Distrito Federal. The species is characterized by its large size; absence of tibial glands; well developed cranial crests; short hands; sexually dimorphic coloration; and by the absence of a spiracle tube of the tadpole. The new species is included in the &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marina&lt;/i&gt; group by the presence of a jagged suture formed by the articulation between the pterygoid medial ramus and the parasphenoid alae, as well as other shared morphological features. Morphological characters and statistical analyses inferred by morphometric feature suggest the existence of two subgroups of species within &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marina&lt;/i&gt; group. However, taxonomic rearrangements are not made here and await phylogenetic analysis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerradensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marina&lt;/i&gt; group; Brazilian Cerrado; tadpole; advertisement call; osteology; morphological analyses</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerradensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marina&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Natan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maciel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Reuber</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brandao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leandro</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <lastname>Sebben</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-39</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new hermit crab species of the &lt;i&gt;Pagurixus anceps&lt;/i&gt; group (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Paguridae) from southern Japan, and supplemental notes on &lt;i&gt;P. patiae&lt;/i&gt; Komai, 2006</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The pagurid hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Pagurixus&lt;/i&gt; Melin, 1939, currently includes 24 species in the Indo-West Pacific, and recent studies have revealed the richness of this genus in southern Japan, particularly in coral reefs. In this paper, we deal with two species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dissimilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; described from southern Japan, and the recently described &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patiae&lt;/i&gt; Komai, 2006. The new species appears closest to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanus&lt;/i&gt; Komai &amp; Takada, 2006 in both morphology and coloration in life, but is distinguished from the latter by having a clearly delimited dorsomesial margin of the dactylus of the right cheliped in males and females, a blunt but distinct median crest and a mesial row of small spines on the dorsal surface of the carpus of the male right cheliped, and paired gonopores in females. The newly obtained specimens of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patiae&lt;/i&gt; from Okinawa Island enable us to describe the coloration in life of the species for the first time and to examine morphological variation. Brief notes on the distribution of the Japanese &lt;i&gt;Pagurixus&lt;/i&gt; species are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Paguridae; &lt;i&gt;Pagurixus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Japan; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masayuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Osawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new and endangered species of the pseudoscorpion genus &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; from a cave in Vietnam, with notes on chelal morphology and the composition of the Tyrannochthoniini (Arachnida, Chelonethi, Chthoniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragilis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from a limestone cave in the Hong Chong karst of Kien Giang Province, southern Vietnam, which is currently threatened by quarrying activities. This is the first record of a troglomorphic species of &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1951 from continental Asia. The presence of chemosensory setae on the dorsum of the chelal palm is interpreted as a synapomorphy of the tribe Tyrannochthoniini Chamberlin, 1962. The New Zealand genus &lt;i&gt;Maorichthonius&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1925 is transferred from the Chthoniini Daday, 1888 to the Tyrannochthoniini. The genus &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthoniella&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1966, also endemic to New Zealand, is assigned to the tribe Chthoniini Daday, 1888. The genus &lt;i&gt;Stygiochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Carabajal Márquez, García Carrillo &amp; Rodríguez Fernández, 2001, from southern Spain, is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Paraliochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1956 (n. subj. syn.). Five new combinations are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovatus&lt;/i&gt; Vitali-di Castri, 1984 (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius);&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paraliochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrancoi&lt;/i&gt; (Carabajal Márquez, García Carrillo &amp; Rodríguez Fernández, 2001) (ex &lt;i&gt;Stygiochthonius);&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvidigitatus&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1997) (ex &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius);&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setiger&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1997) (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius);&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superstes&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1986) (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius).&lt;/i&gt; A key is given to the genera of the Tyrannochthoniini. The parallel evolution in several groups of pseudoscorpions of a characteristic chelal morphology, here termed &lt;i&gt;lagyniform,&lt;/i&gt; is discussed. New designations are proposed for the spot-sensilla of the chelal fingers. The so-called ‘sensorium’ near the tip of the fixed chelal finger of &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; species is shown to be a modified tooth that has migrated dorsally from the dental margin. The new term &lt;i&gt;rallum&lt;/i&gt; is introduced as a replacement for the inappropriate term ‘flagellum’, as applied to the cheliceral blades of pseudoscorpions. The term &lt;i&gt;bothridial&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vestibulum&lt;/i&gt; is introduced for the internal cuticular sheath at the base of the bothridia of the trichobothria.&lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragilis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. est décrit d’une grotte calcaire de la province de Kien Giang, au sud du Vietnam, actuellement menacée par une exploitation de carrière. Elle est la première espèce troglomorphe du genre &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1951 connue de l’Asie continentale. La présence des soies chemosensorielles sur la main de la pince est interprétée comme une synapomorphie de la tribu des Tyrannochthoniini Chamberlin, 1962. Le genre néo-zélandais &lt;i&gt;Maorichthonius&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1925 est transféré des Chthoniini Daday à la tribu des Tyrannochthoniini. Le genre &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthoniella&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1966, également endémique de la Nouvelle Zélande, est attribué à la tribu des Chthoniini Daday, 1888. Le genre &lt;i&gt;Stygiochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Carabajal Márquez, García Carrillo &amp; Rodríguez Fernández, 2001, du sud de l’Espagne, est mis en synonymie avec &lt;i&gt;Paraliochthonius&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1956 (n. syn. subj.). Cinq combinaisons nouvelles sont proposées : &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovatus&lt;/i&gt; Vitali-di Castri, 1984 (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius)&lt;/i&gt; ; &lt;i&gt;Paraliochthonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrancoi&lt;/i&gt; (Carabajal Márquez, García Carrillo &amp; Rodríguez Fernández, 2001) (ex &lt;i&gt;Stygiochthonius)&lt;/i&gt; ; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvidigitatus&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1997) (ex &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius)&lt;/i&gt; ; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setiger&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1997) (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius)&lt;/i&gt; ; et &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superstes&lt;/i&gt; (Mahnert, 1986) (ex &lt;i&gt;Tyrannochthonius).&lt;/i&gt; Une clé de détermination des genres de Tyrannochthoniini est fournite. L’évolution parallèle des facies caractéristiques de la pince, ici qualifié de “ lagyniforme ”, est évoquée chez plusieurs groupes de pseudoscorpions. Desnouveaux sigles sont proposés pour les sensilles punctiformes des doigts de la pince. Il est démontré que le “ sensorium ” à l’extrémité du doigt fixe de la pince des espèces de &lt;i&gt;Lagynochthonius&lt;/i&gt; est une dent modifiée qui a migré dorsalement dès la marge dentale. Le terme inapproprié de “ flagelle ”, dans le sens de son application aux lames chélicèriennes des pseudoscorpions, est remplacé par &lt;i&gt;rallum.&lt;/i&gt; Le terme nouveau &lt;i&gt;vestibule&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trichobothriale&lt;/i&gt; est introduit pour la gaine cuticulaire à la base des bothridies des trichobothries.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pseudoscorpion; Tyrannochthoniini; taxonomy; morphology; endangered species; cave; Vietnam; New Zealand; Spain; sensilla</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pseudoscorpion</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>L. I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Judson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1626.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1626</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three transisthmian snapping shrimps (Crustacea: Decapoda: Alpheidae: &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt;) associated with innkeeper worms (Echiura: Thalassematidae) in Panama</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study deals with three species of &lt;i&gt;Alpheus,&lt;/i&gt; including two new species, living symbiotically in burrows of innkeeper worms (Echiura: Thalassematidae) on the tropical coasts of the western Atlantic and eastern Pacific Oceans. &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;christofferseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of four specimens from Atol das Rocas, northwestern Brazil, and one specimen from Bocas del Toro, Caribbean coast of Panama. All specimens of this species were collected with suction pumps from burrows on intertidal or shallow subtidal sandflats; the Panamanian specimen was collected together with its echiuran host, &lt;i&gt;Ochetostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cf.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edax&lt;/i&gt; (Fisher, 1946). &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of a single specimen found together with its host, &lt;i&gt;Listriolobus&lt;/i&gt; sp., under large intertidal mud-covered rocks of Punta Culebra, Isla Naos, Pacific coast of Panama. Finally, two specimens of &lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aequus&lt;/i&gt; Kim &amp; Abele, 1988 were collected together with their hosts, &lt;i&gt;Ochetostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edax,&lt;/i&gt; in the mixed rock-sand-mud intertidal of Coiba, Pacific coast of Panama. Remarkably, these three species are nearly identical in morphology and are also similar in color patterns. However, despite their morphological and ecological similarities, they are among the most genetically distinct of transisthmian alpheid geminate taxa examined to date. Genetic analyses suggest that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aequus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; form an eastern Pacific clade whose sister taxon is the slightly more distantly related western Atlantic &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;christofferseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Estimated divergence times are ~10 mya for the two eastern Pacific species, and ~11–12 mya for the western Atlantic and eastern Pacific clades. Within &lt;i&gt;Alpheus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;christofferseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aequus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; belong to the pantropical &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; Coutière, 1897 species complex (A. &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; clade), which also includes the eastern Atlantic &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ribeiroae&lt;/i&gt; Anker &amp; Dworschak, 2004 and the Indo-West Pacific &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus.&lt;/i&gt; The association of all three American species with thalassematid echiurans, as well as previous reports of associations between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; and echiurans in the western Pacific, suggest that this symbiosis is relatively ancient, having evolved in the ancestor of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbatus&lt;/i&gt; clade (at least 12 mya and probably earlier).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt;; Alpheidae; snapping shrimp; Echiura; new species; infaunal; symbiosis; western Atlantic; eastern Pacific; transisthmian taxa; cryptic species; barcode; COI</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alpheus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <lastname>Hurt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nancy</firstname>
          <lastname>Knowlton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Ampeliscidae) from Southwestern Atlantic, with a key of the genus for Brazilian species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; species are inhabitant of soft bottom marine benthic communities of tropical to cold – temperate zones. Prior to this paper, 11 species of the genus were recognized from Brazilian coast. Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; are herein described: &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipropoda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meridionalis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi.&lt;/i&gt; The specimens were dredged from the continental shelf of Southwestern Atlantic Ocean between the latitudes 22°06’S and 34°32’S. A key to the &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt; species of the Brazilian coast is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; marine benthic crustaceans; &lt;i&gt;Ampelisca&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Teresa</middlename>
          <lastname>Valerio-Berardo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-37</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comparison of mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; lineages and morphospecies of two avian malaria parasites of the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Haemamoeba&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Giovannolaia&lt;/i&gt; (Haemosporida: Plasmodiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">PCR-based methods have been increasingly used in diagnosis of parasitic diseases. Over 40 morphospecies of avian malaria parasites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Plasmodium&lt;/i&gt; have been described. However, only nine of them have been identified on the level of their mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; (cyt &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; gene lineages, which are frequently used in molecular biology studies of avian blood haemosporidian parasites. In this study, we linked two common mitochondrial cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; lineages P-SGS1 and P-TURDUS1 with their morphospecies. Light infections with two species of malaria parasites of the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Haemamoeba&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Giovannolaia&lt;/i&gt; were isolated from naturally infected adult Hawfinches, &lt;i&gt;Coccothraustes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coccothraustes&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, on the Curonian Spit in the Baltic Sea. These parasites were inoculated to naive juveniles of the Common Crossbill, &lt;i&gt;Loxia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvirostra&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, and House Sparrow, &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domesticus&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus. Heavy parasitemia of &lt;i&gt;Plasmodium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Haemamoeba)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;relictum&lt;/i&gt; Grassi &amp; Feletti, 1891 (lineage P-SGS1) and &lt;i&gt;Plasmodium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Giovannolaia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumflexum&lt;/i&gt; Kikuth, 1931 (P-TURDUS1) developed in the subinoculated Common Crossbills and House Sparrows, respectively, which enabled the detailed illustration of all main blood stages of these parasites and the deposition of their voucher specimens. The parasites of both lineages are actively transmitted in Europe and inhabit a broad range of avian hosts. Lineages closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;relictum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumflexum&lt;/i&gt; were identified. This study contributes to establishing of combined PCR-based and morphological identification of avian malaria parasites.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">avian malaria; &lt;i&gt;Plasmodium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;relictum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Plasmodium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumflexum&lt;/i&gt;; microscopy; PCR; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">avian malaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vaidas</firstname>
          <lastname>Palinauskas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vlad</firstname>
          <lastname>Kosarev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anatoly</firstname>
          <lastname>Shapoval</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Staffan</firstname>
          <lastname>Bensch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gediminas</firstname>
          <lastname>Valkiunas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new phreatic catfish of the genus &lt;i&gt;Phreatobius &lt;/i&gt;Goeldi 1905 from groundwaters of the Itenez River, Bolivia (Siluriformes: Heptapteridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phreatobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguijuela,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from an artificial well located within the Río Paraguá drainage, a tributary of the Río Iténez, Bolivia. The new species is distinguished from its sole congener, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cisternarum,&lt;/i&gt; by the absence of eyes, presence of 25–34 (versus 42–50) dorsal procurrent caudal-fin rays, 14–16 (versus 22–26) ventral procurrent caudal-fin rays, and 45–46 (versus 54–59) vertebrae. Both &lt;i&gt;Phreatobius&lt;/i&gt; species are phreatic and known only from artificial wells penetrating near-surface aquifers of the Amazon River basin. Material of the new species represents the first records of &lt;i&gt;Phreatobius&lt;/i&gt; from the upper Amazon, some 2000 km from reported locations of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cisternarum&lt;/i&gt; near the Amazon River mouth. &lt;i&gt;Phreatobius&lt;/i&gt; can be readily distinguished among siluriforms by the following combination of characters: dorsal and ventral procurrent caudal-fin rays extended rostrally, continuous with anal fin ventrally; caudal fin round; anal-fin rays unbranched; mouth prognathous, with jaws displaced dorsally on head; adductor mandibulae muscle hypertrophied, covering most of skull and posteriorly inserting onto first neural spine; first pectoral-fin ray soft, not spinous; bright red in life. This species is under severe threat from overexploitation by local people, who routinely capture and destroy it on the presumption that it represents a dangerous parasite.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">phreatic catfish; &lt;i&gt;Phreatobius&lt;/i&gt;; groundwaters; Bolivia; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">phreatic catfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lisandro</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Saucedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvajal-Vallejos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Scott</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schaefer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tardigrades from Guizhou Province (China)&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;with&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;description of a new species of genus &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; (Tardigrada: Hypsibiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seventeen species of tardigrades were found in this study. All species are new records for Guizhou Province, including two new records for China (Echiniscus &lt;i&gt;perviridis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zappalai)&lt;/i&gt; and one (Doryphoribius &lt;i&gt;huangguoshuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; new for science. The new species differs from the most similar species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; mainly by different configuration of gibbosities on dorsal side of the body (configuration 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 2, 2 in the new species; 2, 2, 2, 2, 2, 2, 2 in &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dupliglobulatus;&lt;/i&gt; 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 2, 2, 3 in &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibber;&lt;/i&gt; 6, 4, 6, 4, 6,4, 4, 2 in &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zyxiglobus).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; new species; new record; &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huangguoshuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Guizhou Province; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hanping</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lizhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiaochen</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclatural notes on &lt;i&gt;Gastrocopta fulongensis&lt;/i&gt; Chen, Zhang &amp; Zhang 2002 (Mollusca: Pulmonata: Stylommatophora: Pupillidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Qiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1625.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1625</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Meloidae (Coleoptera) of the United Arab Emirates with an updated Arabian checklist</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the first contribution on the blister beetles (Meloidae) of the United Arab Emirates (U.A.E.), but new records from all countries of the Arabian Peninsula are also included, with the addition of some species never recorded before from this region, thus updating the previous checklist. Two species from U.A.E. are described: &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pirata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (distributed also in Oman) and &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dunalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.,&lt;/b&gt; both belonging to different groups of species characterized by an unmodified mesosternum. &lt;i&gt;Mylabris&lt;/i&gt; (Mylabris) &lt;i&gt;desertica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pintoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fraudulentus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Saudi Arabia, are also described. The following species previously referred to different mylabrine genera are here included in the genus &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; as new combinations: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arabicus&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas, 1781), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borchmannianus&lt;/i&gt; (Kaszab, 1983), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gratiosus&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul, 1870), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ligatus&lt;/i&gt; (Marseul, 1870), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudobrunnipes&lt;/i&gt; (Kaszab, 1983), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabratus&lt;/i&gt; (Klug, 1845), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scapularis&lt;/i&gt; (Klug, 1845). &lt;i&gt;Coryna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pitcheri&lt;/i&gt; Kaszab, 1983 is doubtfully referred to &lt;i&gt;Hycleus.&lt;/i&gt; The new synonymies &lt;i&gt;Deridea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; Kaszab, 1960 = &lt;i&gt;Deridea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notata&lt;/i&gt; Thomas, 1897, &lt;i&gt;Mylabris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimaculata&lt;/i&gt; Klug, 1845 = &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexmaculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Olivier, 1811), and &lt;i&gt;Zonabris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugosissima&lt;/i&gt; Pic, 1909 = &lt;i&gt;Hycleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aestuans&lt;/i&gt; (Klug, 1845), are proposed. New information on the relationships of several species, particularly of the genera &lt;i&gt;Lydomorphus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hycleus,&lt;/i&gt; are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Meloidae; Arabian Peninsula; United Arab Emirates; checklist; new species; taxonomy; faunistics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Meloidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bologna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Federica</firstname>
          <lastname>Turco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the coastal marsh water beetle &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius queenslandicus&lt;/i&gt; Hansen (Coleoptera: Hydraenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;str.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandicus&lt;/i&gt; Hansen is taxonomically reviewed. The species is redescribed, male genitalia illustrated, distribution data given, and geographical distributions mapped. High resolution digital images of the holotype are presented (online version in color). &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandicus,&lt;/i&gt; the only Australian member of the genus, is known from four widely separated coastal localities, near the cities of Perth, Darwin, Karumba, and Townsville; only 41 specimens are known. It is primarily a coastal marsh species that appears to be most closely related to a species in Thailand. Members of the subgenus are not yet known from areas between Thailand and Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydraenidae; &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandicus&lt;/i&gt; Hansen; Australia; colonization; aquatic insects; aquatic microhabitats; holotype digital images</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Perkins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-42</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Calochromus &lt;/i&gt;Guerin-Meneville (Coleoptera: Lycidae) from Fiji</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Calochromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;samuelsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Viti Levu, Fiji. Photographs of its habitus, antenna and aedeagus are presented. This new species represents the first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Calochromus&lt;/i&gt; and the subfamily Calochrominae (Coleoptera: Lycidae) from Fiji.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Lycidae; Calochrominae; &lt;i&gt;Calochromus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Fiji</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alistair</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramsdale</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-46</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on some Libyan species of Pamphagidae (Orthoptera: Acridoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study is based on eight species representing five genera and two subfamilies belonging to the family Pamphagidae. Specimens from twenty eight localities in Fezzan region (Southern Libya) infesting various cultivated and wild plants were collected. Brief diagnosis of the family Pamphagidae is given. Key to the subfamilies and genera belonging to this family is provided mainly based on conventional as well as genitalic characters. Additional characters of male and female genitalia at generic level and differentiating characters of all species are briefly described. This is the first systematic collection of Pamphagidae from this region. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Tmethis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cisti&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maroccanus&lt;/i&gt; were recorded for the first time from Fezzan region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Classification; Taxonomy; Genitalia; Pamphagidae; Libya</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Classification</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Kamil</middlename>
          <lastname>Usmani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Holopothrips&lt;/i&gt; species (Thysanoptera: Phlaeothripidae) damaging &lt;i&gt;Mollinedia&lt;/i&gt; (Monimiaceae) leaves in Southern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of leaf-feeding thrips is described, from the Atlantic Rain Forest in Rio Grande do Sul State, Southern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Holopothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;claritibialis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. differs from other species of the genus in the combination of the following characteristics: all tibiae predominantly yellow; maxillary stylets retracted near the postocular setae; metanotum with reticulation, elongated on anterior half and equiangular on posterior half; pelta with equiangular reticulation medially but weak or absent laterally and posteriorly; glandular areas present on sternites VII–VIII in males (usually three glandular areas on each sternite). This species causes deformations and rolls on leaves of &lt;i&gt;Mollinedia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schottiana.&lt;/i&gt; Some aspects of the biology and intraspecific variation of this species are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">leaf damage; &lt;i&gt;Mollinedia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schottiana&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical fauna; sternal glandular area; thrips</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">leaf damage</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <lastname>Cavalleri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lucas</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kaminski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1624.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1624</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Vietnamese species of &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; McLachlan (Trichoptera: Stenopsychidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Larvae of the net-spinning caddisfly &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; McLachlan are very common in Vietnamese streams. Six species of &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; have previously been recorded from Vietnam. Based on comprehensive field studies throughout Vietnam between 2001 and 2003, the following species of &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; were recognized from the country: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustata&lt;/i&gt; Martynov 1930 (new Vietnamese record: male, female, and larva), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dakpri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female, and larva), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; Martynov 1931 (new Vietnamese record: male, female, and larva), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulmeri&lt;/i&gt; Navás 1932 (male, female, and larva), and two additional larval forms (Stenopsyche sp. 1 and &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; sp. 2). &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coomani&lt;/i&gt; Navás 1932, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fissa&lt;/i&gt; Navás 1932, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vicina&lt;/i&gt; Navás 1932 are designated as &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia.&lt;/i&gt; The new species and the newly discovered stages (female and larva of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustata&lt;/i&gt; Martynov and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulmeri&lt;/i&gt; Navás and larve of &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; sp. 1 and &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; sp. 2) are described and figured. Diagnoses, taxonomic remarks, and keys to males and larvae of all known Vietnamese &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stenopsychidae; &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Stenopsyche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dakpri&lt;/i&gt;; net-spinning caddisflies; taxonomy; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stenopsychidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Duc</firstname>
          <middlename>Huy</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yeon</firstname>
          <middlename>Jae</middlename>
          <lastname>Bae</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New taxa and records of Phaneropterinae (Orthoptera: Tettigoniidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera, &lt;i&gt;Semicarinata&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., and &lt;i&gt;Qinlingea&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., are described from China, with description of one new species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colorata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and one new combination, &lt;i&gt;Q.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachystylata&lt;/i&gt; (Liu and Wang, 1998). Two species, i.e., &lt;i&gt;Tamdaopteron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; Gorochov, 2005, and &lt;i&gt;Indogneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lata&lt;/i&gt; Ingrisch and Shishodia, 2000, as well as these two genera, are first records for China. We also gave additional descriptions about male stridulatory area of these two genera and the first female description of the species &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lata.&lt;/i&gt; A key to the genera with open tympana in China is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new genus; new species; new combination; new distribution records; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new genus</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chun-Xiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Le</firstname>
          <lastname>Kang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-29</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of European &lt;i&gt;Stevenia&lt;/i&gt; Robineau-Desvoidy (Diptera: Rhinophoridae) and a key to the Palaearctic species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Stevenia&lt;/i&gt; are described from Europe: &lt;i&gt;Stevenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;etrusca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Italian mainland: Toscana) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palermitana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Italy: Sicily, Palermo prov.). A key to all known Palaearctic species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rhinophoridae; &lt;i&gt;Stevenia&lt;/i&gt;; Europe; Italy; new species; key to species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rhinophoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pierfilippo</firstname>
          <lastname>Cerretti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Pape</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-41</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Chinese species of the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Dayus&lt;/i&gt; Mahmood (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae: Empoascini), with description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Chinese sepcies of the typhlocybine genus &lt;i&gt;Dayus&lt;/i&gt; Mahmood are revised. A total of five species, including three new species—lii &lt;b&gt;n.sp,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamellatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;membranaceus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp&lt;/b&gt; from Fujian Province are described, and a key to Chinese &lt;i&gt;Dayus&lt;/i&gt; species is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homoptera; morphology; distribution; identification; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dao-Zheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Qin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ya-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Anacroneuria&lt;/i&gt; (Plecoptera: Perlidae) from southern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Previously, only three species of &lt;i&gt;Anacroneuria&lt;/i&gt; had been recorded from Rio Grande do Sul State. Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Anacroneuria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fiorentini&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caraa,&lt;/i&gt; are described from the Sinos River catchment.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plecoptera; Perlidae; &lt;i&gt;Anacroneuria&lt;/i&gt;; Rio Grande do Sul; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plecoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Valdelania</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Froehlich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Palaearctic Xantholinini of the Museum of Zoology in Lund, Sweden, with description of two new species (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae). 182&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;contribution to the knowledge of the Staphylinidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The European and Mediterranian specimens of the tribe Xantholinini deposited in the Museum of Zoology, Lund, Sweden, were examined. Two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Phacophallus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuniseus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Tunisia (closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parumpunctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Gyllenhal) from Europe), and &lt;i&gt;Xantholinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cypriacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Cyprus. Keys to Mediterranean species of subgenus &lt;i&gt;Calolinus&lt;/i&gt; (genus &lt;i&gt;Xantholinus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Phacophallus&lt;/i&gt; are provided. Geonemic data for other 23 species are presented. The following new records are provided: &lt;i&gt;Milichilinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leptophius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavocinctus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hypnogyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stenistoderus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalotes&lt;/i&gt; (first record from Bulgaria), &lt;i&gt;Leptophius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavocinctus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stenistoderus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalotes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Xantholinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coiffaiti&lt;/i&gt; (first record from Corfu), &lt;i&gt;Xantholinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipennis&lt;/i&gt; (first record from Crete), and &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;morandi&lt;/i&gt; (first record from Majorca).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Xantholinini; Palaearctic; geonemical data; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arnaldo</firstname>
          <lastname>Bordoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1623.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1623</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sparassidae of China 4. The genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Sparassidae) in Yunnan Province</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda,&lt;/i&gt; Jäger, 2000 is revised for Yunnan Province, China. Fifteen new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinapophysis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interposita&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gongschana&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saetosa&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contentio&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amelia&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yinae&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roganda&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cangschana&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shuqiangi&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daliensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusa&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rivicola&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;digitata&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contraria&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. The male of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bibulba&lt;/i&gt;(Xu and Yin, 2000) and the female of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spiculata&lt;/i&gt; (Wang, 1990) are described for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Yang and Hu, 2001) comb. n. is transferred from the genus &lt;i&gt;Sinopoda&lt;/i&gt; Jäger, 1999. Limits of species groups in &lt;i&gt;Pseudopoda&lt;/i&gt; are discussed. Some characters are confirmed to be dependent on size of the spider (e.g., leg formula, ratio between head region and width of posterior eye row).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; new species; unknown sex; transfer; new combination; revision; zoogeography; Heteropodinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Jager</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vincent</firstname>
          <lastname>Vedel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tadpole and advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus erythros&lt;/i&gt; Caramaschi, Feio &amp; Guimaraes-Neto, 2003 (Amphibia, Anura, Leiuperidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe the tadpole and the advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythros&lt;/i&gt; Caramaschi, Feio &amp; Guimarães-Neto, 2003 from Parque Estadual do Itacolomi, Municipality of Ouro Preto, State of Minas Gerais, Brazil. Our data are compared with the information available for &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rupestris,&lt;/i&gt; the only species of the &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deimaticus&lt;/i&gt; species group with known tadpole and advertisement calls.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Leiuperidae; &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythros&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole morphology; advertisement call; Brazil.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Delio</firstname>
          <lastname>Baeta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Carolina Calijorne</middlename>
          <lastname>Lourenco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luciana</firstname>
          <middlename>Barreto</middlename>
          <lastname>Nascimento</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-46</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First fossil Micropholcommatidae (Araneae), imaged in Eocene Paris amber using X-Ray Computed Tomography</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We apply Very-High-Resolution X-Ray Computed Tomography (VHR-CT) to a minute fossil spider (~1 mm long) from Eocene amber of the Paris Basin, France. We demonstrate that the newly described genus and species of Micropholcommatidae, &lt;i&gt;Cenotextricella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simoni,&lt;/i&gt; retains excellent details of the somatic and male pedipalpal morphology that allows unqualified comparison with extant species. Thus, in addition to calibrating the tree of life, such fossils can now be incorporated into cladistic matrices and their resultant phylogenies. This is the first fossil record of the family Micropholcommatidae, extending the known geological range of the family by 53 million years (lowermost Eocene) and that of the symphytognathoid clade by approximately 5–9 million years.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cenozoic; new species; palaeontology; spider; Symphytognathoidea; Textricellinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cenozoic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Penney</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Dierick</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Veerle</firstname>
          <lastname>Cnudde</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bert</firstname>
          <lastname>Masschaele</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jelle</firstname>
          <lastname>Vlassenbroeck</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luc</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Hoorebeke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patric</firstname>
          <lastname>Jacobs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new scorpion species of genus &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; (Scorpiones: Bothriuridae) from northern Chile</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; (Leptosternus) &lt;i&gt;cepedai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; (Leptosternus) &lt;i&gt;coquimbo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described from Coquimbo region, in northern Chile. &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cepedai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; occurs in coastal dunes and is closely related to &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;sciosciae&lt;/i&gt; Ojanguren-Affilastro, 2002. On the other hand, &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coquimbo&lt;/i&gt; n. sp occurs at high altitudes in the Andes mountain chain and is related to &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; Roig Alsina, 1977, and to several Andean species from Argentina and Chile. Adaptative characters of the psammophilous &lt;i&gt;Br.&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;cepedai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are discussed. 39 scorpion species are now known from Chile, ten of them occur in the Coquimbo Region, being the region with the more diverse scorpion fauna in the country.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scorpiones; Bothriuridae; &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus;&lt;/i&gt; arid zones; new species; Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scorpiones; Bothriuridae; &lt;i&gt;Brachistosternus;&lt;/i&gt; arid zones; new species; Chile</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andres</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ojanguren-Affilastro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <lastname>Agusto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jaime</firstname>
          <lastname>Pizarro-Araya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Camilo</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mattoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1622.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1622</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A catalogue of the ants of Paraguay (Hymenoptera: Formicidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The ant communities of the Paraná River drainage in South America have spawned several major invasive species and a number of cosmopolitan tramp species, including the fire ant &lt;i&gt;Solenopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;invicta&lt;/i&gt; Buren and the Argentine ant &lt;i&gt;Linepithema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humile&lt;/i&gt; (Mayr). Paraguay sits at the center of the Paraná drainage but hosts one of the most poorly-documented ant faunas in the Neotropics, imposing a taxonomic impediment to ant studies in the region. In order to establish a baseline of knowledge about Paraguay’s myrmecofauna, I surveyed nineteen entomological collections and the published literature for records of Paraguayan ants. The resulting catalogue lists 541 ant species, 423 of which could be associated with available names. The Chao-2 estimate of species richness, calculated from the incidence of uniques and doubletons, estimates that the total ant species richness for Paraguay is 698 +/35, suggesting that the catalogue is about 80% complete and more than 100 species remain to be discovered. The Paraguayan ant fauna is characterized by many typical Neotropical elements but shows low endemism, an elevated diversity of attine ants, and only six non-native species. No new taxa are described here, but 40 taxonomic changes are introduced to clean antiquated trinomials from the fauna. The history of Paraguayan myrmecology is discussed, and a reference list is provided for species-level identifications.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">biodiversity; taxonomy; invasive species; neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">biodiversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wild</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-55</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and records of &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt; Mohrig (Diptera, Sciaridae) from the Oriental region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The following new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adunca&lt;/i&gt; (Brunei), &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancylonema&lt;/i&gt; (Malaysia, Selangor and Myanmar, Kambaiti), &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camptonema&lt;/i&gt; (Malaysia, Selangor), &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clinata&lt;/i&gt; (Malaysia, Sabah), &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirabilis&lt;/i&gt; (Malaysia, Selangor and Pahang), and &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orthonema&lt;/i&gt; (Malaysia, Sabah). &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvispina&lt;/i&gt; (Edwards), comb. nov., from Sumatra, is redescribed and a lectotype is designated. &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acerspina&lt;/i&gt; Mohrig, previously known from Nepal, is recorded from Myanmar, Kambaiti.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sciaridae; &lt;i&gt;Keilbachia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Oriental region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sciaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heikki</firstname>
          <lastname>Hippa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pekka</firstname>
          <lastname>Vilkamaa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1621.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1621</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Philautus &lt;/i&gt;Gistel (Amphibia: Anura: Rhacophoridae) from southern Western Ghats, India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the oriental shrub frog genus &lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Kakkayam Reserve Forest of Calicut district, Kerala state, in the southern Western Ghats. This species is distinguished from congeners by the combination of characters such as body small, elongate, squat and flat; head arched, wider than long; snout short rounded, equal or sub equal to diameter of eye; canthus rostralis rounded; tympanum indistinct but visible; eyes protruding, pupil with striking golden yellow dentition like marks; belly granular; vocal sac unpigmented; fleshy brown to cream yellow dorsum with two distinct golden yellow lateral bands bordered by dark brown from upper eyelid to the posterior part of flanks. A description of the advertisement calls and ecology and natural history notes are also provided for the new species which so far is only known from the type locality.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ochlandrae&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov.; shrub frogs; Western Ghats; &lt;i&gt;Ochlandra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setigera&lt;/i&gt; Gamble; advertisement calls</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Philautus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ochlandrae&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kotambylu</firstname>
          <middlename>Vasudeva</middlename>
          <lastname>Gururaja</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dinesh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Muhamed</firstname>
          <middlename>Jafer</middlename>
          <lastname>Palot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Radhakrishnan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramachandra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1917 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Hymenosomatidae), with resurrection of &lt;i&gt;Limnopilos&lt;/i&gt; Chuang &amp; Ng, 1991, and descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The systematics of the false spider crab genus &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1917 (Hymenosomatidae), is revised. &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carteri,&lt;/i&gt; type species of the genus, has a distinct locking structure of male abdomen as well as possession of a strong tubercle on the palm of the chela, features which are quite different from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naiyanetri&lt;/i&gt; (Chuang &amp; Ng, 1991), and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microrhynchus&lt;/i&gt; Ng, 1995. The present study restricts &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1917, for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carteri&lt;/i&gt; and resurrects &lt;i&gt;Limnopilos&lt;/i&gt; Chuang &amp; Ng, 1991, for the other two species. Two new species, one of &lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt; from Myanmar, and one of &lt;i&gt;Limnopilos&lt;/i&gt; from Sumatra, are also described. A key to the species of both genera is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Limnopilos&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; Hymenosomatidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hymenicoides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tohru</firstname>
          <lastname>Naruse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-31</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The mesopelagic copepod &lt;i&gt;Gaussia princeps&lt;/i&gt; (Scott) (Calanoida: Metridinidae) from the Western Caribbean with notes on integumental pore patterns</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The mesopelagic calanoid copepod &lt;i&gt;Gaussia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princeps&lt;/i&gt; (Scott, 1894) was originally described from the eastern Atlantic. It has been recorded in tropical and subtropical latitudes of the world, but has been reported only occasionally from the northwestern tropical Atlantic (NWTA). Comparative morphological studies, particularly of males, have not included specimens from the NWTA. Based on a collection of zooplankton from the Caribbean Sea, an adult male of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princeps&lt;/i&gt; is illustrated in detail and its morphology compared with other sources in order to explore intraand interoceanic differences within the species. The proportions and structure of the Caribbean specimens agree with the description of specimens from the eastern Atlantic and the Indian Ocean, except in details of the ornamentation of some appendages. Additional intraand interspecific differences were found in the number of integumental pores on the male antennules, swimming legs 1–4, and fifth legs. Integumental pores are consistently fewer in the Caribbean male than in the IndoPacific and eastern Atlantic counterparts, but &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princeps&lt;/i&gt; remains as the species of the genus with the largest number of pores on the swimming legs, a potential species-defining character within the genus. The Caribbean record, at 25–50 m deep, is the shallowest occurrence known for this mesopelagic form in the NWTA and represents the first finding of the genus and species in the western Caribbean and in Mexican waters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">zooplankton; Mexico; marine diversity; integumental pores</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">zooplankton</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Suarez-Morales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orestes&lt;/i&gt; Group (Anura: Leptodactylidae) from the Cordillera Occidental in northern Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orestes&lt;/i&gt; Group from cloud forest at 1700–1800 m in the Cordillera Occidental in northern Peru (Departamento de Cajamarca). The type series comprises one adult female and three males. The new species has a maximum snout vent-length of 29.4 mm, a long snout, dentigerous processes of vomers present, discs on outer fingers broadly expanded, males that have vocal slits present and nuptial pads absent, and a distinct color pattern consisting of tan blotches and spots on a brown venter, anterior and posterior surfaces of the thighs, concealed surfaces of the shanks, and axilla and groin, dark brown with tan blotches and spots. The &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orestes&lt;/i&gt; Group contains 12 species, of which nine occur in the Cordillera Occidental in northern Peru. Nuptial pads as diagnostic characters in &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cordillera Occidental; new species; nuptial pads; Peru; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orestes&lt;/i&gt; species Group</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cordillera Occidental</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Edgar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gunther</firstname>
          <lastname>Kohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-54</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Phyllochaetopterus&lt;/i&gt; (Chaetopteridae: Annelida) from near hydrothermal vents in the Lau Basin, western Pacific Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllochaetopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lauensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., a new species of Chaetopteridae, is described from material collected by the DSV &lt;i&gt;Jason&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;II&lt;/i&gt; from the vicinity of hydrothermal vents in the Lau Basin, western Pacific Ocean. The new species is characterized by the coloration and patterning of the ventral shield of the anterior region (region A), the presence of one large cutting chaeta on each parapodium of the fourth chaetiger (A4), the shape of these A4 cutting chaetae (with a pear-shaped head), and presence of two middle-region (region B) chaetigers with foliose notopodia. The new species is very similar to some &lt;i&gt;Spiochaetopterus&lt;/i&gt; species, but belongs in &lt;i&gt;Phyllochaetopterus&lt;/i&gt; based on its possession of a pair of anterior ‘antennae’, which are in fact cirri of chaetiger one with internal chaetae. The new species is compared to other &lt;i&gt;Phyllochaetopterus&lt;/i&gt; species, particularly from the Pacific, and we provide a table for all species currently referred to the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">polychaete; taxonomy; deep sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">polychaete</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eijiroh</firstname>
          <lastname>Nishi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Greg</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rouse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-64</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclatural notes on the names &lt;i&gt;Gaeolaelaps&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Geolaelaps&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Laelapidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Halliday</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lindquist</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1620.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1620</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eulichas&lt;/i&gt; Jacobson, 1913 (Coleoptera: Eulichadidae) I. Introduction, morphology of adults, key to subgenera and species groups, and taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;E. funebris&lt;/i&gt; species group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The predominantly Oriental genus &lt;i&gt;Eulichas&lt;/i&gt; Jacobson, 1913, family Eulichadidae, is reviewed in part. The &lt;i&gt;Eulichas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funebris&lt;/i&gt; species group is revised. A brief history of classification of the genus, as well as the general morphology of the adults, is presented. The following nine new species are described: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birmanica&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Myanmar: Tenasserim), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haucki&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Thailand), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jaechi&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Malaysia), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janbezdeki&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Laos); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kubani&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Laos, Vietnam), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meghalayensis&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (India: Meghālaya), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Sumatra, Nias, Siberut), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strbai&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Malaysia), and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tanahrata&lt;/i&gt; Hájek, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Malaysia). A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediocris&lt;/i&gt; (Pic, 1921) (Sumatra).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Eulichadidae; &lt;i&gt;Eulichas&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Eulichas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funebris&lt;/i&gt; species group; taxonomy; new species; Palaearctic; Oriental; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jiri</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A morphological and molecular description of a new &lt;i&gt;Teleopsis&lt;/i&gt; species (Diptera: Diopsidae) from Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Teleopsis&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera, Diopsidae) from Chiang Mai, Thailand is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Teleopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaii&lt;/i&gt; Földvári &amp; Carr is shown to be a member of a species group, termed the dalmanni species group, along with three previously described species. Presented here are a morphological description of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaii&lt;/i&gt; and an allometric comparison of the species with other members of the &lt;i&gt;Teleopsis&lt;/i&gt; genus. We also present multi-gene phylogenetic analyses to highlight the possible position of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thaii&lt;/i&gt; within the dalmanni species group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diopsidae; &lt;i&gt;Teleopsis&lt;/i&gt;; Thailand; new species; eye span allometry; molecular phylogeny; dalmanni species group</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diopsidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mihaly</firstname>
          <lastname>Foldvari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Pomiankowski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Samuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Cotton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Carr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new species of the &lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus venosus&lt;/i&gt; species-group (Ephemeroptera: Heptageniidae) from the Crimean Peninsula, Ukraine</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larvae and adults of &lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated. This species is found in the mountainous region of the Crimean Peninsula, and belongs to the &lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venosus&lt;/i&gt; species-group. SEM photographs of the eggs of new species are presented. The distinguishing characteristics separating this &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from closely related species of the &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venosus&lt;/i&gt; species-group are discussed. Detailed data on the biology and distribution of the new species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venosus&lt;/i&gt; species-group; Ephemeroptera; Heptageniidae; new species; description; taxonomy; Crimean Peninsula; Ukraine</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ecdyonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venosus&lt;/i&gt; species-group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Malgorzata</firstname>
          <lastname>Klonowska-Olejnik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Grigorii</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prokopov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roman</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Godunko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic study of the genus &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix&lt;/i&gt; Gunther (Orthoptera: Tetrigoidea: Metrodoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sixteen species of &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix&lt;/i&gt; Günther were systematically researched in this paper. One species, &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guangxiensis&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov., is described as new to science. An updated key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix&lt;/i&gt; is presented. The type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi’an, China (5%4&amp;) and Department of Chemistry and Life Science, Hechi University, China (6%10&amp;).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Tetrigoidea; Metrodoridae; &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix;&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Tetrigoidea; Metrodoridae; &lt;i&gt;Macromotettix;&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Weian</firstname>
          <lastname>Deng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhemin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shizhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Wei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1619.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1619</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; Viereck (Hymenoptera: Mutillidae), Part 1, with a description of a new Genus &lt;i&gt;Laminatilla&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study presents part 1 of a revision of &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; Viereck (Hymenoptera: Mutillidae) and includes the &lt;i&gt;cockerelli,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentifera,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exogyra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hexadonta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadridentata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setifera,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuiptera,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;unicornis&lt;/i&gt; species-groups &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Schuster (1958), representing 14 species. This revision also includes the &lt;i&gt;sonora&lt;/i&gt; species-group, which contains &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sonora&lt;/i&gt; (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; and the &lt;i&gt;villosa&lt;/i&gt; species-group, which is newly defined and contains &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villosa&lt;/i&gt; Mickel. &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;nov.,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is described from Baja California and is placed in the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentifera&lt;/i&gt; species-group. &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mexicana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;nov.,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costaricensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;nov.,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; are described from Mexico and Costa Rica, respectively, and are placed in the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuiptera&lt;/i&gt; species-group. A neotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicornis&lt;/i&gt; Schuster. Keys are provided to the &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; species-groups and to the species in these species-groups, where appropriate. &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; (Periphotopsis) &lt;i&gt;mamata&lt;/i&gt; Schuster is placed in the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; species-group and &lt;i&gt;Periphotopsis&lt;/i&gt; is a &lt;b&gt;junior&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of&lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubriventris&lt;/i&gt; (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; was previously placed in &lt;i&gt;Sphaeropthalma&lt;/i&gt; Blake. &lt;i&gt;Photomorphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piceogaster&lt;/i&gt; (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; was previously placed in &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis.&lt;/i&gt; A new genus &lt;i&gt;Laminatilla,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type species &lt;i&gt;Odontophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamellifera&lt;/i&gt; Schuster 1958), is described. This new genus includes the three species &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicornigera&lt;/i&gt; (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamellifera&lt;/i&gt; (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mixtoensis&lt;/i&gt; Schuster (Schuster), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; which were previously placed in the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamellifera&lt;/i&gt; species-groups &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Schuster (1958). A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Laminatilla&lt;/i&gt; and a new key for the males of the Nearctic genera of nocturnal mutillids are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sphaeropthalminae; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Sphaeropthalma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Photomorphus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sphaeropthalminae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pitts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-43</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomy of the dityline genera &lt;i&gt;Diasclera&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, &lt;i&gt;Dityloidea&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire and Germain and &lt;i&gt;Nerdanus&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire (Coleoptera: Oedemeridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New data on the taxonomy of three dityline genera are given. The genera &lt;i&gt;Dityloidea&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire and Germain, 1863 with the type species &lt;i&gt;Dityloidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janthina&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire and Germain, 1863, and &lt;i&gt;Nerdanus&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire, 1897 with the type species &lt;i&gt;Nerdanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coeruleus&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire, 1897 are redescribed and illustrated, their classification in the tribe Ditylini is stated and their relationships are discussed. A new subjective synonym: &lt;i&gt;Diasclera&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1913 = &lt;i&gt;Eumecomera&lt;/i&gt; Arnett, 1951, syn. nov. is proposed. &lt;i&gt;Diasclera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; (Horn, 1870), comb. nov., &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyanipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Horn, 1870), comb. nov. and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; (Le Conte, 1854), comb. nov. are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Diasclera&lt;/i&gt; from the genus &lt;i&gt;Eumecomera&lt;/i&gt; and their distribution is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera; Oedemeridae; Ditylini; &lt;i&gt;Diasclera&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dityloidea&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nerdanus&lt;/i&gt;; new synonymy; new combinations; redescriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Svihla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon sallesi&lt;/i&gt;, new genus and new species of Atalophlebiinae (Insecta: Ephemeroptera: Leptophlebiidae) from West and North of Brazil, and notes on systematics of &lt;i&gt;Hermanella&lt;/i&gt; group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt; is described here with a &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sallesi,&lt;/i&gt; and a &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt; (=Hydrosmilodon) &lt;i&gt;mikei&lt;/i&gt; (Thomas &amp; Boutonnet 2004). &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sallesi&lt;/i&gt; was described based on nymphs from Pindaíba Stream, near Nova Xavantina, State of Mato Grosso, and from Bem Querer Stream, State of Roraima, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from other genera of the &lt;i&gt;Hermanella&lt;/i&gt; group by presence of posterolateral spines on abdominal segments 6 or 7 to 9, tarsal claws with subequal denticles in two separate rows, without large subapical denticle, and clavate setae on legs. &lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt; seems to be closely related to &lt;i&gt;Hydrosmilodon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Leentvaaria.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt;; Atalophlebiinae; new genus; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydromastodon&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Polegatto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Batista</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Gonatocerus&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Mymaridae) from Argentina, an egg parasitoid of &lt;i&gt;Tapajosa rubromarginata &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Cicadellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Specimens of &lt;i&gt;Gonatocerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virlai&lt;/i&gt; S. Triapitsyn, Logarzo &amp; de León &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; which belongs to the &lt;i&gt;ater&lt;/i&gt; species group of &lt;i&gt;Gonatocerus&lt;/i&gt; Nees (Mymaridae), were reared in Argentina mostly from wild-collected and sentinel eggs of the sharpshooter &lt;i&gt;Tapajosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubromarginata&lt;/i&gt; (Signoret) (Cicadellidae: Cicadellinae: Proconiini) on citrus and corn plants. The distribution and host associations (both natural and laboratory) of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virlai&lt;/i&gt; are given. Under quarantine laboratory conditions in the USA, it was successfully reared for many generations on an unnatural host, the glassy-winged sharpshooter, &lt;i&gt;Homalodisca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitripennis&lt;/i&gt; (Germar).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mymaridae; &lt;i&gt;Gonatocerus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Cicadellidae; Proconiini; egg parasitoid; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mymaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Serguei</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Triapitsyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Logarzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Virla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jesse</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Leon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1618.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1618</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of species formerly assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Archocentrus&lt;/i&gt; (Perciformes: Cichlidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A phylogeny for 28 cichlid species that have been included in or near the same clade as &lt;i&gt;Archocentrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;centrarchus&lt;/i&gt; (type species of the genus) in previous phylogenetic analyses is presented, based on 98 morphological characters (osteology, gutcoiling pattern, pigmentation, squamation, meristics, and others), plus one cytogenetic character. Monophyly is supported for &lt;i&gt;Archocentrus&lt;/i&gt; sensu stricto, &lt;i&gt;Cryptoheros,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hypsophrys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Amatitlania,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Rocio;&lt;/i&gt; the relationships among these genera are not resolved. The three subgenera of &lt;i&gt;Cryptoheros&lt;/i&gt; are also supported; &lt;i&gt;Cr.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;panamensis&lt;/i&gt; is the sister group of the rest of the species in the genus. Within &lt;i&gt;Cryptoheros&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Cryptoheros),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cr.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chetumalensis&lt;/i&gt; is the sister group of the clade &lt;i&gt;Cr.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spilurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;+&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cr.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cutteri.&lt;/i&gt; Within &lt;i&gt;Amatitlania&lt;/i&gt; the pattern is: (Am. &lt;i&gt;coatepeque&lt;/i&gt; (Am. &lt;i&gt;nigrofasciata&lt;/i&gt; (Am. &lt;i&gt;siquia&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Am.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kanna))).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">phylogeny; cichlids; Middle America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schmitter-Soto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic status of the Guadalupe Darter, &lt;i&gt;Percina apristis&lt;/i&gt; (Teleostei: Percidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sciera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apristis&lt;/i&gt; (Hubbs &amp; Hubbs) was described as a subspecies based on the hypothesis that the population in the Guadalupe River system was morphologically distinct from other populations and that populations geographically closest to the Guadalupe River were intergrades between &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sciera&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apristis.&lt;/i&gt; Our data confirm the decision to recognize the population in the Guadalupe River as taxonomically distinct; however, western Gulf populations closest to the Guadalupe River do not show a consistent pattern of intermediacy in meristic variables. The Guadalupe population has extreme numbers of preopercular serrae, pored lateral-line scales, modified scales, caudal-peduncle scales, and anal rays. The most extreme trait is the number of preopercular serrae; 95% of individuals from the Guadalupe, but only 6% from other western Gulf drainages, have 0–3 serrae. Sixty-eight percent of Guadalupe individuals, but only 4% from elsewhere, have no serrae. These extreme values demonstrate that the Guadalupe population is genetically isolated and diagnosable as &lt;i&gt;Percina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apristis&lt;/i&gt; (Hubbs &amp; Hubbs), the Guadalupe Darter.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pisces; Guadalupe River; endemicity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pisces</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Robins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; from Departamento Cusco, southern Peru (Anura: Brachycephalidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Brachycephalidae) from two close localities at the upper limits of cloud forest in the southern Peruvian Departamento Cusco, between 3555–3950 m a.s.l. The new species is characterized by having medium size (maximum snout-vent length 23.4 mm), dentigerous processes of vomers absent, tympanic membrane inconspicuous, dorsal skin coarsely shagreen in life, dorsolateral folds, ventral skin areolate, dorsum tan, venter bold black with conspicuous bluish-gray spots, and a bluish-white iris.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; Peru; &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt;; Anura</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ignacio</firstname>
          <lastname>De La Riva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ochoa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edgar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1617.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1617</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic review of the lac insect genus &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; Balachowsky (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Kerriidae), with a revised key to genera of Kerriidae and description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; Balachowsky (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Kerriidae) is revised to include nine species: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorella&lt;/i&gt; (Maskell), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; (Morrison), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mithila&lt;/i&gt; Varshney, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;morobensis&lt;/i&gt; Williams &amp; Watson, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvestri&lt;/i&gt; (Mahdihassan), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ternata&lt;/i&gt; (Chamberlin), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;theae&lt;/i&gt; (Green), and two new species. &lt;i&gt;Tachardina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobata&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin (now &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobata)&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Tachardia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvestri&lt;/i&gt; Mahdihassan (now &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvestri),&lt;/i&gt; based on examination of type specimens. &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capsella&lt;/i&gt; Wang is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Albotachardina&lt;/i&gt; Zhang as &lt;i&gt;Albotachardina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capsella&lt;/i&gt; (Wang) comb. nov. We provide a revised taxonomic key to the genera of the family Kerriidae and to all known species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina.&lt;/i&gt; All &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; species are redescribed and illustrated with the exception of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mithila.&lt;/i&gt; One of the new species described here is the polyphagous and pestiferous lobate lac scale, which damages trees and woody shrubs in Florida, U.S.A., the Bahamas and the territory of Christmas Island, Australia, and has been identified mistakenly as &lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobata&lt;/i&gt; (Chamberlin), an insect native to India and Sri Lanka. Here we recognize the lobate lac scale as a new species, name it&lt;i&gt;Paratachardina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudolobata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and describe it based on all stages of the female (adult, second instar and first instar). In addition, a second new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahdihassani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on adult females from India.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">lac insect; lobate lac scale; pest; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">lac insect</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Takumasa</firstname>
          <lastname>Kondo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Penny</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gullan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-41</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mantodea of Jordan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Mantodea specimens from Jordan were collected from various parts of the country from March 2003 to November 2005. In addition, examination and identification of specimens previously housed in the University of Jordan Insects Museum and other Jordanian collections resulted in recording 16 species in four families. Mantidae included eight species in seven genera; Eremiaphilidae included four species all within a single genus; Empusidae included three species in two genera; and Tarachodidae included a single species. Nine species were recorded for the first time in Jordan: &lt;i&gt;Iris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oratoria,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Holaptilon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillulum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ameles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kervillei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ameles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;syriensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sphodromantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;religiosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eremoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infelix,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Empusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pennata.&lt;/i&gt; World distribution, collecting information within Jordan, some notes on the biology, ecology or diagnostic characters were provided for each of the recorded species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mantodea; Mantidae; Eremiaphilidae; Empusidae; Tarachodidae; praying mantises; Jordan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mantodea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Omar</firstname>
          <lastname>Abu-Dannoun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ahmad</firstname>
          <lastname>Katbeh-Bader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impexus &lt;/i&gt;Horn, a new species, and taxonomic notes and records for other &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; Curtis species (Coleoptera: Buprestidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The name &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impexus&lt;/i&gt; Horn has been found to belong to a Great Plains species and to be misapplied to a common southwestern &lt;i&gt;Agrilus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impexus&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paraimpexus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; is described from New Mexico, Arizona and California to Costa Rica. It is distinguished from both &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impexus&lt;/i&gt; and the closely related &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;addendus&lt;/i&gt; Crotch from Texas to Vera Cruz, México, and a lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;addendus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frisoni&lt;/i&gt; Fisher is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;addendus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonymy.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funestus&lt;/i&gt; Chevrolat is recorded from the United States for the first time and figured.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Identity; &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impexus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Identity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Henry</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hespenheide</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of a pygmy backswimmer (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Pleidae) from Micronesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zack</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aubrey</firstname>
          <lastname>Moore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ross</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1616.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1616</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First report on Rhabdocoela (Rhabditophora) from deep parts of Skagerrak, with the description of four new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this contribution we report on 13 species of Rhabdocoela, found during a marine inventory of Skagerrak by the Swedish Taxonomy Initiative. Four new species are described, two of which are Kalyptorhynchia (Gnathorhychidae and Polycystididae) and two belong to Dalytyphloplanoida (Solenopharyngidae). &lt;i&gt;Uncinorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vorago&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; (Gnathorhynchidae) has a triangular stylet consisting of a double-folded plate, which proximally forms a tube, but without a distal, needle-shaped tip. &lt;i&gt;Austrorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artoisi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Polycystididae), has two prostate stylets. Prostate stylet type II consists of a distal tube and a short proximal funnel, which has a stirrup-shaped ornament, whereas the stylet type III shows an unpronounced foot and style connected to each other by a narrow clasp and a comb-bearing plate. The foot and plate are connected to a thread-like flagellum. &lt;i&gt;Lenopharynx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bathos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Solenopharyngidae) resembles &lt;i&gt;Lenopharynx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tubatus&lt;/i&gt; Schockaert &amp; Martens, 1985, but differs in the detailed structure of the stylet and by the lack of colouration and eyes. &lt;i&gt;Proceropharynx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profundum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has a unique combination of small spines and hard ridges on the cirrus. Additional data are given for the remaining nine species, three of which are new for the Swedish fauna. &lt;i&gt;Espegrendia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;norvegica&lt;/i&gt; Westblad, 1954 (Solenopharyngidae) is redescribed. For the sake of completeness, two more species are mentioned. One is identified as a new species of &lt;i&gt;Acrumena&lt;/i&gt; Brunet, but lack of material prevents its formal description. The second one is probably a representative of the taxon &lt;i&gt;Ceratopera&lt;/i&gt; Den Hartog, but cannot be identified with certainty because of the poor quality of the preserved material. This contribution is one of very few reports on Rhabdocoela collected from a depth exceeding 100 m and some preliminary biogeographical remarks are therefore given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes; turbellaria; Kalyptorhynchia; Dalytyphloplanida; taxonomy; biodiversity; deep-water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wim</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Willems</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sandberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulf</firstname>
          <lastname>Jondelius</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; Agassiz, 1832 (Cypriniformes: Cyprinidae) with sexual dimorphism from the lower Rio Tejo Basin, Portugal</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olisiponensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the lower Rio Tejo Basin. It is a small species (all specimens examined less than 105mm SL) distinguished from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.l.&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination of characters. &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olisiponensis&lt;/i&gt; lacks a horny blade on the lower jaw, has a pronouncedly arched mouth, and lacks an intense reddish coloration at the base of the fins. It has elongated pelvic fins that reach the anus and often pass the anal-fin insertion in males, and dorsal, pelvic and anal fins usually have 8 branched rays. The new species has 36 to 43 scales in the lateral line, 7.0 to 8.5 scales above the lateral line, 13 to 16 circumpeduncular scales, denticulated (vs. smooth) grinding teeth surfaces, 6-5/5 pharyngeal teeth and 15 to 19 gill rakers. &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olisiponensis&lt;/i&gt; is further distinguished from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lusitanicum,&lt;/i&gt; a phylogenetically close species that lives in the same area, by having a higher body, a relatively longer head, and a larger eye. The origins of anal and pelvic fins are displaced anteriorly, while the origin of pectoral fins is displaced posteriorly. Pelvic and pectoral fins and last anal-fin ray are longer in the new species. Unlike the other species in the genus, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olisiponensis&lt;/i&gt; shows external sexual dimorphism, with males having longer pelvic fins whose extremities pass the anus and often overlap with the anal fin. This description raises concerns on the recently proposed splitting of &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.l.&lt;/i&gt; since the morphological traits deemed characteristic of some genera are unsuitable for their diagnosis. The species should be considered Critically Endangered (CR) according to IUCN criteria B1ab(ii,iii,iv)c(iv)+2ab(ii,iii,iv)c(iv).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arched-mouth nase; Iberia; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Chondrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olisiponensis&lt;/i&gt;; Rio Trancão; Rio Maior</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arched-mouth nase</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hugo</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gante</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Judite</middlename>
          <lastname>Alves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-35</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Huntemannia &lt;/i&gt;(Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Huntemanniidae) from the Yellow Sea, Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Huntemannia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;doheoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from a muddy sand flat off the coast of the Yellow Sea, Korea. The new species can be distinguished from its congeners by a combination of characters that include: a strong, hook-like outer process on the P1 coxa; incompletely fused exopod segments and reduced setal formulae of the P2–P4 in the female; and modified outermost spine on the distal segment of P3–P4 in the male. In addition, a key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Huntemannia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Huntemannia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Asia; marine; dichotomous key; SEM</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Huntemannia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sung</firstname>
          <middlename>Joon</middlename>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hyun</firstname>
          <middlename>Soo</middlename>
          <lastname>Rho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Won</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval morphology in four species of Madagascan frogs of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Brygoomantis&lt;/i&gt; (Mantellidae: &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe the tadpole morphology of four species of frogs classified in the endemic Madagascan subgenus &lt;i&gt;Brygoomantis&lt;/i&gt; of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus,&lt;/i&gt; based on larval specimens identified by DNA barcoding: &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;betsileanus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biporus,&lt;/i&gt; and two so far undescribed species that are here named &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; sp. aff. &lt;i&gt;betsileanus&lt;/i&gt; "very slow calls" and "Vohidrazana" referring to their bioacoustic features or collecting locality. The tadpoles of these four species are brown to yellowish benthic forms with a depressed body shape, dorsally directed eyes and relatively low fins. The oral discs are generalised and all species exhibit a wide gap in dorsal papillae. There is variation among different developmental stages with regard to the keratodont row formulae. In &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;betsileanus,&lt;/i&gt; younger stages (25 and 26) exhibit the formula 1:3+3/1+1:2, whereas it is 1:4+4/1+1:2 in older stages (36 and 38). In &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; sp. aff. &lt;i&gt;betsileanus&lt;/i&gt; "very slow calls", keratodont row formulae vary within one developmental stage (25–26) from 1:3+3/3 to 1:4+4/3, whereas it seems to be constantly 1:4+4/3 in all examined developmental stages of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; sp. aff. &lt;i&gt;betsileanus&lt;/i&gt; "Vohidrazana". In general, the larvae of the different &lt;i&gt;Brygoomantis&lt;/i&gt; species studied are morphologically similar to each other. Differences between species mainly concern colouration, shape of body and the number of keratodonts per millimetre, which is approximately 38 in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;betsileanus,&lt;/i&gt; 50 in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biporus,&lt;/i&gt; and 60 in the two undescribed species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Mantellidae; &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Brygoomantis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;betsileanus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biporus&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole descriptions; DNA barcoding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Angelika</firstname>
          <lastname>Knoll</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorn</firstname>
          <lastname>Kohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <lastname>Glaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Meike</firstname>
          <lastname>Teschke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudostomella &lt;/i&gt;(Gastrotricha: Macrodasyida: Thaumastodermatidae) from a sandy beach of Kerala, India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During an interstitial faunal survey along the south-west coast of Kerala, India, gastrotrich fauna were found in abundance. Together with species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Xenotrichula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Halichaetonotus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tetranchyroderma,&lt;/i&gt; were present several undescribed thaumastodermatid gastrotrichs belonging to the buccal palp bearing genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudostomella.&lt;/i&gt; Adults of the new species are characterized by the following traits: total body length of about 300 μ m; cuticular armature made up of medium sized pentancres covering the entire dorsolateral surface; pre-buccal, grasping palps bearing five, large papillae dorsally and 4-6 smaller papillae ventrally; adhesive apparatus made up of six anterior, 22-24 ventrolateral, two dorsolateral and six posterior adhesive tubes; caudal organ pear-shaped; frontal organ spherical. &lt;i&gt;Pseudostomella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cheraensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is the fourth taxon of the genus known from India; however, all the previous species reported hitherto from India have tetrancres instead of pentancres.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">interstitial; meiofauna; taxonomy; gastrotrichs; Arabian Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">interstitial; meiofauna; taxonomy; gastrotrichs; Arabian Sea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Priyalakshmi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Antonio</middlename>
          <lastname>Todaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1615.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1615</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on the subfamily Salyavatinae (Hemiptera: Reduviidae) from Vietnam, with the description of a new genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Vietnamese genera and species of the assassin bug subfamily Salyavatinae are revised. Five species in four genera are recognized, described or redescribed, illustrated, and keyed. One new monotypic genus, &lt;i&gt;Rhachicephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is established, with &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dilatibia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov&lt;/b&gt; as the type species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Salyavatinae; Vietnam; new genus; new species; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xuan</firstname>
          <middlename>Lam</middlename>
          <lastname>Truong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wan</firstname>
          <middlename>Zhi</middlename>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sycanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantiacus &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Reduviidae), a new harpactorine species from Bali, Indonesia, with brief notes on its biology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Sycanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantiacus,&lt;/i&gt; of the assassin bug subfamily Harpactorinae is described on the basis of specimens collected from Bali, Indonesia. This species is distinguished from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Sycanus&lt;/i&gt; by its antennal segment I having two orange annulations; the posterior pronotal lobe being weakly tumid in the middle near the posterior margin; the scutellar spine being erect, short, and rounded at the apex; each femur having two incomplete orange annulations; the hemelytral corium being blackish with the veins yellow to yellowish brown; and the abdominal laterotergites being weakly extended dorsad. This species is notable because it feeds on some serious lepidopteran pests of cabbage.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Harpactorinae; &lt;i&gt;Sycanus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Bali; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tadashi</firstname>
          <lastname>Ishikawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wataru</firstname>
          <lastname>Toriumi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wayan</firstname>
          <lastname>Susila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuji</firstname>
          <lastname>Okajimae</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-27</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the adult male elongate hemlock scale, &lt;i&gt;Fiorinia externa&lt;/i&gt; Ferris (Coccoidea: Diaspididae), with notes on the seasonal development of the species on eastern hemlock, &lt;i&gt;Tsuga canadensis&lt;/i&gt; (L.) Carriere(Pinaceae), in the southern Appalachian region (U.S.A.).</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The adult male of &lt;i&gt;Fiorinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;externa&lt;/i&gt; Ferris is described for the first time. Its morphology agrees with that of previously described adult males in the tribe Diaspidini, and suggests a close affinity to &lt;i&gt;Pseudaulacaspis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;externa&lt;/i&gt; has two complete overlapping generations per year on the needles of eastern hemlock, &lt;i&gt;Tsuga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canadensis&lt;/i&gt; (L.) Carrieré, in the eastern Tennessee (USA) southern Appalachians. Adult females (both gravid and non-gravid) and first-instar nymphs were the dominant overwintering stages, although all stages apart from the adult males were present throughout the winter months. Adult males began emerging in mid March with emergence peaks in mid April to early May and again in mid to late September.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">relationships; taxonomy; life cycle</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">relationships</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paris</firstname>
          <lastname>Lambdin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <lastname>Hodgson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jerome</firstname>
          <lastname>Grant</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-39</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apatrobus osuzuyamanus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new patrobine species from Japan, with a comparative study of the male genital morphology of the tribe Patrobini (Coleoptera: Carabidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apatrobus&lt;/i&gt; (Apatrobus) &lt;i&gt;osuzuyamanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Kyushu, western Japan (type locality: Mt. Osuzuyama [32°16'N, 131°25'E]). This species is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;ohtsukai&lt;/i&gt; Morita by a larger body, a pair of small depressions on the pronotum, and the shape of the aedeagal apex. Based on a comparative study of the male genitalia of several species, the homology of the genital sclerites of the tribe Patrobini are revised and a new terminology is proposed. The implications of present results for Patrobini taxonomy are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">endophallus; genitalia; ground geetles; homology; sclerites; terminology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">endophallus</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Koji</firstname>
          <lastname>Sasakawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wataru</firstname>
          <lastname>Toki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some necessary corrections of the spelling of species-group names within the family Dytiscidae (Coleoptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The spelling of 37 species-group names with the beetle family Dytiscidae is corrected relative to the most recent world catalogue. The original spelling of 11 specific and subspecific names based on personal names are considered incorrect as having the wrong suffix relative to the given etymology. For three specific names, the original spelling is considered correct, and the previously used corrections are unjustified. The remaining names dealt with are adjectives, or nouns misinterpreted as adjectives, and their inflection relative to the genus names is revised.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">specific names; spelling; Dytiscidae; nomenclature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">specific names</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anders</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nilsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-54</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First descriptions of immatures for &lt;i&gt;Megistops &lt;/i&gt;(Boheman) (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Galerucinae) in a new host-plant family, with notes on life history and redescription of &lt;i&gt;M. vandepolli &lt;/i&gt;Duvivier*</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The adult of &lt;i&gt;Megistops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vandepolli&lt;/i&gt; Duvivier is redescribed and previously undescribed features such as mouth parts, wing venation and genitalia are included. Egg, mature larva and pupa are described and illustrated for the first time providing data for future phylogenetic studies in Galerucinae. &lt;i&gt;Megistops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vandepolli&lt;/i&gt; is found in &lt;i&gt;Buddleja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stachyoides&lt;/i&gt; Cham. &amp; Schltdl (Buddlejaceae); their larvae are leaf-miners and the pupation occurs in soil. Additional comments on its life history are also presented and discussed. The genus &lt;i&gt;Megistops&lt;/i&gt; (Boheman) is added to this list of Alticini leaf-miners and a new family of host-plant is recorded for it.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Alticini; &lt;i&gt;Buddleja&lt;/i&gt;; leaf-miner; morphology; pupa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Alticini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adelita</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Linzmeier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cibele</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ribeiro-Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luciano</firstname>
          <lastname>De A. Moura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1614.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1614</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Six new species of &lt;i&gt;Tetra &lt;/i&gt;Keifer (Acari: Eriophyidae: Phyllocoptinae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper, six new species of &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; Keifer from China are described and illustrated, namely &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;actinidiae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Actinidia&lt;/i&gt; sp. Lindl. (Actinidiaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coriariae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Coriaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepalensis&lt;/i&gt; Wall. (Coriariaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantiacae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Rhamnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantiaca&lt;/i&gt; Nakai (Rhamnaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hupeanae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Dalbergia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hupeana&lt;/i&gt; Hance (Leguminosae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinicusis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Dipentodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinicus&lt;/i&gt; Dunn (Celastraceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhouzhis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. on &lt;i&gt;Pistacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; Bunge (Anacardiaceae). A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; in China is provided. The eriophyoid mite species described here are vagrants on leaf surfaces.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">eriophyoid mites; key; taxonomy; Shaanxi Province; Heilongjiang Province; Anthocoptini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">eriophyoid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiao-Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zi-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yue</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Micralestes &lt;/i&gt;(Characiformes, Alestidae) of the lower Congo River, with a description of a new species endemic to the lower Congo River rapids in the Democratic Republic of Congo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new dwarf alestid from the vicinity of Inga on the lower Congo River, Bas Congo Province, Democratic Republic of Congo is described. Assignment of the new taxon to the poorly defined genus, &lt;i&gt;Micralestes,&lt;/i&gt; is discussed and justified on the basis of available morphological character data. With the recognition of &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schelly&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a total of six &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; are now known to inhabit the 350 km stretch of the Congo River from Pool Malebo to Boma near the river’s estuary. These are &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutidens&lt;/i&gt; (Peters, 1852), &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humilis&lt;/i&gt; Boulenger, 1899, &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lualabae&lt;/i&gt; Poll, 1967, &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holargyreus&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1873), &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stormsi&lt;/i&gt; Boulenger, 1902, and the new species &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schelly.&lt;/i&gt; Of these &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schelly&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holargyreus&lt;/i&gt; are considered herein as restricted-range endemics of the lower Congo River. An illustrated key to &lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt; of the lower Congo River is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt;; lower Congo River; identification key; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Micralestes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Melanie</firstname>
          <middlename>L. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stiassny</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Victor</firstname>
          <lastname>Mamonekene</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-29</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; Wagler (Anura, Hylidae) with reticulated pattern on flanks from Southeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; with reticulated pattern on the flanks from the State of Minas Gerais and provide data on its advertisement call, habitat, and tadpole. The new species differs from other species of the &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypochondrialis&lt;/i&gt; group in color pattern, size, advertisement call, and breeding site. &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oreades&lt;/i&gt; topotypes and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephala&lt;/i&gt; differ from the new species by lacking a reticulate pattern bordering the upper jaw and encircling the eyes. In &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ayeaye&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itacolomi&lt;/i&gt; the hidden parts of legs present circular cells while in the new species this pattern is barred. The call of the new species has shorter notes than that of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephala.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is smaller than &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;centralis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephala,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itacolomi.&lt;/i&gt; From &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oreades&lt;/i&gt; topotypes, the new species differs also by presenting a broader reticulated stripe on flanks; a better defined reticulated pattern on throat, belly and ventral surfaces of hind limbs, and less projected nostrils. In life, the new species present dark blue reticulation on flanks, not black as in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;centralis,&lt;/i&gt; gray as in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ayeaye&lt;/i&gt; or deep purple as in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itacolomi.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is a pond breeder while &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;centralis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephala&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oreades&lt;/i&gt; are stream breeders. It can be distinguished from the remaining species of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hypochondrialis&lt;/i&gt; group by presenting a reticulate pattern bordering the upper jaw and eyes and orange cells with dark blue reticulations on flanks.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; advertisement call; tadpole morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ariovaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giaretta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>De C. Kokubum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-41</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hysterothylacium&lt;/i&gt; (Nematoda: Anisakidae) from marine fishes from Yellow Sea, China, with a key to the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hysterothylacium&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hysterothylacium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinense&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. was collected from the intestine of six species of marine fishes, &lt;i&gt;Astroconger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myriaster&lt;/i&gt; (Brevoort), &lt;i&gt;Trichiurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haumela&lt;/i&gt; (Forsskål), &lt;i&gt;Saurida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; Temminck and Schlegel, &lt;i&gt;Coryphaena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hippurus&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, &lt;i&gt;Sillago&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sihama&lt;/i&gt; (Forsskål) and &lt;i&gt;Argyrosomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentatus&lt;/i&gt; (Houttuyn) in the Yellow Sea, China. The new species differs from congeners by the presence of broad lateral alae, the length of the intestinal caecum (1.26–2.33mm long, 61.6– 75.0% of oesophageal length), the number and arrangement of caudal papillae (22–27 pairs of preanal, 1 pair of paranal and 3 pairs of postanal papillae), the size of the spicules (1.65–2.67mm long, 5.1–9.5% of body length) and the vulval position (23.9–31.7% from anterior end). A key to the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hysterothylacium&lt;/i&gt; is also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anisakidae; China; fish; &lt;i&gt;Hysterothylacium&lt;/i&gt;; Nematoda; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anisakidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ruiyong</firstname>
          <lastname>An</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luping</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Jupiaba &lt;/i&gt;Zanata, 1997 (Ostariophysi, Characiformes, Characidae) from the rio Tocantins drainage, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new characid species, &lt;i&gt;Jupiaba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elassonaktis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the rio Tocantins drainage. The new species is distinguished from its congeners by the following combination of characters: medial cusps of premaxillary teeth much larger than remaining cusps, dentary teeth decreasing abruptly in size from the fifth tooth backwards, first dorsaland anal-fin rays not prolonged by an elongate filament, presence of a vertically elongate humeral spot, 33–39 scales on lateral line, 5–7 scales series above lateral line, 9–11 pectoral-fin rays, and a incomplete series of median predorsal scales.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical tetras; Biogeography; Systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical tetras</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thiago</firstname>
          <middlename>N. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pereira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>H. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lucinda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Aclis &lt;/i&gt;(Mollusca: Gastropoda: Aclididae) from the continental slope of northeast Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; Lovén, 1846 are described from the continental slope of northeast Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is recorded off the state of Rio Grande do Norte at depths ranging from 375 to 510 meters. &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was dredged off the state of Sergipe at depths ranging from 365 to 510 meters. There are no similar species along the Brazilian coast. &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watsoni&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt; Smith, 1890, &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trilineata&lt;/i&gt; Watson, 1897, &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;supranitida&lt;/i&gt; (Wood, 1842) and &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ascaris&lt;/i&gt; (Turton, 1819) due to the presence of spiral keels and/or indication of a subsutural ramp. &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrostoma&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;Discaclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canariensis&lt;/i&gt; Moolenbeek &amp; Warén, 1987, &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attenuans&lt;/i&gt; Jeffreys, 1883 and &lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gulsonae&lt;/i&gt; (Clark, 1850) regarding its circular aperture and dilatation of the peristome, with a non-thickened outer lip. The latter two species are much more slender.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarissa&lt;/i&gt;; Caenogastropoda; deep sea; Rio Grande do Norte; Sergipe; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarissa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Carlos N.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Barros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Silvio</firstname>
          <middlename>Felipe B.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonata</firstname>
          <lastname>De A. Francisco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1613.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1613</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic and morphological differentiation of Mosor rock lizards, &lt;i&gt;Dinarolacerta mosorensis&lt;/i&gt; (Kolombatovic, 1886), with the description of a new species from the Prokletije Mountain Massif (Montenegro) (Squamata: Lacertidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of lacertid lizard of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dinarolacerta&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Prokletije Mountain Massif, Montenegro. This new species, &lt;i&gt;Dinarolacerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montenegrina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by its relatively small size, by usually having only one postnasal scale on one or on both sides of the head, a relatively lower number of temporal and postocular scales and a relatively high number of ventral scales. Osteologically, it is mainly characterized by the complete absence of the anteromedial process in the postocular bone, and more reduced supraocular osteoderms. The phylogenetic analysis using partial sequences of the mitochondrial 12S rRNA gene supports the specific status of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montenegrina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and shows that it represents an old independent lineage that separated from its sister species, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mosorensis,&lt;/i&gt; in the late Miocene. The Morača river canyon may have acted as a geomorphological and climatic barrier causing the speciation between the two species of &lt;i&gt;Dinarolacerta.&lt;/i&gt; The discovery of this new species endemic to the Balkan Peninsula highlights the importance of the Dinarides as one of the main European hotspots of biodiversity. This high level of endemicity in the Dinaric region is probably the result of both its geographic situation and its complex geological history and morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phylogeny; Balkan Peninsula; taxonomy; evolution; mitochondrial DNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Katarina</firstname>
          <lastname>Ljubisavljevic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Arribas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Georg</firstname>
          <lastname>Dzukic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Salvador</firstname>
          <lastname>Carranza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic status and ecology of Oriental &lt;i&gt;Pheretima darnleiensis &lt;/i&gt;(Fletcher, 1886) and other earthworms (Oligochaeta : Megascolecidae) from Mt Kinabalu, Borneo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Perichaeta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darnleiensis&lt;/i&gt; Fletcher, 1886, first described from Australian Darnley Island in the Torres Straits, was confused since Beddard (1900) and Michaelsen (1900) wrongly applied the names &lt;i&gt;Perichaeta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulata&lt;/i&gt; Schmarda, 1861 (= &lt;i&gt;Megascolex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulatus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Megascolex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indicus&lt;/i&gt; Horst, 1883 [= &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corticis&lt;/i&gt; (Kinberg, 1828)], respectively. Taxonomic revision of this species now merges several parthenogenetic morphs, including &lt;i&gt;Pheretima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decipiens&lt;/i&gt; Beddard, 1912 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Luzon, Philippines. Final resolution depends on location of missing types or, alternatively, on neotypification, nevertheless new material from Mt. Kinabalu, north Sabah (Borneo) allows augmentation of the description of &lt;i&gt;Pheretima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darnleiensis&lt;/i&gt; from that given by Sims &amp; Easton (1972) who, for its lobate/serrate intestinal caeca, remarked that these “cannot &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regarded&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taxonomic&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;characters&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fully&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formed&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;specimens”.&lt;/i&gt; Body size range is now 45–700 mm, although this suggests either high plasticity or too wide synonymy. Its distribution in the tropical Indo-Australasian Archipelago and islands of Malaysia, Indonesia and Fiji is attributed to human-mediated introductions in recent and pre-historic times that mask its true provenance; reports from Hawaii, Sri Lanka, South Africa and South America are disputed. Sympatric &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;omeimontis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kinabalu&lt;/i&gt; Sims &amp; Easton, 1972 was elevated to species level by Blakemore (2005). Descriptions of &lt;i&gt;Pheretima&lt;/i&gt; (Parapheretima) &lt;i&gt;saba&lt;/i&gt; Sims &amp; Easton, 1972 and &lt;i&gt;Polypheretima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;everetti&lt;/i&gt; (Beddard &amp; Fedarb, 1895: 69) – somewhat similar to &lt;i&gt;Polypheretima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kinabaluensis&lt;/i&gt; (Beddard &amp; Fedarb, 1895: 71) – are augmented and specimens are figured on newly collected material. A new Mt Kinabalu earthworm, &lt;i&gt;Metaphire&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paka&lt;/i&gt; Blakemore &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed that compares with &lt;i&gt;Metaphire&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cai&lt;/i&gt; (Michaelsen, 1916) from Java [originally “Pheretima &lt;i&gt;inflata&lt;/i&gt; (Horst) var. &lt;i&gt;cai”],&lt;/i&gt; bringing the total known earthworms from Mt Kinabalu to six species. Ecological associations are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pheretimoids; earthworm eco-taxonomy; biodiversity; montane</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pheretimoids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Blakemore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Csaba</firstname>
          <lastname>Csuzdi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masamichi</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nobuhiro</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaneko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tatsuya</firstname>
          <lastname>Kawaguchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Menno</firstname>
          <lastname>Schilthuizen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First records of water mites (Acari: Hydrachnidia) from Bhutan, with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New records of water mites (Acari: Hydrachnidia) from streams in Bhutan are presented. Two species new to science are described: &lt;i&gt;Sperchon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;himalayus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Torrenticola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bhutana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Furthermore, the first records from Bhutan are given for &lt;i&gt;Monatractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; (Lundblad), &lt;i&gt;Testudacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tripeltatus&lt;/i&gt; Walter and &lt;i&gt;Sperchon&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;indicus&lt;/i&gt; Kumar &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">water mites; new species; running waters; Sperchontidae; Torrenticolidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">water mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Pesic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Harry</firstname>
          <lastname>Smit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-56</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hydrodynastes&lt;/i&gt; Fitzinger, 1843 from central Brazil (Serpentes: Colubridae: Xenodontinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hydrodynastes&lt;/i&gt; is described from the State of Tocantins, Central Brazil. The new species is distinguished from all congeners by having a melanistic color pattern, with head and dorsum of the body mostly dark-brown to black; absence of postocular stripe; venter grayish-brown, with dark rounded blotches outlining two lateral stripes which become gradually paler towards the posterior region of the belly, disappearing after midbody. Comparisons of the new species are made with others species of the genus and its affinity with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigas&lt;/i&gt; is suggested based on meristic and hemipenial characters.Uma nova espécie de &lt;i&gt;Hydrodynastes&lt;/i&gt; é descrita do estado de Tocantins, Brasil central. A nova espécie é distinta de todos os congêneres por apresentar um padrão de coloração melânico, com cabeça e dorso do corpo predominantemente marrom-escuro a preto; ausência de faixa pós-ocular; ventre marrom-acinzentado, com manchas pretas arredondadas que formam duas faixas laterais que se tornam gradualmente mais pálidas na região posterior do ventre, desaparecendo após o meio do corpo. Comparações da nova espécie são feitas em relação às demais espécies do gênero e sua proximidade com &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigas&lt;/i&gt; é sugerida com base em caracteres merísticos e de hemipênis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; New species; Color pattern; Hemipenis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Franco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bruno</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bentim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-65</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclatural Acts: homonymy in the Ascidiacea (Tunicata) and proposed nomina nova</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Riccardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Brunetti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1612.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1612</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Scincidae) from Sripada Sanctuary (Peak Wilderness), in Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present work describes two new species of &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; from the Sripada Sanctuary (Peak Wilderness Sanctuary) of Sri Lanka. &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sripadensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the largest member in the genus and it is morphologically closely related to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deignani&lt;/i&gt; (Taylor 1950). But &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sripadensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be clearly distinguished from other members of the genus, by having three loreal scales, posterior loreals larger than the anterior in longitudinal axis, prefrontal and upper anterior preocular touching posterior loreal; 2 nd , 3 rd supralabials and 1 st subocular scale touching lower posterior loreal; males with pale brown throat and the ventral head; a dark brown stripe in the light brown background on the dorsal body, divided nasal. The other new species, &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munindradasai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is morphologically closely related to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taprobanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Kelaart, 1854) and can be clearly distinguished from other member of the genus, by having one loreal scale, the loreal is touching the prefrontal, frontonasal, nasal, 1 st and 2 nd supralabial scales, upper and lower preoculars; the loreal is larger than the longitudinal axis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munindradasai&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sripadensis&lt;/i&gt;; New species; Peak Wilderness; Sri Lanka; Sripada Sanctuary; skink; &lt;i&gt;Sphenomorphus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lankascincus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. Mendis</middlename>
          <lastname>Wickramasinghe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roshan</firstname>
          <lastname>Rodrigo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nihal</firstname>
          <lastname>Dayawansa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>U.</firstname>
          <middlename>L. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jayantha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new cichild species &lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cichlidae) from Lake Tanganyika, East Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new cichlid species, &lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitamwebwai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Bangwe peninsula (Tanzania), on the east coast of Lake Tanganyika, are described. Both species belong to the &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;savoryi&lt;/i&gt; species complex, characterised by a lunate tail with long filaments. &lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitamwebwai&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt; are highly stenotopic species, restricted to rocky habitat. They occur sympatrically with each other and with two other species of the complex but occupy different microhabitats. &lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt; lives in large numbers in sheltered areas with rubble substrate whereas &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitamwebwai&lt;/i&gt; occurs in much lower numbers on more exposed parts of the rocky shores, with large boulders, lower sedimentation rates, coarser sediment, and higher visibility. The two new species although closely related, show clear ecological differentiation. Evidence of ecological differentiation between closely related sympatric cichlids is rare in literature. Closely related sympatric cichlids in the large African lakes (with literature mainly referring to Lake Victoria and Lake Malawi) have been suggested to differ little in diet and habitat use, which has encouraged the idea that cichlid species can coexist without niche partitioning. Our paper provides a different perspective with cichlids from Lake Tanganyika.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitamwebwai&lt;/i&gt;; ecology; stenotopic; sympatry; lamprologines; mechanosensory lateral line</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neolamprologus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Piet</firstname>
          <lastname>Verburg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <lastname>Bills</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of S&lt;i&gt;cinax&lt;/i&gt; (Anura, Hylidae) of the &lt;i&gt;S. ruber&lt;/i&gt; clade from Minas Gerais, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of treefrog from the &lt;i&gt;ruber&lt;/i&gt; clade of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scinax,&lt;/i&gt; from Serra do Cabral, State of Minas Gerais, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cabralensis&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by a small size, slightly arched and faintly distinct canthus rostralis, spotted pattern of coloration on dorsum, thighs with transversal bars, granular skin on dorsum and venter, rounded snout in dorsal view, and distinct advertisement call. Additionally, data on advertisement and territorial calls and notes on natural history and habitat are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dendropsophini; &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cabralensis;&lt;/i&gt; advertisement call; territorial call; Serra do Cabral</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dendropsophini; &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cabralensis;&lt;/i&gt; advertisement call; territorial call; Serra do Cabral</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leandro</firstname>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Drummond</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Delio</firstname>
          <lastname>Baeta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Rita Silverio</middlename>
          <lastname>Pires</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new cyprinid species, &lt;i&gt;Labeo meroensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Teleostei: Cyprinidae), from the River Nile</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meroensis,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the River Nile between the 6th and 5th cataract at Shendi and Atbara, Republic of Sudan. It is a small species, up to 52.5 mm standard length, resembling some species of the &lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvus-&lt;/i&gt; group. It is distinguished from all other African &lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; species by the combination of the following characters: cylindriform body, transverse plicae on the inner surface of the lips, 5.5 scale rows between lateral line and mid dorsal line, 39 to 41 scales in lateral line, 16 scales around the caudal peduncle and eye-diameter more than 21% of head-length.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; Africa; freshwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Timo</firstname>
          <lastname>Moritz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Breaking molds: &lt;i&gt;Oswaldella laertesi&lt;/i&gt;, sp. nov., a unique Antarctic species of &lt;i&gt;Oswaldella&lt;/i&gt; Stechow, 1919 (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa: Kirchenpaueriidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the Antarctic genus &lt;i&gt;Oswaldella&lt;/i&gt; Stechow is described and figured, and its position amongst the remaining species of the genus is discussed. The material was collected from the Ross Sea area (Antarctica) during the BioRoss survey of the western Ross Sea and Balleny Islands in 2004. &lt;i&gt;Oswaldella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laertesi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is unique amongst known species of the genus in having hydrocladia arranged in three longitudinal rows.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hydroids; new species; benthos; Antarctic Ocean; biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hydroids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alvaro</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Pena</middlename>
          <lastname>Cantero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1611.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1611</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., a new genus of Lycidae (Coleoptera) from Sulawesi</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Sulawesi and it is placed in the tribe Metriorrhynchini, and a close relationships with &lt;i&gt;Metriorrhynchus&lt;/i&gt; Gemminger &amp; Harold, 1869 is suggested. Twenty–five species are recognized, of which 24 are described as new: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ambangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amporiwensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barclayi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brancuccii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cordatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumongabonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katarinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mamasensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigricordatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocularis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pendolensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufomarginatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenggahensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulci&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Xylobanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigricolor&lt;/i&gt; Pic, 1922 is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and redescribed. The species of &lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt; are classified in five species groups based on the shape of male genitalia and these groups are described with important diagnostic characters illustrated. A species identification key for males is provided. The ecology, zoogeography, evolution and mimicry of &lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are discussed. The high degree of external similarity among distantly related species from several lycid genera in Sulawesi suggests evolution of Müllerian mimicry.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Lycidae; &lt;i&gt;Sulabanus&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; new combination; taxonomy; mimicry; Australian Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Milan</firstname>
          <lastname>Dvorak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ladislav</firstname>
          <lastname>Bocak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Catalog of the types of Staphylinidae (Insecta, Coleoptera) deposited at Museo de La Plata (Argentina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The types of species of Staphylinidae (Coleoptera) housed in the collection of the Entomology Department of Museo de La Plata were examined and listed. These types belong to 46 species assigned to the following subfamilies: Aleocharinae (6 species, 17 types), Megalopsidiinae (1, 4), Osoriinae (4, 19), Oxytelinae (5, 19), Paederinae (12, 32), Proteininae (1, 1), Pselaphinae (9, 17), Staphylininae (5, 15), Steninae (2, 4) and Tachyporinae (1, 20). Types herein treated belong to 34 species described by Bernhauer, eight by Raffray and four by Bruch. Complete information is given for each type, including reference to original description, label data, and preservation condition. Two lists were added in order to support future research: one for specimens labelled with manuscript names, and another for specimens labelled as types but not included in the type series in the original publications.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; types; Museo de La Plata; Bernhauer; Bruch; Raffray</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liliana</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nora</firstname>
          <lastname>Cabrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mariana</firstname>
          <middlename>Chani</middlename>
          <lastname>Posse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cecilia</firstname>
          <lastname>Gabellone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-44</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and first stage associations in &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; (Ephemeroptera: Ephemerellidae: Ephemerellinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The alates of &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri&lt;/i&gt; (Allen and Edmunds) are described for the first time, and morphological variability of the species is discussed. Male adults have penes with dorsal projections at the base of the gonopores and forceps with a relatively straight lateral profile. &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri&lt;/i&gt; female alates and associated eggs have been misidentified as those of a &lt;i&gt;Hyrtanella&lt;/i&gt; species. &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri&lt;/i&gt; is reported from Vietnam for the first time. We describe &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacuna,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;new&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;species,&lt;/i&gt; based on male and female subimagoes and larvae, and the species is included in &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of genitalia morphology. Alates of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacuna&lt;/i&gt; are distinguished from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of a prominent dorsal longitudinal stripe, and larvae are distinguished by having paired median spines on abdominal terga, mouthparts that are not greatly reduced, and gills 3 that are relatively larger than those of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacuna&lt;/i&gt; is reported from India, Thailand and Vietnam. The structures of &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hyrtanella&lt;/i&gt; gill cavities are different and do not represent a synapomorphy for the two genera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ephemeroptera; Ephemerellidae; &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coheri&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Crinitella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacuna&lt;/i&gt;; new species; descriptions; Oriental</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ephemeroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luke</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jacobus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccafferty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-53</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Luciola aquatilis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a new aquatic firefly (Coleoptera: Lampyridae: Luciolinae) from Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of aquatic firefly belonging to &lt;i&gt;Luciola&lt;/i&gt; Laporte is described and illustrated based on external morphology of both males and females, and the genitalia of males. &lt;i&gt;Luciola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquatilis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a common firefly in Thailand was formerly commonly misidentified as &lt;i&gt;Luciola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brahmina&lt;/i&gt; Bourgeois. Other &lt;i&gt;Luciola&lt;/i&gt; species that resemble &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquatilis&lt;/i&gt; are discussed, as well as past confusion concerning their taxonomic affinities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Lampyridae; &lt;i&gt;Luciola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquatilis&lt;/i&gt;; firefly; new species; Thailand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anchana</firstname>
          <lastname>Thancharoen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lesley</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ballantyne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Branham</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Luen</firstname>
          <lastname>Jeng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The study on karyotypes of five Grylloidea species (Orthoptera: Grylloidea) in Northeast China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The karyotypes of five Grylloidea species from Jilin province in northeast China were studied. A clustering analysis of their chromosomal relative lengths was studied for the first. In the males, chromosome numbers vary from 2n = 27 (%) to 2n = 19 (%) and Fundamental Numbers (FN) from 30 to 19. All the species have the basic Orthopteran sex determining mechanism XX&amp;/X0%. The results of clustering analysis showed that the five species form two well-supported groups with a Rescaled Distance of 15: (1) the genus &lt;i&gt;Gryllodes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Teleogryllus&lt;/i&gt; and (2) the genus &lt;i&gt;Oecanthus.&lt;/i&gt; In particular, the morphologically close species of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;supplicans&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sigillatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emma&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occipitalis&lt;/i&gt; are strongly supported. The relationships among the five species are as follows: (((G. &lt;i&gt;supplicans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sigillatus),&lt;/i&gt; (T. &lt;i&gt;emma,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occipitalis)),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Grylloidea; Chromosome; karyotype</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ju-Xia</firstname>
          <lastname>You</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Na</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bing-Zhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hai-Bin</firstname>
          <lastname>Yuan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Li-Na</firstname>
          <lastname>Shang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1610.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1610</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Apseudomorpha (Malacostraca: Tanaidacea) of the ANDEEP III Antarctic Expedition</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper presents results of studies of apseudomorph tanaidacean collected during the ANDEEP III Expedition to the Antarctic, represented exclusively by the family Apseudidae. &lt;i&gt;Apseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paragracilis&lt;/i&gt; Kudinova-Pasternak, 1975, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; Błażewicz-Paszkowycz &amp; Larsen, 2004, &lt;i&gt;Leviapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pleonudus&lt;/i&gt; Błażewicz-Paszkowycz &amp; Larsen, 2004 were previously recorded in the Antarctic abyssal. A redescription of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paragracilis&lt;/i&gt; together with the description of two new species (Leviapseudes &lt;i&gt;angelikae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;n.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sp.&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Collossella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suprema&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. n. sp.) are the subject of the present paper.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Apseudomorpha; &lt;i&gt;Apseudes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Collossella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Langapseudes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leviapseudes&lt;/i&gt;; abyssal; Southern Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Piotr</firstname>
          <lastname>Jozwiak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Magdalena</firstname>
          <lastname>Blazewicz-Paszkowycz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A reassessment of apheloriine millipede phylogeny: additional taxa, Bayesian inference, and direct optimization (Polydesmida: Xystodesmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Millipedes in the tribe Apheloriini occur throughout the eastern United States, predominately in the deciduous forests of the Appalachian Mountains. Herein we present a reassessment of apheloriine millipede phylogeny using mitochondrial DNA sequences and an additional 29 exemplar taxa (including 15 undescribed species and all of the species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Brachoria,&lt;/i&gt; except one). In this study, first we check the results of the previous phylogeny of the tribe (Marek and Bond, 2006) with different alignment and phylogenetic techniques (direct optimization and maximum likelihood), and second reconstruct a new phylogeny evaluating it in the same way with Bayesian, maximum likelihood, and direct optimization. Using this updated and expanded phylogeny, we tested historical classifications with Bayes factor and Shimodaira-Hasegawa hypothesis testing, consistently finding very strong evidence against their implied phylogenetic hypotheses. Lastly, using the new phylogeny as a foundation, we make taxonomic modifications and provide an updated species list of Apheloriini (106 species/17 genera).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myriapoda; Diplopoda; taxonomy; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myriapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jason</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bond</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-39</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic notes and new records of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sphingonaepiopsis &lt;/i&gt;Wallengren, 1858 (Lepidoptera: Sphingidae) in Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy, morphology, biology and distribution of &lt;i&gt;Sphingonaepiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgoniades&lt;/i&gt; (Hübner [1819]) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nana&lt;/i&gt; (Walker 1856) are reviewed. The validity of subspecies within &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgoniades&lt;/i&gt; is re-examined and it is concluded that there is no justification for their continued recognition. &lt;i&gt;Sphingonaepiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgoniades&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pfeifferi&lt;/i&gt; Zerny 1933 is therefore confirmed as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgoniades.&lt;/i&gt; Records of &lt;i&gt;Sphingonaepiopsis&lt;/i&gt; in the collection of the Hayk Mirzayans Insect Museum (HMIM), Tehran, Iran, are collated and mapped, and the first confirmed occurrence reported of the Afrotropical &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nana&lt;/i&gt; in mainland southwest Asia, an increase in the known range of the species. Global distribution maps are provided for both species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Sphingonaepiopsis&lt;/i&gt;; Iran</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kitching</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Reza</firstname>
          <lastname>Zahiri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemigrammus&lt;/i&gt; Gill, 1858 (Characiformes: Characidae) from Rio Caura, Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new characid species, &lt;i&gt;Hemigrammus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taphorni,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Río Caura drainage, Venezuela. The new species is distinguished from its congeners by characters related to its color pattern, number of scale rows below the lateral line, teeth morphology, and dorsal-fin length. A brief discussion about the putative relationships of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taphorni&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; Neotropical tetras; &lt;i&gt;Hemigrammus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Benine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guilherme</firstname>
          <middlename>A. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lopes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-59</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of deep-water spider crab of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rochinia&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1875, from Guam (Crustacea: Brachyura: Majidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of deep-water spider crab (Majidae) of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rochinia&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1875, is described from Guam. &lt;i&gt;Rochinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is distinguished from the allied &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchra&lt;/i&gt; (Miers, 1886), &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;riversandersoni&lt;/i&gt; (Alcock, 1895) and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griffini&lt;/i&gt; Davie &amp; Short, 1989, in the form and position of the carapace spines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Majidae; &lt;i&gt;Rochinia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Guam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bertrand</firstname>
          <middlename>Richer</middlename>
          <lastname>De Forges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1609.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1609</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aplysina&lt;/i&gt; Nardo (Porifera, Verongida, Aplysinidae) from the Brazilian coast with description of eight new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A revision of Brazilian &lt;i&gt;Aplysina&lt;/i&gt; was conducted based on morphological study of species alive as well as preserved in the collections of Museu Nacional. In total, 190 specimens were studied in the lab. Identification was achieved by analysis of the external morphology, in combination with skeletal architecture and its components. Our analyses revealed marked within individual variation for most species in characters associated to the spongin fibres, suggesting a low diagnostic strength for this set of characters in &lt;i&gt;Aplysina.&lt;/i&gt; External morphology, on the other hand, permitted clearcut diagnoses for most species. Fifteen species were identified and are fully described below. Eight of these are new to science. A neotype for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulva&lt;/i&gt; is proposed here. The amended list of &lt;i&gt;Aplysina&lt;/i&gt; species for the Brazilian coast is: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alcicornis&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caissara,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cauliformis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristagallus&lt;/i&gt; sp.n, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fistularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulva,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacunosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lactuca&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lingua&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muricyana&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orthoreticulata&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pergamentacea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudolacunosa&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solangeae&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. A tentative identification key for these species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aplysina&lt;/i&gt;; Porifera; Sponges; Taxonomy; marine biodiversity; continental shelf; SW Atlantic; REVIZEE</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aplysina&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulisses</firstname>
          <middlename>Dos S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinheiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajdu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcio</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Custodio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular phylogeny of the &lt;i&gt;Sceloporus torquatus&lt;/i&gt; species-group (Squamata: Phrynosomatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Sceloporus&lt;/i&gt; is one of the largest genus of lizards in North and Central America, with 22 species groups. Among these, the &lt;i&gt;torquatus&lt;/i&gt; group has a notably wide geographic distribution with populations occurring from southern United States to Guatemala. In spite of the taxonomical work done with the group, some problems remain unsolved. We therefore obtained the phylogeny of the &lt;i&gt;torquatus&lt;/i&gt; group, based on 925 bp of the ribosomal 16S gene, 912 bp of the ribosomal 12S gene, and 893 bp of the ND4 gene, for a total of 54 specimens of 25 taxa. The genes were analyzed, both separately and combined, by means of maximum parsimony and Bayesian inference analyses. The subspecies of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrifer&lt;/i&gt; did not form a monophyletic group. The sequence data refuted the morphological evidence that suggested that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plioporus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyanogenys&lt;/i&gt; are closely related to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrifer&lt;/i&gt; and to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prezygus.&lt;/i&gt; Regardless, these last two were recovered as sister taxa. Moreover, evidence was found that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; does not form a monophyletic group, and that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oberon&lt;/i&gt; are a single species, despite their marked differences in coloration and scutelation. In addition, the non-monophyly of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucronatus&lt;/i&gt; was confirmed and the phylogenetic relationships of its different species were determined. At the same time, the subspecies of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dugesii&lt;/i&gt; were recovered as a monophyletic group, refuting the nonmonophyly of this taxon suggested in the phylogenetic hypothesis of the entire genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phrynosomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Sceloporus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquatus&lt;/i&gt; group; phylogeny; molecular systematics; mtDNA sequences</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phrynosomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Sceloporus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquatus&lt;/i&gt; group; phylogeny; molecular systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Norberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Martinez-Mendez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fausto</firstname>
          <middlename>R. Mendez-De</middlename>
          <lastname>La Cruz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1608.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1608</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A redescription of &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; Sazima and Bokermann (Anura, Leptodactylidae) and the recognition of a new closely related species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on freshly collected and recorded topotypes, we re-describe &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; and describe a closely related new species from the municipality of Uberlândia (MG, Brazil). As some other species of the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscus&lt;/i&gt; group, the new species present longitudinal skin folds on dorsal surface of shank. &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marambaiae&lt;/i&gt; is a shorte-legged species, in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; the shank reaches 61–65% of the SVL, and 62–68 % in the new species. Males &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; are larger (45 mm SVL) than those of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; (38.5 mm), than those of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plaumanni&lt;/i&gt; (31–35 mm), and are smaller and more slender than those of the new species (48.3–53.9). In &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; and in the new species the vomerine teeth are in two straight transverse series, in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; each is a distinct arch. &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plaumanni&lt;/i&gt; has a fast call rate (13–23/s), in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; it is 2.5–4/s, in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; it is just about 0.1–0.3/s and in the new species calls are emitted irregularly (0.02–0.3/s). &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; call is composed by 1–3 pulses, while the new species has a single or double-pulsed call; the call also is 25-100% longer in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; (mode 0.04 s, our sample) than in the new species (mode 0.02 s). We predict that populations in the Cerrado now identified as &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; will turn out to be conspecific with the new species described herein. In the original description the call of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jolyi&lt;/i&gt; is two times longer than that we described here based on topotypes. A possible mistake in time scale in the original description may account for this difference.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Leptodactylidae; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sertanejo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; Atlantic Forest; Cerrado Biome; advertisement call; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plaumanni&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ariovaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giaretta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hugo</firstname>
          <middlename>C. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-10</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Fishes (Elasmobranchii and Actinopterygii) of Picaozinho reef, Northeastern Brazil, with notes on their conservation status</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Shallow reefs on the northeastern coast of Brazil are rich, productive and diverse environments, with great ecological and economical importance. Picãozinho is located 1,500 m off the coast of João Pessoa city, Paraíba state, NE Brazil. The aim of this work is to provide an updated list of the reef fishes of Picãozinho, based on a survey of approximately 350 hours of direct observation using free dive techniques, and complemented by collection data and other unpublished records. A total of 102 species of 43 families were recorded. Of these, 36 are new occurrences for the reef and seven are species that have been recently resurrected from synonymy, mainly with Caribbean species previously cited for Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">ichthyofauna; shallow reef; Paraíba; reef fishes; conservation; checklist</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">ichthyofauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Allan</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Souza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martina</firstname>
          <middlename>Di Iulio</middlename>
          <lastname>Ilarri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>Roberto</middlename>
          <lastname>De Medeiros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renato</firstname>
          <middlename>Grotta</middlename>
          <lastname>Grempel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rosa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <middlename>L. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sampaio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>11-19</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of&lt;i&gt; Cermatobius&lt;/i&gt; Haase, 1885 (Chilopoda: Henicopidae) of China and Neotype Designation for &lt;i&gt;Cermatobius longicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Takakuwa, 1939)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of Chinese occurences of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cermatobius&lt;/i&gt; Haase, 1885 (Lithobiomorpha: Henicopidae) is based on both male and female specimens. Diagnoses, descriptions, distributions, and figures are presented for the two Chinese species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Takakuwa, 1939) and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longitarsis&lt;/i&gt; (Verhoeff, 1934a); at the same time, we designated a neotype for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Review; &lt;i&gt;Cermatobius&lt;/i&gt;; neotype; Henicopidae; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Review</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hui-Qin</firstname>
          <lastname>Ma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Da-Xiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ming-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-30</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllophorus (Phyllophorus) maculatus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of sea cucumber from the Yellow Sea (Echinodermata: Holothuroidea: Dendrochirotida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Phyllophorus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; new species is described from a depth of 22–45 meters near the western edge of the Yellow Sea. The body is cylindrical, with body wall ossicles present only in the anal region. Ossicles are four-pillared tables with low spires and indented disc margin. A revised key to the eleven phyllophorine (Family Phyllophoridae, Subfamily Phyllophorinae) species now known from China is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;members&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfamily&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Phyllophorinae&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;known&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;from&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;China&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;members&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfamily&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Phyllophorinae&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;known&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;from&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;China&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yulin</firstname>
          <lastname>Liao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pawson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-34</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heteromolpadia joyceae&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of sea cucumber from New Zealand, with a key to New Zealand Molpadiidae (Echinodermata: Holothuroidea: Molpadiida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heteromolpadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joyceae,&lt;/i&gt; new species, has been collected from depths of 258–632m off the east coast of New Zealand. It is distinctive in having a tough, leathery skin, gray with scattered red spots. Tables in body wall 100µm in diameter with three larger perforations; tail ossicles with 15–20 perforations, a three-pillared spire, and an average length of 300µm. A key to the eight species of Family Molpadiidae now known from the New Zealand region is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heteromolpadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joyceae&lt;/i&gt;; Holothuroidea; Molpadiida; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heteromolpadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joyceae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pawson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Doris</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vance</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-39</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Botia udomritthiruji&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of botiid loach from southern Myanmar (Teleostei: Botiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Botia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;udomritthiruji&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Tenasserim River drainage in southern Myanmar. It can be distinguished from congeners by its color pattern, consisting of five dark vertical bars on the body, with the central portion of these bars paler than its edges; with increasing age, the edges of these bars become more irregular and darker, and irregular dark spots on the pale interspaces begin to form, sometimes fusing with the edges of the vertical bars. In morphology, it differs from congeners by a combination of: body depth at anus 23.4–27.7% SL, caudal peduncle depth 15.9– 18.7% SL, and 12 dorsal-fin rays. Evidence for considering &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrolineata&lt;/i&gt; a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dario&lt;/i&gt; and for considering &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostrata&lt;/i&gt; a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;almorhae&lt;/i&gt; is also presented here.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tenasserim; Ostariophysi; Cypriniformes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tenasserim</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-49</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akysis pulvinatus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of catfish (Siluriformes: Akysidae) from southern Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akysis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulvinatus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from southern Thailand. It can be distinguished from congeners in having a combination of: length of adipose-fin base 23.0–25.2% SL, body depth at anus 13.2–16.0% SL, caudal peduncle depth 9.4–10.3% SL, head length 27.6–29.8% SL, head width 21.9–25.1% SL, length of nasal barbel 13.9–57.5% HL, length of maxillary barbel 78.5–105.0% HL, smooth posterior edge of pectoral spine, gently forked caudal fin with lower lobe longer than upper, yellow snout, and rounded pale colored patches on body. A possible case of Müllerian mimicry with the syntopic &lt;i&gt;Pseudobagarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; is mentioned and briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Siluriformes; Akysidae; catfish; &lt;i&gt;Akysis&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Siluriformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Satsuma&lt;/i&gt; species (Pulmonata: Camaenidae) endemic to Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of camaenid land snail, &lt;i&gt;Satsuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longkiauwensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from southern Taiwan is established. This large terrestrial and herbivorous snail inhabits the lowland forests with a narrow geographical distribution. The species is characterized by having a large shell, roundly angulated peripheries adjacent to the peristome, an open umbilicus, a robust flagellum, a weak expansion on male genitalia instead of a penial caecum externally and a hemispherical verge instead of an elongated pilaster internally. A key is provided for the first time to identify camaenids from Taiwan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Camaenidae; &lt;i&gt;Satsuma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; anatomy; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Camaenidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shu-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yao-Sung</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chung-Chi</firstname>
          <lastname>Hwang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1607.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1607</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Alcyonium&lt;/i&gt; (Octocorallia: Alcyonacea: Alcyoniidae) in Chile</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Alcyonium&lt;/i&gt; (Octocorallia: Alcyoniidae) are described from Chile. They occur in the shallow waters of the southern fjord region. One of them is an encrusting species, the other three form digitate colonies. Encrusting forms of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; Casas &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 1997, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haddoni&lt;/i&gt; Wright &amp; Studer, 1889 were also found in the fjord region, bringing the number of &lt;i&gt;Alcyonium&lt;/i&gt; species recorded for Chile to eight. For all six recently collected species SEM images of sclerites are presented, and a key to the Chilean &lt;i&gt;Alcyonium&lt;/i&gt; species is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coelenterata; Cnidaria; Octocorallia; Alcyonacea; Alcyoniidae; benthos; &lt;i&gt;Alcyonium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; Casas &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt;; 1997; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haddoni&lt;/i&gt; Wright &amp; Studer; 1889; new species; Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coelenterata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Ofwegen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Haussermann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Forsterra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphometric differentiation between two murid rodents, &lt;i&gt;Praomys tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; (Thomas, 1894) and &lt;i&gt;Praomys rostratus&lt;/i&gt; (Miller, 1900), in West Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Morphometric differentiation between the two species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Praomys&lt;/i&gt; Thomas (1915) inhabiting West Africa was investigated using univariate and multivariate statistics on external, cranial and dental measurements. One hundred and seventy six adult specimens (78 &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; and 98 &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus)&lt;/i&gt; from fifteen localities throughout the Upper Guinean rainforest were analyzed. All specimens had been previously identified to species level by molecular analyses (16S rRNA and/or cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene sequencing). Sexual dimorphism was observed in both species, but was more significant in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; than in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi.&lt;/i&gt; Body weight was significantly lower in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; than in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus.&lt;/i&gt; Moreover, males of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; had a significantly smaller head and body length than males of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus.&lt;/i&gt; Specimens of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; of both sexes were on average smaller than males of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; regarding all cranial and dental measurements, and smaller than females of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; with regard to most measurements. However, none of the cranial or dental measurements treated in our study could be used alone to separate &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi,&lt;/i&gt; because of considerable overlap in the ranges of each variable. A good discrimination between the two species was obtained by means of craniometrical multivariate statistics, several rostrum measurements being significantly lower in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tullbergi&lt;/i&gt; than in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus.&lt;/i&gt; Discrepancies between our results and former published studies are hypothesized to be due to differences between the variables used and/or the geographical areas covered.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Muridae; Systematics; Morphometry; Guinean Lowland forests; Rodentia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Muridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bertin</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Akpatou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Violaine</firstname>
          <lastname>Nicolas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Debra</firstname>
          <lastname>Pires</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eliezer</firstname>
          <lastname>N'goran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <lastname>Colyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-34</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Montealtosuchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arrudacamposi&lt;/i&gt;, a new peirosaurid crocodile (Mesoeucrocodylia) from the Late Cretaceous Adamantina Formation of Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of Peirosauridae (Crocodyliformes, Mesoeucrocodylia), &lt;i&gt;Montealtosuchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arrudacamposi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Late Cretaceous (Turonian-Santonian) strata of the Bauru Basin, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Montealtosuchus&lt;/i&gt; was found at the outskirts of Monte Alto County in reddish sandstones of the Adamantina Formation. This specimen is exquisitely preserved with skull, mandible, postcranial and exoskeletal elements in articulation that provides critical information of the anatomy of this group. The occurrence of Peirosauridae in the Adamantina Formation (Turonian-Santonian) widens the chronostratigraphic range of this Mesoeucrocodylia taxon in Brazil. Recent analysis suggests that the Peirosauridae is restricted to the Late Cretaceous deposits of South America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Montealtosuchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arrudacamposi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; Peirosauridae; Upper Cretaceous; Adamantina Formation; Bauru Basin</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Montealtosuchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arrudacamposi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; Peirosauridae; Upper Cretaceous; Adamantina Formation; Bauru Basin</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ismar</firstname>
          <lastname>De Souza Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Felipe</firstname>
          <middlename>Mesquita</middlename>
          <lastname>De Vasconcellos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sandra</firstname>
          <middlename>Aparecida Simionato</middlename>
          <lastname>Tavares</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-46</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The southernmost South American record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt; Norman, 1903 (Cyclopoida: Cyclopidae) with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the cyclopid genus &lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt; are widespread in coastal, estuarine and even fluvial environments worldwide. On the Atlantic coast of South America several species have been recorded as far south as the state of São Paulo in Brazil, at about 24°25´S. Specimens belonging to this genus have been collected from plankton samples from Laguna de Mar Chiquita, a coastal lagoon on the Argentinean coast at 37°40' S, 57°19' W. These do not fit the diagnosis of any of the known species, and are here described as a new species. Both sexes of &lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramirezi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated. It is distinguished by a combination of characters relating to (1) the last endopodal segment of P4, (2) shape and armature of P5, (3) size and spinulation of the spine on the basipodite of P1, and (4) length/width ratio of the fourth A1 segment. The presence of only one seta and three spines on the male P5 is also characteristic. The presence of &lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glaber&lt;/i&gt; Rocha, 1983 is reported for the first time for Argentina in sediments of the same locality.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt;; new species; distribution; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halicyclops&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Silvina</firstname>
          <lastname>Menu-Marque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dora</firstname>
          <lastname>Sorarrain</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-55</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Parapinnixa bolagnosi, a new species of pinnotherid crab from Cubagua Island and Los Frailes Archipelago, Venezuela (Crustacea: Brachyura: Pinnotheridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapinnixa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bolagnosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Cubagua Island and Los Frailes Archipelago in the Caribbean Sea off Venezuela based on female specimens. The new species is distinguished from the other nominal species of the genus by having a third maxilliped with a biarticulated palp and by the absence of an exopod. The description of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parapinnixa&lt;/i&gt; Holmes, 1894, is amended to accommodate these two distinctive characters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Pinnotheridae; &lt;i&gt;Parapinnixa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bolagnosi&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Caribbean; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Hernandez-Avila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ernesto</firstname>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Geosesarma&lt;/i&gt; from Palawan, Philippines (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Sesarmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of semi-terrestrial, freshwater sesarmid crab, &lt;i&gt;Geosesarma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lawrencei,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Palawan, the Philippines. It is distinguished from its congeners by a unique suite of characters of the carapace, third maxilliped, ambulatory leg, and male first gonopod. This is the first species of &lt;i&gt;Geosesarma&lt;/i&gt; described from Palawan and only the fourth from the Philippines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Sesarmidae; &lt;i&gt;Geosesarma&lt;/i&gt;; Palawan; Philippines; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marivene</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Manuel-Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Darren</firstname>
          <middlename>C. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yeo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Correction to "Some New Zealand Polyclads (Platyhelminthes, Polycladida)"</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1606.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1606</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of larvae of the tribe Hyperini (Coleoptera: Curculionidae): III. Mature larvae of the genus &lt;i&gt;Donus&lt;/i&gt; Jekel, 1865</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions of mature larvae of ten species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Donus&lt;/i&gt; Jekel, 1865 are given: larvae of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;austerus&lt;/i&gt; (Boheman, 1834); &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyrtus&lt;/i&gt; (Germar, 1821); &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osellai&lt;/i&gt; Winkelmann, 2001 and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichei&lt;/i&gt; (Capiomont, 1868) are described for the first time, larvae of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comatus&lt;/i&gt; (Boheman, 1842); &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oxalidis&lt;/i&gt; (Herbst, 1795); &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palumbarius&lt;/i&gt; (Germar, 1821) and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tesselatus&lt;/i&gt; (Herbst, 1795) are described for the first time in detail, and larvae of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crinitus&lt;/i&gt; (Boheman, 1834) and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; (Boheman, 1842) are redescribed. An identification key for the mature larvae of twenty-nine Hyperini-species known so far is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; morphology; larva; chaetotaxy; key; Coleoptera; Curculionidae; Hyperini; &lt;i&gt;Donus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jiri</firstname>
          <lastname>Skuhrovec</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of the myrmecophilous genus &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Aleocharinae: Lomechusini) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper studies the taxonomy of the myrmecophilous genus &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; Gravenhorst, 1806 from China and describes four new species: &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Beijing, &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicornis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Beijing, &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seticornis&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Hunan, and &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Tibet. A key to all seven Chinese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">myrmecophilous; Staphylinidae; &lt;i&gt;Lomechusa&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">myrmecophilous</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yong-Jie</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Zhang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-39</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Resurrection of &lt;i&gt;Crypturgus subcribrosus&lt;/i&gt; Eggers 1933 stat. n., and its close phylogenetic relationship to Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Crypturgus&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera, Scolytinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crypturgus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcribrosus&lt;/i&gt; Eggers is removed from synonymy under &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; (Herbst) and reinstated as a valid species based on evidence from DNA sequence data and morphological features. Phylogenetic analyses of &lt;i&gt;Elongation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Factor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;1α&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cytochrome&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oxidase&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; sequences in conjunction with morphological characters revealed a sister relationship between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcribrosus&lt;/i&gt; and two Nearctic species of &lt;i&gt;Crypturgus,&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; unrelated to any of these taxa. Type material of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; has been located and lectotype with paralectotypes are designated. Amended diagnoses that include DNA barcodes are presented for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcribrosus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; together with an identification key to the Fennoscandian species of &lt;i&gt;Crypturgus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cytochrome Oxidase I; Coleoptera; &lt;i&gt;Crypturgus&lt;/i&gt;; Curculionidae; DNA barcodes; Elongation Factor 1α; phylogeny; Scolytinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cytochrome Oxidase I</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bjarte</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jordal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Milos</firstname>
          <lastname>Knizek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Xestocoris&lt;/i&gt; Van Duzee, with comments on the genus (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Rhyparochromidae: Rhyparochrominae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the rhyparochromine tribe Lethaeini, &lt;i&gt;Xestocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibialis,&lt;/i&gt; from Arizona, is described and figured. The lectotype of &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collinus&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed. A lectotype of &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitens&lt;/i&gt; is designated and redescribed. New distributional records for &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitens&lt;/i&gt; are provided. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Xestocoris&lt;/i&gt; and a discussion of phylogenetic relationships with other lethaeine genera are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arizona; Lethaeini; sky islands; state records; generic phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arizona</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jane</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>O'donnell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-57</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A systematic study of the genus &lt;i&gt;Matsumuraeses&lt;/i&gt; Issiki from China (Lepidoptera: Tortricidae: Olethreutinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven species of &lt;i&gt;Matsumuraeses&lt;/i&gt; Issiki are recorded from China, including one new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;medogensis,&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and two species reported for the first time from the country, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capax&lt;/i&gt; Razowski &amp; Yasuda and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ussuriensis&lt;/i&gt; (Caradja). Photographs of adults and genital structures are provided, along with a key to the Chinese species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Tortricidae; Olethreutinae; &lt;i&gt;Matsumuraeses&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jinmei</firstname>
          <lastname>Lv</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Houhun</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1605.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1605</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Postembryonal development in Caprellidae: SEM description and comparison of ready-to-hatch juveniles and adults of two Mediterranean skeleton shrimps (Crustacea: Amphipoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions of the sets of externally visible characters of “ready-to-hatch” juveniles and redescriptions of females and males of &lt;i&gt;Caprella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavediniae&lt;/i&gt; Krapp-Schickel &amp; Vader, 1998 and &lt;i&gt;Caprella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;equilibra&lt;/i&gt; Say, 1818 (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Caprellidae) are made using the scanning EM and the light microscope. The juveniles of the different species are compared as well as the juveniles with the respective adults. It is shown that juvenile &lt;i&gt;Caprellas&lt;/i&gt; are far from being “miniature editions” of the adults and that numerous morphogenetic changes and reconstructions occur during postembryonal development.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Morphogenesis; direct development; first juvenile stage; adults; Scanning EM; amphipods; &lt;i&gt;Caprella&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Morphogenesis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carola</firstname>
          <lastname>Lang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Traudl</firstname>
          <lastname>Krapp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roland</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Melzer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudoscopelus &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Chiasmodontidae), with a new diagnosis for the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the deep-sea fish genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudoscopelus&lt;/i&gt; are described, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lavenbergi&lt;/i&gt; from the eastern Pacific, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bothrorrhinos&lt;/i&gt; from the western Pacific and Indian Oceans. A new diagnosis for &lt;i&gt;Pseudoscopelus&lt;/i&gt; based on two synapomorphies is proposed: the dorsal margin of the orbit is formed by infraorbital 6; the last pore of the infraorbital canal is on the dorsal edge of the orbit, anterior to the middle of the pupil. Twelve species of the genus are considered valid, with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microps&lt;/i&gt; confirmed as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;altipinnis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stellatus&lt;/i&gt; regarded as &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquerida.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">bathypelagic; deep-sea; swallowers</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">bathypelagic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>R. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Melo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cynthia</firstname>
          <lastname>Klepadlo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A brief review of &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa &lt;/i&gt;(Cypriniformes: Balitoridae) species from the Tarim Basin in Xinjiang, China, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent fieldwork allows a revision of the loaches of the genus &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; inhabiting the Tarim Basin in Xinjiang, China. Eleven species were previously recorded. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stewarti&lt;/i&gt; is a new record. &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papilloso-labiatus&lt;/i&gt; should be regarded as a valid species name. &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laterimaculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; was collected from the Kezile River, a tributary of the Tarim River, Kashigar City, Xinjiang on August 22, 2004. The new species can be distinguished from its congeners by the following combination of the characters: body compressed posteriorly; origin of dorsal fin closer to caudal base than to snout tip; pelvic fin insertion below 2 nd– 3 rd branched dorsal rays, fins extending beyond anus or nearly reaching anal fin origin; caudal fin slightly emarginate; body scaleless; lateral line complete; lips thick with strong furrows and papillae remarkable at mouth angle; anterior margin of lower lip covering anterior margin of lower jaw; intestine with 2 coils; free posterior portion of air bladder nearly equal to eye diameter, connecting to anterior encapsulated portion with long tube.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; review; Tarim Basin; Xinjiang; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jinlu</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Naifa</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Junxing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Microhylidae) from the Iquitos region, Amazonian Peru, with possible direct development</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of microhylid frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; from the upper Amazon basin of Peru (area of Iquitos, Departamento Loreto). The new species is characterized by small size, distinct reduction of fingers I and IV and the presence of large unpigmented eggs in the oviducts. The latter character is so far unknown in the recognized species of the genus and may indicate the presence of a terrestrial reproductive mode. The generic placement of the new species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Microhylidae; &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnova&lt;/i&gt; new species; Iquitos; Amazonia; Peru</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jiri</firstname>
          <lastname>Moravec</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorn</firstname>
          <lastname>Kohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1604.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Oct. 2007</title>
    <volume>1604</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2007</year>
    <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contribution to the knowledge of the genus &lt;i&gt;Harpalus&lt;/i&gt; in China, with description of new taxa (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Harpalini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The paper deals with the taxonomy of six Palaearctic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Harpalus&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1802, two of which are described as new, from China: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vernicosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Sichuan and Tibet) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parasinuatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Sichuan and Qinghai). Three species (H. &lt;i&gt;viridanus&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, 1844, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaznakovi&lt;/i&gt; Kataev &amp; Wrase, 1997, and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giacomazzoi&lt;/i&gt; Kataev &amp; Wrase, 1996) are treated as polytypic and three new subspecies are described from China: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustibasis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;ssp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Qinghai, Tibet, and Sichuan), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaznakovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lilliputa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;ssp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Tibet), and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giacomazzoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;ssp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (Tibet). &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staudingerianus&lt;/i&gt; Schauberger, 1932, &lt;b&gt;stat.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;rest.,&lt;/b&gt; which was formerly synonymized with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridanus,&lt;/i&gt; is treated as a separate subspecies from southernmost Gansu. New data about the distribution of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;potanini&lt;/i&gt; Tschitschérine, 1906 are provided and the taxonomic position of this species is discussed. Lectotypes are designated for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;przewalskyi&lt;/i&gt; Tschitschérine, 1894 (the former designation of the lectotype of this taxon by Kataev in 1989 is invalid), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscipalpis&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;versicolor&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1900 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;potanini&lt;/i&gt; Tschitschérine, 1906.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Carabidae; &lt;i&gt;Harpalus&lt;/i&gt;; China; taxonomy; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Boris</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kataev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hongbin</firstname>
          <lastname>Liang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Additions to the mirid (Hemiptera: Heteroptera) fauna of China, 2000-2006</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A list of Miridae from the Chinese fauna described, recorded, or revised since the 2003 list of mirids by B. Qi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; is presented. Information about descriptions, figures, distributions, type specimens, examined materials, host plants and predation, and references is listed to guide further studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Miridae; Chinese fauna; taxonomic list</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Miridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bao-Ying</firstname>
          <lastname>Qi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carl</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schaefer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lu</firstname>
          <lastname>Xiu-Hua</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-35</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The flower bug genus &lt;i&gt;Montandoniola&lt;/i&gt; Poppius (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Anthocoridae) from Indonesia, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Montandoniola&lt;/i&gt; Poppius are reported, including two new species described from Bali: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moraguesi&lt;/i&gt; (Puton), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawai&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellatula&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. A key to distinguish the three Indonesian species is provided, with photographs and illustrations of important features of the two new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Heteroptera; Anthocoridae; Orini; &lt;i&gt;Montandoniola&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kazutaka</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Toshiya</firstname>
          <lastname>Hirowatari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wayan</firstname>
          <lastname>Susila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuji</firstname>
          <lastname>Okajima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-45</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the male of &lt;i&gt;Mayriphilopterus nystalicus&lt;/i&gt; Mey, 2004&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(Phthiraptera, Ischnocera, Philopteridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male of &lt;i&gt;Mayriphilopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nystalicus&lt;/i&gt; is described and illustrated from two species of Brazilian puffbirds. The Whiteeared Puffbird (Nystalus &lt;i&gt;chacuru)&lt;/i&gt; is confirmed as a true host for this species of chewing lice. A key for identification and a list of hosts of the six species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mayriphilopterus&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">puffbirds; Bucconidae; Ischnocera; &lt;i&gt;Mayriphilopterus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Philopterus-complex&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">puffbirds</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michel</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Valim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Linardi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-51</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Australian spore-feeding Thysanoptera (Phlaeothripidae: Idolothripinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera and six new species of spore-feeding Thysanoptera are described from Australia, with Australian records of two further species, one from California and one from New Zealand. In the Tribe Pygothripini, subtribe Pygothripina, &lt;i&gt;Ecacleistothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glorious&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is a large and highly polymorphic rainforest thrips: the apterous male has a transverse first abdominal tergite, in contrast to the females that have a reduced pelta as is typical of most Phlaeothripidae. Also in this subtribe, &lt;i&gt;Heptathrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cumberi&lt;/i&gt; Mound &amp; Walker from New Zealand is recorded widely around the southern coasts of Australia. A key is provided to the six genera of Pygothripini subtribe Allothripina in which the terminal sensorium of the maxillary palps is unusually large. In this group, four wingless species are considered: &lt;i&gt;Minaeithrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aliceae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;driesseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; in which the maxillary stylets are wide apart, &lt;i&gt;Allothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamideae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; in which the third antennal segment has a basal flange unlike any other member of this widespread genus, and &lt;i&gt;Priesneriella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;citricauda&lt;/i&gt; Hood that was previously known only from California. In the Pygothripini subtribe Macrothripina, &lt;i&gt;Polytrichothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geoffri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from rainforest; this genus was known previously from a single species in Sarawak. A further rainforest species, &lt;i&gt;Malesiathrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described in the Tribe Idolothripini, subtribe Elaphrothripina; this genus was known previously from three species in the Asian and Pacific regions.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thysanoptera; Idolothripinae; Australia; California; polymorphism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thysanoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laurence</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mound</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2007-10-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
