<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Title &amp; copyright page, table of contents, about the editors</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Linnaeus tercentenary &amp; invertebrate taxonomy: an introduction</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Qiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shear</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Invertebrate systematics or spineless taxonomy?</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Quentin</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wheeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Tree of Life Web Project</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Tree of Life Web Project (ToL) provides information on the Internet about our current knowledge of the evolutionary tree of life and associated information about characteristics and diversity of life on Earth. Development of this open-access, database-driven system began in 1994; its official release was in 1996. Core scientific content in the project is compiled collaboratively by more than 540 biologists, all experts in particular groups of organisms, from over 35 countries. Additional learning materials are contributed by over 200 students, teachers, and amateur scientists, while images, movies, and sounds are contributed by both of these groups and over 200 media-only contributors. Administration of the project follows a hierarchical, community-based model, with authors for different parts of the ToL chosen by the scientists working in that particular field. The goals of the project are to document all species on Earth, as well as all significant clades; to provide basic information about the phylogeny of life; to share this information with other databases and analytical tools; and to encourage understanding and appreciation for biodiversity, evolution, and the interrelationships of Earth's wealth of species. Here we provide an outline of the goals and history of the project; the current content, administration, architecture, contributors, and audience, the challenges we have faced, and the future of the project.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Katja-Sabine</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wayne</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Reflections on PEET, the Partnerships for Enhancing Expertise in Taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The 12-year old PEET engages a retired program officer in a question-answer session focused on the aspirations and tribulations of the NSF-sponsored research, training, and computer infrastructure program, Partnerships for Enhancing Expertise in Taxonomy.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity Crisis; taxonomic impediment; training taxonomists</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity Crisis; taxonomic impediment; training taxonomists</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Archives of a small planet: The significance of museum collections and museum-based research in invertebrate taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Museum natural science collections are valuable, in many cases irreplaceable, and vital to research in many disciplines including taxonomy. Since 96% of known multicellular animals belong to one or another of the 34 invertebrate phyla, the value of those collections for invertebrate taxonomy (of both living and fossil taxa) is even higher. Systematic work that does not rely on museum specimens to verify or falsify the identities of the taxa studied is not science. Whether the techniques used are molecular or morphological, high tech analysis, or careful observation, systematics is the primary and most essential use of museum invertebrate collections. Their value and the case for their support for this primary and many other compelling reasons has been argued eloquently time after time, yet support still lags far behind needs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">value of natural history collections; systematics funding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">value of natural history collections</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Judith</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Winston</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Invertebrate taxonomy and evolutionary developmental biology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Evolutionary developmental biology (evo-devo) is a new research area where the traditions of evolutionary biology and developmental biology merge together. As in the past there has been a fruitful two-way exchange between evolutionary biology and taxonomy, and also between developmental biology and taxonomy, now the way is open for two-way exchanges between taxonomy and evolutionary developmental biology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Evo-devo; evolvability; heterochrony; model species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Evo-devo</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Minelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A modern look at the Animal Tree of Life</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogenetic interrelationships of animals (Metazoa) have been elucidated by refined systematic methods and by new techniques, notably from molecular biology. In parallel with the strong molecular focus of contemporary metazoan phylogenetics, morphology has advanced with the introduction of new approaches, such as confocal laser scanning microscopy and cell-labelling in the study of embryology. The discovery of new animal diversity (previously unknown groups like Cycliophora and Micrognathozoa) has invigorated the field as well. At present, broad consensus exists for the monophyly of bilaterian animals, a split of Bilateria into Deuterostomia and Protostomia, a division of protostomes into a clade of mostly spiral cleavers (Lophotrochozoa) and a moulting clade (Ecdysozoa), a ‘restricted’ deuterostome hypothesis that excludes the lophophorate phyla, and a basal position of acoel and nemertodermatid flatworms within Bilateria. However, the position of several protostome phyla, especially Bryozoa and Chaetognatha, remains intractable. Phylogenomic approaches such as Expressed Sequence Tags are showing much promise for resolving ongoing controversies at the base of the animal tree, especially the branching pattern among ctenophores, sponges and cnidarians.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Animals; Ecdysozoa; Expressed Sequence Tags; metazoa; phylogeny; Spiralia; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Animals</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gonzalo</firstname>
          <lastname>Giribet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Casey</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dunn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gregory</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Edgecombe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Greg</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rouse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genera of orders Actiniaria and Corallimorpharia (Cnidaria, Anthozoa, Hexacorallia), and their type species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We determined the type species, if any, for the 425 genera of the order Actiniaria and for the 19 genera of order Corallimorpharia. In Actiniaria, 393 genera have a clear type species; 46 generic names are homonyms, 17 of which are senior, 26 of which are junior (six have been replaced), and three are both junior and senior. Of the 18 available genera of Corallimorpharia, there are no junior homonyms, and one senior homonym.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">sea anemones; nomenclature; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">sea anemones</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daphne</firstname>
          <middlename>Gail</middlename>
          <lastname>Fautin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Taras</firstname>
          <lastname>Zelenchuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dinesh</firstname>
          <lastname>Raveendran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Centipede systematics: progress and problems</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Breakthroughs in centipede systematics over the past 25 years have included: a stable morphology-based cladogram for ordinal interrelationships that is largely congruent with well-sampled nuclear ribosomal genes; the discovery of mid Palaeozoic crown-group fossils, including Silurian-Devonian stem-group Scutigeromorpha and an extinct order in the Middle Devonian; and, a web-based catalogue of all centipede species globally. Challenges include species delimitation in several groups, conflict between different kinds of molecular data (nuclear coding genes versus ribosomal genes), the inter-familial relationships and classification of the Geophilomorpha in particular, and effecting a synthesis between microanatomical studies of selected ‘model’ species and dense taxonomic sampling in numerical phylogenetic analyses.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chilopoda; phylogeny; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chilopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gregory</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Edgecombe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The smaller arachnid orders: diversity, descriptions and distributions from Linnaeus to the present (1758 to 2007)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Carolus Linnaeus’ contribution to the study of the smaller arachnid orders was modest with the description of four taxa: the pseudoscorpions &lt;i&gt;Acarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cancroides&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scorpioides,&lt;/i&gt; the whip scorpion &lt;i&gt;Phalangium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudatum,&lt;/i&gt; and the whip spider &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reniforme.&lt;/i&gt; Since then, more than 5,100 species have been named in eight orders by a plethora of researchers. Trends in species descriptions over time are explored; the presence of different accumulation curves for some orders is thought to be due to advances in the study of morphology combined with a greater focus on collecting small arachnids in tropical ecoregions. Pseudoscorpion species richness is examined against log-transformed area data for all countries of the world. Anomalies, such as the poor representation of pseudoscorpion diversity in some large countries such as China, appear to be due to a low number of active researchers.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Opilioacariformes; Ricinulei; Palpigradi; Uropygi; Amblypygi; Schizomida; Solifugae; Pseudoscorpiones; richness; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Harvey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A brief history of the classification and nomenclature of Odonata</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The classification of insect order Odonata is traced from Linnaeus’ &lt;i&gt;Systema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Naturae,&lt;/i&gt; through 19th and 20th century morphology-based taxonomies, to molecular phylogenies published before November, 2007. Past and present nomenclatural difficulties are reviewed and the current situation in regard to rival taxonomies is outlined. Ordinal classifications based on morphological data continue to suffer from intractable uncertainty concerning wing vein homologies between Odonata and other Pterygota, but molecular analyses may soon show where the phylogenetic tree of Odonata should be rooted. The natural classification will become much clearer once this has been achieved.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Palaeoptera; Anisoptera; Zygoptera; wing venation; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Palaeoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>W. H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Trueman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The insect order Thysanoptera: classification versus systematics</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two widely different classifications of the insect order Thysanoptera are discussed; an essentially phylogenetic system recognizing nine families in two suborders, and an essentially phenetic system recognizing 40 families in two orders. This paper emphasizes the distinction between “classification” and “systematics”, the former stressing the importance of differences, whereas the latter stresses the importance of derived similarities. A phylogenetic (i.e. systematic) classification incorporates predictions concerning evolutionary relationships that are important throughout biological studies, whether in host and parasite associations, biogeography, comparative physiology or development. The available phenetic classification of Thysanoptera serves no such broader purpose in biology. Recent molecular data derived from the gene 18S rDNA are analysed, but although some groups of taxa are well resolved, the deep relationships within the Thysanoptera remain unclear.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thysanoptera; systematics; classification; phylogeny; 18S rDNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thysanoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laurence</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mound</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morris</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and higher classification of the scale insects (Hemiptera: Sternorrhyncha: Coccoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The superfamily Coccoidea contains nearly 8000 species of plant-feeding hemipterans comprising up to 32 families divided traditionally into two informal groups, the archaeococcoids and the neococcoids. The neococcoids form a monophyletic group supported by both morphological and genetic data. In contrast, the monophyly of the archaeococcoids is uncertain and the higher level ranks within it have been controversial, particularly since the late Professor Jan Koteja introduced his multi-family classification for scale insects in 1974. Recent phylogenetic studies using molecular and morphological data support the recognition of up to 15 extant families of archaeococcoids, including 11 families for the former Margarodidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato,&lt;/i&gt; vindicating Koteja’s views. Archaeococcoids are represented better in the fossil record than neococcoids, and have an adequate record through the Tertiary and Cretaceous but almost no putative coccoid fossils are known from earlier. In contrast, the sister group of the scale insects (Aphidoidea) has a more informative Jurassic and Triassic record. Relationships among most scale insect families are unresolved in phylogenetic trees based on nuclear DNA sequences, and most nodes in trees based on morphological data, including those from adult males, are poorly supported. Within the neococcoids, the Eriococcidae is not monophyletic and the monophyly of the Coccidae and Diaspididae may be compromised by the current family-level recognition of a few species-poor autapomorphic groups.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">archaeococcoids; neococcoids; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">archaeococcoids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gullan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cook</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Carl Linnaeus and his scale insects (Hemiptera: Coccoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Carl Linnaeus named 22 species of scale insects in the genus &lt;i&gt;Coccus,&lt;/i&gt; another in the genus &lt;i&gt;Aphis,&lt;/i&gt; and one other probably unintentionally. All are redescribed and discussed. It is established that &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;betulae&lt;/i&gt; L. is a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudum&lt;/i&gt; and that the name was validly described later by Fabricius. A brief history of Linnaeus’ collection is summarised and his scale insect collection described. Linnaeus’ descriptions of scale insects are here translated into English and all the references to scale insect literature cited by Linnaeus are listed in bibliographical form and annotated. Lectotypes are designated for the species names &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aonidum&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, &lt;i&gt;Aphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urticae&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus and &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uvaeursi&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus. One species, &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phalaridis,&lt;/i&gt; is here considered &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilosellae&lt;/i&gt; is recognised as a &lt;b&gt;syn.nov.&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Porphyrophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polonica&lt;/i&gt; (L.). &lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rusci&lt;/i&gt; is recognised as &lt;i&gt;Ceroplastes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rusci&lt;/i&gt; (L.), not &lt;i&gt;Columnea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rusci.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aphis&lt;/i&gt;; English translations; Scale insect literature cited by Linnaeus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Coccus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Weevils, Weevils, Weevils Everywhere</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An overview is presented of the progress made on the taxonomy, classification and phylogeny of weevils in the 250 years since the first taxonomic descriptions of weevils by Carolus Linnaeus. The number of described weevils species is calculated to be about 62 000 and the likely total number of existing species 220 000, indicating that we have described just over a quarter of the diversity of this important group of beetles and that, at current rates of discovery and description, it will take another 650 years or so to describe the rest. Within the framework of the current concept of weevil phylogeny, a brief account is given of the seven main weevil lineages (families), and of the subfamilies of the largest of them, the Curculionidae, summarising their diversity, distribution and biology and identifying the major classificatory problems remaining in each. In conjunction with the phylogenetic hypothesis of weevil relationships and their fossil record, which is briefly summarised, the evolutionary history of weevils is mapped as a sequence of key evolutionary innovations that together have led to the phenomenal diversification and success of weevils.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curculionoidea; diversity; classification; phylogeny; evolutionary history</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curculionoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rolf</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oberprieler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marvaldi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Anderson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and Classification of Hymenoptera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An overview of recent advances in our understanding of the higher phylogeny and classification is presented. Molecular and morphological cladistic and pre-cladistic studies are summarized. A superfamily-level classification of the Hymenoptera is offered to reflect recent advances in our understanding of the phylogenetic relationships of the Hymenoptera. It differs from most recent classifications in the recognition of the Diaprioidea, to include Diapriidae, Monomachidae, and Maamingidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diaprioidea; taxonomy; cladistics; life history; Insecta</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diaprioidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sharkey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny, classification, and species-level taxonomy of ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The current state of ant systematics is reviewed. In recent years substantial progress has been made in identifying the major clades of ants and the relationships among them. Earlier inferences about ant phylogeny based on morphology have been refined and modified as a result of a recent influx of molecular (DNA sequence) data and new fossil discoveries. It is now apparent that much of the biological and taxonomic diversity of ants is contained within the “formicoid clade” which comprises 14 of the 20 extant subfamilies and about 90% of all species. Whether the remaining groups of extant ants (Leptanillinae and the poneroid subfamilies) represent a clade or a grade at the base of the ant tree remains unresolved. The fossil record for crown group ants extends back to 90–100 mya. Stem ants (sphecomyrmines, armaniines) were also present during this period. Molecular divergence date estimates that take into account the fossil record of both ants and other Hymenoptera suggest that crown group ants arose ~115–135 mya. Most of the extant ant subfamilies and genera are well defined morphologically and likely monophyletic, but there are some notable exceptions including the subfamily Cerapachyinae and several large and ambiguously delimited genera such as &lt;i&gt;Pachycondyla.&lt;/i&gt; Several tribes in the large subfamilies Formicinae and Myrmicinae also represent artificial assemblages. Finally, while the specieslevel taxonomy of some ant genera is in a satisfactory state, taxonomic anarchy reigns in others, with numerous illdefined species and many names of uncertain applicability. Progress in this area of ant systematics will require sustained individual efforts, expansion of job opportunities, enlistment of new technologies, and a deeper understanding of the nature of ant species and the differences between them.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">ant systematics; molecular phylogenetics; alpha-taxonomy; fossils; formicoid clade</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">ant systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ward</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and systematics of Diptera: Two decades of progress and prospects</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Diptera, or true flies (mosquitoes, gnats, and house flies) comprise 12-15% of animal species, and are the most ecologically diverse order of insects, spanning ecological roles from detritivory to vertebrate blood feeding and leaf mining. The earliest known fossil Diptera are from the early Triassic 240 mya, and the order probably arose in the late Permian. The earliest brachyceran fossils are found in the late Triassic and earliest Jurassic, but the diversification of the extremely diverse Calyptrata (ca. 30% of described species) began in the late Creataceous. The monophyly of the order is supported by numerous morphological and biological characters and molecular data sets. The major lineages within the order are well established, and we summarize major recent phylogenetic analyses in a supertree for the Diptera. Most studies concur that the traditional subordinal group Nematocera is paraphyletic, but relationships between the major lineages of these flies are not recovered consistently. There is particular instability around the placement of the tipulids and their relatives and the families of the Psychodomorpha as traditionally defined. The other major suborder, Brachycera, is clearly monophyletic, and the relationships between major brachyceran lineages have become clearer in recent decades. The Eremoneura, Cyclorrhapha, Schizophora and Calyptrata are monophyletic, however the “Orthorrhapha” and “Aschiza” are paraphyletic, and it is likely that the “Acalyptrata” are also. Ongoing phylogenetic analyses that span the diversity of the order shall establish a robust phylogeny of the group with increased quantitative rigor. This will enable a more precise understanding of the evolution of the morphology, biogeography, biology, and physiology of flies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">relationships; evolution; taxonomy; molecular data; morphological data; flies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">relationships</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yeates</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wiegmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Greg</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Courtney</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudolf</firstname>
          <lastname>Meier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Pape</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Culicidae (Diptera): a review of taxonomy, classification and phylogeny</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy, classification and phylogeny of family Culicidae are reviewed. The application of explicit methods of phylogenetic analysis has revealed weaknesses in the traditional classification of mosquitoes, but little progress has been made to achieve a robust, stable classification that reflects evolutionary relationships. The current phenetic classification is discussed in view of phylogeny reconstructions based on cladistic analyses of morphological and molecular data. It is concluded that the generic and suprageneric relationships and the validity and monophyly of the generic and subgeneric groupings of Culicidae are in need of extensive reappraisal. If the classification is to reflect evolutionary history, changes to the nomenclature of mosquitoes are inevitable. There is strong morphological and molecular evidence that subfamily Anophelinae and tribes Aedini, Culicini and Sabethini of subfamily Culicinae are monophyletic, but the other taxonomic groupings are not demonstrably monophyletic or have not been subjected to phylogenetic analyses.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Culicidae; mosquitoes; taxonomy; classification; phylogeny; evolution; Anophelinae; Aedini; Culicini; Sabethini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Culicidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralph</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Harbach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Order Trichoptera Kirby 1813 (Insecta), Caddisflies</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy, diversity, and distribution of the aquatic insect order Trichoptera, caddisflies, are reviewed. The order is among the most important and diverse of all aquatic taxa. Larvae are vital participants in aquatic food webs and their presence and relative abundance are used in the biological assessment and monitoring of water quality. The species described by Linnaeus are listed. The morphology of all life history stages (adults, larvae, and pupae) is diagnosed and major features of the anatomy are illustrated. Major components of life history and biology are summarized. A discussion of phylogenetic studies within the order is presented, including higher classification of the suborders and superfamilies, based on recent literature. Synopses of each of 45 families are presented, including the taxonomic history of the family, a list of all known genera in each family, their general distribution and relative species diversity, and a short overview of family-level biological features. The order contains 600 genera, and approximately 13,000 species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; caddisflies; morphology; taxonomy; phylogeny; distribution; diversity; Linnaeus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralph</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holzenthal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Blahnik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aysha</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prather</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karl</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kjer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal"&gt;Phylum Echinodermata &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pawson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal"&gt;Index to authors &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Qiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
