<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3191.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Feb. 2012</title>
    <volume>3191</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of Chinese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes &lt;/i&gt;Ganglbauer, 1895 (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylininae) with description of two species new to science</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes&lt;/i&gt; Ganglbauer, 1895 that occur in the fauna of China are reviewed. &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;napoensis&lt;/i&gt;Yang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Guangxi and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xinqiaoensis&lt;/i&gt; Yang &amp; Zhou, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Fujian provinces ofChina. &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;callistus&lt;/i&gt; (Hochhuth, 1849) is recorded from China for the first time. Male genitalia and other taxo-nomically important characters are illustrated for both new and the following other Chinese species: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurosparsus&lt;/i&gt; (Fau-vel, 1895), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inauratus&lt;/i&gt; (Mannerheim, 1830), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murinus&lt;/i&gt; (Linné, 1758), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Sharp, 1874), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt;Bernhauer, 1906, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proximus&lt;/i&gt; Kirshenblat, 1936, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simulator&lt;/i&gt; Kirshenblat, 1936, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Kraatz, 1859) and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tessellatus&lt;/i&gt; (Geoffroy, 1785). An identification key to all species of &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes&lt;/i&gt; known from China is presented, and their geographical distribution in China is mapped.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Staphylinini; Staphylinina; &lt;i&gt;Ontholestes&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; China; new species; new record; geographic distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Staphylinini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhuo</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Zhang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Confirmation of &lt;i&gt;Aedes koreicus &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Culicidae) in Belgium and description of morphological differences between Korean and Belgian specimens validated by molecular identification</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In 2008, specimens resembling &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; (Finlaya) &lt;i&gt;koreicus&lt;/i&gt; (Edwards) (also &lt;i&gt;Ochlerotatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreicus&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Hulecoeteomyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kore-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ica)&lt;/i&gt; were found in Belgium during a national mosquito survey (MODIRISK). Small but consistent differences were, how-ever, observed between the specimens described from Peninsula Korea and those found in Belgian. To achieve the correctidentification a detailed morphological comparison was made between the Belgian specimens and reference material fromKorean mainland and island populations housed at the Smithsonian Institution (Walter Reed Biosystematics Unit (WR-BU), Washington, USA). The identification was furthermore supported by molecular evidence based on the ND4 region(mtDNA) of available Korean and Belgian mosquito specimens. Morphological and molecular comparison confirmed theinitial identification of &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreicus.&lt;/i&gt; Based on morphological characteristics, the species collected in Belgium mostlikely originated from Jeju-do, an island south of the Korean Peninsula. The observed dissimilarities between Korean andBelgian specimens resembled a number of morphological differences mentioned previously between female adults col-lected on the Korean Peninsula and Jeju-do. This is the first report of &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreicus&lt;/i&gt; outside its natural distribution range.A correct and rapid identification of new invading and spreading vector species is crucial for the implementation of effec-tive control measurements. Hence a correct and easy accessible description of all possible variations of species arrivingin new areas is highly recommended. Therefore, a comparative morphological study on the Smithsonian material of thespecies from Korean mainland, island population and from Belgium is given, pictures of the main aberrant characteristicsand scanning electron microscope images of all stages of the species are included and molecular confirmation of the identification based on the mtDNA ND4 region is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreicus&lt;/i&gt;; morphological comparison; egg structure; molecular identification; ND4; Republic of Korea; Belgium</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Veerle</firstname>
          <lastname>Versteirt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pecor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dina</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fonseca</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <lastname>Coosemans</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wim</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Bortel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-32</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pentapedilum &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer (Diptera: Chironomidae) in the Yaeyama Islands, the Ryukyus, Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As a result of a multi-year survey, we recognize three &lt;i&gt;Pentapedilum&lt;/i&gt; species, including a new species, from Iriomote Is-land, Japan. &lt;i&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/i&gt; (Pentapedilum) &lt;i&gt;acristylum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described as adult male, and compared with the closest &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt;(Pe.) &lt;i&gt;nodosum&lt;/i&gt; Johannsen, 1932.&lt;i&gt;Pentapedilum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iriodeeum&lt;/i&gt; Sasa &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki, 2000 is treated as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; (Tripodura) &lt;i&gt;tananense&lt;/i&gt; Sasa &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt;Hasegawa, 1988. Since the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Pentapedilum&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1913 defined solely by the presence of macrotrichia on thewing membrane may not be enough to support monophyly, we suggest the possibility that species with wing macrotrichiarestricted to the extreme tips of the membrane, like &lt;i&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/i&gt; (Pentapedilum) &lt;i&gt;tigrinum&lt;/i&gt; (Hashimoto, 1983), may be placed in the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer, 1912.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chironomidae; &lt;i&gt;Pentapedilum&lt;/i&gt;; new species; monophyly; Iriomote Island; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nao</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamamoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Toshiya</firstname>
          <lastname>Hirowatari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masaru</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamamoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Trigonidiinae crickets from Rodrigues island: from widespread pantropical species to critically endangered endemic species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Trigonidiinae crickets of Rodrigues are examined. Two species widespread in South Western Indian Ocean islandsare recorded in Rodrigues for the first time: &lt;i&gt;Trigonidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cicindeloides&lt;/i&gt; Rambur, 1839 and &lt;i&gt;Natula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Serville,1839). &lt;i&gt;Nemobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteolus&lt;/i&gt; Butler, 1876 is a Trigonidiinae and not a Nemobiinae, it is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Metioche&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1877 as&lt;i&gt;Metioche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteolus&lt;/i&gt; (Butler, 1876), &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; Two new species are described from the restored areas of the island. Thesenew species are tentatively considered as &lt;i&gt;Metioche&lt;/i&gt; and included in the new subgenus &lt;i&gt;Superstes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subgen.:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Metioche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Su-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;perstes)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subgen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Metioche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Superstes)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;payendeei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subgen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; This new subgenus is charac-terized by the male genitalia asymmetry and the striking hyperthely of the left pseudepiphallic lophi and paramere. Elements of the ecology of endemic Trigonidiinae of Rodrigues are given, and their conservation status is assessed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Mascarene; endemism; conservation; asymmetry; sword-tail cricket</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sylvain</firstname>
          <lastname>Hugel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of soft-winged flower beetles of the genus &lt;i&gt;Kuatunia &lt;/i&gt;Evers, 1945–48 (Coleoptera, Malachiidae) from China and northeastern Russia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new malachiid beetle species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Kuatunia&lt;/i&gt; Evers are described: &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nordica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from Taimyr peninsula,northeastern Russia, and &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wolongensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from China, Wolong Nature Reserve. Figures of male habiti, elytral ap-pendices, genitalia, and a distribution map for newly recorded species are given, and a determination key to all species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Malachiidae; &lt;i&gt;Kuatunia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new locality; China; Yakutia; Taimyr; Russia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergei</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tshernyshev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-64</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Quwatanabius &lt;/i&gt;Smetana—a new genus in the fauna of the Mainland China (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae), with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jiayao</firstname>
          <lastname>Hu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lizhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Meijun</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
