<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3192.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Feb. 2012</title>
    <volume>3192</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new deep-bodied fossil fish (Actinopterygii) from the Rio do Rasto Formation, Paraná Basin, Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fossil fishes from the Paraná Basin are represented by actinopterygians, chondrichthyans, coelacanths and dipnoans. This diverseichthyofauna comprises mainly fragmentary material with few complete specimens. This paper presents a new Upper Permianray-finned fish from the Rio do Rasto Formation of the Paraná Basin, southern Brazil. The holotype and only known specimen of&lt;i&gt;Paranaichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longianalis&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. et sp. nov. is an almost complete poorly preserved specimen of a deep-bodied fish that be-longs to the collection of the Museu de Ciências e Tecnologia-PUCRS, Porto Alegre, Brazil. The head is slightly deep posteriorlyand the oral cavity presents a crushing dentition. The anal fin is remarkably large and long. The heterocercal caudal fin presentsthe chordal and hypochordal lobe equally in size. Flank scales are deeper than long and covered with ganoine. The dermal bonesare also covered by ganoine and present elongated odontodes. The rostral region and the anterior portion of the mandible are cov-ered with conical odontodes. The elongated and long based anal fin is considered apomorphic for this new fish. A reconstructionattempting to correct taphonomic distortions is presented. The systematic relationships of the new taxon suggest that it is relatedto the platysomids. Its crushing dentition indicates a diet based on hardfood, such as conchostraceans and small mollusks, bothvery common in the Rio do Rasto Formation. The new genus and species inhabited rivers and lakes during the Wordian-Captanian (Guadalupian, Permian 268 to 260 M.y.).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Permian; Guadalupian; crushing dentition; Platysomidae; freshwater; Serrinha Member</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Permian</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eliseu</firstname>
          <middlename>Vieira</middlename>
          <lastname>Dias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Postispinatus youngi &lt;/i&gt;n. gen., n. sp. (Apseudomorpha; Tanaidacea; Crustacea): phylogenetic analysis and taxonomic remarks about kalliapseudids </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The presence of setae or a sensorial structure on the dactylus of pereopod 1 as one of the defining features of the familyKalliapseudidae is re-evaluated. A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Postispinatus,&lt;/i&gt; including the new species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; isdescribed and thought to belong to the Kalliapseudidae based on phylogenetic analysis. The diagnostic features of newgenus—and species by monotypy —are: basal article of uropod with two curved spiniform processes; exopods on the fourth and fifth pereopods of the manca stage; absence of a maxillule palp.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Postispinatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi&lt;/i&gt;; Kalliapseudidae; Brazil; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Postispinatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kátia</firstname>
          <middlename>Christol Dos</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <lastname>Santana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria Setubal</middlename>
          <lastname>Pires-Vanin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-38</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Strabomantidae) from Andean cloud forests of northern Peru </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; from cloud forests of the eastern versant of the Andes in northern Peru. Thetype locality lies in Quebrada del Vino, Provincia San Ignacio, Departamento Cajamarca, Peru. The new species is mostsimilar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crucifer,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eriphus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavobracatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucorrhinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucasi,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vilcabambae,&lt;/i&gt; with which it shares thepresence of large conical eyelid tubercles, ulnar tubercles, and heel and tarsal tubercles as well as flash colours on the groinsurrounded by bold black stripes and white stripes. The new species can nonetheless be distinguished from all of them by,having tympanic membrane and annulus, by males having nuptial pads and vocal slits, and by having finger discs scarcely enlarged and truncated with ungual flap not indented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; new species; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crucifer&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eriphus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavobracatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucorrhinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucasi&lt;/i&gt;; Terrarana</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chaparro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Motta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gutiérrez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and record of Serpulidae (Annelida: Polychaeta) from Cross Seamount in the Hawaiian Chain </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the serpulid genus &lt;i&gt;Metavermilia&lt;/i&gt; Bush, 1905 and a new record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Omphalopomopsis&lt;/i&gt; Saint-Joseph, 1894 are described from deep-sea lava rocks collected from 2,013 m at Cross Seamount, southwest of the Hawaiiarchipelago. &lt;i&gt;Metavermilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zibrowii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; differs from its congeners mostly by the presence of a simple and concaveoperculum, extent of the thoracic membrane and tube morphology. &lt;i&gt;Omphalopomopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langerhansii&lt;/i&gt; (Marenzeller, 1885)is the type species of the genus and it is only known through its type specimen. This species is characterized by a simpleoperculum with a shallow convex calcareous endplate, cylindrical peduncle, presence of &lt;i&gt;Apomatus&lt;/i&gt; chaetae and high num-ber of teeth in the thoracic uncini. This is the first record of this species outside the type locality and both genera are newly recorded for the Hawaiian Islands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">serpulids; &lt;i&gt;Metavermilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zibrowii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Omphalopomopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langerhansii&lt;/i&gt;; deep-sea; seamount; lava rocks</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">serpulids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julie</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bailey-Brock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wagner</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Magalhães</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Aculops &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Prostigmata: Eriophyidae) from Serbia on &lt;i&gt;Dipsacus laciniatus &lt;/i&gt;L. (Dipsacaceae), a weed target of classical biological control in the United States of America BRIAN G. RECTOR (USA) &amp; RADMILA U. PETANOVIĆ (Serbia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola ternetzi &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Leiuperidae): two lectotypes for the same taxon </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dario</firstname>
          <lastname>Cardozo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Baldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
