<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3220.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Mar. 2012</title>
    <volume>3220</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-03-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of the Castelo dos Sonhos Hantavirus reservoir, &lt;i&gt;Oligoryzomys utiaritensis &lt;/i&gt;Allen 1916 (Rodentia: Cricetidae: Sigmodontinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Oligoryzomys&lt;/i&gt; are commonly found accross Latin America, and several of them play important rolesas natural reservoirs of Hantaviruses. Here we demonstrate that &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utiaritensis,&lt;/i&gt; the natural reservoir of hantavirus Castelodos Sonhos in northwestwern Brazil and previously considered a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripes&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eliurus,&lt;/i&gt; is a validspecies. Morphology, morphometry, karyotyping, and phylogenetic reconstructions based on nuclear (intron 7 of the beta-fibrinogen gene) and mitochondrial (cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; DNA show that &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utiaritensis&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripes&lt;/i&gt; and from otherforms of the genus, including the recently described taxon &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moojeni.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oligoryzomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utiaritensis&lt;/i&gt; differs in external (whit-ish ventral pelage and tail weakly bicolored) and cranial (incisive foramina never extending posteriorly the alveolus lineof M1) characters from sympatric species. It has the highest diploid number (2n=72) within &lt;i&gt;Oligoryzomys,&lt;/i&gt; and is charac-terized by three putative synapomorphies in cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b,&lt;/i&gt; and one in intron 7 of beta fibrinogen. We also point to theassignment of &lt;i&gt;Oligoryzomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eliurus&lt;/i&gt; as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripes.&lt;/i&gt; Finally, we present phylogenetic analyses of in-trageneric relationships showing that &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utiaritensis&lt;/i&gt; is a member of a clade containing Amazonian and Cerrado taxa, including &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moojeni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rupestris,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delicatus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">pygmy rice rat; hantaviruses; South America; phylogeny; cytocrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; intron 7 beta fibrinogen; karyotype; morphometrics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">pygmy rice rat</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <lastname>Agrellos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cibele</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonvicino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <middlename>Salbé T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rosa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aparecido</firstname>
          <middlename>A. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>D’Andrea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Weksler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the giant pill-millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum &lt;/i&gt;Verhoeff, 1924 from northern Thailand, with an extensive description and molecular characters (Diplopoda: Sphaerotheriida: Zephroniidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As a first step towards an inventory of the giant pill-millipedes in Thailand, a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt;Verhoeff, 1924, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Nan Province, northern Thailand. A determination key is presentedfor all five known &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; species. Clear morphological differences between &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and the other four&lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; species were found on the anterior telopods. For the first time in &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum,&lt;/i&gt; the partial mitochondrialCOI gene was sequenced for &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and compared with distance, maximum parsimony and maximum likeli-hood methods to those of species from other giant pill-millipede genera. &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was found to dif-fer from all other analyzed giant pill-millipedes, including species of &lt;i&gt;Zephronia&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1832, by 22–30%, includingnumerous amino acid changes, supporting the separate status of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; among other giant pill-millipede genera.Maximum likelihood and parsimony analyses support the placement of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; in the Zephroniidae. Figures of allrelevant structures of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobelum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are provided to allow the use of these characters in future descriptions of species of the family Zephroniidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">giant pill-millipede; new species; arthropod; taxonomy; Thailand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">giant pill-millipede</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nattarin</firstname>
          <lastname>Wongthamwanich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Somsak</firstname>
          <lastname>Panha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petra</firstname>
          <lastname>Sierwald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Wesener</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kumthorn</firstname>
          <lastname>Thirakhupt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-43</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new cryptic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Anura: Eleutherodactylidae) from Cuba </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The widely distributed grass frog of Cuba, &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;varleyi,&lt;/i&gt; is shown here to comprise two species. One, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;var-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;leyi,&lt;/i&gt; occurs in western and central Cuba while the other, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feichtingeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; occurs in central and eastern Cuba. The twospecies are sympatric in central Cuba, and syntopic in the vicinity of Sierra de Cubitas, Camagüey Province. A molecularphylogeny of mitochondrial DNA sequences from 18 localities confirms the existence of two well-supported major cladescorresponding to each of these species, and the sympatry of the species. Tympanum size and advertisement call are themost useful diagnostic characters, although the two species are shown to have karyotypic differences as well. Possible character displacement in morphology and vocalization, in the area of sympatry, is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caribbean; West Indies; Terrarana; &lt;i&gt;Euhyas&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; phylogeny; bioacoustics; chromosomes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caribbean</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Díaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Blair</middlename>
          <lastname>Hedges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>44-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Brachyura described by the Australian carcinologist William Aitcheson Haswell: checklist, dates of publication and bibliography (Crustacea: Decapoda) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martyn</firstname>
          <middlename>E. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Low</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-64</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
