<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3223.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Mar. 2012</title>
    <volume>3223</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis spangleri &lt;/i&gt;a new species from Churí-tepui (Chimantá Massif, Venezuela), with a description of the larva of &lt;i&gt;J. spangleri &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;J. reitmaieri &lt;/i&gt;(Insecta: Coleoptera: Elmidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species have been recognized in the genus &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis&lt;/i&gt; Spangler &amp; Faitoute; all collected at isolated table mountains,mostly in cool stenothermal hypocrenal streams. The known distribution of the genus is confined to Venezuela, and eachspecies is here reported as endemic for the respective table mountain where it has been found. Samples from Churí-tepuiand Mount Roraima in south-eastern Venezuela contained numerous adults and larvae of Elmidae among which is a newspecies, &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spangleri,&lt;/i&gt; which is here described. The new species is illustrated and keyed with all other &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis,&lt;/i&gt;and new distributional data for &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reitmaieri&lt;/i&gt;Čiampor, Jr. &amp; Kodada are included. Molecular analysis of partial cytochromeoxidase subunit I (cox1) confirmed conspecific life stages for two species: &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spangleri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;J.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reitmaieri.&lt;/i&gt; The larva of eachspecies is described and illustrated, and the generic diagnosis for &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis&lt;/i&gt; larvae is provided. Among the known larvaeof South American Elmidae, larvae of the genus &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt; Hinton appear to be the most similar. Morphological similarities are discussed. Habitats of adults and larvae are briefly described and illustrated by photographs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Elmidae; &lt;i&gt;Jolyelmis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; larva; Venezuela; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ján</firstname>
          <lastname>Kodada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tomáš</firstname>
          <lastname>Derka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fedor</firstname>
          <lastname>Čiampor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the fruit fly genus &lt;i&gt;Neoceratitis &lt;/i&gt;Hendel (Diptera: Tephritidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neoceratitis&lt;/i&gt; is revised to include six species. &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albiseta,&lt;/i&gt; from Madagascar, is described as new. &lt;i&gt;Trirhithrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lycii&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;min-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;imum&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi, 1924 is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Ceratitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lycii&lt;/i&gt; Coquillett, 1901, new synonym. All known and suspected hostassociations are within the family Solanaceae, with one species (N. &lt;i&gt;cyanescens)&lt;/i&gt; infesting tomatoes and several species of&lt;i&gt;Solanum,&lt;/i&gt; whereas the other species with known hosts are associated with &lt;i&gt;Lycium&lt;/i&gt; spp. &lt;i&gt;Neoceratitis&lt;/i&gt; is probably similar to&lt;i&gt;Trirhithrum&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi and particularly to the little known &lt;i&gt;Paratrirhithrum&lt;/i&gt; Shiraki. Redescriptions (description in the case of the new species) and illustrations are provided for all the species, and a key to all the species is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fruit flies; &lt;i&gt;Neoceratitis&lt;/i&gt;; Ceratitidina; Afrotropical; Palaearctic; Oriental</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fruit flies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <lastname>De Meyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Amnon</firstname>
          <lastname>Freidberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-39</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contribution to the knowledge of Agrypninae (Coleoptera: Elateridae) with description of new species and new records from Pakistan </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Thirty-two species, belonging to ten genera are listed in this work, including eight species newly recorded from the coun-try. The study is based upon material collected in Pakistan between 2004–2010. The genus &lt;i&gt;Cryptalaus&lt;/i&gt; Ohira is recordedfrom Pakistan for the first time. Two species &lt;i&gt;Cryptalaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tamargrahensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dadarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; are de-scribed as new and a key to the Pakistani species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Agrypnus&lt;/i&gt; Eschscholtz, &lt;i&gt;Lanelater&lt;/i&gt; Arnett, &lt;i&gt;Drasterius&lt;/i&gt; Eschscholtz and &lt;i&gt;Heteroderes&lt;/i&gt; Latreille are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Elateridae; Agrypninae; new species; new records; Pakistan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Muhammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Atique</middlename>
          <lastname>Akhter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Drumont</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Syed</firstname>
          <middlename>Anser</middlename>
          <lastname>Rizvi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zubair</firstname>
          <lastname>Ahmed</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-54</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydroporus sejilashan &lt;/i&gt;sp. n., a new diving beetle of the &lt;i&gt;acutangulus&lt;/i&gt;-complex from Xizang, China (Qinghai-Tibet Plateau), and notes on other taxa of the genus (Coleoptera, Dytiscidae, Hydroporinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sejilashan&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is described from Xizang Autonomous Region (Qinghai-Tibet Plateau), China. It belongs tothe &lt;i&gt;acutangulus-complex&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;planus-group&lt;/i&gt; and can be separated from all four other members of the speciescomplex by the completely distinctly matt surface in both sexes. In addition it can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;acutangulus&lt;/i&gt; Thomson, 1856 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polaris&lt;/i&gt; Fall, 1923 by the shape of the anterior protarsal claw, which is strongly curvednear the base and more straight distally in the latter two species, but evenly curved in the new species and in the other twospecies of the complex, namely &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetanus&lt;/i&gt; Zaitzev, 1953 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuvaensis&lt;/i&gt; Pederzani, 2001. The habitus of all fivemembers of the complex are provided, along with illustrations of the male and female genitalia of the new species andthose of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetanus.&lt;/i&gt; The lectotype of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumakovi&lt;/i&gt; Poppius, 1912, a taxon which until now has been treated as a juniorsynonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutangulus,&lt;/i&gt; is designated. Preliminary studies reveal that &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumakovi&lt;/i&gt; is probably more closely relatedto &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polaris&lt;/i&gt; than to &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutangulus.&lt;/i&gt; Older, doubtful previous records of &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigellus&lt;/i&gt; Mannerheim, 1853 fromChina are confirmed with new records from Qinghai and Sichuan Provinces. Twelve species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; Clairville, 1806 are now known from China, only two of which occur in Tibet.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; Hydroporinae; &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutangulus-complex&lt;/i&gt;; new species; lectotype; first record; China; Tibet</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fenglong</firstname>
          <lastname>Jia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuang</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <lastname>Fery</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: SCHMIDT, S (2012) Revision of the Australian sawfly genus &lt;i&gt;Antargidium &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera, Symphyta, Argidae) with description of two new species. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3180, 47–56. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
