<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3237.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Mar. 2012</title>
    <volume>3237</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-03-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Heterothrips &lt;/i&gt;(Thysanoptera) in Brazil, with an identification key and seven new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven new species of &lt;i&gt;Heterothrips&lt;/i&gt; are described from Brazil, and a key presented to the 20 species now known from thiscountry. &lt;i&gt;Heterothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semiflavus&lt;/i&gt; De Santis is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; Hood. The new species are illustrated and notes on their biology included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; Heterothripidae; host specificity; Terebrantia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Veronica</firstname>
          <lastname>Pereyra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <lastname>Cavalleri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Polymorphism in &lt;i&gt;Languria taedata &lt;/i&gt;LeConte, its occurrence in coastal Louisiana &lt;i&gt;Spartina &lt;/i&gt;marshes, and clarification of some Motschulsky languriine types (Coleoptera: Erotylidae: Languriinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We clarify the diagnosis and geographic distribution of the widespread, variable eastern coastal species &lt;i&gt;Languria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taedata&lt;/i&gt;LeConte, 1854, in North America. After examining types and the range of variation and geographical distribution of thespecies, we propose synonymy of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; Blatchley, 1924, with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taedata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonymy.&lt;/b&gt; We report the dis-covery of an all-piceous form (“Form C”), the first of the genus, found primarily along the western Gulf Coast of the Unit-ed States. The recognition of this form requires a modification to the most recent key to North American genera ofLanguriinae. The larvae of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taedata&lt;/i&gt; feed within the stems of &lt;i&gt;Spartina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alterniflora&lt;/i&gt; Loisel (Poaceae). We provide addi-tional notes on the occurrence of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taedata&lt;/i&gt; in coastal marshes in Louisiana. The types of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apicalis&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ni-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;griceps&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufiventris&lt;/i&gt; are reexamined. A revised synonymic checklist is provided for North American Languriini.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cucujoidea; Languriidae; &lt;i&gt;Dasydactylus&lt;/i&gt;; marsh; smooth cordgrass; wetlands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cucujoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gimmel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carlton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>White</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-34</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and description of &lt;i&gt;Eknomia&lt;/i&gt;, a morphologically unusual new genus of Neotropical Cryptinae (Hymenoptera, Ichneumonidae), with three new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Cryptini &lt;i&gt;Eknomia&lt;/i&gt; Santos &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Aguiar &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed, described, and cladistically compared with representativespecies of 40 outgroup genera from twelve cryptine subtribes. A total of 98 morphological characters were evaluated. Allanalyses, conducted in TNT under implied and equal weighting, clearly suggest that &lt;i&gt;Eknomia&lt;/i&gt; is a monophyletic groupand can be treated as a distinct genus. Its likely sister group, however, varied among different analyses and could not beascertained. The relationships of the new genus are therefore unclear, and because of this it is not assigned to any of thecurrently recognized subtribes. &lt;i&gt;Eknomia&lt;/i&gt; can be diagnosed mainly by the anterior transverse carina of propodeum entirelyabsent; propodeum more or less uniformly strigate; clypeus almost entirely flattened; ovipositor stout, with compressed,minutely serrate flange at apex of dorsal valve, subapically crossed by a subvertical line; first metasomal spiracle placedat tergite midlength or nearly so; and hind margin of metanotum with tooth-like projections. The species &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigra&lt;/i&gt; Santos&lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Aguiar, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubra&lt;/i&gt; Santos &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Aguiar, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;propodeator&lt;/i&gt; Santos &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Aguiar, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated. The genus is recorded from Colombia to southern Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phygadeuontinae; Cryptini; implied weighting; pan traps</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phygadeuontinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bernardo</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Aguiar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy and nomenclature of &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus flavicollis &lt;/i&gt;Westwood—type species of the type genus of the Enicocephalidae (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Enicocephalomorpha) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The status and location of the type series of &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavicollis&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1837 (type species of &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus&lt;/i&gt;Westwood, 1837, the type genus of Enicocephalidae) from St. Vincent Island (Lesser Antilles) is discussed, and insteadof two formerly assumed different ‘holotypes’ the lectotype and paralectotype are designated. Males of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavicollis&lt;/i&gt; areredescribed, the 5th instar larva is described for the first time, and diagnostic characters of the species are reviewed. Spe-cies of &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus&lt;/i&gt; are listed and pterygopolymorphism of females is reviewed. &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dominica&lt;/i&gt; Bruner, 1924 is a correct original spelling of the species name (not &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dominicus&lt;/i&gt; nor &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dominicanus).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Enicocephalomorpha; Enicocephalidae; &lt;i&gt;Enicocephalus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavicollis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; redescription; larva; nomenclature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pavel</firstname>
          <lastname>Štys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petr</firstname>
          <lastname>Baňař</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
