<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3253.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Apr. 2012</title>
    <volume>3253</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-04-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of Norwegian streptaster-bearing Astrophorida (Porifera: &lt;i&gt;Demospongiae&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;i&gt;Tetractinellida&lt;/i&gt;), new records and a new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We report and describe new material of streptaster-bearing Astrophorida sponges collected in Norway: &lt;i&gt;Characella&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pachastrelloides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodulosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Poecillastra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Vulcanella&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;aberrans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssorum,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muricata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valdiviae.&lt;/i&gt; Because many of these species were described in the end of the 19thcentury their original descriptions are often incomplete. The Norwegian specimens are the basis for a revision of themorphology, taxonomy and distribution of these species. These are the first records of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachastrelloides&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; cf.&lt;i&gt;aberrans&lt;/i&gt; from the Norwegian coast. &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodulosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monilifera&lt;/i&gt; by (i) its knobbysurface and (ii) the absence of large oxeas, (iii) its amphiasters have on average less actines and are less spiny, finally (iv)microxeas are rare and with a distinct morphology (although there is some doubt concerning their origin). In the presentstudy, &lt;i&gt;Characella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosa&lt;/i&gt; (from South Africa), &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssi&lt;/i&gt; (from the North-West Atlantic) and &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt;(from the North-East Atlantic) are resurrected. To help their future identifications, all the Norwegian species describedwere associated with DNA barcodes: a cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase subunit I (COI) gene partial fragment and/or a 28S ribosomalgene partial fragment (C1–D2 domains). Furthermore, a key to the streptaster-bearing Astrophorida of the North-East Atlantic and the Mediterranean Sea is also given (lithistids not included).Nous signalons la présence et décrivons des spécimens d’Astrophorida à streptasters nouvellement récoltés en Norvège:&lt;i&gt;Characella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachastrelloides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodulosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Poecillastra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Vulcanella&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;aberrans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;abyssorum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muricata&lt;/i&gt; et &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valdiviae.&lt;/i&gt; Plusieurs de ces espèces ont été décrites de manièreincomplète à la fin du 19ème siècle. Les spécimens norvégiens sont l’occasion de réviser la morphologie, la taxonomie etla distribution de ces espèces. C’est la première fois que &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachastrelloides&lt;/i&gt; et &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;aberrans&lt;/i&gt; sont mentionnés sur la côtenorvégienne. &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nodulosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; se distingue de &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monilifera&lt;/i&gt; par (i) sa surface noduleuse et (ii)l’absence de grands oxes, (iii) ses amphiasters ont en moyenne moins d’actines et sont moins épineux, enfin (iv) lesmicroxes sont rares et ont une morphologie distincte (bien qu’il y ait encore des doutes sur leur origine). Au cours de notreétude, &lt;i&gt;Characella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosa&lt;/i&gt; (d’Afrique du Sud), &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssi&lt;/i&gt; (de l’Atlantique Nord-Ouest) et &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; (del’Atlantique Nord-Est) sont ressuscités. Afin d’aider leurs identifications futures, toutes les espèces de Norvège décritesont été associées à des code-barres moléculaires: un fragment partiel du gène de la sous-unité I du cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxydase(COI) et/ou un fragment partiel du gène ribosomique 28S (domaines C1-D2). De plus, une clé pour identifier les Astrophorida à streptasters de l’Atlantique Nord-Est et de Méditerrannée est également fournie (lithistides non inclus).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Characella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Poecillastra&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pachastrella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Vulcanella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thenea&lt;/i&gt;; Pachastrellidae; DNA barcodes; Norway; cosmopolitanism.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paco</firstname>
          <lastname>Cárdenas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <middlename>Tore</middlename>
          <lastname>Rapp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-53</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new feather mite species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Proctophyllodes &lt;/i&gt;Robin, 1877 (Astigmata: Proctophyllodidae) from the Long-tailed Tit &lt;i&gt;Aegithalos caudatus &lt;/i&gt;(Passeriformes: Aegithalidae)—morphological description with DNA barcode data </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new feather mites species, &lt;i&gt;Proctophyllodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valchukae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Long-tailed Tit, &lt;i&gt;Aegithalos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudatus&lt;/i&gt;(Linnaeus, 1758) (Passeriformes: Aegithalidae), captured in the Primoriye (Russian Far East). The new species belongsto the &lt;i&gt;tricetratus&lt;/i&gt; species group and is most closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stachyris&lt;/i&gt; Atyeo et Braasch, 1966. For the first time forfeather mites the standard morphological description is supplemented by sequence data of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase subunit I gene fragment (COI) and nuclear D2 region of 28S rDNA.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Astigmata; feather mites; Proctophyllodidae; new species; DNA barcoding; COI; D2; 28S rRNA; nondestructive DNA extraction</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Astigmata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergey</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mironov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jacek</firstname>
          <lastname>Dabert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miroslawa</firstname>
          <lastname>Dabert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-61</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of frogfish of the genus &lt;i&gt;Histiophryne &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Lophiiformes: Antennariidae) from Lombok and Komodo, Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Histiophryne&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pogonius,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of frogfish of the teleost order Lophiiformes, family Antennariidae, is describedfrom a total of five specimens: three collected in shallow waters surrounding Lombok, Indonesia, one reportedly from thenearshore waters of Cebu, Philippines, and a photograph of a specimen from Komodo Island, Indonesia. The new taxondiffers from its congeners in having an extremely small illicium and esca, barely discernible even with aid of a dissectingmicroscope; dark pink pigmentation overlaying a pale pink background, including a dark pink basidorsal spot; a smallwhite encrusted patch of skin always present posterior to pectoral-fin origin, with similar patches sometimes present oncheeks; body everywhere covered with small dark reddish to black spots, including lips and outer margins of the sclera,spots encircled by a thin white ring; cheeks with shallow depressions, giving head a pitted appearance; head lightlycovered with cutaneous cirri, especially around edges of opercle; upper and lower lips with short cutaneous cirri; andgenetic divergence in mitochondrial gene cytochrome oxidase &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; subunit I (COI). The new species is described andcompared with its congeners, and a phylogenetic tree based on the nuclear recombination activation gene-2 (RAG2) and mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; subunit I (COI) and 16S genes is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Teleostei; Lophiiformes; Antennarioidei; Antennariidae; &lt;i&gt;Histiophryne&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;pogonius&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; marine; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Teleostei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rachel</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
