<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3258.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Apr. 2012</title>
    <volume>3258</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the Lake Malaŵi genus &lt;i&gt;Melanochromis &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cichlidae) with a description of a new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Lake Malaŵi genus &lt;i&gt;Melanochromis&lt;/i&gt; included five species at its inception and was originally distinguished from&lt;i&gt;Pseudotropheus&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of morphology, including the arrangement of teeth on the lower pharyngeal bone. Thediagnosis has been extended twice, first to include all elongate mbuna that possess horizontal stripes and U-shaped toothbands and later to exclude mbuna that do not exhibit a sex-related reversal in their colour pattern. Recently, the diagnosisof the genus was refined on the basis of the melanin pattern. The genus now includes only species with a basic melaninpattern, which consists of two black horizontal lateral stripes on a light background. Most adult members of the genus,thus defined, have a sex-related reversal of pigmentation pattern. Here we describe &lt;i&gt;Melanochromis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mpoto&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from thenorthwestern part of Lake Malawi, synonymize &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parallelus&lt;/i&gt; Burgess &amp; Axelrod 1976 with &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loriae&lt;/i&gt; Johnson 1975,redescribe &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chipokae&lt;/i&gt; Johnson 1975 and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; Johnson 1985, and reclassify and designate a lectotype for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevis&lt;/i&gt; Trewavas, 1935.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cichlid; mbuna; melanin pattern</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cichlid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adrianus</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Konings</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jay</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stauffer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Botrylloides pizoni&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Botryllinae (Ascidiacea) from the Mediterranean Sea R. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new ascidian species belonging to the Botryllinae was discovered in the Gulf of Taranto (South Italy). This new species wascollected in different seasons over a period of several years, which allowed information about its biology to be obtained. Thenew species presents large zooids arranged in ladder systems. The zooids have several rows of stigmata, the second one com-plete, ovary posterior to testis, one larva per side developing in an incubatory pouch, and a peculiar arrangement of the gut loop. The new species is named &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pizoni&lt;/i&gt; after the great French zoologist Antoine Pizon (1860–1942).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tunicata; Ascidiacea; Botryllinae; &lt;i&gt;Botrylloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pizoni&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; Mediterranean Sea; South Italy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tunicata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Brunetti</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mastrototaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>28-36</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chaca serica&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of frogmouth catfish (Teleostei: Siluriformes) from southern Borneo </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chaca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serica,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of frogmouth catfish from the Kahayan, Kapuas and Mentaya river drainages in southernBorneo, is described here. It can be distinguished from congeners in having the following combination of characters: theoral margin of the lower lip lacking (vs. having) a series of rugose ridges, presence of nasal barbels, presence of papillaearound the eyes, a temporal fossa extending to the supraoccipital, 7–8 serrae on the anterior edge of the pectoral spine,four pectoral-fin rays, absence of a row of fimbriate skin flaps on the body dorsal to (and sometimes also ventral to) the lateral line, dorsal procurrent caudal-ray base 32.8–37.3% SL, and ventral procurrent caudal-ray base 16.0–19.2% SL.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chacidae; Kalimantan Tengah</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chacidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maurice</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-45</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">One new and two known species of Dorylaimoidea (Nematoda) from West Bengal, India </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Small populations of &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus&lt;/i&gt; Baqri &amp; Jana, 1982 and &lt;i&gt;Dorylaimus&lt;/i&gt; sp. were collected fromthe soil around the roots of guava at south 24-Parganas district, West Bengal, India. &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is characterizedby its odontostyle being distinctly thicker than the cuticle at the same level, cardia shape: rounded-conoid, wide at pharyngo-intestinal junction, enveloped by intestinal tissue which forms a conical projection extending into the lumen of intestine;delicate ring-like structure between the pharyngeal base and the proper cardia. &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. comes close to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;multialaeus&lt;/i&gt; (Khera, 1970) Baqri, 1985, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siddiqii&lt;/i&gt; Baqri &amp; Jana, 1982 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus&lt;/i&gt; Baqri &amp; Jana, 1982, but can bedistinguished from these species on the basis of different morphometric measurements. The new species differs from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;multialaeus&lt;/i&gt; in having higher &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; value, lower &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; value and longer odontostyle in females, and. longer body, lateral guiding piecesand tail in males. From &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siddiqii&lt;/i&gt; the new species differs in having a shorter tail in relation to body length, shorter cardia withdifferent shape, shorter prerectum and longer rectum in female, different number of ventromedian supplements and shorterspicules in males. From &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus,&lt;/i&gt; it differs in having a longer body, greater &lt;i&gt;a-value,&lt;/i&gt; longer odontostyle and odontophore andlonger tail in females. &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. differs from the males of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus&lt;/i&gt; by its longer body, greater &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; value and in thenumber of ventromedian supplements. The population of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus&lt;/i&gt; from West Bengal agrees well with the original descriptionexcept for some variations in body, odontophore, prerectum and tail length. New data on male characters have been provided inthe present study. The specimens of &lt;i&gt;Dorylaimus&lt;/i&gt; sp. come close to &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geraerti&lt;/i&gt; Baqri &amp; Jana, 1986 except in some morphometricmeasurements including: &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; (4.2–5.1 vs. 4.3–4.7), odontophore length (33–54 μm vs. 40–43 μm, prerectum length in females(120–160 μm vs. 196–241 μm and tail length in females (247.5–294 μm vs. 249–406 μm). In males, the supplements (36 innumber) occur in a contiguous series (as is usually seen in the genus &lt;i&gt;Dorylaimus&lt;/i&gt; Dujardin, 1845), whereas in the typespecimens of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geraerti&lt;/i&gt; 35–38 supplements are largely contiguous except for a set of 4–5 spaced supplements in the middle of the series, showing a resemblance with the genus &lt;i&gt;Ischiodorylaimus&lt;/i&gt; Andrássy, 1969.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; &lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baldus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dorylaimus&lt;/i&gt; sp.; description; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Laimydorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;istvani&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Debabrata</firstname>
          <lastname>Sen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Amalendu</firstname>
          <lastname>Chatterjee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Buddhadeb</firstname>
          <lastname>Manna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-57</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Pill Millipedes from North America, with a comparison of genetic distances of American Pill Millipede Genera (Glomerida, Glomeridae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of the pill millipede order Glomerida, &lt;b&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;inexpectata&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; is describedfrom the Eastern United States. The description of &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; brings the total number of American Glomerida generato three. In two of three known localitites, &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; co-occurs with species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Onomeris&lt;/i&gt; Cook, 1896.&lt;i&gt;Onomeris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; have almost an identical size (4–5.5 mm) and dark colour, but can be readily distingusihedby numerous non-sexual and sexual characters. Sexual characters of the male telopod also place &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; into thefamily Glomeridae, while the third American pill millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Glomeroides&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1922 belongs to theProtoglomeridae. A key to all American genera of Glomerida is presented. For the first time in the order Glomerida, thepartial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase I mitochondrial gene was analyzed for the three American genera of the Glomerida,&lt;i&gt;Glomeroides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Onomeris,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; together with European genera currently placed in different families,&lt;i&gt;Glomeridella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Trachysphaera,&lt;/i&gt; as outgroups. Distance, maximum parsimony and maximum likelihood methods wereemployed. Maximum parsimony and likelihood analyses did not lead to a well-resolved phylogeny, but found a weaklysupported sister-group relationship between &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Onomeris.&lt;/i&gt; All five analyzed pill millipede genera differgreatly in their uncorrected basepairs (15–22%), and moderately in their amino acids (5–10%). As in &lt;i&gt;Onomeris,&lt;/i&gt; the closestrelative of &lt;i&gt;Nearctomeris&lt;/i&gt; can probably be found among the Asian genera &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1910 or &lt;i&gt;Hyperglomeris&lt;/i&gt; Silvestri, 1917. In America, more attention should be given to the search for other small-bodied, cryptic, rare Glomerida.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">soil arthropod; Glomerida; U.S.A.; systematics; barcoding; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase I gene</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">soil arthropod</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Wesener</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
