<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3271.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Apr. 2012</title>
    <volume>3271</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new frog species (Microhylidae: &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt;) from the Australian Wet Tropics region, and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus ornatus &lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In Australia the frog family Microhylidae is largely restricted to tropical rainforests of the Wet Tropics region in the north-east of the country, but in that region the family is diverse. Only one species, &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus,&lt;/i&gt; is widespread in the WetTropics but there has been suspicion that it may comprise multiple species. A recent study (Hoskin &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2011) assessedgenetic and phenotypic variation across the range of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus,&lt;/i&gt; finding three deeply divergent genetic lineages that differin mating call and some aspects of morphology. Two of these lineages abutt in the central Wet Tropics and in that areahybridization was found to be very limited despite sympatry at high densities. Based on multiple lines of data, Hoskin &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2011) concluded that the three genetic lineages represent biological species. The taxonomy of these three lineages isresolved here. I describe two new species, &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hinchinbrookensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; andredescribe &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus.&lt;/i&gt; The three species are not distinguishable based on any single morphological or call trait and arebest identified by genetics or locality. The distributions of the three species are largely allopatric. &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; isfound in rainforest in the northern Wet Tropics, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; occurs in rainforest and adjacent wet sclerophyllforests in the central and southern Wet Tropics, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hinchinbrookensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; inhabits rainforest and montane heathon Hinchinbrook Island. All three species are common. &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; contains three genetic subgroupsthat are considered a single species based on phenotypic similarity and high levels of hybridization at contact zones. Thedescription of &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hinchinbrookensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; brings the number of Australian &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; species to 18, 15 of which are restricted to the Wet Tropics region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hinchinbrookensis&lt;/i&gt;; rainforest; heath; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cophixalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Conrad</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoskin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Late Cretaceous phymosomatids and the true identity of &lt;i&gt;Cidarites granulosus &lt;/i&gt;Goldfuss, 1829 (Echinoidea, Phymosomatoida) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A revision of Late Cretaceous species of the common regular echinoid genus &lt;i&gt;Phymosoma&lt;/i&gt; Haime &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; d’Archiac &amp; Haime,1853 has revealed that &lt;i&gt;Cidarites&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; Goldfuss, 1829 has generally been misinterpreted in the literature. The typespecimen of this species is undoubtedly conspecific with material from the lower Maastrichtian of Rügen, northeast Ger-many. What authors have referred to as &lt;i&gt;Phymosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosum&lt;/i&gt; in northern temperate (boreal) regions of western Europeand in the Middle East in fact represents an undescribed form which we here name &lt;i&gt;Phymosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ravni&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., which dif-fers from &lt;i&gt;Cidarites&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; in having better-developed biserial pore zones adapically, proportionally larger mamelonson primary tubercles, a flush peristome, and stout, non-facetted primary spines. The proper placement of &lt;i&gt;Cidarites&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; within the family Phymosomatidae Pomel, 1883 is ambiguous; it appears to be most closely related to &lt;i&gt;Phymosoma.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Upper Cretaceous; Echinoidea; Phymosomatidae; systematics; new species; palaeogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Upper Cretaceous</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nils</firstname>
          <lastname>Schlüter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manfred</firstname>
          <lastname>Kutscher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jagt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jackie</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lees</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the bromeligenous &lt;i&gt;Scinax perpusillus &lt;/i&gt;group (Anura; Hylidae) from Serra do Brigadeiro, State of Minas Gerais, Southeastern Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the bromeligenous &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perpusillus&lt;/i&gt; group is described from Serra do Brigadeiro, state of Minas Gerais,southeastern Brazil (20º43’13.5´´S; 42º28’48.7´´W). &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cosenzai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is diagnosed by a combination of traits:moderate-size within the group (17.29–20.97 mm in males and 22.65–24.02 mm in females); head longer than wide; snoutprotruding in lateral view and slightly acuminated in dorsal view; prominent medial process between the nostrils; few tu-bercles scattered throughout the dorsal surface, including the head; ventral skin granulated, more intensively near the clo-acal region; dorsum different tones of gray with dark bands; transversal dark bars along limbs; gular region with irregulardark pigmentation; in life, hidden portion of the thigh and tibia region with some irregular bright yellow colored patches;and a distinct advertisement call with 2–14 notes/call, call duration 177.62–2066.75 ms, 1–33 pulses/note and dominant frequency of 3375.91–4571.21 Hz. Additionally, notes on natural history are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; PESB; &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cosenzai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; vocalization</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>João</firstname>
          <middlename>Victor A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lacerda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oswaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>Luiz</middlename>
          <lastname>Peixoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renato</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Feio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on &lt;i&gt;Labronemella labiata &lt;/i&gt;Andrássy, 1985 (Dorylaimida: Qudsianematidae) from Iran, with SEM study and a compendium of the genus </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Labronemella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labiata,&lt;/i&gt; the type species of its genus, is described after studying an Iranian population. An emendeddiagnosis of the species is provided, with new morphological and morphometrical features. The lip region, the mostdistinctive character of &lt;i&gt;Labronemella&lt;/i&gt; is observed under SEM by the first time and its detailed morphology elucidated.Anterior surface (oral field) appears distinctly sunken and with its inner (perioral) area differentiated in six large, separatedliplets protruding on oral field. The lateral, perioral liplets are trapezoidal and visibly larger than subdorsal and subventralones, which are triangular, consequently the lip region shows a bi-radial symmetry. Inner labial papillae migrate to themargin of labial disc, being located close to outer labial and cephalic papillae. The systematics of &lt;i&gt;Labronemella&lt;/i&gt; is brieflydiscussed, including diagnosis, updated list of species, key to their identification as well as a compendium of their main measurements and morphometrics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Compendium; description; diagnosis; key to species; &lt;i&gt;Labronemella&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; nematodes; SEM; taxonomy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Compendium</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Reyes</firstname>
          <lastname>Peña-Santiago</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Joaquín</firstname>
          <lastname>Abolafia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Majid</firstname>
          <lastname>Pedram</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-54</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of callianassid ghost shrimp (Crustacea: Decapoda: Axiidea) from reducing environments in Kyushu, southwestern Japan </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper reports on two species of callianassid ghost shrimps collected from reducing environments in Japan. &lt;i&gt;Cheramus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;cavifrons&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of five specimens from an invertebrate community associated with mass sinkingof whale carcasses implanted off Cape Nomamisaki, Kagoshima Prefecture, Japan, at depths of 219–254 m. This newspecies is compared with &lt;i&gt;Cheramus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; (Sakai, 1970), &lt;i&gt;Callianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aqabaensis&lt;/i&gt; Dworschak, 2003 and&lt;i&gt;Callianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutirostella&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1988. The generic assignment of the new species is provisional, reflecting the flux stateof the taxonomy of the family. &lt;i&gt;Nihonotrypaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thermophila&lt;/i&gt; Lin, Komai &amp; Chan, 2007, originally described fromhydrothermally influenced field off northeastern Taiwan, is first recorded from outside the type locality, based on a singlespecimen from hydrothermally influenced field in Kagoshima Bay, where the siboglinid tube worm &lt;i&gt;Lamellibrachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;satsuma&lt;/i&gt; Miura, Tsukahara and Hashimoto, 1997, is abundant.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Callianassidae; new species; new record; whale-fall community; hydrothermal vents; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Callianassidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yoshihiro</firstname>
          <lastname>Fujiwara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: JANET A. HUNTER &amp; THOMAS H. CRIBB (2012). A cryptic complex of species related to &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema licinum &lt;/i&gt;Manter, 1970 from fishes of the Indo-West Pacific, including descriptions of ten new species of &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema &lt;/i&gt;Witenberg, 1944 (Digenea: Transversotrematidae). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3176, 1–44. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
