<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3279.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Apr. 2012</title>
    <volume>3279</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-04-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Frog-Biting Midges of Borneo—From Two to Eleven Species (Corethrellidae: Diptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; Coquillett of Borneo are described and interpreted, based primarily on material from Brunei Darussalamand a few locations in the Malaysian states of Sarawak and Sabah. The eleven species include three previously named(one newly discovered in Borneo) and eight newly named species. The following new species are attributed to Borkent&amp; Grafe: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilva,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanoantennalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mitra&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bipigmenta.&lt;/i&gt; Two new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicincta&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unizona&lt;/i&gt; are attributed to Borkent, Grafe &amp; Miyagi.Of the eleven Bornean species, 10 are recorded from Brunei Darussalam and eight of these are also known from atleast Sarawak. This distribution of species as well as comparison of species collected directly from calling frogs withthose collected with frog-call traps (some with modified sound) indicate that diversity is not as high as in CentralAmerica (the only other tropical area intensely sampled). Surveys of aquatic habitats show that &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; are absentfrom phytotelmata (water bodies held by plants) in Borneo, other than &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calathicola&lt;/i&gt; Edwards which is present in somespecies of &lt;i&gt;Nepenthes&lt;/i&gt; and a species most closely related to a relatively derived group of Neotropical species occupyingtreeholes (C. &lt;i&gt;calathicola&lt;/i&gt; likely dispersed from the Neotropical Region). Phylogenetic analysis indicates that, other than&lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calathicola,&lt;/i&gt; species are members of an early lineage called the &lt;i&gt;drakensbergensis&lt;/i&gt; species group (n = 6), is the sistergroup of a large assemblage of Old and New World species (n = 1) or cannot be placed phylogenetically (probably because of lack of immatures and males) (n = 3).&lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; Coquillett dari Borneo dideskripsikan dan ditafsirkan berdasarkan sampel-sampel yang diperolehi dariBrunei Darussalam dan beberapa lokasi di Malaysia iaitu Sarawak dan Sabah. Sebelas spesies termasuk tiga spesies yangtelah dinamakan sebelumnya (satu spesies baru saja ditemui di Borneo) dan lapan spesies yang baru dinamakan. Spesiesbaru berikut merujuk kepada Borkent &amp; Grafe: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gilva,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nanoantennalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mitra&lt;/i&gt; dan &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;bipigmenta.&lt;/i&gt; Sementara itu terdapat dua agi spesies baru iaitu &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicincta&lt;/i&gt; dan &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unizona&lt;/i&gt; yang merujuk kepada Borkent,Grafe &amp; Miyagi.Daripada sebelas spesies &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; yang didokumenkan di Borneo, 10 daripadanya direkodkan dari BruneiDarussalam dan lapan daripada spesies ini juga diketahui kewujudannya sekurang-kurangnya di Sarawak. Taburanspesies ini serta perbandingan di antara spesies yang dikumpulkan secara langsung dari katak-katak yang berbunyidengan sampel-sampel yang dikumpulkan melalui perangkap yang telah dipasang dengan bunyi katak (beberapa denganbeberapa bunyi yang telah diubah suai) menunjukkan bahawa kepelbagaian spesies tidak setinggi yang terdapat diAmerika Tengah (iaitu satu-satunya kawasan tropika terperinci yang telah disampel secara mendalam). Penyiasatan keatas habitat-habitat akuatik menunjukkan bahawa spesies &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; tidak wujud di dalam ‘phytotelmata’ (badan airyang dipegang oleh tumbuh-tumbuhan) di Borneo, kecuali &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calathicola&lt;/i&gt; Edwards yang telah didapati di dalam beberapaspesies &lt;i&gt;Nepenthes&lt;/i&gt; dan juga satu spesies &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; yang berkait rapat dengan kumpulan yang berasal dari spesiesNeotropika yang terdapat di dalam lubang di bahagian batang pokok (C. &lt;i&gt;calathicola&lt;/i&gt; berkemungkinan berasal dariWilayah Neotropika). Analisis filogenetik menunjukkan bahawa, selain daripada &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calathicola,&lt;/i&gt; spesies &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt; iniadalah ahli dari keturunan awal yang dikenali sebagai kumpulan spesies &lt;i&gt;drakensbergensis&lt;/i&gt; (n = 6), adalah himpunankelompok spesies yang terbesar di Dunia Lama dan Baru (n = 1) atau tidak dapat diletakkan secara filogenetik (berkemungkinan disebabkan oleh kekurangan sampel yang tidak matang dan sampel jantan) (n = 3).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brunei; Malaysia; &lt;i&gt;Corethrella&lt;/i&gt;; frog; Anura; biodiversity; aquatic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brunei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Art</firstname>
          <lastname>Borkent</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>Ulmar</middlename>
          <lastname>Grafe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-25</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Re-description of two species of &lt;i&gt;Typhlocharis &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera: Carabidae: Anillini) and revision of the models of female genitalia within the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The re-descriptions of &lt;i&gt;Typhlocharis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santschii&lt;/i&gt; Normand, 1915 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadridentata&lt;/i&gt; (Coiffait, 1969) are presented, the onlytwo species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Typhlocharis&lt;/i&gt; for which female genitalia are still undescribed. The status of the material depositedin museums is updated for both species and a type series is established for &lt;i&gt;Typhlocharis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santschii.&lt;/i&gt; Morphologicaldescriptions are increased, including ventral features barely or not used until now (morphology of the last ventrite andintermetacoxal space); two new morphological structures are presented: cephalic semilunar notch and medial hiatus in theanterior margin of pronotum. A nomenclature and the formula to describe setae forming rows are proposed. A comparativeanalysis of relevant morphological structures has been carried out across the whole genus. This allowed the study ofmorphological affinities of both species within the genus, with comments on the taxonomic affinities of both species withother of the genus and to comment on the taxonomic utility of features, other than the umbilicate series, for establishingrelationships among species or species groups. The peculiar morphology of the gonocoxites of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadridentata&lt;/i&gt; and therevision of the different models of female genitalia within the genus led us to define six morphotypes of genitalia. The biogeographic implications of the atypical distribution of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santschii&lt;/i&gt; are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Carabidae; Anillini; &lt;i&gt;Typhlocharis&lt;/i&gt;; re-descriptions; setae formula; new structures; unguiform gonocoxites; Tunisia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Carabidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <lastname>Pérez-González</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zaballos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-62</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the unassigned species of the subfamily Coelidiinae (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five species treated incertae sedis and one overlooked species in Coelidiinae are each assigned to the following respectivegenus and tribe: &lt;i&gt;Jassus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maldivensis&lt;/i&gt; Distant to &lt;i&gt;Thagria&lt;/i&gt; Melichar, &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov&lt;/b&gt; (Thagriiini); &lt;i&gt;Jassus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atkinsoni&lt;/i&gt; Distant to &lt;i&gt;Olidiana&lt;/i&gt;McKamey, &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Coelidinii); &lt;i&gt;Coelidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costalis&lt;/i&gt; Walker to &lt;i&gt;Paracarinolidia&lt;/i&gt; Nielson, &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Teruliini); &lt;i&gt;Coelidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dis-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;integrans&lt;/i&gt; Walker to &lt;i&gt;Paracarinolidia&lt;/i&gt; Nielson, &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Teruliini), &lt;i&gt;Bythoscopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guttatus&lt;/i&gt; Walker to &lt;i&gt;Docalidia&lt;/i&gt; Nielson,&lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Teruliini) and &lt;i&gt;Coelidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semiflava&lt;/i&gt; Lethierry to &lt;i&gt;Pilosana&lt;/i&gt; Nielson, &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov&lt;/b&gt; (Youngolidiini). All of the species areredescribed with photos of the general habitus. The generic placement &lt;i&gt;Coelidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perineti&lt;/i&gt; Evans, previously assigned to thegenus &lt;i&gt;Limentinus&lt;/i&gt; Distant (Coelidiini) and recognized as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Limentinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aldabranus&lt;/i&gt; Distant, is confirmed. Eight species in the subfamily remain problematical.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Leafhoppers; taxonomy; types; new combinations; descriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Leafhoppers</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zahniser</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
