<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3296.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 May. 2012</title>
    <volume>3296</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-05-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes &lt;/i&gt;Jenyns, 1842; proposal of a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Argentinolycus&lt;/i&gt;, for &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes elongatus &lt;/i&gt;(Smitt, 1898), and description of &lt;i&gt;Patagolycus melastomus &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov. (Teleostei, Zoarcidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The osteological characters of the two nominal species of &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; are quite different. Thepresent definition of &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt; based on osteological characters is not valid since it was based on characters found in &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elong-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;atus&lt;/i&gt; but not in &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus,&lt;/i&gt; the type species of the genus. In this paper, &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt; is redefined on the basis of osteologicalcharacters found in the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus&lt;/i&gt; and other specimens of the species, and &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongatus&lt;/i&gt; is placedin another genus: &lt;i&gt;Argentinolycus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. Besides, a new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Patagolycus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melastomus,&lt;/i&gt; is described on thebasis of fourteen specimens, 94−437 mm TL, collected from SW Atlantic Ocean, at depths of 164−489 m. The similaritiesfound between &lt;i&gt;Patagolycus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melastomus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus&lt;/i&gt; in body colour as well as in many meristic and mor-phometric characters, represent a remarkable example of how challenging zoarcid taxonomy can be. The differences betweenthese two species are highlighted. A tree showing interrelationships among the Magellanic endemic lycodine genera is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pisces; Zoarcidae; Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Iluocoetes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Argentinolycus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Patagolycus&lt;/i&gt;; Magellan Province</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pisces</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jesús</firstname>
          <lastname>Matallanas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cecília</firstname>
          <lastname>Corbella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some hydrozoans (Cnidaria) from Central Chile and the Strait of Magellan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This report supplements a series of earlier accounts on the hydrozoan fauna of Chile, and discusses 34 species of hydroidsand one hydromedusa. The available collection was gathered from three distinct biogeographical regions: the southernborder of the Peruvian Province around Punta de Choros, the southern Intermediate Zone around Corral, and the northernand southern parts of the Magellan Province, around Reloncaví Sound and in the Strait of Magellan, respectively. All thespecies are fully illustrated and, when necessary, data on the cnidome composition are provided. Six species, &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;annuliforme,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvitheca,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mixta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Halopteris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumosa,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Clytia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;reloncavia,&lt;/i&gt; are described as new. The gonothecae of &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fjordlandicum&lt;/i&gt; Galea, 2007, &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;magellanicus&lt;/i&gt; (Marktanner-Turneretscher, 1890), and &lt;i&gt;Campanularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hartlaubi&lt;/i&gt; (El Beshbeeshy, 2011) are described for thefirst time, while those of &lt;i&gt;Kirchenpaueria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvata&lt;/i&gt; (Jäderholm, 1904) were rediscovered and are accurately redescribed.Morphological differences between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hartlaubi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lennoxensis&lt;/i&gt; (Jäderholm, 1903), two species with similartrophosomes, are highlighted. Large, fertile specimens of &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallens&lt;/i&gt; Jäderholm, 1904, as well as a female colonyof &lt;i&gt;Hydractinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvispina&lt;/i&gt; Hartlaub, 1905, allowed new redescriptions to be made. Due to insufficient taxonomicinformation on several species created more than a century ago, two Chilean records are doubtfully assigned to&lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;implexa&lt;/i&gt; (Allman, 1888) and &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lagena&lt;/i&gt; Allman, 1876, respectively, the former represented by fertilespecimens, and thus allowing the first description of its gonothecae. The long history of the confused taxonomy of SouthAmerican "Symplectoscyphus &lt;i&gt;subdichotomus&lt;/i&gt; (Kirchenpauer, 1884)" is now entirely settled. All the available records areconfidently assigned to the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filiformis&lt;/i&gt; (Allman, 1888), whose sexual dimorphism ofgonothecae, first indicated by Totton (1930), is confirmed in light of the present material. Five species represent newrecords for the country: &lt;i&gt;Staurocladia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vallentini&lt;/i&gt; (Browne, 1902), &lt;i&gt;Samuraia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tabularasa&lt;/i&gt; Mangin, 1991, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallens,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blanconae&lt;/i&gt; El Beshbeeshy, 2011, and &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paraglacialis&lt;/i&gt; El Beshbeeshy, 2011, the latter twobeing redescribed. Due to the scarcity of available material and the lack of gonophores of both sexes, six species of&lt;i&gt;Eudendrium&lt;/i&gt; Ehrenberg, 1834 could be identified to genus only. Similarly, a species of &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1848 and twobelonging to &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus&lt;/i&gt; Marktanner-Turneretscher, 1890, are awaiting reliable identifications based on fertile specimens. A species of &lt;i&gt;Clytia&lt;/i&gt; Lamouroux, 1812 could not be determined to species in the absence of life cycle studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hydrozoa; hydroids; hydromedusa; new species; south-eastern Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hydrozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Horia</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Galea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dirk</firstname>
          <lastname>Schories</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scleraspis &lt;/i&gt;nom. nov., replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Pycnaspis &lt;/i&gt;Van Syoc &amp; Dekelboum, 2011</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Syoc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Allen</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dekelboum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
