<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3297.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 May. 2012</title>
    <volume>3297</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The spotted flounder, &lt;i&gt;Azygopus flemingi &lt;/i&gt;Nielsen 1961 (Pisces: Pleuronectiformes: Rhombosoleidae), from deep waters off New Zealand: a second valid species of &lt;i&gt;Azygopus &lt;/i&gt;Norman 1926, with notes on distribution, size, maturity, and ecology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since its description, &lt;i&gt;Azyygopus&lt;/i&gt; Norman, 1926 was considered by subsequent authors to be a monotypic genus in the Or-der Pleuronectiformes comprised only of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; Norman, 1926, known from deep waters (90–900 m, usually200–600 m) off the southern and southeastern coasts of Australia. In 1961, a subspecies, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; Niels-en, was described based on three specimens collected at 610 m in the Tasman Sea off the South Island, New Zealand. Fromits description to contemporary literature evaluating its status, recognition of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; as a distinct taxon has beenrejected by all but two studies reporting on &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; from New Zealand waters. Until the late 20th century, specimens of&lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; had been rarely collected off New Zealand and little was known about these fishes. Over the past 25 years, col-lecting by scientific expeditions and expanding deep-sea fisheries have captured over 195 specimens of &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; from avariety of deep-sea locations around New Zealand. Recently-captured specimens of &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; collected around New Zea-land and deposited in fish collections have been identified as either &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; Norman or &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; Nielsen, sug-gesting the possibility that two species of &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; occur in New Zealand waters. This study examined the holotype, aparatype, and 25 non-type specimens of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; collected off Australia, and the most comprehensive series ofspecimens of &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; collected from New Zealand waters. These specimens included the holotype and two paratypes of&lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; and 191 other specimens collected from throughout the entire depth range (153–942 m) and representingwide coverage of geographic areas around New Zealand where &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; have been collected. Comparisons of these spec-imens indicate that a second species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; Nielsen, should be recognized in the genus &lt;i&gt;Azygopus,&lt;/i&gt; and that this speciesis the only member of this genus occurring in New Zealand waters. &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; is readily distinguished from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; by conspicuous differences in ocularand blind-side color patterns, in numbers of ocular-side pelvic-finrays, total vertebrae, lateral-line scales, and gillrakers on the first gill arch, morphology of blind-side scales and squama-tion patterns, length of blind-side pectoral fins, presence/absence of scales between upper jaw and ventral margin of lowereye, and pigment patterns on dorsal and anal fins of adults. Adult &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus&lt;/i&gt; are sexually dimorphic in several features. Data on maximum size and size at maturity, and depth of occurrence are summarized for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flemingi.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">rhombosoleid flatfish; taxonomy; New Zealand endemic fishes; deep-sea flatfish; species re-description; squamation; scale morphology; &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus;&lt;/i&gt; sexual dimorphism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">rhombosoleid flatfish; taxonomy; New Zealand endemic fishes; deep-sea flatfish; species re-description; squamation; scale morphology; &lt;i&gt;Azygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnifasciatus;&lt;/i&gt; sexual dimorphism</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Munroe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of deep-sea barnacles (Cirripedia: Thoracica: Scalpelliformes) from the Clarion-Clipperton region, Pacific Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Barnacles (Cirripedia: Thoracica) taken in the Clarion-Clipperton region, central Pacific, during cruises of the Research Vessel&lt;i&gt;Yuzhmorgeologia&lt;/i&gt; (2003, 2006, 2007, 2010, 2011) were studied. Three species, &lt;i&gt;Amigdoscalpellum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torbenwolffi&lt;/i&gt; Zevina, 1981,&lt;i&gt;Arcoscalpellum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radiatum&lt;/i&gt; Rao et Newman, 1972 and &lt;i&gt;Catherinum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortilum&lt;/i&gt; (Zevina, 1973), were collected in five samples from depths of 4680–4877m. The data obtained considerably extend the previously known distributions of these three species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scalpellidae; deep-sea barnacles; Clarion-Clipperton region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scalpellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oleg</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Poltarukha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vyacheslav</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mel’Nik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new false spider mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudoleptus &lt;/i&gt;Bruyant (Acari: Tenuipalpidae) from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudoleptus&lt;/i&gt; are described from Iran: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamedaniensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Bromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tectorum&lt;/i&gt; (Poaceae),&lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iranensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Bromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;danthoniae&lt;/i&gt; (Poaceae), and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kermanshahiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Alopecurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myosuroides&lt;/i&gt;(Poaceae). The genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudoleptus&lt;/i&gt; is rediagnosed and its relationship with the &lt;i&gt;Aegyptobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macswaini&lt;/i&gt; species group discussed. A key to all known species of this genus is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tetranychoidea; taxonomy; identification; new species; key.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tetranychoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masoumeh</firstname>
          <lastname>Khanjani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <lastname>Khanjani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alireza</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Owen</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Seeman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-56</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sertularella maureenae&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of hydroid (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa: Sertulariidae) from the Pacific coast of Canada</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maureenae,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Hydrozoa: Sertulariidae), is described from the Pacific coast of Canada. The species is charac-terized by its predominantly stolonal colony form with pedicellate, annulated hydrothecae, together with the presence of large,ovate gonothecae having distinct annulations, a prominent neck, and 4–6 well-developed cusps surrounding the gonothecalaperture. The new species is compared to other stolonal species of the genus and to other typically erect species of Sertulariidaewith reported stolonal forms. The presence of both stolonal and semi–erect colony forms with pedicellate hydrothecae within &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;maureenae,&lt;/i&gt; along with its hydrothecal characters, suggests that colony form alone may be an insufficient criterion for assigning species of pedicellate &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; with individual hydrothecae rising from their hydrorhizae to a separate genus &lt;i&gt;Calamphora.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Leptothecata; &lt;i&gt;Calamphora&lt;/i&gt;; stolonal hydroid colony; epizoic; pedicellate</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Leptothecata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Henry</firstname>
          <middlename>H. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Choong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dale</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Calder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anita</firstname>
          <lastname>Brinckmann-Voss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-63</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Kamaka &lt;/i&gt;(Amphipoda: Kamakidae) from Lake Tonle Sap, Cambodia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kamaka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonlensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Lake Tonle Sap, Cambodia. This species is peculiar in having no marginal setae onthe outer ramus of uropod 2 and relatively elongate dactylus of male gnathopod 1. It brings the number of species of &lt;i&gt;Kamaka&lt;/i&gt; up to 13.&lt;b&gt;Keywords.&lt;/b&gt; Crustacea, Amphipoda, Kamakidae, &lt;i&gt;Kamaka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonlensis,&lt;/i&gt; new species, Cambodia, Lake Tonle Sap</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hiroshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Morino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
