<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3314.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 May. 2012</title>
    <volume>3314</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new species of sea bass (Teleostei: Latidae: &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt;) from Myanmar and Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt; Cuvier are described. &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lakdiva,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from western Sri Lanka, differs from its Indo-Pacific congeners by its lesser body depth, 26.6‒27.6% SL; 5 rows of scales in transverse line between base of third dorsal-fin spine and lateral line; 31‒34 serrae on the posterior edge of the preoperculum; third anal-fin spine longer than second;47‒52 lateral-line scales on body; and greatest depth of maxilla less than eye diameter. &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uwisara,&lt;/i&gt; new species, fromeastern Myanmar, is distinguished by possessing 7 scales in transverse line between base of third dorsal-fin spine and lat-eral line; eye diameter 4.4‒4.7% SL; body depth 28.4‒34.5% SL; and third anal-fin spine shorter than the second. Despitesubstantial genetic variation, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calcarifer&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato is widely distributed, from tropical Australia through Indonesia, Sin-gapore and Thailand, westwards to at least the west coast of India. Caution is urged in translocating &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt; in the Indo-Pacific region as other yet unrecognized species likely exist. The status of the type specimens of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calcarifer&lt;/i&gt; is discussed,and a common lectotype designated for &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heptadactylus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nobilis.&lt;/i&gt; While &lt;i&gt;Lates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vacti&lt;/i&gt; (type locality Bengal) may bea valid species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavifrons&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darwiniensis&lt;/i&gt; are considered synonyms of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calcarifer.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Plectopomus&lt;/i&gt; Goldfuss and &lt;i&gt;Ptertopomus&lt;/i&gt; Goldfuss are shown to be incorrect subsequent spellings of &lt;i&gt;Plectropomus&lt;/i&gt; Oken.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Australia; Burma; cryptic species; giant perch; barramundi; sibling species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Australia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rohan</firstname>
          <lastname>Pethiyagoda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gill</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a rheophilic &lt;i&gt;Tilapia &lt;/i&gt;species Smith, 1840 (Teleostei: Cichlidae) from Guinea with comments on &lt;i&gt;Tilapia rheophila &lt;/i&gt;Daget, 1962</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tilapia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;konkourensis,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described on the basis of three specimens from the upper Konkouré River and itstributary Kakrima. The rheophilic species differs from all other &lt;i&gt;Tilapia&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato except &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusiforme&lt;/i&gt; Dunz &amp; Schliewen,2010 in a shallower body 30.0–31.5% vs. 32.9–52.5% SL and from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusiforme&lt;/i&gt; in having eight instead of nine to twelvelower lateral-line scales. It is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Tilapia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rheophila&lt;/i&gt; Daget, 1962, type species of the monotypic subgenus &lt;i&gt;Tila-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pia&lt;/i&gt; (Dagetia) Thys van den Audenaerde, 1969. An evaluation of the putative autapomorphies diagnosing &lt;i&gt;Dagetia&lt;/i&gt; re-vealed that all are shared with members of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Coptodon&lt;/i&gt; Gervais, 1853 sensu Thys van den Audenaerde, 1969; hence, &lt;i&gt;Tilapia&lt;/i&gt; (Dagetia) is placed in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Tilapia&lt;/i&gt; (Coptodon).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">ichthyofauna; freshwater; Fouta Djalon; West Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">ichthyofauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dunz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulrich</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schliewen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of Cranaidae from Ecuador (Opiliones: Laniatores)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new genus &lt;i&gt;Zannicranaus&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Andes in central Ecuador based on two new species. It is characterizedby a guitar-shaped body, short sturdy pedipalpus, unique strong spiniform process in the frontal hump, sexually dimorphicbasichelicerite (very strong in male), an erect spine on the cheliceral bulla and paired ventral armature on male coxa IV.&lt;i&gt;Zannicranaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monoclonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a species profusely colored in red, yellow and green, is described from ChimborazoProvince (Sibambe). &lt;i&gt;Zannicranaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;morlacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a dull-brown colored species, is the first reported harvestman from Azuay Province (Molleturo). The stylar caps, a novel structure, is described in the male genitalia of Cranaidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; Arachnida; Azuay; Chimborazo; Ecuador; Grassatores; harvestmen; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-44</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy and distribution of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eurydice &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1815 (Crustacea, Isopoda, Cirolanidae) from the Arabian region, including three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new subtidal species of &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; are described, i.e. &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marisrubri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;from the Red Sea, and &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marzouqui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Arabian/Persian Gulf. These species can be separated fromall other &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; in the Arabian region by the absence of robust setae on the posterior margin of the pleotelson. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maris-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;rubri&lt;/i&gt; has a truncate posterior margin bearing 5 apical teeth, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marzouqui&lt;/i&gt; has a rounded pleotelson posterior margin with6 apical teeth and in &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentata&lt;/i&gt; the posterior margin is truncate, bearing 7 apical teeth, the central 3 prominent. Addi-tional information is provided for two previously described species: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peraticis&lt;/i&gt; Jones, 1974 and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arabica&lt;/i&gt; Jones, 1974.Previous records of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt; are attributed to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt; is excluded from the region. A key is providedto separate all the &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; species likely to be found in the Arabian region. The distribution of all the Arabian &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt; is described, and morphology is discussed in relation to habitat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Isopoda; &lt;i&gt;Eurydice&lt;/i&gt;; Arabian Sea; /Persian Gulf; Red Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>Alan</middlename>
          <lastname>Jones</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manickam</firstname>
          <lastname>Nithyanandan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of Halichondriidae, &lt;i&gt;Topsentia vaceleti &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Halichondrida, Demospongiae, Porifera), collected from coralligenous bottoms of the Aegean Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Topsentia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vaceleti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; was collected from 70m depth, on a coralligenous bed of the Aegean Sea by trawl(sponge fishing gear “gagava”). The specimen is spherical, 8 cm in diameter, with deep surface grooves. It has a totallydisordered choanosome and a tangential ectosomal skeleton, typical of &lt;i&gt;Topsentia,&lt;/i&gt; but exhibits a different type of spicula-tion. This species differs from the other members of the genus by possessing both principal oxeas and secondary oxeas,the latter much longer but thinner, bent and in some cases flexuous or twisted. This is the fourth species of &lt;i&gt;Topsentia&lt;/i&gt; Berg, 1899 reported from the Mediterranean Sea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; Halichondrida; Halichondriidae; &lt;i&gt;Topsentia&lt;/i&gt;; Mediterranean Coralligenous substratum; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Efthimios</firstname>
          <lastname>Kefalas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeanne</firstname>
          <lastname>Castritsi-Catharios</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
