<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3320.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 May. 2012</title>
    <volume>3320</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Cumacean (Crustacea: Peracarida) Genus &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia &lt;/i&gt;(Pseudocumatidae) from the Pacific Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The distribution of the cumacean family Pseudocumatidae is restricted to the North Atlantic, Mediterranean and brackishwaters of the Pont-Caspian region, except for three known species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia.&lt;/i&gt; The present study describes ninespecies of &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia&lt;/i&gt; from Japanese waters, the Sulu Sea, the North-west Pacific, the Indo-West Pacific, and the Tasman Sea,Australia. The occurrence of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;declivis&lt;/i&gt; (Sars, 1865) in northern Hokkaido agrees with the reported circumpolar distribution ofthis species. Four species from the Pacific coast of southern Japan and the East China Sea, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevirostris&lt;/i&gt; Gamô 1986, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovalis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ryukyuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gamoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are characterized by prominent dorsolateral carinae with teeth anteriorlyand the basis of the 2nd maxilliped with a semicircular plate on the ventral surface. Nine specimens collected from the Sulu Seaincluded five species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevirostris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gamoi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jonesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;suluensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicauda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The latterthree species were characterized by no or faint dorsolateral carinae on the carapace. Among them, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jonesi&lt;/i&gt; was similar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;longirostris&lt;/i&gt; from the eastern tropical deep Atlantic. &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Tasman Sea is characterized by onefaint pair of dorsolateral carinae running for the entire length of the carapace. The species richness of &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia&lt;/i&gt; in the SuluSea and the Indo-West Pacific suggests a wide distribution of ancestors of Pseudocumatidae around the ancient Tethys Sea, with the Ponto-Caspian region located near the center. The habitat of &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia&lt;/i&gt; was mostly deeper than 200 m.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cumacea; &lt;i&gt;Petalosarsia&lt;/i&gt;; Pseudocumatidae; Northwest Pacific; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cumacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tadashi</firstname>
          <lastname>Akiyama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sarah</firstname>
          <lastname>Gerken</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploops antennata&lt;/i&gt;, a new species from the North Atlantic Ocean (Crustacea: Gammaridea: Ampeliscidae) [Contribution to the knowledge of the &lt;i&gt;Haploops &lt;/i&gt;genus. 7. ]</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antennata,&lt;/i&gt; a new &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; species is described based on an adult femelle collected in the Concarneau area(French coast, North Atlantic Ocean). This species is characterized by the presence of only one superior pair of corneallenses, the antenna 1 longer than the antenna 2 and the pereopod 7 basis narrow with inner side setose. A comparison isdone with the &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; species known and having only one superior pair of corneal lenses. A key of the 20 valid species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Ampeliscidae; &lt;i&gt;Haploops&lt;/i&gt;; corneal lenses; France; Atlantic Ocean; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kaim-Malka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-46</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biodiversity assessment of the Lower Mekong Basin: A new species of &lt;i&gt;Corvospongilla &lt;/i&gt;(Porifera: Spongillina: Spongillidae) from Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Only six species (four genera, one family) of freshwater sponges are known until now from Thailand. A first record of thegenus &lt;i&gt;Corvospongilla&lt;/i&gt; Annandale, 1911 with the description of a new species is here reported from the Pong River in the LowerMekong Basin. The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Corvospongilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is discussed in comparison to the 18 speciesassigned to the genus. The new species is characterised by &lt;i&gt;i)&lt;/i&gt; alveolate, paucispicular skeletal network with scanty spongin,thick ascending tracts towards the sponge surface to support conules; &lt;i&gt;ii)&lt;/i&gt; skeleton of stout microspined strongyles, andextremely rare, abruptly pointed oxeas usually with a few tubercles, plus micropseudobirotules with smooth shaft; &lt;i&gt;iii)&lt;/i&gt; gem-mules belonging to a single gemmular morph, typically sessile; &lt;i&gt;iv)&lt;/i&gt; gemmular cage notably stout, of tangentially arrangedstrongyles of variable length from tubercled to spiny; &lt;i&gt;v)&lt;/i&gt; gemmular theca with abundant laminar compact spongin, lackingpneumatic layer, armed by short, tubercled to spiny strongyles tangentially embedded; &lt;i&gt;vi)&lt;/i&gt; larvae armed by spiny oxeas. &lt;i&gt;Corvo-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;spongilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all the other known species of the genus in its unique combination of diagnostic traits,particularly a) acanthostrongyles (megascleres), b) gemmuloscleres, both in the cage and in the theca, as strongyles showing the tendency towards ring-shape and button-like shape, and c) larval spiny oxeas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; Freshwater sponges; &lt;i&gt;Corvospongilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Oriental Region; Pong River; Taxonomy; Biogeography; SEM</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nisit</firstname>
          <lastname>Ruengsawang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Narumon</firstname>
          <lastname>Sangpradub</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chutima</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanjavanit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renata</firstname>
          <lastname>Manconi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Oxypleurodon &lt;/i&gt;Miers, 1886 (Crustacea, Brachyura, Majoidea) from the Bismarck Sea, Papua New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recently collected specimens from the deep sea off Papua New Guinea revealed the presence of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Oxy-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pleurodon&lt;/i&gt; Miers, 1886 (Majoidea). The new species is a member of the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auritum&lt;/i&gt; group but its flattened rostral spines and the triangular shape of the carapace easily distinguishes it from congeners.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Majoidea; &lt;i&gt;Oxypleurodon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Papua New Guinea.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bertrand</firstname>
          <middlename>Richer</middlename>
          <lastname>De Forges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Laure</firstname>
          <lastname>Corbari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Discovery and redescription of type material of &lt;i&gt;Nausithoe simplex &lt;/i&gt;(Kirkpatrick, 1890), comb. nov. (Cnidaria: Scyphozoa: Coronatae: Nausithoidae) from the North Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">With discovery and examination of type specimens in the Natural History Museum, London, UK, we reassign &lt;i&gt;Stephanoscyph-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;istoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; (Kirkpatrick, 1890) to the genus &lt;i&gt;Nausithoe&lt;/i&gt; Kölliker, 1853, as &lt;i&gt;Nausithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex,&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov., and designate alectotype for the species. Use of morphometric measurements is considered important in coronate systematics, but key featuresalso include the unique whorl of internal cusps and the shape of these cusps. All previous records of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; must be re-evaluated, taking into consideration the morphology of these internal cusps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stephanoscyphus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nausithoe&lt;/i&gt;; polyp; systematics; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Stephanoscyphistoma&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stephanoscyphus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morandini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gerhard</firstname>
          <lastname>Jarms</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
