<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3328.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 May. 2012</title>
    <volume>3328</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of three &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus &lt;/i&gt;tadpoles (Lissamphibia: Anura: Rhacophoridae) from Sarawak, Malaysia (Borneo)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This communication reports the discovery of the hitherto unknown larval forms of &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penanorum,&lt;/i&gt; andre-describes the tadpole of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulitensis.&lt;/i&gt; Tadpoles of all three species were discovered at Gunung Mulu National Park, Sarawak(Borneo), Malaysia. The identity of the larvae was determined by DNA barcoding techniques using partial 16S rRNA mito-chondrial gene sequences. Larval DNA sequences matched those of syntopic adults of respective species. Detailed descriptionsof external morphology and colouration in life are provided along with ecological notes. The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;dulitensis&lt;/i&gt; can be classified as generalized, benthic-nectonic type, whereas tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penanorum&lt;/i&gt; show adaptations typical for a lotic, rheophilous lifestyle.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penanorum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dulitensis&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole description; larval morphology; oral disc; rheophilous tadpole; DNA barcoding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Haas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hertwig</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wenke</firstname>
          <lastname>Krings</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Enzo</firstname>
          <lastname>Braskamp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Maximilian</middlename>
          <lastname>Dehling</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pui</firstname>
          <middlename>Yong</middlename>
          <lastname>Min</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <lastname>Jankowski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Schweizer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Indraneil</firstname>
          <lastname>Das</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax gracilis &lt;/i&gt;(Günther, 1872) from Borneo and taxonomic status of two populations of &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) from Peninsular Malaysia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A number of populations of &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; from Borneo and Peninsular Malaysia have been assigned to &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; in thepast, rendering it a supposedly morphologically variable and widespread species. Whereas some of the Bornean populationshave since been described as distinct species, many lowland populations from Borneo and montane populations from Peninsu-lar Malaysia remain assigned to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis.&lt;/i&gt; Several distinct species appear to be hidden under this nominal taxon. In order toresolve the identity of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; and clarify the character states and their variation within the topotypic population, the speciesis redescribed based on examination of the holotype and recently collected topotypic material. Furthermore, the taxonomic sta-tus of two populations from Peninsular Malaysia (Gunung Benom, Gunung Tahan) that have been assigned to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; isreassessed. Reexamination of the corresponding vouchers revealed strong morphological differences between the two popula-tions and between each population and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; from Borneo. The population from Gunung Benom differs from all species ofthe genus and is apparently undescribed. The population from Gunung Tahan is represented only by two not fully metamor-phosed juveniles and cannot be assigned unambiguously to any of the described species of the genus. It is possibly another undescribed species but more specimens, especially adults, need to be collected.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Matang Range; Gunung Serapi; Gunung Benom; Gunung Tahan; endemism; cryptic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Maximilian</middlename>
          <lastname>Dehling</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-34</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Roquettea &lt;/i&gt;Mello-Leitão, 1931 from northern Brazil (Opiliones: Laniatores: Cosmetidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Roquettea&lt;/i&gt; Mello-Leitão, 1931 (Opiliones: Cosmetidae) are described from Pará State,northern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Roquettea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carajas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has two broad swellings on mesotergal area I of male and &lt;i&gt;Roquettea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has a wide and high eye mound with globoid eyeballs and the closest structure to a chelate pedipalpus in Laniatoresso far described. Both species have greatly thickened conic apophyses on mesotergal area III. A key is given to the (now)6 species of &lt;i&gt;Roquettea.&lt;/i&gt; The described diversity of genus &lt;i&gt;Roquettea&lt;/i&gt; increased from only one species to six in only a few years, mostly known from only a few specimens, suggesting a high degree of undersampling of those rare cosmetids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazonia; terrestrial arthropods; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazonia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cláudio</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-46</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola &lt;/i&gt;Miranda-Ribeiro (Leiuperinae: Leptodactylidae: Anura) from the Cerrado of southeastern Brazil with a distinctive advertisement call pattern</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Cerrado of southeastern Brazil. The new taxon is diagnosedfrom the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusilla&lt;/i&gt; species group by the absence of either T-shaped terminal phalanges or toe tips expanded, and promptlydistinguished from all (13) recognized taxa currently assigned to &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; by possessing isolated (instead of regular call series), long (117–187 ms) and non-pulsed advertisement calls.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Advertisement call; Cerrado; &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giarettai&lt;/i&gt; new species; State of Minas Gerais</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Advertisement call</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thiago</firstname>
          <middlename>Ribeiro</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-54</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new polymorphic &lt;i&gt;Phrynobatrachus &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Anura: Phrynobatrachidae) from western Nigeria</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new small &lt;i&gt;Phrynobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; species from western Nigeria, the eastern-most part of the Upper Guinea bio-diversity hotspot. The new species exhibits a combination of unique morphological characters and a belly without pattern.Morphologically it is characterised by small size, compact roundish body with a round and short snout, large eyes, absenceof an eyelid cornicle, presence of a conspicuous row of warts with pores on the upper mandible, absence of discs on toeand finger tips, well developed webbing, larger warts on forehead and inter-orbital space and a pair of, sometimes indis-tinct, elongated chevron like ridges on the back. Analysis of mitochondrial 16S rRNA revealed that the new species differsfrom 33 other West and Central African species of the genus by a minimum distance of 6.6%. Genetically the new speciesis most similar to &lt;i&gt;Phrynobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ghanensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guineensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phyllophilus,&lt;/i&gt; all being endemic to the western part of the Upper Guinea forest zone.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phrynobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rainerguentheri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Central Africa; degraded forest; Upper Guinea Forest; West Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phrynobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rainerguentheri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Central Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark-Oliver</firstname>
          <lastname>Rödel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Abiodun</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Onadeko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barej</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Laura</firstname>
          <lastname>Sandberger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-65</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Terebra limatula &lt;/i&gt;Dall,1889 and &lt;i&gt;T. acrior &lt;/i&gt;Dall, 1889 (Gastropoda: Terebridae); two problematic taxa from the western Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emilio</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Garcia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-05-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
