<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3331.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Jun. 2012</title>
    <volume>3331</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-06-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records and new species of Magelonidae (Polychaeta) from the Arabian Peninsula, with a re–description of &lt;i&gt;Magelona pacifica &lt;/i&gt;and a discussion on the magelonid buccal region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornuta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenulifrons,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obockensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchella,&lt;/i&gt; and an undescribed species (identifiedby Louis Amoureux as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornuta&lt;/i&gt; in 1983 and described herein as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; have been previously reportedfrom the seas surrounding the Arabian Peninsula. The present study details a further six &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; species off the coastsof Iran and Qatar, collected between 1998 and 2007. Five species are newly recorded for the region: &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;agoen-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;sis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;cincta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conversa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;falcifera&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;symmetrica,&lt;/i&gt; and one species (M. &lt;i&gt;sinbadi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt;is deemed new to science. A key is provided for the 15 species with verified reports currently known from the westernIndian Ocean region. &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; originally described from Panamá is discussed and re-described due to its simi-larity to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A ‘buccal organ/tube’ in addition to an everted proboscis was observed in one specimen (Ma- &lt;i&gt;gelona&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;agoensis)&lt;/i&gt; and is herein described and discussed in relation to previous morphological studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Buccal organ; Iran; &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Magelona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinbadi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Qatar; Key; Western Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Buccal organ</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-43</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Complementary redescription of &lt;i&gt;Raja lintea &lt;/i&gt;Fries, 1839 (Elasmobranchii, Rajidae) and its revised generic assignment</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The generic status of many skate species has been revised during the past six decades by various authors having introducednew diagnostic morphological and anatomical characters. As a consequence, the original family Rajidae and its very di-verse type genus &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 have been split into several families, subfamilies, genera and subgenera which werein several cases provisionally established due to the lack of specific material required. However, quite a number of speciesoriginally in &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; remained incompletely studied and still assigned to &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato,&lt;/i&gt; because, e.g., mature males werenot yet available for studies of their relevant clasper features. One of these species is the northern North Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;lintea&lt;/i&gt; Fries, 1839 which Stehmann (1970, 1973) and Stehmann and Bürkel (1984) could not assign definitively to the up-dated diagnosis of any revised rajid genus, because a mature male was not available. McEachran and Miyake (1990) andMcEachran and Dunn (1998) reallocated &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lintea&lt;/i&gt; to the subgenus/genus &lt;i&gt;Dipturus&lt;/i&gt; Rafinesque, 1810, respectively, with-out evidence or explanation given.Since a mature male of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lintea&lt;/i&gt; became available, the author has reinvestigated the species, presents here its so farunknown diagnostic characters of clasper morphology and skeleton, scapulocoracoid and pelvis, and assigns the species on this basis to the genus &lt;i&gt;Rajella&lt;/i&gt; Stehmann, 1970.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Skates; North Atlantic; generic status; clasper features; &lt;i&gt;Rajella&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Skates</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthias</firstname>
          <middlename>F. W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stehmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>44-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
