<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3361.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Jun. 2012</title>
    <volume>3361</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Pre-imaginal stages of &lt;i&gt;Cychrus schmidti &lt;/i&gt;Chaudoir, 1837, and &lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semigranosus &lt;/i&gt;Palliardi, 1825, with a key to the larvae of the European &lt;i&gt;Cychrus &lt;/i&gt;species (Coleoptera: Carabidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Among the several European and Asiatic species belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; Fabricius, the pre-imaginal morphology isknown just for a few of them. In the present work the larval morphology of &lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semigranosus&lt;/i&gt; is described.The morphology of the first species is unique due to its chaetotaxy, which is completely different from that of all of the other&lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; larvae described so far. The latter are characterized by completely glabrous thoracic and abdominal tergites. In &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;schmidti,&lt;/i&gt; the tergites are covered by several long setae, a feature never recorded in other Carabidae Carabinae species. Basingon actual knowledge, a preliminary identification key of the European larvae of the &lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; genus is provided. In the presentcontribution, the pupa of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; is also described; this is the first pupa of a species belonging to the &lt;i&gt;Cychrus&lt;/i&gt; genus to be depicted. Moreover, new data on the biology of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidti&lt;/i&gt; were collected from a laboratory breeding programme.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biological notes; Ground beetles; Larval morphology; Pupa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biological notes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Enrico</firstname>
          <lastname>Busato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Centorisoma &lt;/i&gt;Becker in China, with a key to world species (Diptera, Chloropidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Centorisoma&lt;/i&gt; Becker from China is provided. The following 5 species are described as newto science: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;divisum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gansuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helanshanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scutatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shaanxiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A key to the world species of genus &lt;i&gt;Centorisoma&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Chloropidae; &lt;i&gt;Centorisoma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xiaoyan</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ding</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-32</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description and bioacoustics of a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Isophya &lt;/i&gt;(Orthoptera: Tetigoniidae: Phaneropterinae) from Turkey</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species for the genus &lt;i&gt;Isophya,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bumerangoides,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Northeastern Black Sea Region of Turkey. Thenew species differs from closely related species in some aspects of morphology, mainly in male and female genitalia. Illustra-tions of external morphological characters and male and female songs are provided. Additional data on male calling song andfemale song of closely related bush-cricket &lt;i&gt;Isophya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rizeensis&lt;/i&gt; Sevgili, 2003 are also given. Scanning Electron Microscopeimages of stridulatory file of the other related species &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;redtenbacheri&lt;/i&gt; Adelung, 1907 are provided. &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bumerangoides&lt;/i&gt; clearlybelongs to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amplipennis&lt;/i&gt; group. Our bioacoustic results suggest that within the genus &lt;i&gt;Isophya,&lt;/i&gt; changes in calling song seem to appear more slowly than those in external morphological characters as in most tettigoniid.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Isophya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bumerangoides&lt;/i&gt;; Orthoptera; bush-cricket; Tettigoniidae; Phaneropterinae; bioacoustics; new species; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Isophya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bumerangoides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hasan</firstname>
          <lastname>Sevgili</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ali</firstname>
          <lastname>Demirsoy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Battal</firstname>
          <lastname>Çiplak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-44</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Macrostomus &lt;/i&gt;Wiedemann (Diptera, Empididae, Empidinae). III. The &lt;i&gt;limbipennis &lt;/i&gt;species-group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">All species of &lt;i&gt;Macrostomus&lt;/i&gt; Wiedemann allied with &lt;i&gt;Macrostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limbipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Bezzi), are treated in the &lt;i&gt;limbipennis&lt;/i&gt; species-group, which is defined on the basis of characters of the male and female terminalia, and a relatively wide female frons. Threecurrently recognized species and two new species are included, namely &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inflatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil (Federal District), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;limbipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Bezzi, 1909), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigriventris&lt;/i&gt; (Macquart, 1846), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil (Goiás and Mato Grosso states)and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penai&lt;/i&gt; Rafael &amp; Cumming, 2006. All primary types were examined and a lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limbipennis&lt;/i&gt;(Bezzi, 1909). A key to the species is presented along with the geographical distribution pattern exhibited by the &lt;i&gt;limbipennis&lt;/i&gt; species-group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropics; Amazon Basin; Atlantic Forest; Empididae; &lt;i&gt;Macrostomus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Albertino</middlename>
          <lastname>Rafael</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cumming</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Association of larvae and adults of Mexican species of &lt;i&gt;Macrelmis &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera: Elmidae): a preliminary analysis using DNA sequences</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Insect life stages are known imperfectly in many cases, and classifications are usually based on adult morphology. This isunfortunate as information on other life stages may be useful for biomonitoring. The major impediment to using elmid(Coleoptera) larvae for freshwater biomonitoring is the lack of larval descriptions and illustrations. Reliable molecular proto-cols may be used to associate larvae and adults. After adults of seven species of Mexican &lt;i&gt;Macrelmis&lt;/i&gt; were identified morpho-logically, seven larval specimens were associated to them based on two gene fragments: Cox1 and Cob. The phylogeneticanalysis allowed identifying the larval specimens as &lt;i&gt;Macrelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leonilae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scutellaris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; species 7, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; species 10, and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt;species 11. Two species based on adults associated uncertainly with one larva, and one larva did not match with any adult. Adult/larval association in elmids using DNA sequence data seems to be promising in terms of speed and reliability.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Elmidae; systematics; identification; Mexico; beetles; fresh water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Elmidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Josefina</firstname>
          <lastname>Curiel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morrone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-62</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ficothrips&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Thripinae Thysanoptera from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Ficothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; with one new species, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moundi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Fars province in south of Iran. Thesystematic position of this genus is discussed and its relationships to &lt;i&gt;Scolothrips&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Parascolothrips,&lt;/i&gt; two genera of leaf-living and predatory species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Fars province; &lt;i&gt;Ficus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carica&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; Thripidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Fars province</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kambiz</firstname>
          <lastname>Minaei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
