<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3362.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3362</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lynx spiders from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China (Araneae: Oxyopidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The lynx spiders (Araneae: Oxyopidae) from the tropical forests of Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, China were studied. Atotal of three genera and 16 species were examined and studied, including 10 new species from two genera: &lt;i&gt;Hamataliwa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fove-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;menglunensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedicula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentagona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pilulifera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;submanca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;complicatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;submirabilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hamataliwa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subhadrae&lt;/i&gt;(Tikader, 1970) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1804. The females of &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirabilis&lt;/i&gt; Zhang, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tenellus&lt;/i&gt; Song, 1991 are described for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Hamadruas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hieroglyphica&lt;/i&gt; (Thorell, 1887) and &lt;i&gt;Hamataliwa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subhadrae&lt;/i&gt;(Tikader, 1970) are newly recorded from China. The species &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bianatinus&lt;/i&gt; Xie &amp; Kim, 1996 is considered a junior syn-onym of &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fujianicus&lt;/i&gt; Song &amp; Zhu, 1993. &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorosus&lt;/i&gt; Zhang &amp; Zhu, 2005 is recorded from the Yunnan Province, China for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; tropical forests; &lt;i&gt;Hamadruas&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hamataliwa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Oxyopes&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guo</firstname>
          <middlename>Tang And Shuqiang</middlename>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Resolution of taxonomic problems associated with the complex publication history of the seminal Torre and Bartsch monograph on Cuban Urocoptidae (Gastropoda, Pulmonata)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper clarifies the confusion relating to the publication of Carlos de la Torre &amp; Paul Bartsch’s taxonomic study of theCuban Urocoptidae. This massive work, which described &gt;500 new taxa, was completed in manuscript form in 1943, butwas not published during the authors’ lifetime. In 1972 Miguel Jaume and Alfredo de la Torre (a nephew of C. de la Torre)published a slightly modified version of a large portion of this manuscript in the &lt;i&gt;Circulares&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;del&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Museo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Biblioteca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;de&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Zoología&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;de&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;la&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Habana,&lt;/i&gt; a mimeographed journal which is available for taxonomic purposes per ICZN Code Article 8. The420 new taxa introduced in this paper were made available under the ICZN Code (even though many were differentiatedonly in identification keys) and should be attributed to C. de la Torre &amp; Bartsch because the descriptions were copied fromthe 1943 manuscript and Jaume &amp; A. de la Torre explicitly credited this work to the former two authors (per Article 50 ofthe 1964 edition of the ICZN Code). The 1972 paper does not delineate type material for most of the new species-grouptaxa; however the detailed information provided in the 1943 manuscript constitutes valid evidence of the type series perICZN Code (1999) Article 72.2. The 1972 paper was republished by Jaume &amp; A. de la Torre in 1976 in the &lt;i&gt;Ciencias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bi-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ológicas&lt;/i&gt; of the Universidad de la Habana. In 1980 Jaume &amp; A. de la Torre prepared a typescript describing the remainingnew taxa from the 1943 manuscript, which was slated to be published in the &lt;i&gt;Circulares;&lt;/i&gt; however we have not found anyevidence that it was distributed or otherwise made available in a manner satisfying the ICZN Code criteria for availability.In 2008 Carolina de la Torre, grand-niece of C. de la Torre, published the entire 1943 manuscript in a book of more than760 pages that was printed in Havana. The authorship of this book was credited to C. de la Torre &amp; Bartsch. The bookdescribes as new the taxa already treated in the 1972 paper as well as 130 additional taxa, which also should be attributedto C. de la Torre &amp; Bartsch. We briefly discuss the disposition of the Cuban urocoptid material studied by C. de la Torre &amp; Bartsch and the subsequent citations to their taxonomic study of this fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Urocoptoidea; land snails; Caribbean; biodiversity; taxonomy; nomenclature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Urocoptoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alan</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kabat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Hershler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adrian</firstname>
          <lastname>González-Guillén</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the shrimp-associated goby genus &lt;i&gt;Lotilia &lt;/i&gt;(Actinopterygii: Perciformes: Gobiidae), with description of a new species from the West Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Indo-West Pacific gobiid fish genus &lt;i&gt;Lotilia,&lt;/i&gt; symbiotically associated with alpheid shrimps, is reviewed. The genus com-prises two species, viz. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graciliosa&lt;/i&gt; Klausewitz, 1960 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klausewitzi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., the latter of which is described herein basedon 11 specimens (including seven type specimens) from Japan, Australia and the Bismark Archipelago. &lt;i&gt;Lotilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klausewitzi,&lt;/i&gt; pre-viously misidentified as &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graciliosa&lt;/i&gt; in the West Pacific, is readily distinguished from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graciliosa&lt;/i&gt; by having the followingfeatures, in addition to some minor differences in the sensory-papillae configuration on the cheek: cephalic sensory canals andassociated pores present (vs. absent in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graciliosa);&lt;/i&gt; 7+6=13 branched caudal-fin rays (vs. 7+7=14); pale area on dorsum fromsnout to dorsoanterior part of body relatively long, extending posteriorly to, or beyond, base of fifth spine of first dorsal fin (vs.extending posteriorly to around base of third or fourth spine); a faint, relatively small dark grayish brown spot at center of firstdorsal fin behind third or fourth spine, and its paler margin usually absent or obscure (vs. conspicuous ocellated black spot withvivid pale margin at center of first dorsal fin, extending anteriorly beyond third spine); and a submarginal row of black spots oncaudal fin (vs. absent). Geographic records based on the specimens examined and underwater photographs indicate that &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gra-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ciliosa&lt;/i&gt; appears to be restricted to the Red Sea and its adjacent areas, whereas &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klausewitzi&lt;/i&gt; is widely found in the West Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Lotilia&lt;/i&gt; is re-diagnosed, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graciliosa&lt;/i&gt; is re-described based on five specimens including the holotype.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Perciformes; Gobiidae; &lt;i&gt;Lotilia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; shrimp-associated goby; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Perciformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Koichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Shibukawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Toshiyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Suzuki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Senou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-64</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
