<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3388.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3388</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton &lt;/i&gt;(Caudata: Salamandridae) from the Nanling Mountain Range, southeastern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New species of amphibians are being reported at an astonishingly fast rate. These include some that have been known tothe commercial pet trade for years but have not been formally described due to uncertain origin. The distinctive phenotypeof “Pachytriton B” among the Chinese stout newts (also known as paddle-tailed newts) is one such example. Throughexamination of museum specimens, we locate a population from Mt. Mang within the Nanling Mountain Range with mor-phology and coloration similar to &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton&lt;/i&gt; B. Molecular phylogenetic analyses strongly suggest that this populationand &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton&lt;/i&gt; B belong to the same species, which differs from congeners morphologically and chromatically and isdescribed here as a new species. This species is characterized by a large and stout body, uniformly light brown dorsum,and orange spots or blotches that extend ribbon-like along the dorsolateral sides of the body. A mitochondrial genealogysuggests that the new species is the sister taxon to the group (P. &lt;i&gt;brevipes&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feii).&lt;/i&gt; Morphologically, this species is significantly stouter than &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feii&lt;/i&gt; and has significantly longer limbs than &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevipes.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chinese stout newt; salamander; mitochondrial genealogy; principal-components analysis; &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xanthospilos&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chinese stout newt; salamander; mitochondrial genealogy; principal-components analysis; &lt;i&gt;Pachytriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xanthospilos&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yunke</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuezhao</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanken</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ampithoe bizseli &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Crustacea, Amphipoda) from the west coast of Turkey</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new species &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bizseli&lt;/i&gt; from the west coast of Turkey is described. It can be distinguished by a circular ischiumlobe on gnathopod 2 in the male sex from the similar species &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramondi&lt;/i&gt; where this lobe is slender. &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bizseli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; appears to occur also on the coast of Tansania.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; new species; Mediterranean Sea; &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bizseli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ampithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramondi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Murat</firstname>
          <lastname>Özaydinli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ch.</firstname>
          <middlename>Oliver</middlename>
          <lastname>Coleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-28</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scutiger &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) from southeastern Tibet, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Scutiger&lt;/i&gt; Theobald, 1868 is described from Medog, southeastern Tibet, China. &lt;i&gt;Scutiger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuguanfui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from congeners in the following combination of characters: (1) large adult size, female is much largerthan male; (2) maxillary teeth absent; (3) male with a pair of pectoral glands and a pair of axillary glands, axillary glandssimilar to pectoral glands, all of them covered by black spines in breeding season; (4) in breeding male, nuptial spines ondorsal surface of firs and second fingers, and inner side of third finger; (5) male with an internal single subgular vocal sac,a pair of slit-like openings of vocal sac near corners of the mouth. This new species is currently known only from the type locality.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scutiger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuguanfui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Amphibia; Anura; Megophryidae; Tibet</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scutiger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuguanfui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ke</firstname>
          <lastname>Jiang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dingqi</firstname>
          <lastname>Rao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Siqi</firstname>
          <lastname>Yuan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jishan</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pipeng</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mian</firstname>
          <lastname>Hou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maihe</firstname>
          <lastname>Che</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jing</firstname>
          <lastname>Che</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of kukri snake (Colubridae: &lt;i&gt;Oligodon &lt;/i&gt;Fitzinger, 1826) from the Phnom Samkos Wildlife Sanctuary, Cardamom Mountains, southwest Cambodia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of kukri snake &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; Fitzinger, 1826 is described from the Phnom Samkos Wildlife Sanctuary, Carda-mom Mountains, southwest Cambodia. &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kampucheaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other Indochinese and SoutheastAsian species of &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; by having 15–15–15 dorsal scale rows; 164 ventral scales; 39 subcaudal scales; anal plate un-divided; deep bifurcated hemipenes, lacking papillae and spines extending to subcaudal scale 11; 17 transverse cream andblack-edged bands on body; three bands on tail; eight or nine scales long between dorsal bands; white ventrolateral spotson the lateral margin of every dark brown squarish or subrectangular ventral blotch. The hemipenial characters place it asthe tenth species of the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclurus&lt;/i&gt; group but it has a lower dorsal scale count than other species in this group. The dis-covery of this species from the Phnom Samkos Wildlife Sanctuary increases the number of kukri snakes for Cambodia to ten and indicates the importance of additional field studies in the Cardamom Mountains.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hemipenis; herpetofauna; Indochina; natural history; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hemipenis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thy</firstname>
          <lastname>Neang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jennifer</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Daltry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new, high-elevation glassfrog (Anura: Centrolenidae) from Manu National Park, southern Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of glassfrog from the cloud forest of Manu National Park, southern Peru, at elevations of 2750–2800m. The new species is similar in morphology to &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lemniscatum,&lt;/i&gt; which occurs in northern Peru at elevations of2000–2280 m. Both species have white labial stripes, humeral spines, and lack vomerine teeth. The new species differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;lemniscatum&lt;/i&gt; by its larger size, labial stripe extending into a distinct lateral stripe instead of a discontinuous lateral stripe, snoutprofile inclined anteroventrally instead of bluntly rounded, greater depression in the internarial area, and by having stronglyprotruding nostrils. Males of the new species emit long calls with 8–14 peaked notes, instead of a short tonal note in &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lemnis-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;catum.&lt;/i&gt; Another morphologically similar species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buckleyi,&lt;/i&gt; has a short advertisement call composed of 1–5 notes, and isgenetically distinct from the new species. This new &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; extends the known distribution of &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; to the south by 600 km, and is the southernmost species of this genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Andes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Catenazzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudolf</firstname>
          <lastname>Von May</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edgar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giussepe</firstname>
          <lastname>Gagliardi-Urrutia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
