<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3390.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3390</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular phylogeny and morphological revision of the &lt;i&gt;Ctenotus labillardieri&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Squamata: Scincidae) species group and a new species of immediate conservation concern in the southwestern Australian biodiversity hotspot</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ctenotus&lt;/i&gt; is the largest and most diverse genus of skinks in Australia with at least 97 described species. We generated largemitochondrial and nuclear DNA data sets for 70 individuals representing all available species in the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labillardieri&lt;/i&gt; species-group to produce the first comprehensive phylogeny for this clade. The widespread &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labillardieri&lt;/i&gt; was sampled extensively toprovide the first detailed phylogeographic data set for a reptile in the southwestern Australian biodiversity hotspot. Wesupplemented our molecular data with a comprehensive morphological dataset for the entire group, and together these data areused to revise the group and describe a new species. The morphologically highly variable species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;labillardieri&lt;/i&gt; comprisesseven well-supported genetic clades that each occupy distinct geographic regions. The phylogeographic patterns observed inthis taxon are consistent with studies of frogs, plants and invertebrates, adding strength to emerging biogeographic hypothesesin this iconic region. The species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catenifer,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngsoni,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmula&lt;/i&gt; are well supported, and despite limited samplingboth &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catenifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmula&lt;/i&gt; show substantial genetic structure. The threatened &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lancelini&lt;/i&gt; from Lancelin Island and theadjacent mainland is the sister taxon to a new species from the Swan Coastal Plain, which we describe as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Thisspecies is a habitat specialist, occurring primarily in sandy regions south of Perth that currently are under intense development. &lt;i&gt;Ctenotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; should be considered for conservation attention immediately.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cryptic species; lizard; skink; ND2; ATP; southwestern Australia; biodiversity hotspot; Swan Coastal Plain</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cryptic species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Geoffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Scott</middlename>
          <lastname>Keogh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and new record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cumella &lt;/i&gt;(Cumacea: Nannastacidae) from Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new species, &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levitergus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and the newly recorded species, &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arguta&lt;/i&gt; Gamô, 1962 are described andillustrated. &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabera&lt;/i&gt; Gamô, 1962 is proposed as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arguta&lt;/i&gt; in this study. &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levitergus&lt;/i&gt; is obviouslydistinguished from other known species of &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; by the combination of the following features: 1) the carapace surface is pit-ted, and has abundant minute alveolate sculpturing, which is round and tightly arranged; 2) the dorsomedian carina is obsoleteand not decorated; 3) the flagellum of the male antenna 2 does not extend past the posterior border of the pleonite 4; 4) the car-pus of pereopod 1 has 3 setae on the inner margin; 5) the carpus of pereopod 2 is shorter than the length of the dactylus; 6) the uropod exopod is 0.65 times as long as the exopod. A key to the Korean &lt;i&gt;Cumella&lt;/i&gt; species is also given.Key words: Taxonomy, Cumacea, Nannastacidae, &lt;i&gt;Cumella,&lt;/i&gt; new species, synonym, Korea</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chang-Mok</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kyung-Sook</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-32</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular systematics of the armored neotropical catfish subfamily Neoplecostominae (Siluriformes: Loricariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Morphological and molecular studies in the family Loricariidae have revealed that the relationships among its membersare not yet well resolved, and the present study was conducted with the main objective of improving our knowledge aboutthis highly diversified group of catfishes. Maximum parsimony and Bayesian analysis were conducted on a matrix of 53terminal taxa and 4676 characters with partial sequences of the genes COI, CytB, 16S rRNA, 12S rRNA and F-reticulon4. As outgroups, samples of the species &lt;i&gt;Hemipsilichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gobio&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papillatus&lt;/i&gt; (subfamily Delturinae), &lt;i&gt;Rineloricaria&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;jaraguensis&lt;/i&gt; (subfamily Loricariinae), &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigromaculatus&lt;/i&gt; (subfamily Hypostominae), &lt;i&gt;Hypoptopoma&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;inexpectatum&lt;/i&gt; (subfamily Hypoptopomatinae), and &lt;i&gt;Corumbataia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuestae&lt;/i&gt; (subfamily Otothyrinae) were used. The resultsshowed that the subfamily Neoplecostominae is monophyletic, including &lt;i&gt;Pseudotocinclus,&lt;/i&gt; and three clades wererecognized. The first one is composed of &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudolphi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;rudolphi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudotocinclus.&lt;/i&gt; The second iscomposed of &lt;i&gt;Isbrueckerichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhaphis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Kronichthys&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ribeirensis.&lt;/i&gt; The third is composed ofthe remaining species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus,&lt;/i&gt; except &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ribeirensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carrancas,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;carrancas,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina&lt;/i&gt; sp. 1 (possible new species) and an undescribed taxon referred to in this paper as new genus and species 2. In our analyses, &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; are paraphyletic taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">freshwater; Loricariidae; mitochondrial DNA; nuclear gene; phylogenetic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">freshwater</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fábio</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Roxo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cláudio</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zawadzki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guilherme</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Costa Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chiachio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fausto</firstname>
          <lastname>Foresti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the endemic Australian cladoceran &lt;i&gt;Alona willisi &lt;/i&gt;(Smirnov, 1989) and its assignment to &lt;i&gt;Acanthalona &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. (Cladocera: Anomopoda: Chydoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;willisi&lt;/i&gt; (Smirnov, 1989) (Anomopoda: Chydoridae) is a poorly known cladoceran endemic to Australia. The presentmorphological study revealed numerous unique and rare features of the species and justifies its assignment to &lt;i&gt;Acanthalona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The new genus differs by its postabdomen armed with very long, thick marginal denticles and by exopodite of limb Vwith only three setae. It also differs from most Aloninae by antennal formula (setae 0-0-3/0-1-2, spines 1-0-1/0-0-1), sharedonly with &lt;i&gt;Bryospilus&lt;/i&gt; Frey, 1980. In our opinion, &lt;i&gt;Acanthalona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is related to &lt;i&gt;Armatalona&lt;/i&gt; Sinev, 2004 and &lt;i&gt;Matralona&lt;/i&gt;Van Damme &amp; Dumont, 2009. These three genera form a clade, basal for the subfamily, and not directly related to the majorityof Aloninae. The records of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;willisi&lt;/i&gt; show that the species inhabits both acidic and alkaline freshwaters and seems to be algivorous as well as detritivorous.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">apomorphies; &lt;i&gt;Acanthalona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Armatalona&lt;/i&gt;; Australian endemism; Cladocera; &lt;i&gt;Matralona&lt;/i&gt;; Royal National Park; sister groups; synapomorphies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">apomorphies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Artem</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tsuyoshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kobayashi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Parotocinclus &lt;/i&gt;(Siluriformes: Loricariidae) from the upper Rio São Francisco, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the hypoptopomatine loricariid &lt;i&gt;Parotocinclus&lt;/i&gt; is described based on material from three rivers belongingto the upper and middle Rio São Francico basin, the Rio das Velhas and Rio Jequitaí on the right margin and the RioParacatu on the left margin. The new species is readily distinguished from all congeners by having the abdomencompletely devoid of dermal plates between the pectoral girdle and the anus, by differences in rostral and postrostral plates, and by having the pectoral girdle covered by skin medially and exposed and supporting odontodes only laterally.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Catfishes; Hypoptopomatinae; Neotropical; taxonomy; biogeography; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Catfishes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <middlename>Lehmann</middlename>
          <lastname>A.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Reis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-64</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Intellagama lesueurii &lt;/i&gt;(Gray, 1831), the correct binomial combination for the Australian Eastern Water Dragon (Sauria, Agamidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Amey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Couper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Glenn</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Naruse, T., Chan, T.-Y., Tan H.H., Ahyong, S.T. &amp; Reimer, J.D. (2012) Scientific Results of the Marine Biodiversity Expedition—KUMEJIMA 2009. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3367, 1–280. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-04-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
