<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3400.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3400</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe &lt;/i&gt;Conlan &amp; Bousfield, 1982 from Korean waters (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Ampithoidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe&lt;/i&gt; have been recorded in Korean waters. Herein we add two peramphithoid species,&lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chujaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eoa&lt;/i&gt; (Brüggen). The new species is easily distinguished from congeners by: (1)male antenna 2 with plumose setae ventrally, (2) male gnathopod 2, propodus 0.7 x as wide as long and palm excavated,(3) male pereopods 5–7, meri and carpi expanded, (4) in both sexes, gnathopod 1, carpus subequal in length to propodus.The newly recorded species in Korea, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eoa&lt;/i&gt; is well accorded with the original description. A key to and description ofKorean peramphithoid species is also provided. To examine relationships among species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe&lt;/i&gt; fromKorea, a morphological and molecular phylogenetic study was conducted using 657 bp of the gene for the mitochondrialcytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase subunit 1 (mtCO1). This gene showed good resolution as a molecular marker for species identification of the genus &lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe&lt;/i&gt; in Korea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Ampithoidae; &lt;i&gt;Peramphithoe&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; mtCO1; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Young-Hyo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Soon-Sang</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kathleen</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conlan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kyungsook</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Cumacea), and a new genus and species from Japan, Northwest Pacific, with observations on the degeneration of mouthparts in ovigerous females</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of the cumacean genus &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt; from the southern coast of Honshu, Japan, 781–861 m depth, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gamoi&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ojii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudopicrocuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Nansei Islands, 566–1769 m depth,are described. &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gamoi&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by (1) carapace elevated in preparatory and ovigerous female, (2)antero-lateral angle of carapace with 3 teeth in females, and (3) pseudorostrum of carapace of adult males truncate,anterolateral angle without teeth. &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ojii&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by (1) carapace not elevated in preparatory females,but elevated in ovigerous females, (2) inferior margin of carapace in ovigerous female serrated for entire length, (3)pseudorostrum of carapace in adult males truncate, (4) uropod exopod with 1–2 spiniform setae on inner margin, exceptfor subterminal one. The new genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopicrocuma,&lt;/i&gt; which is similar to &lt;i&gt;Picrocuma&lt;/i&gt; from shallow waters of easternAustralia, is characterized by (1) well-developed exopods present on maxilliped 3 and pereopods 1–3 in both sexes, (2)antenna 1 of adult males with many aesthetascs-like sensory setae on peduncle articles 2 and 3, (3) male antenna 2 ofclasping form, and (4) uropod slender, peduncle shorter than rami. &lt;i&gt;Pseudopicrocuma&lt;/i&gt; shows affinity to &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt; exceptfor (1) arrangement of well-developed exopods on pereopods, (2) male antenna 2 flagellum of clasping form, and (3)uropod peduncle shorter than rami. In addition, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicum&lt;/i&gt; and the new Japanese &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt; species are characterizedby a similar trend in degeneration of mouthparts (mandibles – maxillipeds 2) in ovigerous females, suggesting a ratherclose relationship of these genera with quite different arrangements of exopods on pereopods. These 2 genera are currentlyplaced in Nannastacidae. Other possible relatives of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopicrocuma&lt;/i&gt; are &lt;i&gt;Spilocuma&lt;/i&gt; (Bodotriidae) and &lt;i&gt;Claudicuma&lt;/i&gt; (Nannastacidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Cumacea; &lt;i&gt;Atlantocuma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pseudopicrocuma&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; deep-sea; Northwest Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tadashi</firstname>
          <lastname>Akiyama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The stream-dwelling larva of the Ruwenzori River Frog, &lt;i&gt;Amietia ruwenzorica&lt;/i&gt;, its buccal cavity and pathology of chytridiomycosis</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;Amietia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ruwenzorica&lt;/i&gt; (Pyxicephalidae, Cacosterninae) were collected in the Ruwenzori Mountains, Uganda(identified by DNA barcoding). The ventrally directed enlarged oral disc with a high number of labial tooth rows (LTRF9(4)/9(1)) and the narrow tail with robust caudal musculature characterise them as stream-dwellers. We name this mor-photype the 'common or standard type of stream-adaptation', because special additional adhesive organs are missing in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ruwenzorica.&lt;/i&gt; The uniserially arranged oral teeth of the spoon-shaped type with 16 to 18 cusps per tooth are known fromother anuran larvae, especially from pyxicephalids. The buccal morphology resembles generalized tadpoles with some re-strictions and all features of a suspension-feeding pyxicephalid larva are present in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ruwenzorica.&lt;/i&gt; This leads us to theconclusion that tadpoles of this species are suspension-feeders scraping periphyton off the surface and ingesting bottomand deposit particles. Histopathological and scanning electron microscopy investigations demonstrated the presence of theamphibian chytrid fungus (Batrachochytrium &lt;i&gt;dendrobatidis)&lt;/i&gt; in part of our material resulting in signs of chytridiomycosis indicated by the loss of labial teeth and by corrosion of jaw sheaths.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; &lt;i&gt;Batrachochytrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dendrobatidis&lt;/i&gt;; DNA barcoding; larval morphology; Pyxicephalidae; Uganda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bruno</firstname>
          <lastname>Viertel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Veith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Susanne</firstname>
          <lastname>Schick</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alan</firstname>
          <lastname>Channing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <lastname>Kigoolo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Baeza-Urrea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulrich</firstname>
          <lastname>Sinsch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <lastname>Lötters</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-57</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Austrobatrachus iselesele&lt;/i&gt;, a new toadfish species from South Africa (Teleostei: Batrachoididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The second known species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Austrobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; is described from KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa. Its live color-ation is very different from the other known species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foedus,&lt;/i&gt; having many black spots on the body and solid colored fins. It also has a longer snout and larger eye. The species lives in holes in the reef at depths of 49–50 m.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Austrobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iselesele&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Austrobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foedus&lt;/i&gt;; toadfishes; South Africa; Batrachoididae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Austrobatrachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iselesele&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Greenfield</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-63</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new terrestrial talitrid genus from the Philippine Islands (Crustacea, Amphipoda, Talitrida, Talitridae) and the designation of two informal subgroups</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Curiotalitrus,&lt;/i&gt; a new genus of terrestrial land-hoppers (Amphipoda, Talitridae) is described from rain-forests in the Phil-ippines. &lt;i&gt;Curiotalitrus&lt;/i&gt; includes one species: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curioi&lt;/i&gt; (Javier &amp; Coleman, 2010). Informal &lt;i&gt;Talitrus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Orchestia&lt;/i&gt; groups are proposed based on the condition of the male second gnathopod.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Talitridae; Philippines; taxonomy; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Curiotalitrus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>Oliver</middlename>
          <lastname>Coleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
