<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3404.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3404</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the giant geckos of New Caledonia (Reptilia: Diplodactylidae: &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We employed a molecular phylogenetic approach using the mitochondrial ND2 gene and five associated tRNAs(tryptophan, alanine, asparagine, cysteine, tyrosine) and the nuclear RAG1 gene to investigate relationships within thediplodactylid geckos of New Caledonia and particularly among the giant geckos, &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus,&lt;/i&gt; a charismatic group oflizards that are extremely popular among herpetoculturalists. The current generic allocation of species within NewCaledonian diplodactylids does not adequately reflect their phylogenetic relationships. &lt;i&gt;Bavayia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;madjo,&lt;/i&gt; a high-elevationendemic is not closely related to other &lt;i&gt;Bavayia&lt;/i&gt; or to members of any other genus and is placed in a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Paniegekko&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; is not monophyletic. The small-bodied and highly autapomorphic genus &lt;i&gt;Eurydactylodes&lt;/i&gt; isembedded within &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; as sister to &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chahoua.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarasinorum&lt;/i&gt; are sister taxa but arenot part of the same clade as other giant geckos and the generic name &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt; Guichenot is resurrected for them.Remaining New Caledonian giant geckos (R. &lt;i&gt;leachianus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachrhynchus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auriculatus)&lt;/i&gt; receive weak support as amonophyletic group. Although the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (including &lt;i&gt;Eurydactylodes)&lt;/i&gt; exclusive of &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt;cannot be rejected, our results support the recognition of a &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chahoua&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Eurydactylodes&lt;/i&gt; clade separate from&lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto.&lt;/i&gt; Because of the distinctiveness of &lt;i&gt;Eurydactylodes&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chahoua&lt;/i&gt; (and other NewCaledonian ‘giant geckos’), we retain this name for the four species to which it has been consistently applied and erect anew genus, &lt;i&gt;Mniarogekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; to accommodate &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chahoua.&lt;/i&gt; There is little genetic differentiation within the narrowlydistributed &lt;i&gt;Corrrelophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarasinorum,&lt;/i&gt; but &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliatus&lt;/i&gt; from southern New Caledonia are both genetically andmorphologically differentiated from a recently discovered &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt; from the Îles Belep, north of the Grande Terre,which is here described as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;belepensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Although only subtley different morphologically, the populations of&lt;i&gt;Mniarogekko&lt;/i&gt; from the far northwest of the Grande Terre and from the Îles Belep are strongly differentiated geneticallyfrom &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chahoua&lt;/i&gt; populations in the central part of the Grande Terre and are described as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jalu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;auriculatus&lt;/i&gt; exhibits some genetic substructure across its nearly island-wide range in New Caledonia, but overalldivergence is minimal. &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leachianus&lt;/i&gt; exhibits low levels of divergence across its range and southern insularforms previously assigned to &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henkeli&lt;/i&gt; are not divergent from southern Grande Terre populations. The few populationsof &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachyrhynchus&lt;/i&gt; sampled are strongly divergent from one another and a specimen from Îlot Môrô near the Île des Pinsis especially distinctive. This specimen and others examined from Îlot Môrô are morphologically assignable to the speciesdescribed by Boulenger in 1878 as &lt;i&gt;Chameleonurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachycephalus&lt;/i&gt; and is recognized here as a full species. New diagnosesare provided for each of the eight genera of endemic New Caledonian diplodactylid geckos now recognized. The resultsof our study necessitate determinations of the conservation status of the new species described or recognized.&lt;i&gt;Mniarogekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jalu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is considered Endangered, but is locally abundant. &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;belepensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; isconsidered Critically Endangered and is restricted to the ultramafic plateaux of Île Art. Although described from the Îledes Pins, we have only been able to confirm the existence of &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachycephalus&lt;/i&gt; on the tiny satellite island ÎlotMôrô and consider it to be Critically Endangered. If indeed restricted to this islet, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trachycephalus&lt;/i&gt; may well have the smallest range and perhaps the smallest population of any gecko in the world.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; &lt;i&gt;Rhacodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mniarogekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paniegekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Correlophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;belepensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mniarogekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jalu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; New Caledonia; molecular phylogenetics; conservation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Todd</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jackman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ross</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sadlier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whitaker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on three poorly known &lt;i&gt;Arctosa &lt;/i&gt;species from China (Araneae: Lycosidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Arctosa&lt;/i&gt; are revised and their relationship with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinerea,&lt;/i&gt; the type species of the genus, is dis-cussed. &lt;i&gt;Arctosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;binalis&lt;/i&gt; Yu &amp; Song, 1988 is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;depectinata&lt;/i&gt; (Bösenberg &amp; Strand, 1906). Males of&lt;i&gt;Arctosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gougu&lt;/i&gt; Chen &amp; Song, 1999 and &lt;i&gt;Arctosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vaginalis&lt;/i&gt; Yu &amp; Song, 1988 are described for the first time. All specimensexamined were collected from the Yunnan Province, China. Morphological illustrations, photos, descriptions and SEMphotographs of the male bulbus of all species are given. Stridulatory files on chelicerae in Lycosidae are reported for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; wolf spiders; morphology; redescription; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lu-Yu</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marusik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhi-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
