<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3436.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Aug. 2012</title>
    <volume>3436</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new cryptic species allied to &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon japonicus &lt;/i&gt;(Peters, 1864) (Squamata: Scincidae) from eastern Japan, and diagnoses of the new species and two parapatric congeners based on morphology and DNA barcode</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of scincid lizard allied to &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; (Peters, 1864) was described as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; fromthe eastern part of Honshu and Hokkaido, Japan. A previous DNA study reported the taxonomic status of the easternJapanese populations of &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; as an undescribed species on the basis of their collective genetic distinctness from aparapatric congener &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; sensu strict from the western part of mainland Japan. We present the diagnostic featuresof &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus&lt;/i&gt; compared to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latiscutatus&lt;/i&gt; Hallowell, 1861, the other parapatric species occurring in theIzu Peninsula and Izu Islands of central Japan, on the basis of morphological characteristics and DNA barcode patterns.Both &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; have a small postnasal and large anterior loreal that contacts the supralabials. In contrast,the Izu Peninsular populations of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latiscutatus,&lt;/i&gt; which had no known diagnostic features relative to the other two species,usually have a large postnasal and small anterior loreal, with the latter separated from the supralabials by the former, ormay otherwise lack a postnasal. In most populations of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus,&lt;/i&gt; the right and left prefrontals are usually isolated fromeach other, whereas they exhibit medial contact in most populations of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus.&lt;/i&gt; Although all the above characters arevariable both within and between populations, 60–90% of the specimens from each locality on mainland Japan werecorrectly identified using a combination of these characters. Based on these characters, the Russian Far East populationof &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; was also identified as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus.&lt;/i&gt; The interspecific sequence differences in the standard DNA barcoderegion (a 658 base pair fragment of the cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidase subunit I gene of mitochondrial DNA) were distinct, andeach of the three species was exclusively clustered in a neighbor-joining tree. The limited hybridization among the threespecies indicated by previous studies suggests that DNA barcodes could provide a reliable key for their correctidentification. The implications for the biogeography and speciation of the three parapatric lizard species are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mainland Japan; &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;finitimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latiscutatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Plestiodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okadae&lt;/i&gt;; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mainland Japan</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Taku</firstname>
          <lastname>Okamoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tsutomu</firstname>
          <lastname>Hikida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apocuma &lt;/i&gt;(Cumacea: Bodotriidae): two new species from the West-Atlantic and a significant extension of the known distribution of this genus in the Atlantic Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Apocuma&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerkenae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Apocuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iorgui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Bothspecies were found off the coast of Brazil, but &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gerkenae&lt;/i&gt; was also recorded off the coasts of Georgia and Florida (bothon the Atlantic Ocean and in the Gulf of Mexico). Additionally, specimens of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliense&lt;/i&gt; collected off the coast of Riode Janeiro were examined. These three species differ mainly by (1) the presence / absence of a rudimentary exopod on thethird pereopod of the female, (2) the sculpture of the carapace, and (3) the uropod setation. The distribution of this genusin the Atlantic Ocean is substantially extended based mainly on an unpublished database compiled by the late Norman S. Jones.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apocuma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; distribution; Atlantic Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apocuma&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Roccatagliata</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Natalia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alberico</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>24-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Processa &lt;/i&gt;in the vicinity of Carrie Bow Cay (Belize) with description of a new species (Crustacea: Decapoda: Processidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt; are reported from shallow waters of Belize. &lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manningi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a newmember of the burrow-dwelling group, was most commonly found in burrows of the callianassid &lt;i&gt;Neocallichirus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;grandimana&lt;/i&gt; on a lower intertidal unvegetated sand flat. Both sexes of the new species, sometimes as mated pairs, wereobtained along with the host during sampling of burrows with yabby pumps. &lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bermudensis&lt;/i&gt; (Rankin) and &lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;fimbriata&lt;/i&gt; Manning &amp; Chace occurred frequently in sweep net samples taken nocturnally in seagrass beds, but were alsotaken occasionally from interstices of eroded conch shells and other shallow rubble collected in daylight. Coloration is documented, and its utility as a character discussed. The genus has not been previously reported from Belize.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Processidae; Belize</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sammy</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Darryl.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Felder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus dactylodon &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Decapoda: Pontoniinae), from Heron Island, Queensland, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Pontoniinae) from Heron Island, Queensland, Australia, is described andillustrated. &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dactylodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; an ascidian associate, was collected from a coral reef at 25 m and increases to 17 the number of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; known from Heron Island and to 23 the number of species known from Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dactylodon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Crustacea; Decapoda; Pontoniinae; Heron Island; Great Barrier Reef; Australia; ascidian host</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dactylodon&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the validity of &lt;i&gt;Pelvicachromis sacrimontis &lt;/i&gt;Paulo, 1977 (Perciformes, Cichlidae), with designation of a neotype, and redescription of the species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pelvicachromis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacrimontis&lt;/i&gt; Paulo, 1977 was originally described on the basis of an iconotype in an aquarium journal.Herein, the validity of the name as well as the species status is discussed, an updated diagnosis and description of thespecies is given, and a neotype and a series of paraneotypes is designated. The species differs from congeners in acombination of coloration features including a broad dark midlateral band, the absence of blue and reddish dots in the caudal fin of males, and the specific coloration of the dorsal fin in females.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">type series</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">type series</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anton</firstname>
          <lastname>Lamboj</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <lastname>Pichler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
