<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3439.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Aug. 2012</title>
    <volume>3439</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-08-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Trichobothrial morphology of Theraphosidae and Barychelidae spiders (Araneae, Mygalomorphae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Clavate trichobothria are present on tarsi of all Theraphosidae and some Barychelidae spiders. They are also here reportedon the tibiae of some theraphosids. A comparative analysis of their occurrence is presented. Representatives of allsubfamilies of Barychelidae and Theraphosidae were studied. The following morphological patterns were recognized:filiform, thickened, and clavate. The surface of these trichobothria can be plumose or non-plumose. Five patterns in thedisposition of clavate trichobothria on tarsi, were recognized: 1—two parallel rows; 2—two diverging rows; 3—onenarrow, long median row; 4—one wide central row, intermixed with short covering setae; 5—a short row, restricted to thedistal half of the tarsus. The disposition of trichobothria on tibiae did not differ among the taxa examined, except for thoseon lateral surfaces, where they can form a row or be grouped. Some patterns of morphology and distribution can be usedas diagnoses of subfamilies and genera (e.g., Aviculariinae, &lt;i&gt;Ischnocolus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Heterothele).&lt;/i&gt; The significance of such patterns in systematics is discussed and the usage in phylogeny is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">filiform; thickened; clavate; tarantula; subfamilies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">filiform</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Paulo Leite</middlename>
          <lastname>Guadanucci</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liopropoma randalli, &lt;/i&gt;a new serranid (Teleostei: Perciformes) fish from the Indian Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new serranid fish, &lt;i&gt;Liopropoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;randalli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from four specimens collected from the Indian Ocean offsouthwestern India and eastern Indonesia. It differs from all other species in the genus in its striking color pattern, a broadblack band from behind the eye to the caudal peduncle, semicircular dark-brown to black spots that cover the pink to red-dish body, and a combination of the following characters: 46 to 49 lateral line scales; 1–2 (4 as rudiments) + 12–13 (4–5as rudiments) gill rakers on the first arch (total 17–19); longest dorsal soft ray 2.1–2.3 in head length; 1st anal-fin spine10.4–12.2 in head length; 2nd anal-fin spine 4.4–4.9 in head length; pelvic fin relatively short, 5.1–5.7 in SL; and body depth 3.2–3.6 in SL.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liopropoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;randalli&lt;/i&gt;; Serranidae; Perciformes; Indian Ocean; India; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liopropoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;randalli&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Akhilesh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bineesh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>White</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-50</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">São João del Rei &lt;i&gt;is &lt;/i&gt;the type locality of &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus speluncae &lt;/i&gt;(Aves: Passeriformes: Rhinocryptidae)—a response to Maurício &lt;i&gt;et al&lt;/i&gt;. (2010)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The type locality and the identity of the holotype of the southeast Brazilian endemic &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; (Ménétriés,1835) have attracted considerable recent scrutiny and controversy, based in large part on doubts expressed in theornithological literature concerning some of the same author’s other Brazilian type localities. Most recently, Maurício &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2010) recommended substituting a new type locality, the Serra dos Órgãos, for &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae,&lt;/i&gt; based almost entirely onan analysis of photographs of the holotype. Separately, some of the same authors (Whitney &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2010) described a newspecies, &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrophilus,&lt;/i&gt; including, as a paratype, a specimen from Ménétriés’ original type locality. Our ownknowledge of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; is based on a thorough examination of the holotype and a comprehensive review of all availablehistorical data concerning its collection. Because the holotype itself is partially damaged and the identification of somesoutheast Brazilian &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; is unquestionably difficult using plumage alone (due to intraspecific variation), and furtherbecause all authors agree that only one species of &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; occurs in the environs of São João del Rei, correctlyidentifying the type locality is of overriding importance to ensure the correct nomenclature of the entire species-group ofwhich &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; is the senior synonym. All contemporaneous data (three expedition diaries, the original specimen label,and the original description) clearly demonstrate that Ménétriés collected &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; close to a well-known limestonecave in the region of São João del Rei, in the state of Minas Gerais, on 7 June 1824. Even the bird’s name, &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt;(pertaining to “the cave”) witnesses the validity of these facts. The available historical evidence was dismissed byMaurício &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2010) in clear contravention of the recommendations of Article 76A.1 of the ICZN (1999), which governssuch cases. It is also relevant that all available first-hand information concerning the holotype’s morphology, as well asthe evidence from its topotypes, supports the proposition that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; was collected where Ménétriés claimed. Wefurther demonstrate that: (1) &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; is the name applicable to the paler gray species with buff-fringed blackishfeathers on the flanks, thighs, vent and upper tail coverts; (2) &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrophilus&lt;/i&gt; must be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae;&lt;/i&gt; (3)the only historical argument presented by Maurício &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2010) &lt;i&gt;contra&lt;/i&gt; the type locality is based on an unrepresentativetranslation; and (4) their morphological analysis uses incomplete, contradictory or misleading data, and focuses onsearching for specimens similar to the paler gray &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; within the variation of the dark gray &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notorius,&lt;/i&gt; in order tojustify emending the type locality. Crucially, none of these specimens of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notorius&lt;/i&gt; is apparently similar to the holotype and topotypes of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt; in respect to all of the latter’s distinguishing characters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; type locality; &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrophilus&lt;/i&gt;; synonymization</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;speluncae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcos</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Raposo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guy</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kirwan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Loskot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claydson</firstname>
          <middlename>Pinto</middlename>
          <lastname>De Assis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: Anker, A. (2011) “Four new infaunal decapod crustaceans (Caridea: Alpheidae and Gebiidea: Axianassidae) from Lizard Island, Australia, one of them also occurring in Moorea, French Polynesia”. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2734, 1–22. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
