<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3441.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Aug. 2012</title>
    <volume>3441</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new shrew of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cryptotis &lt;/i&gt;(Mammalia: Soricomorpha: Soricidae) from the Sierra de Aroa, an isolated mountain range in northwestern Venezuela, with remarks on biogeography and conservation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In South America, shrews of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cryptotis&lt;/i&gt; have a primarily Andean distribution. Based on specimens from the non-Andean Sierra de Aroa in Venezuela, we name &lt;i&gt;Cryptotis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aroensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., which we assign to the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomasi&lt;/i&gt; group of thegenus owing to its possession of characters that include a relatively large body size, luxuriant fur, moderately enlargedforefeet with elongated and narrow claws, unicuspid teeth relatively narrow and concave on the posteroventral margin,ectoloph of first upper molar with the anterior element reduced relatively to the posterior element, and mandible with thearticular process not robust, high, and broad, and with the coronoid process joining the ramus at a low angle. The newspecies can be differentiated from other members of the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomasi&lt;/i&gt; group on the basis of its possession of a uniquecombination of characters, that include a rich grayish brown pelage, a narrow palate at the level of the second upper molars(no overlap in this measurement observed with 146 specimens of 10 other species of the group), nasal cavity and ethmo-turbinals partially visible in occlusal view of palate, lacrimal foramina wide and deep, tympanic process of petromastoidsshowing a minute foramen, unicuspid teeth with posterolingual cuspules, fourth unicuspid tooth labially placed, thirdupper molar complex and nearly as wide as the second upper molar, and bicuspulate lower incisors. The new species isknown from only 3 specimens obtained at the type locality, which is in a pristine patch of cloud forest at elevation 1730m, and represents the first mammalian taxon known to be endemic to the Sierra de Aroa, a small and isolated mountainrange that was previously reported to possess numerous biotic elements that are either exclusive, or shared with the muchlarger Cordillera de la Costa to the east. The clear morphological differentiation of the new species with respect to itsAndean relatives suggests that its ancestors colonized the Sierra de Aroa several glacial maxima ago, when montanevegetation belts were lower than today. The presumably optimal habitat of the new species (cloud forests of the Sierra deAroa above 1500 m) covers less than 40 km2 , and is threatened by deforestation and global climate change. Therefore, thenew species can be categorized as endangered by application of criteria B2a and E of the current “Red List Categories and Criteria” of the International Union for Conservation of Nature.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">climate change; elevation shifts; mountain endemics; Yaracuy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">climate change</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcial</firstname>
          <lastname>Quiroga-Carmona</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jesús</firstname>
          <lastname>Molinari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea, Amphipoda, Phliantidae) from Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; are described and compared with the only previously known species from thisgenus, &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olono&lt;/i&gt; J.L. Barnard, 1972. Different from this species, the dorsum of &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gabiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; doesnot have a carina. &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kerstinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has a dorsal carina, but it is very shallow on pereonite 1, whereas &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olono&lt;/i&gt;has a large mid-dorsal process on pereonite 1. All three species can also be distinguished from each other by characteristics on antenna 1.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Phliantidae; &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gabiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kerstinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gabophlias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olono&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; coral rubble; algae; shallow water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ch.</firstname>
          <middlename>Oliver</middlename>
          <lastname>Coleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-35</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus nucleocondensus &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Haemosporida, Haemoproteidae) from a Eurasian sogbird, the Great Reed Warbler &lt;i&gt;Acrocephalus arundinaceus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Parahaemoproteus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleocondensus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Haemosporida, Haemoproteidae) is described from aEurasian songbird, the Great Reed Warbler &lt;i&gt;Acrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arundinaceus&lt;/i&gt; based on the morphology of its blood stages andpartial sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene. Transmission of this haemoproteid occurs in Africa, where theGreat Reed Warblers are infected. Due to unclear reasons, its transmission does not occur at European breeding groundsof this bird, resulting in absence of the parasites in juvenile birds before and during seasonal migration. &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;nucleocondensus&lt;/i&gt; can be readily distinguished from other avian haemoproteids by tiny, compact microgametocyte nucleithat are significantly smaller than macrogametocyte nuclei, a rare character of haemosporidian parasites. By thismorphological feature, the new species is similar to &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;payevskyi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micronuclearis,&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleofascialis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleocondensus&lt;/i&gt; can be readily distinguished from both &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;payevskyi&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micronuclearis,&lt;/i&gt; primarily due to its numerous growing gametocytes (size greater than erythrocyte nuclei), which donot touch the envelope of erythrocytes along their entire margin; such gametocytes do not develop in &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;payevskyi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micronuclearis,&lt;/i&gt; but present in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleofascialis.&lt;/i&gt; However, microgametocyte nuclei are band-like inshape in the latter parasite; that is not a case in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleocondensus.&lt;/i&gt; Illustrations of blood stages of the new species aregiven, and morphological and phylogenetic analyses identify the DNA lineages that are associated with these parasites.Genetic distance between cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene sequences of the new species and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;payevskyi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micronuclearis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;nucleofascialis&lt;/i&gt; is 4.4%, 5.9%, and 8.1%, respectively. Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene sequences (GenBank no. JX026901) can be used for bar-coding in studies of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nucleocondensus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">avian haemosporidians; &lt;i&gt;Haemoproteus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Acrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arundinaceus&lt;/i&gt;; microscopy; PCR; barcoding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">avian haemosporidians</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Asta</firstname>
          <lastname>Križanauskienė</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tatjana</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Iezhova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vaidas</firstname>
          <lastname>Palinauskas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nikita</firstname>
          <lastname>Chernetsov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gediminas</firstname>
          <lastname>Valkiūnas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-46</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Coboldus chazaroi&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of iphimediid amphipod (Amphipoda, Gammaridea, Iphimediidae) from a submarine cave, north Cuba</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The amphipods of &lt;i&gt;Coboldus&lt;/i&gt; are considered as antipolar members of iphimediids with loss of a maxilla 1 palp article 2. Anew amphipod species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Coboldus&lt;/i&gt; (Family Iphimediidae) collected from soft bottom in a submarine cave,Northern Cuba, is described. &lt;i&gt;Coboldus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chazaroi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; differs from all other known species by the following characters:pereonal dorsal processes bifid and equal in length, coxa 1 ventrally acute and bifid, article 5 of gnathopod 2 longer than6, dactylus longer than palm, posterior margin of pleonal epimeron 3 with 3 teeth, mandibular palp article 2 with 1 subdistal plumose seta, molar poorly developed with 1 basal seta, lacinia mobilis rectangular and finely serrate.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Peracarida; Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Coboldus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Cuba</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Peracarida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Ortiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ignacio</firstname>
          <lastname>Winfield</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Varela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-55</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Hylarana darlingi &lt;/i&gt;Boulenger 1902 (Anura: Ranidae) from the Mulanje Area, Malawi</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Werner</firstname>
          <lastname>Conradie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Denis</firstname>
          <lastname>Tweddle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tuuli</firstname>
          <lastname>Mäkinen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <lastname>Bills</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-58</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Adelophryne &lt;/i&gt;Hoogmoed and Lescure 1984 (Amphibia: Anura: Eleutherodactylidae) from the Atlantic rainforest of southern Bahia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Adelophryne&lt;/i&gt; for the municipalities of Ilhéus, Itacaré and Una, Bahia state, Brazil (typelocality: Reserva Particular do Patrimônio Natural Nova Angélica, municipality of Una, state of Bahia, Brazil,15º15’03.2” S, 39º04’51.0” W, 79 m elevation). This new species is characterized by having small size, anal flap, andpointed tips of all fingers. The advertisement call consists of a single note with average duration of 29.5 ms (22–34 ms).The new species was found under dense leaf litter in primary and disturbed ombrofilous Atlantic rainforest, but in lower abundance in the latter and exclusively in shaded areas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Atlantic rainforest; Advertisement call; Morphology; Natural history</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Lourenço-De-Moraes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mirco</firstname>
          <lastname>Solé</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luís</firstname>
          <middlename>Felipe</middlename>
          <lastname>Toledo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-08-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
