<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3479.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Sep. 2012</title>
    <volume>3479</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the families, genera and species of Dicyemida Van Beneden, 1876 </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The classification of the species in the phylum Dicyemida Van Beneden, 1876, a group of small organisms whichparasitise the renal appendages of benthic cephalopods, is reviewed. While dicyemid parasites have simple multicellularmorphology, their lifecycle is complex and it is uncertain whether their affinities are with the protozoans or metazoans.Hence they are commonly given an intermediate ‘mesozoan’ status. Although 112 species are described, confusion existsfor 20% of the taxa over the validity of certain families, genera and species, which has been attributed to incomplete andinformation-poor descriptions, loss of type specimens, errors in taxonomy and conceptual differences. The history ofdicyemids dating from the first known reference by Filippo Calvolini of Italy in 1787 is presented, along with thecharacteristics which are commonly used to classify genera and species. All species described to date are listed withreference to the original published records and the validity of ambiguous records is explored. A way forward usingalternative technologies such as molecular genetic methods based on next generation sequencing platforms is suggested,which may help to address unresolved systematic and life history questions surrounding this parasite group. This review aims to assist taxonomists to help unravel the confusion surrounding the poorly studied and little understood Dicyemida.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">classification; taxonomy; Mesozoa; parasite; Mollusca; Cephalopoda; kidneys</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">classification</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sarah</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Catalano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Blattisocius &lt;/i&gt;(Acari, Blattisociidae) species from Brazil, with description of a new species, redescription of &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius keegani &lt;/i&gt;and a key for the separation of the world species of the genus </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fifteen species have been placed in &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius&lt;/i&gt; Keegan of which only three were previously reported from Brazil. Thesemites are found in several different habitats and often mentioned as predators of pests of stored food. In this work,specimens of this genus collected from commercial dog food in Brazil were determined as a new species which is heredescribed as &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;everti&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and the closely related &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;keegani&lt;/i&gt; Fox, here redescribed. Subsequently,other specimens of &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius&lt;/i&gt; deposited in the mite collection of “Departamento de Entomologia e Acarologia of EscolaSuperior de Agricultura “Luiz de Queiroz”, Universidade de São Paulo” were examined and identified. Finally, adichotomous key to separate the world species of &lt;i&gt;Blattisocius&lt;/i&gt; was elaborated based on the examination of the specimens at hand and on the descriptions and redescriptions of other species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; predator; stored food</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Erika</firstname>
          <middlename>P. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Britto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paula</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lopes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gilberto</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Moraes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-51</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new larval species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Erythraeus &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Erythraeus&lt;/i&gt;) (Acari: Erythraeidae) from Iran </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Erythraeus&lt;/i&gt; are described from western Iran: &lt;i&gt;Erythraeus&lt;/i&gt; (Erythraeus) &lt;i&gt;populi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;from pear lace bug, &lt;i&gt;Stephanitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyri&lt;/i&gt; F. (Heteroptera: Tingidae), and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; (E.) &lt;i&gt;chrysoperlae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from a green lacewing,&lt;i&gt;Chrysoperla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolthoffi&lt;/i&gt; (Navas) (Neuroptera: Chrysopidae). A key to the Iranian larval species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Erythraeus&lt;/i&gt; (Erythraeus) is given, as is data on leg setae and measurements for all 44 species of the subgenus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mite; ectoparasite; &lt;i&gt;Erythraeus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new host</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <lastname>Khanjani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ali-Naghi</firstname>
          <lastname>Mirmoayedi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bahman</firstname>
          <middlename>Asali</middlename>
          <lastname>Fayaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tahereh</firstname>
          <lastname>Sharifian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Zoogeography of the echiuran fauna of the East Pacific Ocean (Phylum: Echiura) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This report provides a checklist of the echiuran fauna of the East Pacific Ocean and analyses their distribution. All thespecies are mapped and keys for their identification are provided. Currently the echiuran fauna of the East Pacificcomprises three families, 9 genera and 17 species. The family Bonelliidae contains two genera and three species, theUrechidae has a single genus with two species, and the Echiuridae contains six genera and 12 species. This investigationshows that the East Pacific has a very low species diversity comprising only about 10% of the world fauna. Of the recordedspecies in the East Pacific, 12 are found in the North Pacific, four are circumtropical and only two species are found in theSouth Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Ochetostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baronii&lt;/i&gt; is the only species considered to be cosmopolitan and eleven species appear to be endemic to the Eastern Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Zoogeography; Echiura; East Pacific Ocean; Bonelliidae; Urechidae; Echiuridae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Zoogeography</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ramlall</firstname>
          <lastname>Biseswar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>69-76</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Protoblepharon mccoskeri&lt;/i&gt;, a new flashlight fish from eastern Taiwan (Teleostei: Anomalopidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new flashlight fish of the genus &lt;i&gt;Protoblepharon&lt;/i&gt; is described based on a large male specimen collected from easternTaiwan, northwestern Pacific Ocean. It differs from the only congener, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosenblatti,&lt;/i&gt; in having the following characters:a smaller light organ with a larger cup; a deeper body; a strongly convex dorsal profile; a smaller and anterior placed pelvicfin, the appressed fin reaching to the midpoint between origins of pelvic and anal fins; a smaller pectoral fin, the apressedfin not reaching the lateral line; second dorsal-fin spine the longest; a shorter snout; a smaller eye; about 30 scale rows between first dorsal-fin base and lateral line; and more than 260 scale rows along the body axis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pisces; Beryciformes; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pisces</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hsuan-Ching</firstname>
          <lastname>Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>David</middlename>
          <lastname>Johnson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>77-87</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">LUCAS SILVEIRA ANTONIETTO, CLÁUDIA PINTO MACHADO, DERMEVAL APARECIDO DO CARMO &amp; JOSÉ WILSON CORREA ROSA (2012) Recent Ostracoda (Arthropoda, Crustacea) from São Pedro-São Paulo Archipelago, Brazil: a preliminary approach. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3335, 29–53. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
