<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3480.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Sep. 2012</title>
    <volume>3480</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of &lt;i&gt;Ancorina, Stryphnus&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Ecionemia &lt;/i&gt;(Demospongiae, Astrophorida, Ancorinidae), with descriptions of new species from New Zealand waters </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New collections of New Zealand ancorinid sponges with sanidasters, regular and sanidaster-like microrhabds, andamphiaster-like microscleres, has prompted us to review the integrity of ancorinid genera &lt;i&gt;Ancorina&lt;/i&gt; Schmidt, &lt;i&gt;Ecionemia&lt;/i&gt;Bowerbank, and &lt;i&gt;Stryphnus&lt;/i&gt; Sollas (Demospongiae, Astrophorida, Ancorinidae). The varietal name in &lt;i&gt;Ancorina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;progressa&lt;/i&gt;(von Lendenfeld 1907) var. &lt;i&gt;diplococcus&lt;/i&gt; Dendy, 1924 has been elevated to full species status, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stalagmoides&lt;/i&gt; (Dendy,1924) has been redescribed. Two new species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Three Kings Islands, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;globosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt;from Campbell Rise, have been described. Two New Zealand species previously assigned to &lt;i&gt;Ancorina&lt;/i&gt; by Dendy (1924)have been transferred to &lt;i&gt;Ecionemia:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alata&lt;/i&gt; (Dendy 1924) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novaezelandiae&lt;/i&gt; (Dendy 1924). The genus &lt;i&gt;Stryphnus&lt;/i&gt; isrecorded for the first time in New Zealand waters, and 6 new species are described here; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;poculum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novaezealandiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelunca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atypicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Specimens identified as &lt;i&gt;Asteropus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt;(Carter 1879) by Dendy (1924) and Bergquist (1968), a genus without triaenes, have been transferred to &lt;i&gt;Stryphnus&lt;/i&gt; and renamed as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ariena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; as all specimens contained rare triaenes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michelle</firstname>
          <lastname>Kelly</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carina</firstname>
          <lastname>Sim-Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-47</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of cave catfish from Brazil, &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus rubbioli &lt;/i&gt;sp.n., from Serra do Ramalho karstic area, São Francisco River basin, Bahia State (Silurifomes: Trichomycteridae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubbioli,&lt;/i&gt; herein described, is a new species from the limestone caves of the Água Clara system from theSerra do Ramalho karstic area, southwest of Bahia State, north-eastern Brazil. The new species is diagnosed by the com-bination of the following non-exclusive characters: highly reduced skin pigmentation; reduced eyes, externally visible assmall black or reddish-brown spots; long barbels, especially the nasal (86.9–127.1% of head length) and maxillary (98.1–129.3% of head length); and pectoral-fin ray count reaching I, 9. The troglobitic status is suggested by the presence oftroglomorphisms on an advanced degree, especially the reduction of skin pigmentation and the regression of the eyes, be-sides the absence of individuals in superficial drainages of the region. Population densities, recorded on two occasions,were extremely low. &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubbioli&lt;/i&gt; occurs in water bodies formed by infiltration in the rock, and, because of this, it must be considered fragile and as a priority in conservation programs of Brazilian karstic areas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New cavefish; troglobite; subterranean ichthyofauna; north-eastern Brazil; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New cavefish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Elina</middlename>
          <lastname>Bichuette</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>Pereira</middlename>
          <lastname>Rizzato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-66</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Areopaguriste&lt;/i&gt;s Rahayu &amp; McLaughlin, 2010 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Diogenidae) discovered in the Mesoamerican Barrier Reef of Belize, Caribbean Sea </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of hermit crab, &lt;i&gt;Areopaguristes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tudgei,&lt;/i&gt; family Diogenidae, is fully described and illustrated, including acolor photograph. A dense population of this new species was discovered living intertidally in a concealed habitat undercoral boulders covered with calcareous algae, on the crest to fore-reef zone in Carrie Bow Cay, a small island located onthe western Caribbean Mesoamerican Barrier Reef of Belize. This new species, the 24rd of &lt;i&gt;Areopaguristes&lt;/i&gt; Rahayu &amp;McLaughlin, 2010, and fourth known in this genus from the western Atlantic, is superficially similar to those of the&lt;i&gt;Paguristes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortugae&lt;/i&gt; complex. As in species of that complex, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tudgei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. has dense plumose setation on the chelipeds,and at least in females, a fringe of plumose setae on the dorsolateral margins of the chelae, and on the dorsal margins ofthe walking legs. The presence in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tudgei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. of this setal arrangement, previously considered the only definingcharacter of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortugae&lt;/i&gt; complex, can be attributed to convergence. The new species is contrasted with all other westernAtlantic congeners, and a key is presented to aid in their identification. A list of all western Atlantic species of &lt;i&gt;Paguristes&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato and their current generic assignments is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Anomura; Diogenidae; &lt;i&gt;Areopaguristes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paguristes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortugae&lt;/i&gt; complex; new species; Mesoamerican Barrier Reef; Belize</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <lastname>Lemaitre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Darryl</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Felder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-79</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the previously unknown advertisement calls of &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium fragile, H. pellucidum&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Vitreorana antisthenesi &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Centrolenidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We provide for the first time detailed descriptions of the advertisement calls of three species of glassfrogs of the familyCentrolenidae. The call of &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pellucidum&lt;/i&gt; is a single, high-pitched tonal note, lacking amplitudemodulation, lasting 0.12–0.18 s, and with a dominant frequency of 4863.54–5408.68 Hz. The call of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragile&lt;/i&gt; is alsocomposed of a single tonal note, lasting 0.12–0.15 s, with a dominant frequency of 3774.78–3931.89 Hz; however, thecall of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragile&lt;/i&gt; exhibits amplitude modulation that resembles the shape of a Goldfish cracker when visualized as anoscillogram. The call of &lt;i&gt;Vitreorana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antisthenesi&lt;/i&gt; consists of a single note of modulated pulses that decrease in energy,lasting 0.03–0.05 s, and with a dominant frequency of 5345.44–5484.73 Hz. We compare these three calls to those of congeneric species in a phylogenetic context.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">advertisement call; bioacoustics; glassfrogs; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fragile&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hyalinobatrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pellucidum&lt;/i&gt;; Peru; Venezuela; &lt;i&gt;Vitreorana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antisthenesi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">advertisement call</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>April</firstname>
          <lastname>Wen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Neida</firstname>
          <lastname>Vasquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Santiago</firstname>
          <lastname>Castroviejo-Fisher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>80-87</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">KIRSTEN E. NICHOLSON, BRIAN I. CROTHER, CRAIG GUYER &amp; JAY M. SAVAGE (2012) It is time for a new classification of anoles (Squamata: Dactyloidae). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3477, 1–108.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-09-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
