<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3512.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Oct. 2012</title>
    <volume>3512</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescriptions and descriptions of new species of &lt;i&gt;Austrostrongylus &lt;/i&gt;Chandler, 1924 (Nematoda: Trichostrongylina), from Australian marsupials with a comparative study of features of the synlophe </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Redescriptions are provided of &lt;i&gt;Austrostrongylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aggregatus&lt;/i&gt; Johnston &amp; Mawson, 1940, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chandleri&lt;/i&gt; Mawson, 1973, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;macropodis&lt;/i&gt; Chandler, 1924, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;victoriensis&lt;/i&gt; Cassone, 1983 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wallabiae&lt;/i&gt; Johnston &amp; Mawson, 1939 from macropodidmarsupials from eastern Australia. Two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mawsonae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Wallabia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt;(Desmarest) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smalesae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Macropus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufogriseus&lt;/i&gt; (Desmarest), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuliginosus&lt;/i&gt; (Desmarest), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giganteus&lt;/i&gt;Shaw and &lt;i&gt;W.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; (Desmarest). &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paratypicus&lt;/i&gt; Mawson, 1973 is treated as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macropodis.&lt;/i&gt; The synlopheis described from serial transverse sections of males and females of each species and the origins and terminations of thecuticular ridges documented for use in specific identification. Females of some species could be distinguished only bydifferences in the synlophe. The geographical and host ranges of all know species are expanded based on newercollections. Based on a study of seven species, comments are provided on the remaining congeners. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrogale&lt;/i&gt;Beveridge &amp; Durette-Desset, 1986 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;safestatus&lt;/i&gt; Beveridge &amp; Durette-Desset, 1986 are removed to the genus&lt;i&gt;Sutarostrongylus&lt;/i&gt; Beveridge &amp; Durette-Desset, 1986 as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrogale&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;safestatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Keys are provided to males based on the features of the spicules and to females based on features of the synlophe.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; Trichostrongylina; Herpetostrongylidae; &lt;i&gt;Austrostrongylus&lt;/i&gt;; redescriptions; new species; synlophe</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Durette-Desset</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Beveridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-41</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Epictia munoai &lt;/i&gt;(Orejas-Miranda, 1961) (Squamata: Serpentes: Leptotyphlopidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The wormsnakes Leptotyphlopidae include the smallest and thinnest snakes of the world. This group has historically fewtaxonomic studies and the descriptions of taxa in general are superficial, frequently preventing an accurate identification.This family includes the genus &lt;i&gt;Epictia&lt;/i&gt; with many representatives with taxonomic major issues, including &lt;i&gt;Epictia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munoai.&lt;/i&gt;We redescribe and compare &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munoai&lt;/i&gt; with other related cisandine species in order to evaluate its taxonomic status con-sidering the morphological analysis of specimens. A table with some diagnostic characters of each species is presented.&lt;i&gt;Epictia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munoai&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from other related species mostly by low number of middorsal and midventral scales, and is distributed in coastal areas in southern Brazil, Uruguay and northeastern Argentina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scolecophidia; wormsnakes; Epictini; redescription; geographic variation; Cisandine species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scolecophidia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bárbara</firstname>
          <middlename>Cristina S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Francisco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberta</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Strabomantidae) from the Cordillera de Carpish in central Peru (Departamento de Huánuco) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new species of &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; from cloud forests of the Cordillera de Carpish, Departamento de Huánuco incentral Peru, increasing the number of currently known &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; to 23. &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interstinctus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described basedon one female (SVL 23.8 mm) and two males (SVL 14.9–16.5 mm). Specimens were found between 3100 and 3180 melevation. This species has weakly developed dorsolateral folds, minute dentigerous processes of vomers, no tympanum,and coloration in life consisting of a reddish-brown, dark grayish-brown or olive-brown dorsum, a black venter with whiteblotches and flecks, and a black groin with large white blotches that are partially pale salmon. &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vestigiatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a single female (SVL 18.8 mm) specimen that was found at 3100 m elevation. This species hasprominent, discontinuous, undulated dorsolateral folds, a X-shaped ridge in occipital region, a middorsal Y-shaped ridge,short postocular folds, minute dentigerous processes of vomers, no tympanum, and a coloration in life consisting of a creamish-brown dorsum, a dark brown venter with white spots, and a dark brown groin with red blotches.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; Andes frogs; amphibia; &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interstinctus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Phrynopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vestigiatus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Edgar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anahí</firstname>
          <lastname>Oróz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-63</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina &lt;/i&gt;(Siluriformes: Neoplecostominae) from Rio São Francisco basin </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pareiorhina&lt;/i&gt; (Neoplecostominae) from the Rio São Francisco basin, Minas Gerais State, Brazil, is de-scribed. The new species is distinguished from its congeners (Pareiorhina &lt;i&gt;brachyrhyncha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carrancas,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudolphi)&lt;/i&gt;by traits related to small plates covered with odontodes randomly distributed on the abdomen, minute lateral cusps on theteeth, pointed odontodes covering pectoral, pelvic, and anal-fin first rays, caudal-fin being completely dark with one hy-aline bar, absence of a ridge on the postdorsal surface of trunk, shape of premaxillae and dentaries, and by the absence of odontodes at the ventral tip of the snout.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cascudinhos; catfish; freshwater; Loricariidae; Neotropical region; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cascudinhos</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fábio</firstname>
          <middlename>Fernandes</middlename>
          <lastname>Roxo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gabriel</firstname>
          <lastname>De Souza Da Costa E Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mahmoud</firstname>
          <lastname>Mehanna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-74</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new fossil echinoids (Echinodermata: Echinoidea) from the Early Hauterivian (Early Cretaceous) of the Paris Basin (France) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new echinoid genera and species, &lt;i&gt;Salvaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roberti&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Pygolampas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edita&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov. are de-scribed. They were collected in the Calcaires à Spatangues Formation (CSF) that consists of limestone and clay sedimentsdeposited in the southeast of the Paris Basin (France) during the Early Hauterivian (Early Cretaceous). The CSF is datedfrom the &lt;i&gt;Acanthodiscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radiatus&lt;/i&gt; chronozone, a time-interval of overall high sea level in Western Europe, but it yields arich shallow-water fossil fauna mostly represented by benthic invertebrates. Of the 54 echinoid species ever described inthe CSF, 26 species are recognized here. They are distributed into 16 different families, among which regular (13 species)and irregular (13 species) echinoids are represented in equal proportion. This work confirms the high level of echinoid diversity in the CSF for that time-period.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hauterivian; Holasteroida; Cassiduloida; systematics; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hauterivian</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Saucède</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean-Christophe</firstname>
          <lastname>Dudicourt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <lastname>Courville</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>75-88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
