<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3523.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Oct. 2012</title>
    <volume>3523</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tanaidacea (Tanaidacea: Crustacea) from Brazil. IV. A new genus and two new species from the family Leptocheliidae </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study is based on the material collected from REVIZEE Program and under the Petrobrás oil-exploration programs.These collections revealed a number of representatives from the family Leptocheliidae in its broadest sense, with descrip-tions of one new genus, &lt;i&gt;Makraleptochelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; and two new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;potiguara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Intermedichelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jesseri&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; The new genus appears to be closely related to &lt;i&gt;Konarus-Parakonarus-Pseudoleptochelia&lt;/i&gt; complex of species anddiffers mainly in the extremely elongated habitus of the male. &lt;i&gt;Intermedichelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jesseri&lt;/i&gt; is only the second recorded speciesof this genus and is separated from the other species by having two distal simple setae on the lateral projections of pere-onite 3, two distal simple setae on the maxilliped basis, one ventrodistal spiniform seta on the merus-carpus-propodus ofpereopod 3, and pereopods 4 and 5 propodus with one dorsodistal simple seta marginally longer than dactylus and unguis combined. &lt;i&gt;Intermedichelia&lt;/i&gt; is here included in the family Leptocheliidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustaceans; Tanaidaceans; REVIZEE Program; Leptocheliidae; &lt;i&gt;Makraleptochelia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Intermedichelia&lt;/i&gt;; northeastern coast of Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustaceans</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Catarina</firstname>
          <lastname>De L. Araújo-Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kim</firstname>
          <lastname>Larsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Opistognathus pardus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of jawfish (Teleostei: Opistognathidae) from the Western Indian Ocean </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of jawfish, &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pardus,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on a single specimen, 98.8 mm SL, recently collectedfrom the Western Indian Ocean off Quilon (Kerala), India. The combination of a rigid maxilla without flexible lamina pos-teriorly, a unique color pattern in which most of the head is covered with small, irregular-shaped, dark spots, dorsal-finrays XI, 11, and the outermost segmented pelvic-fin ray tightly bound to adjacent ray, with the interradial membrane notincised distally distinguishes the new species from other congeners. This is the fourth species of &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt; known from the coast of India or Sri Lanka. A range extension for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrolepis&lt;/i&gt; is also reported.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Jawfish; &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Jawfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith-Vaniz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bineesh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Akhilesh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-24</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa &lt;/i&gt;McIntosh, 1885 (Polychaeta, Polynoidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Long-bodied polynoids, like &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; McIntosh, 1885 and similar species which are often associated with cold-water corals, are regularly reported from Antarctic, Subantarctic and adjacent cold-temperate waters. The taxonomy ofthese species is confused and has been subject to various discussions in the past. For the revision presented here weexamined the available type material and additional specimens of the following species: &lt;i&gt;Polynoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; Kinberg,1858, &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; McIntosh, 1885, &lt;i&gt;Enipo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhombigera&lt;/i&gt; Ehlers, 1908, &lt;i&gt;Hololepidella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flynni&lt;/i&gt; Benham, 1921, &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;dubia&lt;/i&gt; Hartmann-Schröder, 1965, &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monroi&lt;/i&gt; Averincev, 1978, and &lt;i&gt;Polynoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thouarellicola&lt;/i&gt; Hartmann-Schröder,1989. As a result we consider &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; McIntosh, 1885, &lt;i&gt;Parapolyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flynni&lt;/i&gt; (Benham, 1921) n. comb., and&lt;i&gt;Neopolynoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; (Kinberg, 1858) n. comb. as valid species. &lt;i&gt;Enipo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhombigera&lt;/i&gt; Ehlers, 1908, &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia&lt;/i&gt;Hartmann-Schröder, 1965, and &lt;i&gt;Polynoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thouarellicola&lt;/i&gt; Hartmann-Schröder, 1989 are junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;laevis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monroi&lt;/i&gt; Averincev, 1978 is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Hololepidella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flynni&lt;/i&gt; Benham, 1921 for which the newgenus &lt;i&gt;Parapolyeunoa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;n.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gen.&lt;/i&gt; is erected. &lt;i&gt;Polynoe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; Kinberg, 1858 is transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Neopolynoe&lt;/i&gt;Loshamn, 1981 and represents the third known species within this genus. Three comprehensive tables illustrating the distinctive characters of the considered genera and species are given to facilitate the identification of the valid species.&lt;b&gt;Keywordstaxonomy,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polyeunoa,&lt;/i&gt; Parapolyeunoa &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neopolynoe,&lt;/i&gt; Southern Ocean, SOAP workshop, cold-water corals</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ruth</firstname>
          <lastname>Barnich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Cristina</middlename>
          <lastname>Gambi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dieter</firstname>
          <lastname>Fiege</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-38</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon &lt;/i&gt;(Cnidaria, Hydrozoa) in the southwestern Atlantic Ocean, with a revision of the species recorded from the area </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; includes seven species, two of which (H. &lt;i&gt;prolifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicus)&lt;/i&gt; have been recorded in the south-western Atlantic. These reports were based on the medusa stage and only a few diagnostic characters were described, ren-dering some of these records rather doubtful. Additionally, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prolifer&lt;/i&gt; has a boreal distribution, suggesting that the reportsof this species from the southern hemisphere could correspond to other &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; species. Recently, we sampled benthicand planktonic specimens of &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; in the southwestern Atlantic and two species were identified: polyps andmedusae of &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; Hartlaub, 1905, and medusae of &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicus&lt;/i&gt; (Browne, 1902). These samples al-lowed us to review and discuss the geographical distribution and validity of previous records of &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; species forthis area. We conclude that &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicus&lt;/i&gt; are the only &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; species presently known for the southwestern Atlantic Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hydroid; hydromedusa; taxonomy; geographical distribution; Tubulariidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hydroid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carolina</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodriguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thaís</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miranda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hermes</firstname>
          <lastname>Mianzan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gabriel</firstname>
          <lastname>Genzano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola &lt;/i&gt;Miranda-Ribeiro, 1926 (Anura: Leiuperidae) from the state of Mato Grosso, Brazil, with comments on the geographic distribution of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola canga &lt;/i&gt;Giaretta &amp; Kokubum, 2003 </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; is described from the state of Mato Grosso, western Brazil. The new species inhabitsthe transition zone between Brazilian Cerrado and Amazon rainforest in northern Mato Grosso, and is characterized by itsmedium size (snout-vent length 12–17 mm), lack of T-shaped terminal phalanges, toe tips not expanded laterally, presenceof two antebrachial tubercles, and smooth upper eyelids. The advertisement call of the new species consists of a seriescomposed of 11–74 non-pulsed notes. Mean dominant frequency is 3938 Hz. Each note presents a slight ascendantfrequency modulation in its first half, and another ascendant modulation in its last half. We also present new data on the distribution and conservation status of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canga.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; advertisement call; geographic distribution; new species; &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <lastname>Pansonato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dráusio</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morais</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robson</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ávila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kawashita-Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christine</firstname>
          <lastname>Strüssmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Itamar</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the nursery-web spider genus &lt;i&gt;Hypsithylla &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1903 (Araneae: Pisauridae) and its synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Hygropoda &lt;/i&gt;Thorell, 1894 </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Estevam</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Cruz</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-63</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Dates of publication and the organisation of &lt;i&gt;Versuch einer Naturgeschichte der Krabben und Krebse &lt;/i&gt;by Johann Friedrich Wilhelm Herbst </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martyn</firstname>
          <middlename>E. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Low</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription and notes on the reproductive biology of the sea anemone &lt;i&gt;Urticina fecunda &lt;/i&gt;(Verrill, 1899), comb. nov. (Cnidaria: Actiniaria: Actiniidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The externally brooding sea anemone &lt;i&gt;Epiactis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fecunda&lt;/i&gt; (Verrill, 1899) is redescribed as &lt;i&gt;Urticina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fecunda,&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov., onthe basis of preserved type material and anatomical and behavioural observations of recently collected animals. The sea-sonal timing of reproduction and aspects of the settlement and development of brooded offspring are reported. Preciselocality data extend the bathymetric range to waters as shallow as 10 m, and the geographical range east to the AvalonPeninsula (Newfoundland, Canada). We differentiate it from other known northern, externally brooding species of seaanemone. Morphological characters, including verrucae, decamerous mesenterial arrangement, and non-overlapping sizesof basitrichs in tentacles and actinopharynx, agree with a generic diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Urticina&lt;/i&gt; Ehrenberg, 1834 rather than &lt;i&gt;Epiactis&lt;/i&gt; Verrill, 1869.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brooding; &lt;i&gt;Epiactis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Epigonactis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brooding</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Larson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean-François</firstname>
          <lastname>Hamel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annie</firstname>
          <lastname>Mercier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>69-79</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of Indo-Pacific fish, &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster criobe&lt;/i&gt;, with comments on other &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster &lt;/i&gt;(Tetraodontiformes: Tetraodontidae) at the Gambier Archipelago </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the tetraodontid fish genus &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt; was discovered during a recent expedition to theGambier Archipelago, French Polynesia. The new species, named &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criobe&lt;/i&gt; herein, is the only knownspecies of &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt; having 12–14 brown stripes along the body (stripes beginning in front of the eye,extending along the body, and abruptly ending at the base of the caudal fin). It also has 17 pectoral rays, the originof the anal fin inserts posterior to a vertical from the rear base of the dorsal fin and lacks spots on the caudal fin.&lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criobe&lt;/i&gt; is currently known from a single specimen collected at the Gambier Archipelago. It appearsto be most similar to the white-spotted &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janthinoptera,&lt;/i&gt; a wide-ranging, Indo-Pacific species, which also inhabitsthe Gambier Archipelago, and to the Hawaiian endemic &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jactator&lt;/i&gt; forming a species complex that exhibitsincomplete lineage sorting. Specimens of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;axiologus,&lt;/i&gt; or an undescribed but very similar sibling species, werealso collected at the Gambier Archipelago. Molecular analysis of these samples reveals an affiliation with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;axiologus&lt;/i&gt; specimens collected from disjunct localities in the western Central Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;axiologus&lt;/i&gt; wasnot previously known to occur east of the Tonga Islands. Geographic range expansions are also reported for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapaensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amboinensis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Tetraodontidae; &lt;i&gt;Canthigaster&lt;/i&gt;; new species; French Polynesia; Gambier Archipelago</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Erwan</firstname>
          <lastname>Delrieu-Trottin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Serge</firstname>
          <lastname>Planes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>80-88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
