<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3532.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Oct. 2012</title>
    <volume>3532</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nematodes from galls on Myrtaceae. III. &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia &lt;/i&gt;from flower bud and stigma galls on &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt;, with descriptions of four new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; from flower bud galls and a stigma gall on &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt; spp. in Australia are described. &lt;i&gt;Fer-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;gusobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eugenioidae&lt;/i&gt; Davies &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterised by having an arcuate, open C or C-shaped parthenogenetic female witha conoid tail, an arcuate to open C-shaped infective female with a hooked tail region and a broadly rounded tail tip, andarcuate or open C-shaped males with angular spicules and short bursa. &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciculosae&lt;/i&gt; Davies &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is character-ised by the combination of an arcuate parthenogenetic female with a short, broadly conoid tail, an open C-shaped infectivefemale with a hemispherical tail tip, and J-shaped males with angular spicules and short peloderan bursa. This is the first&lt;i&gt;Fergusobia/Fergusonina&lt;/i&gt; association to be described from flower stigma galls. &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;juliae&lt;/i&gt; Davies &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is character-ised by the combination of an arcuate to C-shaped parthenogenetic female with a short, broadly conoid tail, a J-shaped in-fective female with a hooked tail region, a cuticular plate around the vulva, and a broadly rounded tail tip, and J-shapedmales with angular spicules and short peloderan bursa. &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;morrisae&lt;/i&gt; Davies &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a C-shaped parthenogeneticfemale with a narrowly conoid tail, an arcuate or J-shaped infective female with most curvature behind the vulva and a shorttail with an almost hemispherical tip, and arcuate or J-shaped males with strongly sclerotised, angular spicules and a longpeloderan bursa. Other known similar forms of &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia/Fergusonina&lt;/i&gt; flower bud galls from &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt; spp. are outlinedand the larval shield morphology of their associated mutualistic fly species is discussed where known. An inventory of allknown &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia/Fergusonina&lt;/i&gt; associations from flower bud galls from &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt; spp. is presented. Molecular analysisof &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; nematodes was inferred from DNA sequencing of 28S rDNA D2/D3 domains and a portion of mitochondrial DNA cytochrome oxidase subunit I (mtCOI). Possible evolutionary relationships are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myrtaceae; galls; Neotylenchidae; &lt;i&gt;Fergusonina&lt;/i&gt;; nematodes; flies; morphology; taxonomy; DNA sequencing; molecular phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myrtaceae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kerrie</firstname>
          <lastname>Davies</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robin</firstname>
          <lastname>Giblin-Davis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weimin</firstname>
          <lastname>Ye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gary</firstname>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kelley</firstname>
          <lastname>Thomas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A peculiar case of intraspecific variability in the Chinese &lt;i&gt;Notholca dongtingensis &lt;/i&gt;(Rotifera: Monogononta: Brachionidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We review the rare Chinese rotifer &lt;i&gt;Notholca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dongtingensis&lt;/i&gt; Zhuge, Kutikova &amp; Sudzuki, 1998, including abundant mate-rial collected during the winter months of 2009–2011 in and around the man-made Dishui Lake Southeast of Shanghai,PR China. Both an SEM study of its trophi and an account of its intraspecific variability are provided. The latter consistsin particular of a unique and previously unknown type of spine formation involving the anterolateral spines, a characterpreviously considered morphologically constant and even diagnostic in &lt;i&gt;Notholca&lt;/i&gt; and related genera. The observations in-dicate that phenotypic plasticity invoked by a plesiomorphic triggering mechanism is not &lt;i&gt;per&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;se&lt;/i&gt; connected to the type orposition of structures developed, but may activate responses resulting in the formation of quite different, autapomorphic structures throughout monogonont Rotifera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">phenotypic plasticity; morphology; taxonomy; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">phenotypic plasticity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yongting</firstname>
          <lastname>Luo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Quanxi</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Segers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-44</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Isaura &lt;/i&gt;Lamouroux, &lt;i&gt;in &lt;/i&gt;Audouin, Bourdon, de Candolle, d’Aubebard de Férussac, Deshayes, Deslongchamps, É. Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, I. Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Guérin, Guillemin, de Jussieu, Kunth, Delafosse, Lamouroux, Latreille, Prévost, Richard &amp; Bory de Saint-Vincent, 1826, an available name and objective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Isaurus &lt;/i&gt;Gray, 1828: reversal of precedence (Cnidaria: Anthozoa: Hexacorallia) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martyn</firstname>
          <middlename>E. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Low</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>Davis</middlename>
          <lastname>Reimer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-50</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New synonym and descriptions of two new species of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Clubiona &lt;/i&gt;Latreille, 1804 from Thailand (Araneae, Clubionidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The female holotype of &lt;i&gt;Clubiona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distincta&lt;/i&gt; Thorell, 1887 from Myanmar is illustrated for the first time. It is considered ajunior synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filicata&lt;/i&gt; Pickard-Cambridge, 1874 originally described from India. Two new species belonging tothe genus &lt;i&gt;Clubiona&lt;/i&gt; are described from Thailand. These taxa are &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;digitata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aberrans&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. The con-specific female of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filifera&lt;/i&gt; Dankittipakul, 2008 is designated and described. &lt;i&gt;Clubiona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanothele&lt;/i&gt; Thorell, 1895 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corrugata&lt;/i&gt; Bösenberg &amp; Strand, 1906 are recorded from Thailand for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thailand—Myanmar—biodiversity—alpha taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thailand—Myanmar—biodiversity—alpha taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pakawin</firstname>
          <lastname>Dankittipakul</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <lastname>Tavano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wimolwan</firstname>
          <lastname>Chotwong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tippawan</firstname>
          <lastname>Singtripop</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-63</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new quill mite &lt;i&gt;Syringophiloidus pseudonigritae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Prostigmata, Syringophilidae) parasitizing &lt;i&gt;Pseudonigrita arnaudi &lt;/i&gt;(Passeriformes, Ploceidae)—a combined description using morphology and DNA barcode data </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new quill mite species &lt;i&gt;Syringophiloidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudonigritae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described using a combination of morphological dataand COI sequence data. The mite was found parasitizing a Grey-headed Social-Weaver &lt;i&gt;Pseudonigrita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arnaudi&lt;/i&gt; (Bonaparte) (Passeriformes, Ploceidae), which was captured in Tanzania and died in a German aviary.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">quill mites; &lt;i&gt;Syringophiloidus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pseudonigrita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arnaudi&lt;/i&gt;; DNA barcoding; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">quill mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eliza</firstname>
          <lastname>Glowska</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <lastname>Dragun-Damian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jacek</firstname>
          <lastname>Dabert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
