<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3534.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Nov. 2012</title>
    <volume>3534</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Pyrisinellidae, a new family of anascan cheilostome bryozoans </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new family of anascan-grade cheilostome bryozoans, Pyrisinellidae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.,&lt;/b&gt; is introduced, together with two new gen-era, &lt;i&gt;Pyrisinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Spinisinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; Containing species previously assigned either to the large, paraphyleticCalloporidae, or Microporidae, pyrisinellids are characterized by having small autozooids with a conspicuous pear-shapedridge formed by the mural rim and distal rim of the opesia, articulated oral spines, and hyperstomial ovicells recumbenton the distal zooid and indenting its mural rim. Five species of pyrisinellids are described, two of which are new: &lt;i&gt;Spin-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;isinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zagorseki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Cenomanian or Turonian (Upper Cretaceous) of the Czech Republic, and &lt;i&gt;Seto-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;sinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perfluxa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Langhian (Middle Miocene) of Kalimantan, Indonesia. A Recent species, &lt;i&gt;Megapora&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ringens&lt;/i&gt; (Busk), is redescribed and questionably assigned to Pyrisinellidae. Important evolutionary changes within Py-risinellidae having parallels elsewhere among anascan cheilostomes include: (1) the development of opesiules for passageof the parietal muscles which correlates with a change from a trifoliate to a semielliptical opesia; and (2) the transitionfrom an open spinose ovicell in the oldest species (Spinisinella &lt;i&gt;zagorseki)&lt;/i&gt; to a conventional ovicell with a solid hood-like ooecium that characterizes all other species belonging to the family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bryozoa; Cheilostomata; new taxa; fossil; Recent</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bryozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emanuela</firstname>
          <middlename>Di</middlename>
          <lastname>Martino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>D</middlename>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Caligus &lt;/i&gt;Müller, 1785 (Copepoda: Siphonostomatoida): two new species from reef associated fishes in New Caledonia, and some nomenclatural problems resolved </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;praecinctorius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of females taken from the gills of &lt;i&gt;Gymnocranius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandoculis&lt;/i&gt;Valenciennes, 1830, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;euanus&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1879) and &lt;i&gt;Epinephelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt; (Forsskål, 1775), all caught in New Caledonia.The new species is characterised by having the posteromedian lobe of the cephalothorax completely covering the fourthpedigerous somite in dorsal view, and by the genital complex being 2.7 times wider than long. A second new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;macoloricola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on material from the gills of &lt;i&gt;Macolor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niger&lt;/i&gt; (Forsskål, 1775). It is distinguishedby the combination of a 3-segmented leg 4 with 4 spines on the distal segment, a vestigial post-antennal process, and theconfiguration of the setal elements on the exopod of leg 1. The status of a number of other &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; species is reviewed. Itis proposed to treat &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustatus&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1863 as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gurnardi&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1863, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dactylus&lt;/i&gt;Ho, Lin &amp; Chang, 2007 as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dactylopteni&lt;/i&gt; Uma Devi &amp; Shyamasundari, 1981, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;kirtioides&lt;/i&gt; Ho &amp; Lin, 2004 as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jawahari&lt;/i&gt; Hameed &amp; Adamkutty, 1985. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bifurcatus&lt;/i&gt;Pearse, 1952 is recognised as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Tuxophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caligodes&lt;/i&gt; Wilson, 1908. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristatus&lt;/i&gt;Gould, 1841 is here treated as a species inquirendum in the pandarid genus &lt;i&gt;Dinemoura&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1829. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elevatus&lt;/i&gt;Kirtisinghe, 1964 is discovered to be an incorrect subsequent spelling of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavatus&lt;/i&gt; Kirtisinghe, 1964. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gayi&lt;/i&gt;Nicolet, 1849 is here treated as a species inquirendum. It is proposed to treat &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oligoplitisi&lt;/i&gt; Carvalho, 1956, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;validus&lt;/i&gt;Pearse, 1952 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mercatoris&lt;/i&gt; Capart, 1941 as junior subjective synonyms of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; Bassett-Smith, 1898 and a listof known hosts of this species is presented. &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pterois&lt;/i&gt; Kurian, 1949 has priority over &lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;russellii&lt;/i&gt; Kurien, 1950,which is here treated as a junior objective synonym, since the two descriptions were based on the same material. We rejectCressey’s (1991) proposal to treat &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenax&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1865 as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chorinemi&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1863 and we retain &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenax&lt;/i&gt;as a valid species. We propose to treat &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosurculus&lt;/i&gt; Pearse, 1951 as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenax.&lt;/i&gt; Wepropose to treat &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multispinosus&lt;/i&gt; Shen, 1957 as a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stromatei&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1863. We note that&lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trichiuri&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1863 is the oldest available name for the taxon &lt;i&gt;Metacaligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uruguayensis&lt;/i&gt; Thomsen, 1949. So&lt;i&gt;Caligus&lt;/i&gt; (Metacaligus) &lt;i&gt;uruguayensis&lt;/i&gt; Thomsen, 1949 becomes a junior subjective synonym and the valid name for this taxon is &lt;i&gt;Metacaligus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trichiuri&lt;/i&gt; (Krøyer, 1863).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caligidae; parasite; taxonomy; new species; new synonyms</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caligidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Polly</firstname>
          <lastname>Hayes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean-Lou</firstname>
          <lastname>Justine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Geoffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Boxshall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-39</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Graptocarcininae n. subfam., an extinct subfamily of Dynomenidae Ortmann, 1892 (Crustacea, Brachyura, Podotremata) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Newly available material of a dynomenid crab, &lt;i&gt;Graptocarcinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urbasaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Upper Cretaceous of northernSpain (Álava and Navarra), allowed the study of the morphology of well preserved ventral surfaces. We describe a newsubfamily of Dynomenidae, comprising the middle-Upper Cretaceous &lt;i&gt;Graptocarcinus&lt;/i&gt; and the Upper Jurassic &lt;i&gt;Cyclothy-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;reus.&lt;/i&gt; Graptocarcininae &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; shows a primitive configuration of the abdomen and an abdominal holding mechanismthat is similar to that of the Acanthodromiinae. Recognition of this ancient extinct subfamily confirms that the Dynomenidae is amongst the most basal brachyuran families.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Dynomenidae; Acanthodromiinae; &lt;i&gt;Graptocarcinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cyclothyreus&lt;/i&gt;; fossil crab; new subfamily; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Barry</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Bakel (The Netherlands)</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danièle</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Carmelo</middlename>
          <lastname>Corral</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Artal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte brachycarpus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a further new hippolytid shrimp (Decapoda, Caridea, Hippolytidae) associated with soft coral from Taiwan, with the key to the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte &lt;/i&gt;Marin, Okuno &amp; Chan, 2011 </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of soft coral associated hippolytid shrimp of the hippolytid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; Marin, Okuno&amp; Chan, 2011 is described from northern Taiwan. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachycarpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; inhabits softcoral “Sinularia sp.”, the same host as for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; Marin, Okuno &amp; Chan, 2011. At the same time, the new speciescan be easily separated from A. maculata by different coloration as well as having shorter carpal segments of pereiopodsII in females. Though occurring simpatrically, these two species have not yet been found inhabiting the same host together.The key for all known species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; is given based on morphology of females as no males have yet been known for the type species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dossena&lt;/i&gt; Marin, Okuno &amp; Chan, 2010.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Hippolytidae; Alcyonohippolyte; new species; soft coral; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new oryzomyine (Rodentia: Sigmodontinae) from the Quaternary of Curaçao (West Indies) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A collection of 17 isolated rodent molars from a cave in the eastern part of Duivelsklip, Curaçao, Dutch West Indies, isdescribed as &lt;i&gt;Dushimys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larsi,&lt;/i&gt; new genus and species. The new species is characterized by relatively large size, broad mo-lars, absence of mesolophid and presence of anterolophid and anterolabial cingulum on m3, absence of metaloph on M3,and m2 with three roots. Phylogenetic analysis could not conclusively resolve the position of the new species, and it isprovisionally regarded as a representative of an otherwise unknown oryzomyine genus. The material is likely middle Pleistocene in age.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curaçao; new species; Oryzomyini; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curaçao</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jelle</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zijlstra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
