<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3546.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Nov. 2012</title>
    <volume>3546</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new &lt;i&gt;Carlia &lt;/i&gt;species (Reptilia: Scincidae) from north-east Australia, elevation of &lt;i&gt;Carlia pectoralis inconnexa &lt;/i&gt;Ingram &amp; Covacevich 1989 to full species status, and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Carlia pectoralis &lt;/i&gt;(de Vis 1884) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Scincid lizards belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; are found in eastern and northern Australia and in New Guinea andassociated islands. These skinks are a particularly diverse component of the reptile fauna of north-east Australia. &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pectoralis&lt;/i&gt; (de Vis 1884) was formerly regarded as occurring over much of eastern Queensland, in north-east Australia.Here we show that it consists of four species: &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectoralis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubigo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;inconnexa&lt;/i&gt; Ingram &amp; Covacevich 1989 (which was formerly described as a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectoralis).&lt;/i&gt; Herein, wedescribe two new species, elevate &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inconnexa&lt;/i&gt; to full species status with a revised description, and redescribe &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pectoralis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto.&lt;/i&gt; The four species differ in aspects of scalation, morphology and colour pattern. &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; occurs in vine thickets, rainforest margins and moist open forests in high rainfall coastal areas of mid-east and north-east Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubigo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; occurs in dry open forests of inland eastern Queensland and in some coastal areasof mid-eastern Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectoralis&lt;/i&gt; is distributed through open forests of south-east Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;inconnexa&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to rocky open forests on islands of ‘the Whitsundays’ off mid-eastern Queensland. The addition of these three species brings the number of Australian &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; to 22 species, 17 of which are found in Queensland.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubigo&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inconnexa&lt;/i&gt;; reptile; lizard; skink; Queensland; Whitsunday islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decora&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Conrad</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoskin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Couper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First report of the male of &lt;i&gt;Zamora granulata &lt;/i&gt;Roewer, 1928, with implications on the higher taxonomy of the Zamorinae Kury, 1997 (Opiliones, Laniatores, Cranaidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Males of &lt;i&gt;Zamora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulata&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1928—a species known from Zamora, Ecuador—are reported for the first time. Thestudy of this species, especially the male genitalia, along with all species of Zamorinae Kury, 1997, allowed to reach thefollowing conclusions: 1) &lt;i&gt;Zamora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vulcana&lt;/i&gt; Kury, 1997, from Cotopaxi, Ecuador, does not belong to &lt;i&gt;Zamora&lt;/i&gt; and istransferred to &lt;i&gt;Rivetinus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1914; 2) &lt;i&gt;Zamora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulata,&lt;/i&gt; the name-bearer of Zamorinae, is not an Agoristenidae andtherefore Zamorinae is placed in Cranaidae; 3) Zamorinae is redefined based on previously unavailable information frommale genitalia; (4) some genera hitherto placed in Zamorinae which present a combination of a generalized gonyleptoidhabitus plus an agoristenid genitalia (which includes &lt;i&gt;Globibunus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1912 and &lt;i&gt;Rivetinus),&lt;/i&gt; are placed in Globibuninae&lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Based on the examination of the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Prostygnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vestitus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1913 (from Ecuador, notColombia, nor Venezuela), and new material of &lt;i&gt;Cutervolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopunctatus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1957, the Prostygninae are restrictedto &lt;i&gt;Cutervolus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1957 and &lt;i&gt;Prostygnus&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1913, with distribution accordingly restricted to southern Ecuadorand northern Peru. Iconographic complements are made on the type species of these two genera, and their male genitaliaare illustrated for the first time. All other Prostygninae are considered Gonyleptoidea &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis.&lt;/i&gt; Emended diagnoses are provided for Globibuninae, Prostygninae and Zamorinae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; harvestmen; Grassatores; Neotropics; Ecuador; Agoristenidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-42</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new and commercial species of &lt;i&gt;Gastrosaccus &lt;/i&gt;Norman, 1868 (Peracarida: Mysida: Mysidae) from Java, Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of gastrosaccid mysid, &lt;i&gt;Gastrosaccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yuyu,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the higher tidal levels of wave-exposed surfbeaches of Java, Indonesia. It belongs to that group of &lt;i&gt;Gastrosaccus&lt;/i&gt; species with a fringe of slender spine-like filamentsalong the posterodorsal margin of the carapace, and, in having a mid-dorsal apophysis on the fifth abdominal somite inthe adult and filaments which extend onto the postero-lateral lobes of the carapace, is close only to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorrentoensis.&lt;/i&gt; It isdistinct in having fewer marginal carapace filaments than &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorrentoensis,&lt;/i&gt; as well as apical telson spines which are hardlylonger than the sub-apical lateral spines and are separated from those spines by a gap distinctly larger than those betweenthe previous spines, a more pronounced rostrum, and a distinct conformation of the distal tip of the mandibular palp, &lt;i&gt;inter&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;alia.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gastrosaccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yuyu&lt;/i&gt; is collected commercially by artisanal fishermen in Java, and cooked into a fried rice-flour crisp biscuit, known locally as “peyek”.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mysidae; &lt;i&gt;Gastrosaccus&lt;/i&gt;; peyek; yuyu; Indonesia; commercial</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mysidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>N</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <lastname>Morton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Xenophrys &lt;/i&gt;Günther, 1864 (Amphibia: Anura: Megophryidae) from Mount Jinggang, China, based on molecular and morphological data </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Xenophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jinggangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a series of specimens collected from Mount Jing-gang, Jiangxi Province, Eastern China. The new species can be easily distinguished from other known congeners by mor-phology, morphometrics and molecular data of the mitochondrial 16SrRNA gene. The new species is characterized by itssmall size with adult females measuring 38.4–41.6 mm in snout-vent length and males measuring 35.1–36.7 mm; headlength approximately equal to head width; tympanum large and distinct, about 0.8 times of eye diameter; vomerine teethon two weak ridges; tongue not notched behind; relative finger length II &lt; I &lt; IV &lt; III; slight lateral fringes present ondigits; toes bases with thick, fleshy web; dorsum with tubercles and swollen dorsolateral folds; large pustules scattered on flanks; and unique color patterns. The new species represents the thirty-first known &lt;i&gt;Xenophrys&lt;/i&gt; in China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Megophryidae; &lt;i&gt;Xenophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jinggangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; morphology; mitochondrial DNA; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Megophryidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ying-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tian-Du</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yik-Hei</firstname>
          <lastname>Sung</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jian-Huan</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong</firstname>
          <lastname>Pang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-67</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of the hippolytid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Eualus &lt;/i&gt;Thallwitz, 1892 from Japan, and clarification of the status of &lt;i&gt;E. kikuchii &lt;/i&gt;Miyake &amp; Hayashi, 1967 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study reports on two species of the hippolytid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Eualus&lt;/i&gt; Thallwitz, 1892 from Japan. The first, &lt;i&gt;Eualus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ctenomerus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described on the basis of six specimens from off southern Kyushu. The new species appears closestto &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cteniferus&lt;/i&gt; (Barnard, 1950) from South Africa, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;drachi&lt;/i&gt; Noël, 1978 from the Mediterranean, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lebourae&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis,1951 from the eastern Atlantic, and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectiniformis&lt;/i&gt; Hanamura, 2008 from southeastern Australia. The second is referredto &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kikuchii&lt;/i&gt; Miyake &amp; Hayashi, 1967, which has been considered to be synonymous with &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bulychevae&lt;/i&gt; Kobjakova,1955, described from the South Kuril Islands, Far East Russia. &lt;i&gt;Eualus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kikuchii&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed as a valid species on thebasis of the holotype and additional specimens from various Japanese localities. Both species occurred in the whale-fall ecosystems located off Cape Nomamisaki, Kyushu, Kagoshima Prefecture.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Hippolytidae; &lt;i&gt;Eualus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yoshihiro</firstname>
          <lastname>Fujiwara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68-80</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Podosiridae, a new family of North Atlantic deep sea amphipod (Crustacea, Amphipoda) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A</middlename>
          <lastname>Myers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>81-84</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Caristius groenlandicus &lt;/i&gt;Jensen and &lt;i&gt;Pteraclis fasciatus &lt;/i&gt;Borodin (Pisces: Caristiidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Manefishes of the family Caristiidae are rare meso-bathypelagic oceanic fishes with numerous problems regarding theirspecies-level taxonomy. We revisit Hartel and Triant’s assertion (Copeia, 1998, 746) that &lt;i&gt;Pteraclis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt; Borodin and&lt;i&gt;Caristius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;groenlandicus&lt;/i&gt; Jensen are synonyms. We found additional support for this idea in the modification of theventral unbranched caudal-fin rays. We conclude that the names are synonyms and that &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt; has priority over &lt;i&gt;groenlandicus&lt;/i&gt; because the former is the older name.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralf</firstname>
          <lastname>Britz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karsten</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hartel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>85-88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
