<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3569.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2012</title>
    <volume>3569</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cladocerans of genus &lt;i&gt;Alona &lt;/i&gt;Baird, 1843 (Cladocera: Anomopoda: Chydoridae) and related genera from Aguascalientes State, Mexico </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight cladoceran species of &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; s. lato and related genera were found in Aguascalientes state, Mexico, after extensivesampling efforts. Two of them are new for science. Both new species belong to the &lt;i&gt;pulchella-group&lt;/i&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; and sharedistinctive features of the group. &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aguascalientensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the other species of the group by thepresence of denticles on posteroventral corner of valves, by a moderately elongated narrow postabdomen with weaklyprotruding distal angle and postanal marginal denticles of the same size, and by the morphology of major head pores, withconnection between central and posterior pores always absent, while connection between anterior and central porespresent or interrupted. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anamariae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the other species of the group by the long last seta in the anteriorgroup of setae of the ventral margin of valves, by short, relatively wide, evenly narrowing distally postabdomen, and bythe small size (it is the smallest species of the group). Both new species seems to be endemic of Central Mexican Plateau.Other species found are &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glabra&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1901, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;guttata&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1862, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ossiani&lt;/i&gt; Sinev, 1908, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setigera&lt;/i&gt; Megard, 1967, &lt;i&gt;Coronatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumfimbriata&lt;/i&gt; (Megard, 1967) and &lt;i&gt;Leberis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;davidi&lt;/i&gt; (Richard, 1895).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt;; Aguascalientes State; Cladocera; endemics; Mexico; morphology; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Artem</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <lastname>Silva-Briano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heterorhabditis beicherriana &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Nematoda: Heterorhabditidae), a new entomopathogenic nematode from the Shunyi district of Beijing, China </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new heterorhabditid nematode was recovered in orchards in the Beijing area. Morphological and molecular dataconfirmed this nematode as a new species, which belongs to the &lt;i&gt;bacteriophora-group&lt;/i&gt; with sister taxa &lt;i&gt;Heterorhabditis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;bacteriophora&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgiana.&lt;/i&gt; The nematode was named &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beicherriana&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and is characterized by males,hermaphrodites, females and infective juveniles. In males the peloderan bursa is characterized by the formula 1 2 3 3,spicule length 45 (41–51)μm. Male body length is substantially higher than that of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacteriophora&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgiana&lt;/i&gt;(1028μm vs 820 and 838μm, respectively). In hermaphrodites there are six labial and six cephalic papillae; the vulvalpattern is smooth, rounded or slightly elliptical. Tail is conoid with a moderately prominent post-anal swelling slightlylonger than anal body width. In females vulval lips are non-protruding, tail conical without or with a slightly developedpost-anal swelling, about twice as long as anal body width. In infective juveniles, the body is elongate, slender and straightwhen heat-killed, on average 639μm long, which is longer than in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacteriophora&lt;/i&gt; (558μm) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgiana&lt;/i&gt; (598μm),respectively. &lt;i&gt;Heterorhabditis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beicherriana&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is further characterized by internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and D2D3rDNA sequences, the most similar species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgiana,&lt;/i&gt; being separated by 21 bp across 994 bp of the ITS and 3 across890 bp of the D2D3 region. ITS and D2D3 regions of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beicherriana&lt;/i&gt; evolved five and one autapomorphies, respectively. Phylogenetic analyses placed &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beicherriana&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. as a member of the &lt;i&gt;bacteriophora-group.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; description; morphology; taxonomy; systematics; phylogeny; SEM</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Xing-Yue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Liu</firstname>
          <lastname>Qi-Zhi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jiří</firstname>
          <middlename>Nermuť (The Czech</middlename>
          <lastname>Republic)</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimír</firstname>
          <lastname>Půža</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zdeněk</firstname>
          <lastname>Mráček</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Clinal pattern of morphological variation in &lt;i&gt;Sakesphorus luctuosus &lt;/i&gt;(Lichtenstein, 1823), with comments on the enigmatic &lt;i&gt;Sakesphorus hagmanni &lt;/i&gt;Miranda-Ribeiro, 1927 (Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sakesphorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luctuosus&lt;/i&gt; (Glossy Antshrike) is endemic to Brazil, harboring two subspecies. The nominal subspecies iswidespread in the Amazon region, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;araguayae&lt;/i&gt; is endemic to the Rio Araguaia valley. In this paper we investigatedthe hypothesis that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;araguayae&lt;/i&gt; represents the end of a cline. We examined 588 specimens housed in Brazilian, NorthAmerican and European museums and based our conclusions on plumage coloration and morphometric characters. Wefound no significant differences in morphometric characters between subspecies, except for culmen length, which wasslightly shorter in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;araguayae,&lt;/i&gt; but with wide overlap in measurements. The main proposed diagnostic character be-tween subspecies (length of the white tips to tail feathers) showed clinal variation, with northern birds showing more whiteon the tail, and southern birds showing less white on the tail, irrespective of hydrographic basin. The other diagnostic char-acter proposed (width of the white edges to the outer webs of the scapular feathers) showed high individual variation andno taxonomic consistency. We conclude that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;l.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;araguayae&lt;/i&gt; is a junior synonym of the nominal taxon. On the other hand,&lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hagmanni,&lt;/i&gt; known only from the holotype and long thought to be a junior synonym of the nominal taxon, proved to be a unique specimen that should be considered as &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda&lt;/i&gt; until further investigations determine its status.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Glossy Antshrikes; Rio Araguaia; river-created-habitats; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Glossy Antshrikes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leonardo</firstname>
          <middlename>Esteves</middlename>
          <lastname>Lopes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>Pedreira</middlename>
          <lastname>Gonzaga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of prickleback, &lt;i&gt;Dictyosoma tongyeongensis &lt;/i&gt;(Perciformes: Stichaeidae) from the South Sea of Korea </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new prickleback is described based on six specimens collected by fish trap in southern Korea (water depth 5–12 m) in2009 and 2010. The new prickleback is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Dictyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burgeri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Dictyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubrimaculatum&lt;/i&gt; in generalmorphology, but differs in the following combination of characters: dorsal contour of head almost a straight line; anal-finrays 45–47; vertebrae 70–74; no blackish-brown blotches on head. In addition, mitochondrial DNA cytochrome oxidasesubunit I (COI) sequences and recombination activating gene 2 (RAG2) sequences were analyzed for clarifying their ge-netic relationship. The neighbor-joining tree using mtDNA COI and nDNA RAG2 shows the reciprocal monophyly of thenew prickleback. Accordingly, our specimens are regarded as a new species, named &lt;i&gt;Dictyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongyeongensis,&lt;/i&gt; after its type locality (Tongyeong).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stichaeidae; &lt;i&gt;Dictyosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongyeongensis&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial DNA cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI); recombination activating gene 2 (RAG2); new species; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stichaeidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hwan-Sung</firstname>
          <lastname>Ji</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jin-Koo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-66</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Leptus kattikus &lt;/i&gt;Haitlinger, 2009 (Actinotrichida, Parasitengona, Erythraeidae) and molecular identification of its host from DNA barcoding </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A morphology-based redescription of &lt;i&gt;Leptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kattikus&lt;/i&gt; Haitlinger, 2009, including re-examination of the holotype and sup-plemented with data of a series of specimens collected in Vietnam, is provided. Larvae at different levels of engorgement,all separated from one phasmid host, were examined. A polymerase chain reaction, conducted in order to amplify and se-quence the DNA of parasitic larvae, resulted in molecular identification of the host species. This represents an alternativemethod of establishing the host identification for larvae which have already detached from the host prior to examination, and can therefore be employed in further studies of host spectrum.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; morphology; host identification; COI; Phasmida</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joanna</firstname>
          <lastname>Mąkol</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Magdalena</firstname>
          <lastname>Felska</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hanna</firstname>
          <lastname>Moniuszko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Grzegorz</firstname>
          <lastname>Zaleśny</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-78</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Spengelidae (Hemichordata: Enteropneusta) from the Eastern Pacific including a new species, &lt;i&gt;Schizocardium californicum, &lt;/i&gt;from California </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty one enteropneusts have been described from the west coast of North America, but those reports include no Spen-gelidae. Here we describe two species of acorn worms in the genus &lt;i&gt;Schizocardium&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;californicum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruvianum)&lt;/i&gt;on the basis of morphology. The former represent the first spengelid worm described from North American waters. Thelatter is a previously described species, and here we expand on its morphological description and extend its geographicrange north from Peru to California. Notes on the habit and localization of each species, as well as a dichotomous key tothe genera of the family Spengelidae are provided. Based on morphology, spengelids appears to represent an intermediatebetween the enteropneust families Harrimaniidae and Ptychoderidae, and &lt;i&gt;Schizocardium&lt;/i&gt; is sister taxon to the ptychode-rids. The disjunct and widely distributed populations of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruvianum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliense,&lt;/i&gt; with populations in South Amer-ican and North America, but none between, could represent the relict populations of formerly wide spread species, or the two extremes of ranges.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Enteropneusta; acorn worm; Spengelidae; California; dichotomous key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Enteropneusta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cameron</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Perez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>79-88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
