<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3583.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Dec. 2012</title>
    <volume>3583</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of land flatworms and comments on the genus &lt;i&gt;Pasipha &lt;/i&gt;Ogren &amp; Kawakatsu, 1990 (Platyhelminthes: Continenticola) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Geoplaninae, &lt;i&gt;Pasipha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;backesi&lt;/i&gt; Leal-Zanchet, Rossi &amp; Seitenfus, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevilineata&lt;/i&gt; Leal-Zanchet, Rossi &amp; Alvarenga, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from southern Brazil are described herein. The two new sympatric species can bedistinguished from each other by differences in colour pattern and the copulatory apparatus, especially regarding the pro-static vesicle. They show similar characteristics regarding the relative position of the ovaries and anteriormost testes inrelation to body length, the position where ovovitelline ducts emerge from the ovaries, pharyngeal morphology and gen-eral morphology of the copulatory apparatus. Comments on the most important morphological characters of the 22 speciesoriginally assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Pasipha&lt;/i&gt; are presented in order to highlight the heterogeneity of the genus as well as fa-cilitate the comparative discussion of the new species. In addition, based on the current diagnosis of the genus, we propose the placement of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cafusa&lt;/i&gt; into &lt;i&gt;Pasipha.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geoplaninae; taxonomy; land planarians; triclads</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geoplaninae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal-Zanchet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ilana</firstname>
          <lastname>Rossi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Lúcia Ramos</middlename>
          <lastname>Seitenfus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juliana</firstname>
          <lastname>Alvarenga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus hikidai &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Squamata: Gekkonidae): a new bent toed gecko from Mount Ranai, Bunguran island, Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hikidai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a new gekkonid species described on the basis of 13 specimens collected from MountRanai, Bunguran Island, Indonesia. This large &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (female SVL up to 102.2 mm, male SVL up to 100.6 mm)differs from all other Sunda Shelf species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; by the combination of a reticulated color pattern on the dorsumof the head, body banded, enlarged precloacal scales, six pore-bearing precloacal scales in a deep groove in both malesand females, tubercles on forelimbs, hind limbs and occiput, absence of enlarged femoral scales, and absence of femoral pores.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hikidai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Mount Ranai; Bunguran Island</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Awal</firstname>
          <lastname>Riyanto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-30</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Apseudomorph Tanaidacea from the continental shelf of Angola and Namibia with descriptions of three new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four apseudomorph tanaidaceans are recorded from benthos of the shelf off Angola and off northern Namibia (SouthWest Africa). Of these, three are new to science, one each in the genera &lt;i&gt;Hemikalliapseudes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Calozodion&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;Apseudopsis.&lt;/i&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Hemikalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; now contains four species, all described from West Africa (Angola andMauretania). The new species &lt;i&gt;Hemikalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sebastiani&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is separated from other species of this genus byfeatures of several appendages, and the shape of the cephalothorax, pereonites and telson. The genus &lt;i&gt;Calozodion&lt;/i&gt; ismainly distributed in the Atlantic and also in the Indian Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Calozodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dominiki&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is the tenth representativeof the genus and is readily distinguished from all others in that the cheliped propodus of the male has only smallprocesses proximo-ventrally. The new species was widely distributed in the investigation area. &lt;i&gt;Apseudopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuanzanus&lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. is a new member of this species-rich and widely-distributed genus. It differs from the other species of this genusby a combination of several morphological features, including the absence of a dorsodistal spine on the pereopod 1merus, the lack of anterolateral spines on the pereonites, the shape of rostrum and by the absence of plumose setae on pereopod six basis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Apseudidae; Metapseudidae; Kalliapseudidae; marcozoobenthos; biogeography; Benguela Current; West Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Apseudidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralf</firstname>
          <lastname>Bochert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-50</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A re-assessment of &lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera &lt;/i&gt;Dudich, 1931 (Crustacea: Tanaidacea: Tanaidae), with designation of three new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The tanaid genus &lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera&lt;/i&gt; has long been considered to be monotypic, comprising a cosmopolitan species predom-inantly commensal on turtles, or, more rarely, manatees. Recent discovery of material of a distinct species of&lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera&lt;/i&gt; living on the hulls of yachts in south-west England encouraged re-assessment of the literature on this taxon,and re-examination of free-living benthic material from the eastern Mediterranean. As a result, five species are recognizedwithin the genus &lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera;&lt;/i&gt; two new species are described, &lt;i&gt;Pancoloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moverlyi&lt;/i&gt; is moved to &lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robusta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Edgar is elevated to specific rank and re-named.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera&lt;/i&gt;; Tanaidae; commensalism; cosmopolitanism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hexapleomera&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-70</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the Genus &lt;i&gt;Microbrotula &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Bythitidae) from Cenderawasih Bay, New Guinea, Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Following the recent revision of &lt;i&gt;Microbrotula&lt;/i&gt; (Schwarzhans &amp; Nielsen, 2011), an additional nine specimens of the vivi-parous genus &lt;i&gt;Microbrotula&lt;/i&gt; (Teleostei: Bythitidae), all caught in the Cenderawasih Bay, Irian Jaya, New Guinea, Indone-sia, were made available to us. These specimens represent a new species described here as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geraldalleni.&lt;/i&gt; It belongs tothe group of species with 6 caudal and 14 pectoral fin rays and is closest to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;greenfieldi,&lt;/i&gt; differing in the higher dorsaland anal fin ray counts (68–73 and 61–65 &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; 62–70 and 58–61, respectively), the presence of 3 posterior mandibular pores(vs. none), 2–3 preopercular pores (vs. none), a connected squamation over the head including cheek, opercle and occiput(vs. 3 separated scale patches) and with a unique scale-less triangular window just above the opercle. &lt;i&gt;Microbrotula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geraldalleni&lt;/i&gt; may be endemic to the Cenderawasih Bay.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bythitidae; viviparous brotulas; Cenderawasih Bay; New Guinea; Indonesia; coral reef fishes; new species; &lt;i&gt;Microbrotula&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bythitidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Werner</firstname>
          <lastname>Schwarzhans</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jørgen</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>71-76</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Fissiphallius &lt;/i&gt;Martens 1988 from Brazil and notes on the mor-phology of Fissiphalliidae (Arachnida, Opiliones) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The seventh species of Fissiphallidae, &lt;i&gt;Fissiphallius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orube&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and the fourth from Brazil (type locality state of Acre,Cruzeiro do Sul, at the Moa river), is described. The new species differs from the remaining species of the family in lack-ing a pergula, having a knob at the base of the rutrum, and the ocularium spiniform projection with apical portion single or divided in two to three parts.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazonian Rainforest; harvestmen; taxonomy; Laniatores; genitalic morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazonian Rainforest</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nathalia</firstname>
          <middlename>Sena</middlename>
          <lastname>Polydoro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Pinto-Da-Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>77-82</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stereocyclops &lt;/i&gt;Cope (Anura, Microhylidae) from Southeastern Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stereocyclops&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Zona da Mata Regional Airport (21o 31’S, 43o 11’W; 408 m a.s.l.),Municipality of Goianá, State of Minas Gerais, Southeastern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Stereocyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmipes&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is characterized by itsmedium size (SVL 43.7–48.5 mm in males; SVL 48.4–56.7 mm in females); in males, large, numerous dermal spinesconcentrated in the inferior border of mandible, forming a band; dermal spines scattered on ventral surfaces of body, arms,fingers, legs, toes, and pericloacal region of males, and agglomerate only in pericloacal region and ventral surfaces of thighs infemales; fringes and interdigital membranes of toes developed; color pattern composed by two mid-dorsal, poorly defined, dark brown stripes from the inguinal regions to head, passing on the occipital dermal fold and reaching the upper eyelid.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Gastrophryninae; &lt;i&gt;Stereocyclops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Southeastern Brazil; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulisses</firstname>
          <lastname>Caramaschi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Lula Salles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Alberto Gonçalves</middlename>
          <lastname>Cruz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>83-88</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
