<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1248.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1248</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the &lt;i&gt;Sphaeropthalma imperialis &lt;/i&gt;species-group (Hymenoptera: Mutillidae), with descriptions of females and taxonomic notes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A study of Schuster’s &lt;i&gt;Sphaeropthalma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; species-groups was completed. &lt;i&gt;Sphaeropthalma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megagnathos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurifera&lt;/i&gt; Schuster is a &lt;b&gt;junior&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megagnathos&lt;/i&gt; Schuster and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flammifera&lt;/i&gt; Schuster is a &lt;b&gt;junior&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; (Cresson). New sex associations make &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialiformis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maracopae&lt;/i&gt; Schuster and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialiformis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialiformis&lt;/i&gt; (Viereck) &lt;b&gt;junior&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonyms&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marpesia&lt;/i&gt; (Blake), and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erato&lt;/i&gt; (Blake) a &lt;b&gt;junior&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; (Blake). The &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; species-group is redefined to contain &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; (Blake) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marpesia,&lt;/i&gt; which were previously placed in the &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; group &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Schuster (1958), and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megagnathos&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii,&lt;/i&gt; which were previously placed in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; group &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Schuster (1958). The female of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; is described and the females of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imperialis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marpesia&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed. Keys are presented for both sexes of this species-group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sphaeropthalminae; solitary wasp; velvet ant</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sphaeropthalminae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pitts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Larinus &lt;/i&gt;Dejean from Turkey and Syria (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Lixinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perrinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from southeastern Turkey and Syria based on material from J. Desbrochers’ and M. Pic’s collections. Lectotype of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lejeunei&lt;/i&gt; Capiomont is designated. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perrinae&lt;/i&gt; is closely related to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lejeunei&lt;/i&gt; but, differing in the elongated body, pattern of pubescence and shape of aedeagus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perrinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lejeunei&lt;/i&gt; Capiomont; lectotype; Coleoptera; Curculionidae; Lixinae; new species; Turkey; Syria</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perrinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lejeunei&lt;/i&gt; Capiomont</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gültekin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-26</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The freshwater ribbon-worm &lt;i&gt;Prostoma graecense&lt;/i&gt; (Hoplonemertea: Monostilifera) in South America (Argentina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphological species &lt;i&gt;Prostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graecense&lt;/i&gt; (Böhmig, 1892) is reported for the first time from Argentina and South America. Some diagnostic characters, such as the ciliated epithelium of the non-rhynchodaeal oesophagus and the backward extension of the cephalic glands up to the brain commisure, were confirmed for the Argentine material; the rhynchodaeal longitudinal muscles were present, but did not form a thick layer as expected from some previous descriptions. Adding South America to its distribution range supports the hypothesis that this morphotype &lt;i&gt;Prostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graecense&lt;/i&gt; actually has a cosmopolitan distribution.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cosmopolitan&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distribution&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Enopla&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nemertea&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;taxonomy&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tetrastemmidae&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cosmopolitan&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distribution&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tamburi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cazzaniga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-34</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Laimaphelenchus australis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov&lt;i&gt;. &lt;/i&gt;(Nematoda: Aphelenchina) from exotic pines, &lt;i&gt;Pinus radiata &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;P. pinaster, &lt;/i&gt;in Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Laimaphelenchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from bark of the exotic pines, &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinaster&lt;/i&gt; from Kuitpo, South Australia, and &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radiata&lt;/i&gt; from Dartmoor, Victoria. This is the second record of &lt;i&gt;Laimaphelenchus&lt;/i&gt; from Australia, and the first from exotic &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; spp. The new species is characterised by having a tail with a single offset terminus, bearing 3–4 pedunculate tubercles, ending with 4–6 finger-like protrusions. In addition, the anterior region of the new species, as seen with SEM, lacks a distinct labial disc.Key words: Aphelenchina, Australia, &lt;i&gt;Laimaphelenchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Nematoda, &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinaster,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radiata&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Z</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davies</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Riley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nobbs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Understanding saproxylic beetles: new records of Tetratomidae, Melandryidae, Synchroidae, and Scraptiidae from the Maritime Provinces of Canada (Coleoptera: Tenebrionoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New species records for Tetratomidae, Melandryidae, Synchroidae, and Scraptiidae from the Maritime Provinces of Canada are given. Known bionomics of these saproxylic species are summarized and new bionomic observations are provided. Twenty-five species are newly recorded from Nova Scotia, 10 from Prince Edward Island, and three from New Brunswick. Thirty-seven species are now known from the region, a substantial increase from the 23 species known hitherto. Range extensions for 19 species are noted. The composition of the region’s fauna is briefly discussed, focusing on a disparity in the collection efforts between provinces, and also on island faunas. Finally the fauna is examined in the context of a developing knowledge of saproxylic beetles in Nova Scotia, along with potential concerns about the impact that forest management practices.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Tetratomidae; Melandryidae; Synchroidae; Scraptiidae; Maritime Provinces; New Brunswick; Nova Scotia; Prince Edward Island; Canada; biodiversity; saproxylic; new records</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Majka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pollock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1247.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1247</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Characidium longum &lt;/i&gt;(Characiformes: Crenuchidae), a new fish from Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Characidium&lt;/i&gt; Reinhardt, 1867, from tributaries of the blackwater rivers Capanaparo, Cinaruco, Caura and Casiquiare in Apure, Bolivar and Amazonas states of Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Characidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longum&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed by an extremely elongate body and a unique pigmentation pattern consisting of 13 or more black vertical bars, each with a concentrated spot of pigment at mid-body. These bars are united with a series of reddish-brown dorsal saddles, which cross over the dorsum and unite with bars from the opposite side of the body.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Characidium&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Venezuela; Orinoco; Caura; Casiquiare; Cinaruco; Capanaparo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Characidium&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Taphorn</middlename>
          <lastname>B.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Montaña</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Buckup</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ventichthys biospeedoi &lt;/i&gt;n. gen. et sp. (Teleostei, Ophidiidae) from a hydrothermal vent in the South East Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of ophidiid fishes, &lt;i&gt;Ventichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biospeedoi,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on two male specimens caught in the French BIOSPEEDO expedition to the South East Pacific Rise. They were caught by a baited trap at the hydrothermal vent site Oasis (17°25.38’S, 113°12.29’W) at 2586 m. The new genus differs from all of the 48 known ophidiid genera by its thick skin, posteriorly placed and enlarged kidneys, broad head, and 4 lateral lines. The most similar genera are &lt;i&gt;Benthocometes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Petrotyx&lt;/i&gt; having a blunt snout, one basibranchial tooth patch, granular teeth, and no free pectoral fin rays. Remarks on the ecology of the new species are based on analysis of video documents taken in situ by a submarine &lt;i&gt;Nautile.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ophidiidae; &lt;i&gt;Ventichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biospeedoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; South East Pacific Rise hydrothermal vent</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ophidiidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Møller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Segonzac</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>13-24</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brevisomabathynella &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. with two new species from Western Australia (Bathynellacea, Syncarida): the first definitive evidence of predation in Parabathynellidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brevisomabathynella&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. is established for two new species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cooperi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunyuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Western Australia. An illustrated description of both species is given. The two species stand out in the family Parabathynellidae by their pygmoid body (the ratio of length to width: 5) and the relatively long head (equaling the anterior five thoracic segments combined). The following characters of both new species associated with the mouthparts are also unique within the Parabathynellidae: (i) the gargantuan labrum with a high number (&gt; 30) of narrow teeth, (ii) the incisor process with four main and three tiny additional teeth, arranged in two size groups, and (iii) the two disto-inner spines of the distal endite of the maxillule being longer than the terminal spines. These unusual characters seem to have developed in response to the predatory habits, which is evidenced by the presence of an unidentified ostracod prey in the gut of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunyuensis.&lt;/i&gt; The new genus, with its primitive characters, closely resembles the genus &lt;i&gt;Notobathynella&lt;/i&gt; Schminke, 1973.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Parabathynellidae; &lt;i&gt;Brevisomabathynella&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.; two new predatory species; Western Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Parabathynellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.-L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Park</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Reddy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-42</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudourostyla pelotensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Ciliophora, Stichotrichia, Urostylida): a new psammophilic ciliate from the southern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In samples of sand collected from the Laranjal beach, a lake shore located in the state of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, we found a new urostylid species characterized as: &lt;i&gt;Pseudourostyla&lt;/i&gt; measuring about 190 x 80 µm &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo;&lt;/i&gt; body very flexible, dorsoventrally compressed in almost 2:1 proportion, with ovoid and ellipsoid colorless cortical granules and displaying a short beak-like projection oriented to the left at the anterior region of the cell. Two contractile vacuoles present. Somatic ciliature with a typical bicorona and urostylid midventral complex formed by cirral pairs, that ends below the equatorial region of the cell. Pre-transverse cirri lacking; on average two frontoterminal cirri, five left and six right marginal cirral rows, six transverse cirri and eight dorsal kineties. Adoral zone composed of about 50 membranelles. &lt;i&gt;Pseudourostyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pelotensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other congeners by the presence of an anterior beak-like projection, two contractile vacuoles instead of one, and a unique combination of other characters including extension of the midventral complex, number of adoral membranelles and of macronuclear nodules.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lagoa dos Patos; new species; Rio Grande do Sul; Spirotrichea; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lagoa dos Patos; new species; Rio Grande do Sul; Spirotrichea; taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>D. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Paiva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva-Neto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Lacertilia: Gekkonidae) from Papua New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murua,&lt;/i&gt; from Woodlark Island, off the southeastern tip of Papua New Guinea. The new species differs from all Papuan congeners except &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;louisiadensis&lt;/i&gt; (de Vis) and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aaroni&lt;/i&gt; Günther &amp; Rösler in having a single row of enlarged subcaudal scales. From &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;louisiadensis,&lt;/i&gt; the new species is easily distinguished by its color pattern and by having fewer rows of enlarged dorsal tubercles; from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aaroni&lt;/i&gt; by its larger size and fewer dark dorsal bands. The new species is almost certainly restricted to Woodlark Island and represents the first endemic reptile described from that island.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">lizard; gecko; Milne Bay; Woodlark Island; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">lizard</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kraus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Allison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1246.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1246</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rivulus mahdiaensis, &lt;/i&gt;a new killifish from central Guyana (Cyprinodontiformes: Rivulidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahdiaensis,&lt;/i&gt; new species, was found in a small creek, a tributary of the Potaro River, near Mahdia, central Guyana. Males differ from all other species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; by possessing elongate anal and dorsal fins, and an extremely large and lyre-shaped caudal fin with long extensions. Females differ from other species of the genus, except for three closely related species, by the presence of a narrow, dark longitudinal band on the sides. &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahdiaensis&lt;/i&gt; possesses a unique karyotype (2n=38) among members of this group. Comparison of mitochondrial DNA sequences place this species as a member of a monophyletic clade which includes other small species from the Guyana shield and adjacent areas of northeastern South America.&lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahdiaensis,&lt;/i&gt; una nueva especie, se encontró en un pequeño arroyo tributario del Rio Potaro cercano a la localidad de Madhia , en la Guyana Central. Los machos difieren de todas las otras especies del género Rivulus por sus aletas anales y dorsales extremadamente largas y una aleta caudal en forma de lira con largos filamentos en sus extremos. Las hembras difieren de otras especies del Género , excepto por tres especies relacionadas, por la presencia de una estrecha y obscura banda longitudinal en ambos lados. &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahdiaensis&lt;/i&gt; posee un único cariotipo (2n=38) entre los miembros de este grupo. Comparando la secuencia de DNA mitocondrial podemos situar a esta especie como un miembro de un clado monofilético que incluye otras pequeñas especies de la región de la Guyana y áreas vecinas del Noroeste de Sudamérica</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cyprinodontiformes; Rivulidae; &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt;; Guyana; molecular phylogeny; karyotype; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cyprinodontiformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Suijker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Collier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-13</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of Mesozoic Myodocopina (Ostracoda) and a new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Mesoleberis hollandica&lt;/i&gt;, from the Upper Cretaceous of Belgium and The Netherlands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Although Paleozoic strata have produced many ostracode fossils in the suborder Myodocopina, which are also abundant in today’s seas, their record is extremely sparse in Mesozoic strata. A new genus and species of myodocopid, &lt;i&gt;Mesoleberis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hollandica,&lt;/i&gt; from the upper Maastrichtian (Upper Cretaceous) of the southeast Netherlands and nearby Belgium is described herein. In addition, brief supplementary descriptions and illustrations are presented of other Myodocopina that have been reported from Mesozoic deposits; many of those species are referred to different genera, and six are placed in the category “species &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia.”&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ostracoda; Myodocopida; Mesozoic; Cretaceous; The Netherlands; Belgium; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ostracoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kornicker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Bakel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>H. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fraaije</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jagt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Northeastern Palaearctic light coloured &lt;i&gt;Neocrepidodera&lt;/i&gt; Heikertinger, 1911 (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae), with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The light coloured &lt;i&gt;Neocrepidodera&lt;/i&gt; Heikertinger from East Siberia are reviewed. Six species are recognized in this region, including the newly described &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;konstantinovi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and the new record of &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;motschulskii&lt;/i&gt; (Konstantinov) from Primorskiy Kray that represents a major range extension. A neotype is designated for N. sublaevis (Motschulsky) and a re-description is provided for this species. A diagnosis along with figures of pronotum, aedeagus, vaginal palpi and spermatheca are presented for all species, and a key for the Eastern Siberian light coloured taxa is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae; &lt;i&gt;Neocrepidodera&lt;/i&gt;; Eastern Siberia; new species; neotype; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Baselga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1245.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1245</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new records of dendrochirotid and dactylochirotid holothuroids (Echinodermata : Holothuroidea) from off the east coast of South Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Numerous unidentified specimens of Holothuroidea received from the Natal and South African Museums or present in the collections of the former University of Durban-Westville, contain several new species and many that are new to the fauna of South Africa. This paper includes descriptions of new species or new records of several dendrochirotid holothuroids and a dactylochirotid from off the east coast of South Africa, extending from Kosi Bay in the north to the Port St Johns-East London area, in the Eastern Cape Province, the latter region represents the transition zone between the southern African subtropical and warm-temperate zoogeographical provinces. A few other species have been added if they represent juvenile material, or considered extensions of ranges (bathymetric or otherwise) of previously known species, or confirmation of a species previously recorded from a single locality in the region under consideration. Of the 16 species here treated, four are new to science, seven new to the fauna of South Africa, whereas the rest are either extension of ranges or additional records. The four new species are &lt;i&gt;Psolidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multipes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acorbula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ekkentropelma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;groovia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Psolidothuria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yasmeena.&lt;/i&gt; The following six species are additions to the fauna of South Africa: &lt;i&gt;Thyone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;avenusta&lt;/i&gt; Cherbonnier, 1970; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comata&lt;/i&gt; Cherbonnier, 1988; &lt;i&gt;Selenkiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxa&lt;/i&gt; Cherbonnier, 1970; &lt;i&gt;Ohshimella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocula&lt;/i&gt; (Cherbonnier, 1988); &lt;i&gt;Plesiocolochirus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessellarus&lt;/i&gt; (Cherbonnier, 1970) and &lt;i&gt;Staurothyone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosacea&lt;/i&gt; (Semper, 1869). &lt;i&gt;Pseudocolochirus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dispar&lt;/i&gt; (Lampert, 1889) is new to the fauna of southern Africa, recorded for the first time from Mozambique. The remaining species include &lt;i&gt;Stolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoalbescens&lt;/i&gt; Thandar, 2005; &lt;i&gt;Sclerothyone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;velligera&lt;/i&gt; (Ludwig &amp; Heding, 1935); &lt;i&gt;Ohshimella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ehrenbergii&lt;/i&gt; (Selenka, 1868); &lt;i&gt;Pawsonellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africanus&lt;/i&gt; Thandar, 1986 and &lt;i&gt;Trachasina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crucifera&lt;/i&gt; (Semper, 1869).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Thandar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lyonetiidae of Turkey with notes on their distribution and zoogeography (Lepidoptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five species of Lyonetiidae are reported from Turkey: &lt;i&gt;Lyonetia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prunifoliella&lt;/i&gt; (Hübner, 1796), &lt;i&gt;Lyonetia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clerkella&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1758), &lt;i&gt;Leucoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malifoliella&lt;/i&gt; (Costa, 1836), &lt;i&gt;Bedellia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;somnulentella&lt;/i&gt; (Zeller, 1847), and &lt;i&gt;Leucoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laburnella&lt;/i&gt; (Stainton, 1851). The last was collected from &lt;i&gt;Genista&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tinctoria&lt;/i&gt; in Ordu province and is considered a new pest in Turkey.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Lyonetiidae; Türkiye; pest; distribution; host plants</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Seven</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Choroterpes &lt;/i&gt;Eaton (Ephemeroptera: Leptophlebiidae) from Costa Rica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gregoryi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Maquenco, Costa Rica) and &lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mairena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; (type locality: Cuajiniquil, Costa Rica) (Ephemeroptera: Leptophlebiidae: Atalophlebiinae) are described from imagos and nymphs. Both species occur along the west coast of Costa Rica in streams on or near the Nicoya Complex. &lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mairena&lt;/i&gt; is adapted to living in temporary streams with long dry seasons, while &lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gregoryi&lt;/i&gt; is found in permanent streams. Both species occur in pools with extensive leaf packs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt;; Ephemeroptera; Leptophlebiidae; Osa; Nicoya; Santa Elena; new species; temporary streams; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Choroterpes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Ávila</middlename>
          <lastname>A.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Flowers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1244.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1244</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Centrolene &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Anura: Centrolenidae) from Ecuador with comments on the taxonomy and biogeography of Glassfrogs</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of Glassfrog, &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mariaelenae&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., from the Contrafuerte de Tzunantza, southeastern Ecuador. The new species is assigned to the &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorzulai&lt;/i&gt; species group, a clade previously known only from the Guayana Shield region, because the parietal peritoneum is transparent and the hepatic peritoneum is covered by guanophores. We analyze the diversity patterns of Glassfrogs from eastern Ecuador. The distribution of the new species herein described supports previous hypothesis of a biogeographical connection between the Andes and the Guayana Shield for various groups of plants and animals; particularly a relationship between the Guayana Shield and the sandstone outcrops mountain ranges of southeastern Ecuador and northeastern Peru. We also comment on the infrageneric and generic classification of Glassfrogs, and propose the new combinations &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balionotum&lt;/i&gt; n. comb., &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antisthenesi&lt;/i&gt; n. comb., and &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulverata&lt;/i&gt; n. comb.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mariaelenae&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; biogeography; Ecuador</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mariaelenae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cisneros-Heredia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdiarmid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Amphipoea &lt;/i&gt;Billberg, 1820, from northwestern Iran (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amphipoea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maryamae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the low mountains of West Azerbaijan province in northwestern Iran. The habitat is semi-steppe with herbaceous vegetation and scattered trees. Adults and male and female genitalia are described and illustrated and compared with presumably closely related &lt;i&gt;Amphipoea&lt;/i&gt; species. The genus &lt;i&gt;Amphipoea&lt;/i&gt; previously was unrecorded from Iran.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; Iran; Noctuidae; &lt;i&gt;Amphipoea&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zahiri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fibiger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-39</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of the seasonal killifish genus &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt;, subgenus &lt;i&gt;Hypsolebias &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cyprinodontiformes: Rivulidae) from the rio Paracatu drainage, rio São Francisco basin, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of the neotropical seasonal killifish genus &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt; are described from the middle rio Paracatu drainage of the middle rio São Francisco basin, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virgulatus&lt;/i&gt; is a typical member of the &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notatus&lt;/i&gt; species group, diagnosed by the derived A-pattern frontal squamation and presence of blue spots on distal margin of the dorsal fin in males. It is similar to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trilineatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auratus&lt;/i&gt; in having the anterior portion of the flanks golden, with dark brown to black blotches in males, and differs from those species by having more blotches on the flank, bars present on the caudal peduncle, and hyaline pectoral fins in males. &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alternatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delucai&lt;/i&gt; in having the combination of anal fin rounded in males and anal fin spatula-shaped in females, but differs in having the dorsal-fin origin anteriorly positioned and a dark gray to black stripe on the distal margin of dorsal fin in males. &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibberatus&lt;/i&gt; differs from all other congeners by the pronounced and convex profile of the anterodorsal portion of the body in females.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Annual fish; killifish; Cyprinodontiformes; Rivulidae; &lt;i&gt;Simpsonichthys&lt;/i&gt;; rio São Francisco; systematics; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Annual fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. E. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brasil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla circumdata &lt;/i&gt;group (Amphibia: Anura: Hylidae) from Chapada Diamantina, State of Bahia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumdata&lt;/i&gt; group, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Serra dos Barbados, Municipality of Abaíra, State of Bahia, Brazil. This locality belongs to Chapada Diamantina, a semiarid region in central Bahia. This is the first record of a species of the &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumdata&lt;/i&gt; group from the Brazilian semiarid. &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantina&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed by the medium size (snout-vent length 47.0–51.7 mm in adult specimens); head length 2.8–2.9 times smaller than snout-vent length; tympanum medium-sized, its diameter 1.3–1.5 times smaller than eye diameter (tympanum diameter/snout-vent length 0.07); thigh and tibia lengths 0.48–0.52 and 0.49–0.51 of snout-vent length, respectively; dorsum medium to blackish brown, with weak transverse dark brown bars; flanks, anterior, and posterior surfaces of thighs with dark transverse brown stripes, lacking additional thin stripes between them; distinct vocal slits in adult males; advertisement call with 2–4 notes, and dominant frequency from 0.39–0.56 kHz.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chapada Diamantina; &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumdata&lt;/i&gt; species group; advertisement call; Northeastern Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chapada Diamantina; &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diamantina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Bokermannohyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumdata&lt;/i&gt; species group; advertisement call; Northeastern Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Napoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Juncá</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1242.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1242</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the gekkotan lizards of Bénin, with the description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The gecko fauna of Bénin is extremely poorly known, with only two species having previously been mentioned in the literature on the basis of voucher specimens. We provide evidence for the occurrence of seven additional species, bringing the national total to nine confirmed species. Another five species are known from localities to both the east and west of Bénin and almost certainly are part of the national fauna. One of the species confirmed for Bénin is a new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus.&lt;/i&gt; This new form is distinguished by its 14–16 dorsal tubercle rows, enlarged median subcaudal scales, atuberculate tail dorsum, 38 precloacal-femoral pores, and 6–7 (usually 7) divided scansors beneath digit four of both the manus and pes. We also provide the first record of &lt;i&gt;Lygodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conraui&lt;/i&gt; for Togo.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">West Africa; Bénin; Togo; Gekkonidae; Eublepharidae; &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; description</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">West Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tchibozo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>S. G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pauwels</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lenglet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Natural history and distribution of the enigmatic southern Appalachian opilionid, &lt;i&gt;Fumontana deprehendor &lt;/i&gt;Shear (Laniatores: Triaenonychidae), with an assessment of morphological variation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The opilionid species &lt;i&gt;Fumontana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deprehendor&lt;/i&gt; Shear, 1977 (Laniatores: Triaenonychidae) represents a monotypic genus, previously known from only four specimens collected at two published localities, both old-growth forest sites in the southern Appalachian mountains. In an effort to increase the biogeographic and taxonomic information available for this phylogenetically and morphologically unique opilionid, we undertook a focused sampling effort throughout the southern Appalachians. These field efforts uncovered both more individuals (n = 141) and a broader distributional range (22 newly-discovered populations) for this monotypic genus. Examination of both somatic and penis morphology reveals little geographic variation across spatially disjunct populations. Our results provide a new perspective on conservation priorities for &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deprehendor.&lt;/i&gt; Rather than representing a single, hyper-rare taxon of limited distribution, our data suggest a broader distribution across the uplands of the southern Appalachians. We recommend that conservation attention be focused on learning more about the distribution, biology and relative rarity of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deprehendor&lt;/i&gt; in the smaller, geographically isolated units.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Appalachian mountains; Opiliones; cryophilic arthropod; cryptic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Appalachian mountains</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Thomas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hedin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-36</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Coenosopsia &lt;/i&gt;Malloch (Diptera, Anthomyiidae) from southern Brazil and a reappraisal of the cladistic relationships of the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Coenosopsia&lt;/i&gt; Malloch (Diptera, Muscidae), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albuquerquei&lt;/i&gt; Bortolanza and Carvalho, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Telêmeco Borba, in the state of Paraná, southern Brazil. With this new species included, a cladistic re-analysis of the genus was performed, using the data matrix of Nihei and Carvalho (2004). Results of this analysis suggest a close relationship between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albuquerquei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrari.&lt;/i&gt; This clade is the sister-group of the other &lt;i&gt;Coenosopsia&lt;/i&gt; species: (C. &lt;i&gt;prima&lt;/i&gt; (C. &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruviana)&lt;/i&gt; (C. &lt;i&gt;michelseni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;floridensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mexicana))).&lt;/i&gt; Biogeographically, the vicariant events previously proposed for South America support the evolutionary history of this genus. Additionally, we discuss the possibility that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;michelseni&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrari&lt;/i&gt; were not always restricted to the “cerrado” of central Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anthomyiidae; biogeography; &lt;i&gt;Coenosopsia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anthomyiidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bortolanza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the American species of &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis &lt;/i&gt;Hinton (Coleoptera: Elmidae), with a new species from Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt; Hinton is taxonomically reviewed. A new species of riffle beetle from Argentina, &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uruzuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated from adults of both sexes and the larva. Ten additional species of &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt; are treated: &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sandersoni&lt;/i&gt; Brown, &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bufo&lt;/i&gt; (Sharp), &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt; Delève, X. &lt;i&gt;leechi&lt;/i&gt; Perkins &amp; Steiner, &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marcapata&lt;/i&gt; Perkins &amp; Steiner, &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarsalis&lt;/i&gt; Hinton, X. &lt;i&gt;teres&lt;/i&gt; Hinton, &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;audax&lt;/i&gt; Hinton, &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comis&lt;/i&gt; Hinton and &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laura&lt;/i&gt; Brown. Male genitalia of each species are illustrated, some of them for the first time. Distributional records, diagnoses and a key to distinguish the species of &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt; are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">riffle beetles; Elmidae; Elminae; &lt;i&gt;Xenelmis&lt;/i&gt;; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">riffle beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Manzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1241.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1241</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new endemic species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Mus &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia, Mammalia) on the Island of Cyprus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The house mouse &lt;i&gt;(Mus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;musculus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domesticus)&lt;/i&gt; and the short-tailed mouse of the eastern Mediterranean area &lt;i&gt;(M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macedonicus)&lt;/i&gt; were thought to live sympatrically on Cyprus Island. Recently, a phylogenetic survey has shown that the non-commensal mouse of Cyprus was an unknown sister species of European wild mice. Here, we describe this new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Mus&lt;/i&gt; (Rodentia, Mammalia), namely &lt;i&gt;Mus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cypriacus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., based on 19 specimens trapped in the southern part of Cyprus. These animals were first compared to Eurasian species of mice using both molecular genetics (complete D-loop sequences and nuclear gene intron) and cytogenetics to state on its systematic status. Then classical and geometric morphometric analyses on both cranial and dental characters</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cucchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Orth</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Auffray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Renaud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fabre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Catalan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hadjisterkotis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bonhomme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vigne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the rotifer fauna of Disko Island, Greenland, with notes on selected species from a stagnant freshwater lake</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The rotifer fauna in Moraine Lake on Disko Island was investigated. 24 species were identified, of which 22 are new for Disko Island and three are new to Greenland. The new findings are presented in a species list that summarizes all records of rotifers from Disko Island, including several previously unpublished records. Furthermore, notes are given on the morphology of some selected species, including &lt;i&gt;Eothinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mikrocodides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chlaena&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Resticula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nyssa.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arctic; Rotifera; SEM; species list; trophi morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arctic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sørensen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-49</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Closterocerus oryzamyntor &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Eulophidae: Entedoninae), a larval parasitoid of the rice hispa &lt;i&gt;Dicladispa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armigera &lt;/i&gt;in Bangladesh (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Hispinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Closterocerus&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae), &lt;i&gt;Closterocerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oryzamyntor&lt;/i&gt; Gumovsky &amp; Zhu &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on morphological and molecular data. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oryzamyntor&lt;/i&gt; is a larval endoparasitoid of a major pest of rice, &lt;i&gt;Dicladispa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armigera&lt;/i&gt; (Chrysomelidae: Hispinae). &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oryzamyntor&lt;/i&gt; is known so far only from Bangladesh, and only from this host. The species is characterized by the following morphological features: 1) deep sutures on the vertex of the male, connected to form a complete transvertexal suture in the female; 2) a comparatively long malar space, which is 0.3 times as long as the eye height, and 0.7 times as long as the breadth of the mouth; 3) predominantly pale femora, tibiae, tarsi and antennal scape; 4) the comparatively wide scape of the male, 2.6–2.7 times as long as broad; 5) the male pedicel, flagellum, coxae and gaster, which are all dark. Partial gene sequences of the 28S D2 ribosomal region were identical for all individuals sampled, but differed from two &lt;i&gt;Closterocerus&lt;/i&gt; sequences on GenBank by 24 and 27 base pairs (about 6%). Both CytB and COI mitochondrial gene fragments demonstrated slight variation within the species, but no other eulophids have been sequenced for these genes, thus comparative data are lacking for these genes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">28S; Bangladesh; biological control; Chrysomelidae; &lt;i&gt;Closterocerus&lt;/i&gt;; COI; Cytochrome B; &lt;i&gt;Dicladispa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armigera&lt;/i&gt;; DNA; Eulophidae; gene sequences; hispa; parasitoid wasps; rice</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">28S</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gumovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Polaszek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Murphy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rabbi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.-D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Belminus corredori&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Bolboderini (Hemiptera: Reduviidae: Triatominae) from Santander, Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Belminus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corredori,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of Bolboderini, is described on the basis of specimens collected in Puente Tierra, municipality of San Gil, Departament of Santander, Colombia. Specimens were found in well-built dwellings located approximately 1,810 meters of altitude in a region characterized by the presence of dry mountain forest.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Belminus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corredori&lt;/i&gt;; Reduviidae; Triatominae; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Belminus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corredori&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Galvão</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>M</middlename>
          <lastname>Angulo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1240.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1240</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new endemic species of mountain lizard from Northwestern Spain: &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta galani &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Squamata : Lacertidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Montes de León (northwest Iberia). This new species, &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by its relatively large size, high number of blue ocelli on the shoulders and the relatively frequent contact or near-contact between the supranasal and the first loreal scale, the fairly straight squamosal bone (only curved on its posterior part), a unique karyotype in &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta&lt;/i&gt; combining 2n=36 chromosomes, an L-type NOR and differentiated W and Z sex chromosomes, and unique mitochondrial DNA sequences for the cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and 12S rRNA genes. The correlation analyses show that morphology in general, but especially scalation, is strongly correlated with the amount of precipitation during the months of lizard activity, which suggests that these are not good taxonomic characters, and that other characters apparently independent of the climate like for instance osteological, karyological and DNA features are much more reliable in delimiting species boundaries in &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta.&lt;/i&gt; According to our phylogenetic analyses, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; nov. is part of a very well supported clade that originated around 2.5 mya and also includes &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinezricai.&lt;/i&gt; Phylogeny suggests &lt;i&gt;I.martinezricai&lt;/i&gt; might be the sister taxon to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; nov. from which it split approximately 2 mya, at the beginning of the Pleistocene. The clade containing &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; nov., &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinezricai&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; was probably widely distributed across western Iberia during moderately cool and moist phases of the Pleistocene, but it was probably restricted to its present range as a result of the general temperature increase during the Holocene and competition with other lacertid lizards. &lt;i&gt;Iberolacerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; nov. is endemic to the Montes de León, where it is isolated from the other species of the “monticola-group” by the Duero and Miño-Sil Rivers, but particularly by the Bibei river valley.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mountain lizards; speciation; evolution; biogeography; taxonomy; phylogeny; cytochrome b; 12S rRNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mountain lizards</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <lastname>Arribas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Carranza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Odierna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthaxius &lt;/i&gt;Sakai &amp; de Saint Laurent, 1989, including two new to science, from the Solomon Islands and New Caledonia (Crustacea, Thalassinidea, Axiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Material recently collected from the Solomon Islands include three species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthaxius&lt;/i&gt; Sakai &amp; de Saint Laurent, 1989, two of which are new to science: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadaletae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and a specimen of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polyacantha&lt;/i&gt; Miyake &amp; Sakai, 1967. Two specimens from New Caledonia are assigned to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadaletae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; The new taxa are readily differentiated from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polyacantha&lt;/i&gt; by their longer rostrum and the glabrous postcervical region of carapace. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by a slender rostrum longer than the eyestalks, with two lateral and a suborbital spine, the gastric region with a median, submedian and lateral carina, setose pereopods 1 with three and two upper spines on the propodal palm and dactylus respectively, the telson longer than broad with three teeth and one spinule on the lateral border. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadaletae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; but differs by the gastric region with two submedian carinae, the pereopod 1 with four upper spines both on the propodal palm and the dactylus, the maxilliped 3 basis with a large lower distal spine (absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.)&lt;/b&gt; and the abdominal pleura 3–5 with an anterior spinule (absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.).&lt;/b&gt;Trois espèces d’Acanthaxius Sakai &amp; de Saint Laurent, 1989, dont deux nouvelles, des Iles Salomon et de Nouvelle Calédonie (Crustacea, Thalassinidea, Axiidae). Du matériel récemment récolté des Iles Salomon a permis d’identifier trois espèces d’Acanthaxius dont deux sont nouvelles : &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadaletae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; et un spécimen d’A. &lt;i&gt;polyacantha&lt;/i&gt; Miyake &amp; Sakai, 1967. Deux spécimens de Nouvelle Calédonie sont placés dans &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadaletae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Les deux nouveaux taxa se distinguent aisément d’A. &lt;i&gt;polyacantha&lt;/i&gt; par leur rostre plus long et la région postcervicale de la carapace inerme. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clevai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; se distingue par un rostre long et grêle avec deux épines latérales et une suborbitale, la région gastrique avec une carène médiane, une submédiane et une latérale, un péréiopode 1 pourvu de nombreuses soies et de trois et deux épines dorsales respectivement sur le paume et le dactyle, un telson plus long que large muni</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ngoc-Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1239.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1239</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Coeloides &lt;/i&gt;Wesmael of subfamily Braconinae (Hymenoptera: Braconidae) in China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of &lt;i&gt;Coeloides&lt;/i&gt; Wesmael of the tribe Coeloidini (Hymenoptera: Braconidae: Braconinae) are revised in China, and eleven species are recognized. Among them, four new species: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glaboventris&lt;/i&gt; Wang et Chen, sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longquanus&lt;/i&gt; Wang et Chen, sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; Wang et Chen, sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;changbaiensis&lt;/i&gt; Wang et Chen, sp. nov., are described and illustrated in detail. Some of the known species of this genus and one new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; Wang et Chen described in this paper are parasitoids of larvae of various species of Scolytidae, Curculionidae and Buprestidae (Coleoptera), many of which are notorious pests in coniferous and broadleaved trees. The type and other voucher specimens are deposited in the Parasitic Hymenoptera Collection, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, and Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Braconidae; Braconinae; Coeloidini; &lt;i&gt;Coeloides&lt;/i&gt; Wesmael; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Braconidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.-P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.-X.</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-H.</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Himantura hortlei &lt;/i&gt;n. sp., a new species of whipray (Myliobatiformes: Dasyatidae) from Irian Jaya, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Indo-Malay region, which is represented by at least 17 whiprays of the genus &lt;i&gt;Himantura,&lt;/i&gt; has the richest dasyatid fauna of any region. &lt;i&gt;Himantura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hortlei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described based on specimens from coastal marine and estuarine habitats in the Arafura Sea off Irian Jaya (southwestern New Guinea). The mature male holotype was caught in the estuary of the Minajerwi River. It is a moderately large ray that reaches at least 0.7 m disc width and 2.4 m total length. This species can be distinguished from most of its congeners by the combination of a relatively narrow, heart-shaped disc with a very long angular snout, very small eyes, a non-protrusible mouth, no deep circumoral grooves, larger and more slowly developing denticles, a less well-developed lateral prepelvic process, a yellowish ventral surface when fresh, denticles present along the upper anterior snout margin, and a denticle band ending well forward of the eyes in adults.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Himantura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hortlei&lt;/i&gt;; Myliobatiformes; whipray; southwestern Irian Jaya; Indo-Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Himantura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hortlei&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Last</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Manjaji-Matsumoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kailola</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-34</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new wobbegong shark, &lt;i&gt;Orectolobus hutchinsi &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Orectolobiformes: Orectolobidae) from southwestern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Orectolobus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hutchinsi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.. is a moderate-sized wobbegong shark found in shallow continental shelf habitats off Western Australia. It occurs from Coral Bay (near North West Cape) south to Groper Bluff (west of Bremer Bay) in depths of 9–106 m where it is caught as by-catch of local gillnet, longline, rock lobster and recreational fisheries. It is sympatric with two other commercial wobbegong species, &lt;i&gt;Orectolobus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus,&lt;/i&gt; but differs from these and other IndoPacific species in having the combination of a few unbranched dermal lobes, relatively tall dorsal fins, no warty tubercles on the back of adults, and dark brown corrugated saddles without white spots and blotches. Some details of its biology are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Orectolobus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hutchinsi&lt;/i&gt;; Orectolobiformes; wobbegong shark; southwestern Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Orectolobus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hutchinsi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Last</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chidlow</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Compagno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Quantitative analysis of interspecific and ontogenetic variation in &lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum &lt;/i&gt;species (Teleostei: Osteoglossiformes: Osteoglossidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Patterns of interspecific and intraspecific variation were investigated on samples of postembryos, juveniles, and adults of the two species of the osteoglossid genus &lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt; (O. &lt;i&gt;bicirrhosum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferreirai).&lt;/i&gt; Twenty-two morphometric characters were analyzed, utilizing principal component analysis (PCA) that discriminate ontogenetic classes and between species. The results showed differences in both categories. Morphometric characters related to dorsal and anal fin lengths proved to be the most important in taxonomic recognition. The comparison of growth trajectories for these characters showed that growth offset for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicirrhosum&lt;/i&gt; overlaps with growth onset for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferreirai,&lt;/i&gt; which may be indicative of a peramorphic morphology in the latter species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt;; PCA; morphometrics; ontogeny; heterochrony; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Osteoglossum&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>E. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Sant-Anna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1238.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1238</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Reports on the results of the N.Oc. "Prof. W. Besnard" expeditions to the southern coast of Brazil under the Revizee Program: Chirostylidae and Galatheidae (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The distribution patterns of the species of the family Chirostylidae and Galatheidae collected under the Revizee Program (Living Resources in the Exclusive Economic Zone) off the Brazilian southern coast are analyzed. The study area extended from the Cape São Tomé (Rio de Janeiro; 22°00’S) south to Chui (Rio Grande do Sul; 34°30’S). The collections were made during several cruises of N.Oc. “Prof. W. Besnard” between December 1997 and April 1998 over the shelf and slope (60–808 m). One species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Agononida,&lt;/i&gt; seven species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Munida,&lt;/i&gt; one species of &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; and one of &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt; were collected.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chirostylidae; Galatheidae; &lt;i&gt;Agononida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt;; Brazilian southern coast</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chirostylidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>A. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Melo-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new anchialine shrimp of the genus &lt;i&gt;Procaris &lt;/i&gt;from Christmas Island: the first occurrence of the Procarididae in the Indian Ocean (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A fifth species of the anchialine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Procaris&lt;/i&gt; is described from Christmas Island, northeast Indian Ocean. This marks the first record of the Procarididae from the Indian Ocean. The closest known congeneric species, and the only other known from the Indo-West Pacific region, is &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hawaiiana&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1973, from Hawaii. The new species can be separated from other described species by its angular fifth abdominal pleuron, having the medial eye lobe longer than the lateral, and by having a distolateral tooth on the scaphocerite. A cladistic analysis suggests the new species is sister to the clade containing the Pacific, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hawaiiana,&lt;/i&gt; and the Atlantic &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anchialine; Procarididae; &lt;i&gt;Procaris&lt;/i&gt;; Indian Ocean; new species; Christmas Island</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anchialine</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-33</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Dendrobatidae) with maternal care from Kaieteur National Park, Guyana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Kaieteur National Park, Guyana, South America. The new species can be distinguished from close relatives by the presence of a median lingual process, first finger equal to second, Finger III not distinctly swollen but all fingers slightly swollen in males, presence of fringes on fingers, presence of a dorsolateral stripe from posterior corner of eye, absence of an oblique lateral stripe, and differences in tadpole morphology, colouration and pattern, vocalizations and ecology. This is only the second species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; known to provide maternal care for tadpoles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Dendrobatidae; &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaiei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; maternal care; Kaieteur National Park; Guyana; Guiana Shield</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sambhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Roopsind</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lenglet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bourne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The issid genus &lt;i&gt;Gelastyrella &lt;/i&gt;Yang (Hemiptera: Fulgoroidea: Issidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Oriental planthopper genus &lt;i&gt;Gelastyrella&lt;/i&gt; Yang is reviewed. Two new species, &lt;i&gt;G..&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hainanensis&lt;/i&gt; Ran &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Liang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (China: Hainan) and &lt;i&gt;G..&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; Ran &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Liang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (China: Yunnan), are described and illustrated. A key to the species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Issidae; &lt;i&gt;Gelastyrella&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.-P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Liang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1237.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1237</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of phytoseiid mites (Acari: Mesostigmata) from southern Tunisia, with discussion of its phylogenetic position</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phytoseiid mite &lt;i&gt;Africoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flechtmanni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from specimens collected on an unknown small weed growing under palm trees in an oasis in southern Tunisia. This mite is unique in the following combination of characteristics: dorsal shield of both sexes and male ventri-anal shield eroded; all dorsal shield setae minute; peritreme very short; setae JV1, JV3, JV4 and ZV1 absent; hypostome elongate; chelicera with long median segment but digits short and edentate; legs short and without macrosetae. The phylogenetic relationships of this new genus with close taxa are analysed; its taxonomic position within the Typhlodrominae is uncertain.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Phytoseiidae; taxonomy; predatory mites; &lt;i&gt;Africoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flechtmanni&lt;/i&gt;; Tunisia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kreiter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.-S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tixier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Apogonalia &lt;/i&gt;from Mexico (Insecta: Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Cicadellini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Apogonalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielsoni,&lt;/i&gt; a new cicadelline leafhopper species from Mexico (Nayarit State), is described and illustrated. The color pattern of the new species is similar to that of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;germana&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler), whereas the male genital characteristics are similar to those of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler). The aedeagal shaft of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielsoni&lt;/i&gt; has a pair of short, triangular lateral processes that are absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola.&lt;/i&gt; The paraphyses in both species are formed by a curved, Y-shaped basal plate and by a pair of narrow and very long rami. &lt;i&gt;Apogonalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielsoni&lt;/i&gt; has the arms of the basal plate longer than those of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola.&lt;/i&gt; Moreover, the rami of the new species are dorsally or ventrally curved, whereas in the latter species they are approximately straight.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cicadellinae; &lt;i&gt;Apogonalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielsoni&lt;/i&gt;; sharpshooter; taxonomy; morphology; North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cicadellinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Felix</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mejdalani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New &lt;i&gt;Carlia fusca &lt;/i&gt;complex lizards (Reptilia: Squamata: Scincidae) from New Guinea, Papua-Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent rapid-assessment surveys in western New Guinea have provided well-documented voucher specimens that show greater speciation within the &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt; complex in this area than indicated by the examination of older museum specimens. Variation in the morphometric and scalation traits of these new species does not differ greatly from other &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt; complex species. This result was anticipated owing to the overall low level of variation in these morphological features in the &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt; complex. Regionalization of distinct color patterns and abrupt shifts from one pattern to another indicate the existence of a distinct species along much of the southern coast from the Eilanden River basin to Etna Bay and another species from the northern coast of the Bomberai Peninsula. The variation and distribution of &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt; complex species are examined for populations in the southern and western “mainland” Papua-Indonesia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; Scincidae; &lt;i&gt;Carlia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt;; Papua-Indonesia; New Guinea; geographic variation; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zug</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Allison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Probreviceps &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Anura) from the Eastern Arc Mountains, Tanzania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Probreviceps&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Ukaguru Mountains in Tanzania, and is distinguished morphologically by its pointed and ridged snout. The species also differs from other members of the genus in its call and mitochondrial DNA. An updated phylogeny of all known Tanzanian &lt;i&gt;Probreviceps&lt;/i&gt; species and subspecies is presented, based on 12S and 16S rRNA mitochondrial sequences. An updated key of the species of &lt;i&gt;Probreviceps&lt;/i&gt; is also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanzania; amphibians; brevicipitines; &lt;i&gt;Probreviceps&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Ukaguru Mountains; Eastern Arc Mountains</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanzania</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Channing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Menegon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>R. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davenport</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The description of &lt;i&gt;Moritiella &lt;/i&gt;Buffington, new genus (Hymenoptera: Figitidae: Eucoilinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Moritiella&lt;/i&gt; Buffington, n. gen., is described, diagnosed and illustrated (Hymenoptera: Figitidae: Eucoilinae). Two species new to science are described: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;astrudae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Phylogenetic evidence suggests &lt;i&gt;Moritiella&lt;/i&gt; is among the &lt;i&gt;Zaeucoila&lt;/i&gt; group of genera, a group of eucoilines chiefly parasitic upon leaf-mining Agromyzidae (Diptera).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Moritiella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zaeucoila&lt;/i&gt; group; Eucoilinae; Figitidae; Cynipoidea; new species; new genus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Moritiella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Buffington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1236.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1236</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scirpophaga &lt;/i&gt;Treitschke, 1832 in China (Lepidoptera: Pyralidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scirpophaga&lt;/i&gt; are recognized from China; six are reported for the first time, and two are described as new: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linguatella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adunctella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Scirpophaga &lt;i&gt;melanostigma&lt;/i&gt; is proposed as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavidorsalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Keys to the species recorded from China are provided. The adults of the new species and the genital structures of all examined species are illustrated. The types of the new species and other specimens examined are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pyralidae; Schoenobiinae; &lt;i&gt;Scirpophaga&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; China; new species; new synonym</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pyralidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Distribution of larval Stomiidae of the Brazilian central coast, southwest Atlantic Ocean (12°S22°S)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study was designed to describe the occurrence and distribution of Stomiidae along the Brazilian central coast. Three oceanographic cruises were made in the Brazilian central coast during the spring/1998, winter/1999 and autumn/2000. Stomiid larvae were very rare in the samples, occurring in 13% of the sampled stations. A total of 102 stomiid larvae were collected representing 11 species, some of which could only be identified to genus: &lt;i&gt;Aristostomias&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Astronesthes&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Bathophilus&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Eustomias&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Melanostomias&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Stomias&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Chauliodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sloani,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Flagellostomias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boureei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Photonectes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirabilis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Photostomias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guernei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Stomias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis.&lt;/i&gt; All species identified have already been recorded from the Brazilian coast as adults, except for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guernei,&lt;/i&gt; first recorded in this study. Most taxa were distributed both in the northern and southern regions of the study area, including the banks of the Vitória-Trindade Ridge. &lt;i&gt;Stomias&lt;/i&gt; sp. was the most abundant taxon among all groups and was widely distributed along the study area. The species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sloani&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boureei&lt;/i&gt; were only collected in the south and north regions, respectively.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spatial distribution; Stomiidae; mesopelagic larvae; Southwest Atlantic Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spatial distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Castro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonecker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-36</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A cladistic analysis of the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Sepedonea &lt;/i&gt;Steyskal (Diptera: Sciomyzidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A cladistic analysis of the 13 known species of &lt;i&gt;Sepedonea&lt;/i&gt; Steyskal, 1973, is presented and a new species, &lt;i&gt;Sepedonea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giovana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described. The monophyly of the genus is confirmed, as is the genus’ sister-group relationship to &lt;i&gt;Sepedomerus&lt;/i&gt; Steyskal, 1973. The cladistic analysis was done using NONA and a matrix of 27 adult morphological characters, including structures of the male and female terminalia. The relationships in parenthetic notation are: (S. &lt;i&gt;guatemalana&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;veredae&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;lindneri&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;isthmi&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;lagoa&lt;/i&gt; ((S. &lt;i&gt;barbosai+&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canabravana)&lt;/i&gt; ((S. &lt;i&gt;neffi&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;giovana+S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guianica))(S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;telson&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;incipiens+S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trichotypa))))))))).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sciomyzidae; &lt;i&gt;Sepedonea&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical; cladistic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sciomyzidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Marinoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mathis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on some tardigrades from southern Mexico with description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight species of tardigrades are reported from southern Mexico (Chiapas: Selva El Ocote). Two of them (Pseudechiniscus &lt;i&gt;juanitae&lt;/i&gt; De Barros, 1939 and &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibber&lt;/i&gt; Beasley &amp; Pilato, 1987) are new to Central America, three are new to science: &lt;i&gt;Pseudechiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gullii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. and &lt;i&gt;Minibiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;continuus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; south Mexico; &lt;i&gt;Pseudechiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gullii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; &lt;i&gt;Minibiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;continuus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada; south Mexico; &lt;i&gt;Pseudechiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gullii&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1235.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1235</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematic revision of the fruit fly genus &lt;i&gt;Carpophthoromyia &lt;/i&gt;Austen (Diptera, Tephritidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Afrotropical fruit fly genus &lt;i&gt;Carpophthoromyia&lt;/i&gt; Austen is revised. In total, 17 species are recognized of which 7 are new to science: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;debeckeri&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dividua&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavofasciata&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interrupta&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radulata&lt;/i&gt; sp.n., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schoutedeni&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virgata&lt;/i&gt; sp.n.. &lt;i&gt;Carpophthoromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoena&lt;/i&gt; Enderlein is considered a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius). &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticeps&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi is considered not to belong to &lt;i&gt;Carpophthoromyia&lt;/i&gt; but to the gastrozonine genus &lt;i&gt;Clinotaenia&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi: &lt;i&gt;Clinotaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticeps&lt;/i&gt; (Bezzi) comb.nov. A lectotype is designated for each of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litterata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudotritea,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessmanni.&lt;/i&gt; All species are described or re-described, with illustrations of wing patterns and male and female terminalia where deemed necessary for unambiguous identification. An identification key to species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fruit flies; &lt;i&gt;Carpophthoromyia&lt;/i&gt;; Ceratitidina; Afrotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fruit flies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Meyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the feather mite subfamily Pterodectinae (Acari: Astigmata: Proctophyllodidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new pterodectine feather mites (Analgoidea: Proctophyllodidae) from Brazilian passerines (Passeriformes): &lt;i&gt;Pterodectes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaurochalinus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., from &lt;i&gt;Turdus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amaurochalinus&lt;/i&gt; Cabanis (Turdidae), and &lt;i&gt;Dolichodectes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropicus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., collected from &lt;i&gt;Elaenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chiriquensis&lt;/i&gt; Lawrence (Tyrannidae). A key to species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dolichodectes&lt;/i&gt; is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Astigmata; Analgoidea; feather mite; systematics; &lt;i&gt;Pterodectes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dolichodectes&lt;/i&gt;; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Astigmata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Valim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of &lt;i&gt;Greenidea psidii &lt;/i&gt;van der Goot and comparison with &lt;i&gt;Greenidea ficicola &lt;/i&gt;Takahashi (Hemiptera: Aphididae) in Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Greenidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psidii&lt;/i&gt; van der Goot, 1916 is registered by the first time in Brazil. It was found associated with &lt;i&gt;Psidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guajava&lt;/i&gt; L. in Paraná, Santa Catarina, and São Paulo States, and with &lt;i&gt;Psidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cattleianum&lt;/i&gt; Sabine in the city of Curitiba, Paraná. A brief comparative synopsis and pictures of the main diagnostic characters are given for this species and for &lt;i&gt;Greenidea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ficicola&lt;/i&gt; Takahashi, 1921, which was also recently found in Brazil, collected on &lt;i&gt;Ficus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;benjamina&lt;/i&gt; (L.) in Paraná and Santa Catarina, and on &lt;i&gt;Ficus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microcarpa&lt;/i&gt; L. in São Paulo State.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ficus aphid; Greenideinae; guava aphid; ornamental plants; &lt;i&gt;Psidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guajava&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ficus aphid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lazzari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zonta-De-Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cardoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Calado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1233.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1233</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Culoptila &lt;/i&gt;(Trichoptera: Glossosomatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The caddisfly genus &lt;i&gt;Culoptila&lt;/i&gt; is revised to include 17 previously described species and 9 new species. Illustrations of the male genitalia and a key are provided for all species. In addition, illustrations of male head and thoracic features, larval characters and cases, and female genitalia are included. New species described here include: &lt;i&gt;Culoptila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bidentata&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buenoi&lt;/i&gt; (Mexico), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cascada&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamata&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pararusia&lt;/i&gt; (Mexico), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plummerensis&lt;/i&gt; (eastern United States), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tapanti&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unispina&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica, Panama), and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vexillifera&lt;/i&gt; (Guatemala).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Glossosomatidae; Protoptilinae; &lt;i&gt;Culoptila&lt;/i&gt;; caddisfly; revision; new species; Neotropics; Nearctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Blahnik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holzenthal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of the River Shark &lt;i&gt;Glyphis &lt;/i&gt;(Carcharhinidae) reported from Cape York Peninsula, northern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The distribution of the river shark &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; in northern Australia is extended with new records of occurrence in the Gulf of Carpentaria and a reassessment of historical survey data from Cape York Peninsula. Nine new specimens of &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; sp. A were collected in 2005 from the Weipa region on the Queensland coast of the Gulf of Carpentaria. A re-examination of archival records from 1978–86 marine and estuarine fish surveys in the Gulf of Carpentaria and along the northern Queensland East Coast allowed a further nineteen &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; specimens to be identified. Combined this gives twenty-eight new records of &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; specimens from the coasts of Cape York Peninsula, Queensland. Common habitat characteristics for all captures were turbid, shallow, fast running tidal water in the upper reaches of coastal rivers. The substrate was generally muddy and the rivers lined with mangrove. In all surveys the representation of &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; was low, being less than 1% of the total shark captures historically and 0.002 sharks 50 m net hour -1 in Weipa 2005. The size range captured was 1000–1800 mm total length historically and 705 –1200 mm total length from Weipa 2005, with none recorded as sexually mature. Diagnostic characteristics of the Weipa specimens, identified as &lt;i&gt;Glyphis&lt;/i&gt; sp. A, were: lower jaw teeth protruding and “spear-like”; second dorsal fin greater than half the height of the first dorsal fin; the snout relatively short and fleshy in the lateral view; pectoral fin ventral surface black in colouration; the precaudal vertebral count between 118 and 123; and the total vertebral count between 204 and 209.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Speartooth shark; Wenlock River; whaler shark</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Speartooth shark</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peverell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcpherson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Garrett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gribble</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1232.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1232</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nematocysts of the Cubozoa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nematocysts (stinging organelles) are an important part of cnidarian identification, but the cnidomes of many species remain poorly known because of identification difficulties and confusing nomenclature. Currently, the cnidomes of 20 cubozoan species are documented in whole or in part (including four undescribed species and five newly described species); 18 of these are re-examined in detail, and the cnidomes of 13 species are newly presented. Type material was used for these studies where possible. A new category of nematocyst is designated, namely ‘p-rhopaloid’, characterized by having a v-shaped notch in the undischarged shaft, as in &lt;i&gt;p-mastigophores,&lt;/i&gt; but having a lobed discharged shaft, as in rhopaloids; this type of nematocyst is found in both the Carybdeida and Chirodropida. Measurements, shape descriptions, and photographs are presented for all cnidomes studied. Also presented are a glossary to nematocyst terminology, descriptive sections on nematocyst nomenclature and preparation, and a key to the nematocysts of theCubozoa. Special remarks sections for taxonomists and forensic specialists are given, along with a summary of phylogenetic patterns. This catalogue will be useful to taxonomists, envenomation physicians, and toxinologists, as well as anyone wishing to identify cubozoan specimens or stings.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Box jellyfish; Irukandji; sea wasps; cnidomes; cnidae; stinging organelles; stinging cells; Cnidaria; Cubomedusae; Carybdeida; Chirodropida; morphology; taxonomy; forensics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Box jellyfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.-A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gershwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of Barleeidae Gray, 1857 (Mollusca, Gastropoda) and the first occurrence of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudodiala &lt;/i&gt;Ponder, 1967 off the Brazilian coast</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ketosia&lt;/i&gt; new genus, Barleeidae, is described from off the Brazilian coast, based on conchological analysis of specimens collected through the REVIZEE Program and others from oil prospecting, off the coast of Rio de Janeiro State (24 o W). The new genus is characterised by: anteriorly convex to slightly convex shell profile; protoconch paucispiral, dome-shaped, its surface covered with irregular pits; and teleoconch smooth but with minute deep pits. The aperture is oval, and may be separated from the peripheral region of the teleoconch by a depression. Two new species belonging to this new genus are described herein. We also record, for the first time, the occurrence of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudodiala&lt;/i&gt; Ponder, 1967 from the Brazilian coast, describing a new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mollusca; Barleeidae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudodiala&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ketosia&lt;/i&gt; n. gen.; new species; marine biodiversity; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mollusca</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>N. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Absalão</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1231.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1231</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comments on &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus &lt;/i&gt;(Cnidaria: Cubozoa: Chirodropida): a preliminary revision of the Chiropsalmidae, with descriptions of two new genera and two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The nomenclature and identity of &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrigatus&lt;/i&gt; have been extensively confused. Originally described from Rangoon, Burma, based on an immature and badly damaged specimen, subsequent Philippine and Australian redescriptions do not match primary characters of the holotype. This has led to widespread messiness in identification and classification of this and related species. In order to clarify the nomenclature of the &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus-type&lt;/i&gt; cubomedusae, a preliminary revision of the Chiropsalmidae is given. &lt;i&gt;Chiropsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrigatus&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov. is proposed, in order to reflect the close relationship of this taxon with &lt;i&gt;Chiropsoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buitendijki,&lt;/i&gt; based on the shared character of linear-branching pedalia. A common Australian form, often attributed to &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrigatus,&lt;/i&gt; is herein described as a new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Chiropsella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bronzie.&lt;/i&gt; This new form differs from other Chirodropida in having sessile, solid, smooth gastric saccules, whereas in other Chirodropida these structures are pendant whether they are smooth or branched. This new species is not dangerous to humans. Another form, &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alipes&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is described from the Pacific coast of southern Mexico; this new species differs from others in having long, blade-like pedalia similar to those of the Carybdeida, only four tentacles at maturity per pedalium, each branching in a different direction, and a warty body; comments are made regarding its apparent relationship to the enigmatic &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zygonema.&lt;/i&gt; The recently described &lt;i&gt;Chiropsalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; is moved to a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Chirodectes&lt;/i&gt; in the family Chirodropidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chirodropidae; Cubomedusae; box jellyfish; sea wasps; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chirodropidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.-A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gershwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hennobrimus hennemanni &lt;/i&gt;n. gen. n. sp., a remarkable new genus and species of the tribe Obrimini from the Philippine Islands. (Phasmatodea: Heteropterygidae: Obriminae: Obrimini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species (Hennobrimus &lt;i&gt;hennemanni&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. n. sp.) of the tribe Obrimini from the Philippine Islands of Mindanao and Leyte are described and illustrated from both sexes. The holotype is preserved in the State Zoological Collections Munich, Germany (ZSMC). Paratypes are deposited in the private collection of the author (OC) and in the private collection of Frank H. Hennemann (Kaiserslautern, Germany; FH).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phasmatodea; Heteropterygidae; Obriminae; Obrimini; &lt;i&gt;Hennobrimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hennemanni&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. n. sp.; Philippines; Mindanao Island; Leyte Island</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phasmatodea; Heteropterygidae; Obriminae; Obrimini; &lt;i&gt;Hennobrimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hennemanni&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. n. sp.; Philippines; Mindanao Island; Leyte Island</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of rajid egg cases from southeastern Australian waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Egg cases from nine skate species occurring in Tasmanian waters were examined and measured. A species-specific identification key is provided for eight of these species. The key was developed primarily from fresh egg cases dissected from the oviduct, although specimens collected from the ocean floor or found dried on the beach were also used to test the key. Egg cases for the ninth species could not be included because the only egg case pair recovered was partially formed. A diagnosis of the posterior end of this egg case is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Rajid; egg case; fibroids; anterior; posterior; apron; lateral keel</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Rajid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Treloar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Laurenson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>D</middlename>
          <lastname>Stevens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1230.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1230</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dardanus sanguinocarpus &lt;/i&gt;Degener, 1925 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Diogenidae) species complex: a redescription of &lt;i&gt;D. sanguinocarpus &lt;/i&gt;and descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Examination of &lt;i&gt;Dardanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguinocarpus&lt;/i&gt; Degener, 1925 (type locality Hawaii), and specimens closely allied to &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguinocarpus&lt;/i&gt; collected from several localities in the western Pacific revealed the existence of three hitherto unknown species superficially resembling &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguinocarpus.&lt;/i&gt; These three species are described here as &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longior,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;umbella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Dardanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguinocarpus&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anomura; Diogenidae; &lt;i&gt;Dardanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanguinocarpus&lt;/i&gt;; hermit crab; species complex; French Polynesia; Ogasawara; Philippines</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anomura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Asakura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dinotoperla walkeri &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Plecoptera: Gripopterygidae), a brachypterous stonefly from western Victoria, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new brachypterous species of stonefly (Dinotoperla &lt;i&gt;walkeri&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.) is described from Hopkins Falls in western Victoria. The species is large compared to other species of the genus, and the robust nymph is adapted to live on or under boulders in fast currents. Such conditions appear not to occur elsewhere in the region of the type locality, and it is speculated that brachyptery may be an adaptation which ensures that adults do not disperse away from the nymphal habitat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stonefly; &lt;i&gt;Dinotoperla&lt;/i&gt;; Australia; new species; brachyptery</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stonefly</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Dean</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>St Clair</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Hyla roeschmanni &lt;/i&gt;De Grys, 1938 (Anura: Hylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roeschmanni&lt;/i&gt; De Grys, 1938 (Anura: Hylidae) is reviewed. We place &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roeschmanni&lt;/i&gt; as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Hypsiboas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raniceps&lt;/i&gt; Cope, 1862. Because the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roeschmanni&lt;/i&gt; was destroyed, we designate a neotype from Department Beni, Bolivia, and provide a description of the neotype.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Bolivia; &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roeschmanni&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hypsiboas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raniceps&lt;/i&gt;; Hylidae; neotype; new synonym</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Padial</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Köhler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>De La Riva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1229.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1229</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the catshark genus &lt;i&gt;Poroderma &lt;/i&gt;Smith, 1837 (Chondrichthyes: Carcharhiniformes: Scyliorhinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper examines the alpha level taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Poroderma&lt;/i&gt; Smith, 1837 (Chondrichthyes: Scyliorhinidae), which is endemic to South Africa. A novel species identification key is presented for &lt;i&gt;Poroderma,&lt;/i&gt; and a comprehensive review of the taxonomy (including type material and synonyms) and distribution of all taxa is presented. &lt;i&gt;Conoporoderma&lt;/i&gt; Fowler, 1934 is shown to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Poroderma&lt;/i&gt; Smith, 1837, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marleyi&lt;/i&gt; Fowler, 1934 is shown to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherinum,&lt;/i&gt; and a new colour form of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherinum&lt;/i&gt; is described. This review is the first to offer a comprehensive description of the colour variation exhibited by &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherinum.&lt;/i&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Poroderma&lt;/i&gt; contains the contemporary taxa &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africanum&lt;/i&gt; (Gmelin, 1789) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherinum&lt;/i&gt; (Smith &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Müller and Henle, 1838).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scyliorhinidae; &lt;i&gt;Poroderma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africanum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Poroderma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherinum&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; revision; South Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scyliorhinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Human</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hexantheda &lt;/i&gt;Ogloblin (Hymenoptera, Colletidae), a genus of bees with labial palpi of variable number of segments</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Hexantheda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;entrerriana,&lt;/i&gt; from the province of Entre Ríos, Argentina, is described. These bees have an unusual labial palp with eight segments. Features distinguishing the new species from the other two species of the genus are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Colletinae; taxonomy; morphology; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Colletinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Roig-Alsina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Integripelta acanthus &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Bryozoa: Eurystomellidae) a tropical prey species of &lt;i&gt;Okenia hiroi &lt;/i&gt;(Nudibranchia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Integripelta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., the first known tropical species of Eurystomellidae (Bryozoa, Cheilostomata), is described from Hong Kong. It differs from all other species of the family in that most zooids in the zone of astogenetic repetition bear thorn-like spines. The species is preyed upon by the specialist-feeding nudibranch &lt;i&gt;Okenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiroi.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bryozoa; Eurystomellidae; &lt;i&gt;Integripelta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Okenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiroi&lt;/i&gt;; Nudibranchia; Goniodorididae; Hong Kong; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bryozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gordon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rudman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ramazzottius bunikowskae&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Tardigrada (Eutardigrada, Hypsibiidae) from Russia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Ramazzottius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bunikowskae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from a lichen sample collected in Russia. The new species is the most similar to &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caucasicus&lt;/i&gt; Biserov, and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tribulosus&lt;/i&gt; Bertolani &amp; Rebecchi in the shape of the egg processes but it differs from these species by some differences in the egg processes’ appearance and measurements and also by measurements of some structures in adult specimens. We also provide first observations of peribuccal lobes, papillae and porous areas on the head (possibly external parts of chemoreceptors) in the genus &lt;i&gt;Ramazzottius.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ramazzottius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bunikowskae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species; taxonomy; tundra; Russia; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caucasicus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tribulosus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ramazzottius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bunikowskae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaczmarek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Michalczyk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Diduszko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudolaguvia ferula&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of sisoroid catfish (Teleostei: Erethistidae) from India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudolaguvia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferula,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of erethistid catish, is described from the Brahmaputra River drainage in India. It can be distinguished from congeners in having a terete (vs. depressed) head and body, manifested in the narrower head width (17.1–19.1% SL vs. 19.4–23.4), a smaller anterior fontanel (about one third the length of the frontals vs. at least half the length), and very faint, poorly contrasting cream bands that are sometimes absent on some individuals (vs. sharply contrasting cream bands on a brown body). It can be further distinguished from congeners in having a unique combination of the following characters: dorsal-spine length 17.3–18.7% SL, pectoral-spine length 20.2–24.3% SL, pelvic-fin length 13.0–14.7% SL, length of adipose-fin base 11.5–13.0% SL, caudal peduncle depth 6.9–7.8% SL, body depth at anus 12.1–13.8% SL, eye diameter 8.6–11.7% HL, vertebrae 28–30, and thoracic adhesive apparatus reaching to midway between bases of last pectoral-fin ray and first pelvic-fin ray. with its unculiferous ridges joined at their posterior ends.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Siluriformes; Sisoroidea; Brahmaputra River; South Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Siluriformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1228.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1228</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of the Chinese species from the genus &lt;i&gt;Ascelosodis &lt;/i&gt;Redtenbacher (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae), with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Ascelosodis&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1868, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emarginata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctulata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Tibetan Plateau, China. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emarginiventris&lt;/i&gt; Koch, 1948, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;everestina&lt;/i&gt; Blair, 1923, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longstaffi&lt;/i&gt; Blair, 1923, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitida&lt;/i&gt; Blair, 1923 &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibetana&lt;/i&gt; Blair, 1923, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waltoni&lt;/i&gt; Blair, 1923 are originally known in Tibet, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haagi&lt;/i&gt; Bates, 1879, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reinigi&lt;/i&gt; Koch, 1948, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmidi&lt;/i&gt; Kaszab, 1965 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serripes&lt;/i&gt; Redtenbacher, 1868 are reported from China for the first time. A key to all 13 species of Chinese &lt;i&gt;Ascelosodis&lt;/i&gt; is given. All Chinese species are distributed in Midwest Tibet (the eastern border is Nang County, 29°06’ N, 93°12’ E).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Tenebrionidae; &lt;i&gt;Ascelosodis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; identification key; Tibet; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.-D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.-M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Shi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new subgenus and three new species of leafcutter bees, &lt;i&gt;Megachile&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Austrosarus&lt;/i&gt;) (Hymenoptera, Megachilidae) from central Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new subgenus, &lt;i&gt;Austrosarus,&lt;/i&gt; and three new species of &lt;i&gt;Megachile&lt;/i&gt; from central Brazil are described. &lt;i&gt;Austrosarus&lt;/i&gt; shares some characteristics with the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Austromegachile,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chrysosarus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sayapis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frankieana&lt;/i&gt; occurs in the Federal District of Brasília, in Goias and Minas Gerais states and in eastern and southern Mato Grosso, while &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diasi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candanga&lt;/i&gt; have been collected only in the Federal District. A key is provided to identify the females.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Solitary bees; Neotropics; cerrado</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Solitary bees; Neotropics; cerrado</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Raw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-34</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Species boundaries among barred river frogs, &lt;i&gt;Mixophyes &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Myobatrachidae) in north-eastern Australia, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mixophyes&lt;/i&gt; are large ground-dwelling myobatrachid frogs from eastern Australia and New Guinea. We use analyses of allozyme frequencies, nucleotide sequences of mitochondrial DNA and morphology to define species boundaries in &lt;i&gt;Mixophyes&lt;/i&gt; from the Wet Tropics World Heritage Area of northern Queensland. The molecular analyses identify a minimum of three species in the region. Morphometric and meristic analyses corroborate these distinctions. The existence of two of these species was not previously suspected, and they are formally described herein.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">allozyme electrophoresis; Anura; &lt;i&gt;Mixophyes;&lt;/i&gt; morphology; species boundaries</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">allozyme electrophoresis; Anura; &lt;i&gt;Mixophyes;&lt;/i&gt; morphology; species boundaries</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mahony</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnellan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Richards</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mcdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Thaumastocoris &lt;/i&gt;Kirkaldy from Argentina (Heteroptera: Thaumastocoridae: Thaumastocorinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thaumastocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peregrinus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from Argentina is described. New morphological characters are studied and compared with other related species. This is the first record of a member of the subfamily Thaumastocorinae (Thaumastocoridae) from the New World.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thaumastocorinae; &lt;i&gt;Thaumastocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peregrinus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Neotropics; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thaumastocorinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carpintero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dellapé</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1227.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1227</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First stage zoeal descriptions of five Galatheoidea species from Western Pacific (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first zoeal stages of the galatheids &lt;i&gt;Neonida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agononida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;squamosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javieri,&lt;/i&gt; and the chirostylids &lt;i&gt;Eumunida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capillata&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated from laboratory-hatched material obtained from ovigerous females collected from south western Pacific. The morphologies of the first zoeae are compared with the same larval stage of other known anomuran species. The larval characters of &lt;i&gt;Agononida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;squamosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neonida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; are similar to those described for &lt;i&gt;Agononida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incerta.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javieri&lt;/i&gt; exhibits features not present in other described species of &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; such as the setation of the endopod of the maxillule and the antennal morphology. &lt;i&gt;Eumunida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capillata&lt;/i&gt; do not show abbreviated development as in other described chirostylids such as &lt;i&gt;Uroptychus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Gastroptychus,&lt;/i&gt; and its larval morphology is equivalent to the first stage of galatheid zoeae. However, many morphological characters of &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;umunida&lt;/i&gt; species are typically pagurid, such as the two terminal plumose setae of the antennal endopod, the three-segmented endopod of the maxillule, the posterior margin of the carapace without spines, and the scaphognathite with 5 plumose setae and without a posterior lobe.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anomura; Galatheoidea; Galatheidae; Chyrostilidae; &lt;i&gt;Neonida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Agononida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;umunida&lt;/i&gt;; first stage zoea; descriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anomura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Enrique</firstname>
          <lastname>Macpherson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Samadi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Forges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.-C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Boisselier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy and phylogenetic relationships among species of the seasonal, internally inseminating, South American killifish genus &lt;i&gt;Campellolebias &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cyprinodontiformes: Rivulidae), with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Campellolebias,&lt;/i&gt; a genus of South American annual killifishes, is diagnosed by a unique specialized structure, the pseudogonopodium, on the anterior part of the anal fin in males, which is used for internal insemination; a derived caudal skeleton morphology; an apomorphic color pattern on the ventral portion of the head in males; and a unique courtship behavior pattern in males. Four species are included, all endemic to Brazil’s southern coastal plains: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., from the rio Ribeira de Iguape basin, São Paulo; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysolineatus,&lt;/i&gt; from northern Santa Catarina; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei,&lt;/i&gt; from southern Santa Catarina. A clade comprising &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysolineatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; is defined by the pelvic-fin bases medially separated by a short interspace, seven longitudinal rows of iridescent marks on the flank in males, and dark horizontal lines between flank scales on females. A clade comprising &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysolineatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed by long dorsal, anal and pelvic fins in males.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Killifishes; Cyprinodontiformes; Rivulidae; &lt;i&gt;Campellolebias&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropica; Atlantic forest; internal insemination; morphology; phylogenetic relationships</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Killifishes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. E. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Camioleum choi&lt;/i&gt;, a new species in the omaliine tribe Anthophagini (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae) from Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Camioleum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choi&lt;/i&gt; Shin &amp; Ahn, new species (type locality: Mt. Odaesan, Korea) is described, and habitus photo and line illustrations of diagnostic features are provided for its recognition. The differences between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loripes&lt;/i&gt; Lewis and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choi&lt;/i&gt; are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Omaliinae; &lt;i&gt;Camioleum&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Shin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.-J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ahn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neobythitoides serratus&lt;/i&gt;, a new bathyal genus and species from the East China Sea (Teleostei, Ophidiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Ophidiidae is described on the basis of two specimens from the East China Sea. It is characterized by the following combination of characters: body slender, opercular spine strong, eye small (twice in snout), hind margin of preopercle serrated, two median basibranchial tooth patches with or without a pair of small circular tooth patches, sagitta large with undivided sulcus and 10–11 long rakers on anterior gill arch. It seems most similar to &lt;i&gt;Neobythites,&lt;/i&gt; from which it can be separated by the small horizontal diameter of eye window 2.5–2.7 % SL &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; 3.7–6.0 % SL, the serrated hind margin of preopercle &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; preopercle with 0–3 spines and no serration, and a sagitta with undivided sulcus &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; divided sulcus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ophidiiformes; Ophidiidae; &lt;i&gt;Neobythitoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratus&lt;/i&gt; gen. et sp. nov.; bathyal; East China Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ophidiiformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Machida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1226.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1226</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the Mutillidae (Hymenoptera) of Yemen</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Forty species in 19 genera are recorded from Yemen. Three new genera are described: &lt;i&gt;Paglianotilla&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (type species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hogenesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.), &lt;i&gt;Rasnitsynitilla&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (type species &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachyptera&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.), and &lt;i&gt;Vanhartenidia&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (type species &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;felix&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.). Ten new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Arnoldtilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;achterbergi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;Dentilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ehrenbergi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen, Saudi Arabia), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hogenesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachyptera&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;invreai&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmideggeri&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arabica&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;felix&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tihama&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen), and &lt;i&gt;Spinulomutilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yemenita&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Yemen). Hitherto unknown females are recognized for &lt;i&gt;Arnoldtilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, &lt;i&gt;Omotilla&lt;/i&gt; Invrea, and &lt;i&gt;Tropidotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;milmili&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti). New synonymy is proposed for &lt;i&gt;Omotilla&lt;/i&gt; Invrea 1943 = &lt;i&gt;Conjunctotilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller 1996, syn. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Pseudophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurea&lt;/i&gt; (Klug 1829) = &lt;i&gt;Mutilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kassalina&lt;/i&gt; Magretti 1898, syn. nov., &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;continua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arabica&lt;/i&gt; Hammer 1962, syn. nov. New status is proposed for &lt;i&gt;Arnoldtilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, &lt;i&gt;Myrmilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubida&lt;/i&gt; Magretti, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvula&lt;/i&gt; Magretti, &lt;i&gt;Glossotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;djiboutiensis&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kassalana&lt;/i&gt; (Bischoff), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrrhospilota&lt;/i&gt; (Bischoff). New combination is proposed for: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bischoffi&lt;/i&gt; (Arnold), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvestris&lt;/i&gt; (Arnold), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conjuncta&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conjunctoides&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grazianii&lt;/i&gt; (Invrea), &lt;i&gt;Dentilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arabica&lt;/i&gt; (Hammer), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dives&lt;/i&gt; (Smith), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kassalana&lt;/i&gt; (Bischoff), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pyrrhospilota&lt;/i&gt; (Bischoff), &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tricolor&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unguiculata&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti). Eleven genera are recorded for the first time from Yemen: &lt;i&gt;Arnoldtilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, &lt;i&gt;Omotilla&lt;/i&gt; Invrea, &lt;i&gt;Macromyrme&lt;/i&gt; Lelej, &lt;i&gt;Ronisia&lt;/i&gt; Costa, &lt;i&gt;Strangulotilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, &lt;i&gt;Tropidotilla&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;Dentilla&lt;/i&gt; Lelej, &lt;i&gt;Glossotilla&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;Dentotilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, &lt;i&gt;Spinulomutilla&lt;/i&gt; Nonveiller, and &lt;i&gt;Dasylabris&lt;/i&gt; Radoszkowski. Seventeen species are recorded for the first time from Yemen: &lt;i&gt;Pseudophotopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maura&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mascatiana&lt;/i&gt; Invrea, &lt;i&gt;Myrmilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvula&lt;/i&gt; Magretti, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubida&lt;/i&gt; Magretti, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellii&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinulifera&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frontalis&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;milmili&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti), &lt;i&gt;Strangulotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;samharica&lt;/i&gt; (Magretti), &lt;i&gt;Ronisia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;idonea&lt;/i&gt; (André), &lt;i&gt;Dentilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; (Klug), &lt;i&gt;Glossotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;djiboutiensis&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, &lt;i&gt;Dentotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auricoma&lt;/i&gt; (Bischoff), &lt;i&gt;Dasylabris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biblica&lt;/i&gt; Invrea, &lt;i&gt;Tricholabiodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niloticus&lt;/i&gt; Suárez, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedunculatoides&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff, and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sudanensis&lt;/i&gt; Suárez. &lt;i&gt;Dentilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; (Klug) and &lt;i&gt;Tricholabiodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chloroticus&lt;/i&gt; (Gribodo) are recorded for the first time from Saudi Arabia. &lt;i&gt;Tricholabiodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sudanensis&lt;/i&gt; Suárez is recorded for the first time from Oman. &lt;i&gt;Glossotilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;djiboutiensis&lt;/i&gt; Bischoff is recorded for the first time from Eritrea. Keys to eight species of &lt;i&gt;Vanhartenidia&lt;/i&gt; and three species of &lt;i&gt;Rasnitsynitilla&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mutillidae; solitary wasps; velvet ants; Arabia; Yemen; Saudi Arabia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mutillidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lelej</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Harten</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-50</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the larval instars of &lt;i&gt;Gonatopus bartletti &lt;/i&gt;Olmi, 1984 (Hymenoptera: Dryinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The postembryonic development and external morphology of each larval instar of &lt;i&gt;Gonatopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bartletti&lt;/i&gt; Olmi, 1984 are described and illustrated. The affinities among the immature and mature larvae of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bartletti&lt;/i&gt; and corresponding instars of other species of the same subfamily are discussed. The mature larva shows a peculiar structure never observed in other Gonatopodinae species; near the base of each mandible is a peculiar subrectangular heavily sclerotized and dark pigmented area with a lens-shaped transparent protuberance in its anterolateral angle. Its function is unknown.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; Fulgoromorpha; Cicadomorpha; Gonatopodinae; postembryonic development; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Guglielmino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bückle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Moya-Raygoza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the pupa and observations on the distribution, ecology, and life history of &lt;i&gt;Quedius spelaeus spelaeus &lt;/i&gt;Horn (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae) in Nova Scotia, Canada</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The troglophilic staphylinid beetle &lt;i&gt;Quedius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeus&lt;/i&gt; Horn 1871, has been found in a number of porcupine dung caves in Nova Scotia where it appears to be the dominant predator on other invertebrates. In culture, late-instar larvae were observed to excavate and remain in cavities excavated in dung, and to pupate in these cavities. The pupa is described for the first time and compared with other pupae in the genus &lt;i&gt;Quedius&lt;/i&gt; Stephens. The apparently disjunct distribution of the species in Nova Scotia is discussed and it is suggested that it may have colonized the province from Atlantic glacial refugia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; &lt;i&gt;Quedius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeus&lt;/i&gt;; Canada; Nova Scotia; description of pupa; life history; cavernicole; troglophile; glacial refugia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Moseley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Klimaszewski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Majka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1225.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1225</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Six new species of Rhyncaphytoptinae from northwestern China (Acari: Eriophyoidea: Diptilomiopidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six new species of diptilomipid eriophyoid mites from northwestern China are described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Rhyncaphytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fargesis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Abies&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fargesii&lt;/i&gt; Frnach. (Pinaceae); &lt;i&gt;Rhyncaphytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cotoneasteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Cotoneaster&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Rosaceae); &lt;i&gt;Rhyncaphytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abiesis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Rhyncaphytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Abies&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabri&lt;/i&gt; (Mast.) Craib (Pinaceae); &lt;i&gt;Rhinophytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunninghamiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Cunninghamia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lanceolata&lt;/i&gt; (Lamb.) Hook. (Taxodiaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Rhinophytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roxburghis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Rosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roxburghii&lt;/i&gt; Tratt. (Rosaceae). All species are vagrant on leaf surfaces. No damage to their host plants was observed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">eriophyoid mites; new species; Acari; Diptilomiopidae; Rhyncaphytoptinae; taxonomy; Shaanxi and Gansu Provinces</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">eriophyoid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Z.-W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akrokolioplax&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Southeast Asian labeonine fishes (Teleostei: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akrokolioplax,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, is erected for the reception of &lt;i&gt;Epalzeorhynchos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicornis&lt;/i&gt; Wu, 1977. It shares with the remaining species of &lt;i&gt;Epalzeorhynchos&lt;/i&gt; what have usually been called “rostral lateral lobes” on the snout, which are non-homologous structures used to distinguish the two genera from all other Labeoninae genera. &lt;i&gt;Akrokolioplax&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Epalzeorhynchos&lt;/i&gt; differ in the position and structure of these lobes, and also in the morphology of the oromandibular structures. A detailed redescription is also provided for the type species of this monotypic genus, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicornis.&lt;/i&gt; It is presently known from the upper Salween River (=Nu Jiang in Chinese) basin in Yunnan (South China), Myanmar and Thailand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akrokolioplax&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Epalzeorhynchos&lt;/i&gt;; new genus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akrokolioplax&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-30</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agalliota maculata &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. from Brazil and a key to the species of the genus (Insecta: Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Agalliinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; Oman is described and illustrated from southeastern Brazil (Minas Gerais State). &lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished by its longitudinal pronotal stripes, anal tube processes, and aedeagus shape. With the addition of the new taxon, the number of &lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; species is increased to eight, seven of them occurring in Brazil. A key to the known species of the genus is provided. Notes on the distinction between &lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Agallia&lt;/i&gt; Curtis are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Agallia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; morphology; leafhopper; Auchenorrhyncha; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agalliota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gonçalves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mejdalani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>B. N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coelho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new natricine snake of the genus &lt;i&gt;Amphiesma &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Colubridae: Natricinae) from the central Truong Son, Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Amphiesma&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Truong Son (Annamite mountain range) of Quang Binh Province in central Vietnam. This new species is characterized by the combination of the distinct coloration and pattern, the slender body and tail (tail/total length ratio 0.31), the large eye diameter, a single loreal and preocular, three postoculars, a single anterior and posterior temporal, nine supralabials (fourth to sixth reach the eye), nine infralabials, 179 ventrals (plus two preventrals), anal plate divided, 99 divided subcaudals, dorsal scales in 19-19-17 keeled rows, 34 maxillary teeth (the two posteriormost enlarged), hemipenis simple, with undivided sperm groove, covered with small spines except for a single, strongly enlarged spine next to the sperm groove at the hemipenis base and except for irregularly arranged medium-sized spines that encircle the organ horizontally at the trunco-pedicel area. The new taxon is known only from a single male specimen that was collected in a limestone forest valley.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Vietnam; Truong Son (Annamite mountain range); Quang Binh Province; Reptilia; Colubridae; &lt;i&gt;Amphiesma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andreae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; morphology; taxonomy; natural history</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Vietnam</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Quyet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on the genus &lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Aphididae: Greenideinae), with the description of one new species from Hong Kong, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The aphid genus &lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum&lt;/i&gt; is reviewed here. &lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclobalanopsidis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from &lt;i&gt;Cyclobalanopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neglecta&lt;/i&gt; in Hong Kong, China is described. Keys to the species of &lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum&lt;/i&gt; worldwide are provided. The type specimens studied are deposited in the Natural History Museum, London, U.K.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum&lt;/i&gt;; Greenideinae; new species; China (Hong Kong)</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allotrichosiphum&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>X.</middlename>
          <lastname>Qiao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jiang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1224.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1224</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus nielbrucei &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae), a new sponge associate from the Capricorn Islands, Queensland, with notes on related &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus &lt;/i&gt;species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielbrucei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a coral reef sponge associate, is described from specimens from the Capricorn Islands, Great Barrier Reef, Queensland, Australia. The rostral dentition is unique in &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus,&lt;/i&gt; with the dorsal carinal teeth diverging irregularly from the midline. The Australian &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; fauna is now increased to 24 species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielbrucei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Crustacea; Caridea; Pontoniinae; Australia; Queensland; sponge associate</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nielbrucei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aega sheni&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Aegidae (Crustacea: Isopoda: Cymothoida) from southern China and Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aega&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sheni&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Chinese and Australian waters, is described and figured. This species is characterized by the plate-like expansion of antennule peduncle articles 1 and 2, very large eyes (nearly making contact), numerous robust setae on the inferior margins of the ischium of pereopods 2 and 3, large distal lobe on the propodus of pereopods 1–3, shape and setation of the uropods, and the rounded pleotelson posterior margin. &lt;i&gt;Aega&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sheni&lt;/i&gt; has been recorded at depths of 300–435 metres.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Aegidae; &lt;i&gt;Aega&lt;/i&gt;; South China Sea; Coral Sea; China; Australia; Pacific Ocean; Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Labeo &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from the lower Congo River</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new labeonine cyprinid, &lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulakariensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from material recently collected in rapids on the lower Congo River near the mouth of the Foulakari River, a large north bank tributary, in the Republic of Congo, and from the Yelala rapids in the Democratic Republic of Congo. The new species is readily distinguished from other Congolese &lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; except &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;greenii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidi&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination of characters: plicate lips, characteristic striping of the flanks, and a dark spot on the base of the caudal peduncle. &lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulakariensis&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;greenii&lt;/i&gt; by dorsal fin shape and snout without a deep transverse furrow or upwardly directed fleshy anterior appendage, and from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidi&lt;/i&gt; by the position of the eyes, the circumpeduncular scale count (16 vs 17 to 20 in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidi)&lt;/i&gt; and maxillary barbels hidden and smaller than in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reidi.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt;; Cyprinidae; new species; Africa; lower Congo River</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Labeo&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tshibwabwa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stiassny</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schelly</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris &lt;/i&gt;from Korea (Diplopoda: Glomerida: Glomeridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of the millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1910 (Glomeridae) are described from South Korea: &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicolorata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confragosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alutacea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Several earlier misidentifications are corrected. All currently known &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt; species from Korea are keyed, including new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">South Korea; myriapoda; Diplopoda; &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; descriptions; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">South Korea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ceratomyxa thunni &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Myxozoa: Ceratomyxidae) in Atlantic northern bluefin tuna (&lt;i&gt;Thunnus thynnus&lt;/i&gt;) caught in the Adriatic Sea, Island of Jabuka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of coelozoic myxozoan, &lt;i&gt;Ceratomyxa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thunni,&lt;/i&gt; was isolated from gall bladders of young wild Atlantic northern bluefin tuna (Thunnus &lt;i&gt;thynnus&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758), caught in the Adriatic Sea, Island of Jabuka (type locality). The prevalence was 23.3 % with low intensity (1–5 spores per microscope field at magnification of 400 x), inducing no pathological changes in the gall bladder epithelium. Light and TEM microscopy of spores revealed that this new species differs from other marine &lt;i&gt;Ceratomyxa&lt;/i&gt; in morphology and size; the length of spores is 3.4–4.3 µm, thickness 11.6–15.3 µm and polar capsules 1.3 x 1.6 µm. A distinctive characteristic is densely self-coiled polar filaments. Spores are small, slightly semilunar or elongated with arcuate edges. Early forms are shorter, clubber, thicker, paniform, with slightly convex or blunt edges. Mature spores are slimmer, elongated, concave at the posterior margin, with edges finishing slightly sharper, semilunar in appearance. Bluefin tuna is a new host for this genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myxozoa; &lt;i&gt;Ceratomyxa&lt;/i&gt; genus; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thunni&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; bluefin tuna; Adriatic Sea; gall bladder</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myxozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mladineo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bocina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1223.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1223</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Immature stages of three Japanese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Plecia&lt;/i&gt;Wiedemann (Diptera: Bibionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The eggs, larvae, and pupae (male and female) of three Japanese species of the Bibionidae, &lt;i&gt;Plecia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adiastola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;membranifera,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hadrosoma,&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated, and ecological notes are included. Morphological characters of the immature stages of &lt;i&gt;Plecia&lt;/i&gt; species are compared for the first time, and a diagnosis is presented. The taxonomic and phylogenetic importance of morphological characters, especially of the larval head and the arrangement of the larval and pupal body processes, is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Bibionidae; &lt;i&gt;Plecia&lt;/i&gt;; immature stages; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sutou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comments on eye-flukes (Philophthalmidae Looss, 1819) in the genera &lt;i&gt;Philophthalmus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;, with a re-designation of the type-species of &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new systematic organization on the eye-flukes of family Philophthalmidae including generic features and keys were published by Kanev &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2005). However, that publication contains a mistake (lapsus &lt;i&gt;calami)&lt;/i&gt; in the type species information given within the key to the genera of Philophthalmidae. Instead of the original name &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrymosus&lt;/i&gt; (Braun) n. comb. being used, another name &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hegeneri&lt;/i&gt; (Penner &amp; Fried) was listed as the typespecies. We apologize for this mistake and would like to provide important but rare and difficult to find information for the future correction of this mistake in the agreement with the International Code of Zoological Nomenclature.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eye-flukes; Philophthalmidae; &lt;i&gt;Philophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;; Type species; &lt;i&gt;lapsus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calami&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrymosus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Natterophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hegeneri&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eye-flukes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Radev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kanev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fried</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Bahamian cave-fishes of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lucifuga&lt;/i&gt; (Ophidiiformes, Bythitidae), with description of a new species from islands on the Little Bahama Bank</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since the description of the Bahamian cave-fish &lt;i&gt;Lucifuga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeotes&lt;/i&gt; Cohen &amp; Robins, 1970, which was based on two specimens from New Providence Island, the species has been observed and/ or collected several times in marine blue-holes and inland caves on various Bahamian Islands. Hitherto, all &lt;i&gt;Lucifuga&lt;/i&gt; records from the Bahamas have been referred to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeotes,&lt;/i&gt; but examination of 50 specimens (42–166 mm SL) collected at 7 different islands showed that two species are represented in the Bahamas: 44 specimens from Berry, New Providence, Eleuthera, Great Exuma and Long Island belong to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeotes,&lt;/i&gt; whereas 6 specimens from Grand Bahama and Abaco Islands are referable to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucayana,&lt;/i&gt; new species. The new species is here described and compared to the material of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeotes,&lt;/i&gt; which includes specimens from several hitherto unpublished locations. The two species are well separated from the Cuban species in number of caudal finrays (10 vs. 8), size of eye (0.7–1.8 vs. 0.0–0.3 % SL) and number of vertebrae (50–55 vs. 45–48). The Bahamian species differ from each other mainly in head squamation, palatine dentition, number of finrays and pigmentation of the three elongated gill-rakers. &lt;i&gt;Lucifuga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucayana&lt;/i&gt; is geographically separated from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spelaeotes&lt;/i&gt; by the deep waters of the Northeast and Northwest Providence Channels.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Viviparous brotulas; Bahamas; anchialine caves; blue holes; cave-fishes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Viviparous brotulas</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Møller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Schwarzhans</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Iliffe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nielsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-46</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of Prolecithophora (Platyhelminthes) from Argentina: &lt;i&gt;Plagiostomum cilioejaculator &lt;/i&gt;sp. n.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this work a new benthic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Plagiostomum&lt;/i&gt; is described from the littoral zone of Río de la Plata (Argentina). &lt;i&gt;Plagiostomum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cilioejaculator&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is the fourth eyeless species of the genus to be described. The male reproductive system is characterized by a muscular and somewhat curved penis, approximately 260 µm long. The ejaculatory duct is lined by a densely ciliated epithelium.The female reproductive system is typical of the genus. &lt;i&gt;Plagiostomum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cilioejaculator&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is the first species of Prolecithophora described from Argentinian waters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plagiostomidae; benthos; turbellarian ; Río de la Plata; estuary</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plagiostomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brusa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Platysetosus occultus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus and species of mite from Tasmania (Acari: Uropodina)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new endemic Australian genus &lt;i&gt;Platysetosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Uropodina: Uropodoidea) from Tasmania and its type species &lt;i&gt;Platysetosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occultus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described and figured. &lt;i&gt;Platysetosus&lt;/i&gt; is very distinctive, and its relationship to other genera of Uropodina is not clear.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Uropodina; &lt;i&gt;Platysetosus&lt;/i&gt;; Tasmania; endemism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Dylewska</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bloszyk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Halliday</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-64</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First report on the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Caknesia &lt;/i&gt;Dworakowska (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae: Typhlocybini) from China, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Oriental leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Caknesia&lt;/i&gt; Dworakowska is reported for the first time from China. One new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sichuanensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., from Sichuan of China, is described and illustrated; a key to all species, based on the male genitalia, is given. The type specimens are deposited in the collections of the Entomological Museum, Northwest A&amp;F University, Yangling, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Cicadellidae; Typhlocybinae; &lt;i&gt;Caknesia&lt;/i&gt;; new record; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Huang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1222.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1222</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of Amphipoda (Crustacea: Peracarida) from the Solitary Islands, New South Wales, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hughes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on recently described Chilean trophonines (Gastropoda: Muricidae), description of a new species and notes of their occurrence at a cold seep site</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Additional specimens of three newly described Chilean species of &lt;i&gt;Trophon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.l.&lt;/i&gt; Monfort, 1810 have been dredged recently off south-central Chile, and we here list the new data and illustrate the radulae. Another species, &lt;i&gt;Trophon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wilhelmensis&lt;/i&gt; Ramírez-Bohme, 1981, is combined with &lt;i&gt;Coronium&lt;/i&gt; Simone, 1996. &lt;i&gt;Pagodula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concepcionensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described and another species remains unidentified. A type species is designated for &lt;i&gt;Pagodula&lt;/i&gt; Monterosato, 1884. Part of the new material comes from an area of methane seepage located northwest of the Bay of Concepción, from 726 to 930 m depth. Many drilled valves of two species of chemosymbiotic clams (Calyptogena &lt;i&gt;gallardoi&lt;/i&gt; Sellanes &amp; Krylova, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;Thyasira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;methanophila&lt;/i&gt; Oliver &amp; Sellanes, 2005) were also obtained at the seep site. We assume that this holes document attacks of this trophonines to the clams.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Muricidae; &lt;i&gt;Trophon&lt;/i&gt;; methane seep; Chile; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Muricidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Houart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sellanes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1221.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Jun. 2006</title>
    <volume>1221</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On a new species of &lt;i&gt;Isomeria &lt;/i&gt;Beck and redescription of species of &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus &lt;/i&gt;Beck from South America (Gastropoda: Stylommatophora: Camaenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Camaenid genera &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus&lt;/i&gt; Beck, 1837 and &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; Beck, 1837 are mainly distributed in northern South America. Current anatomical information available for both genera is scarce, particularly that concerning &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; species. The morphology of the pallial organs, genital and digestive systems of three species of &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus&lt;/i&gt; [L. &lt;i&gt;subplanatus&lt;/i&gt; (Petit, 1843), &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dunkeri&lt;/i&gt; (Pfeiffer, 1852), &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarapotoensis&lt;/i&gt; Moricand, 1858] and a new species of &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; are described. The morphology of hooked denticles that topped wall ridges inside penis and vagina in some species of &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus&lt;/i&gt; and in &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; are species-specific characters, differing in shape and size. These structures were not sufficiently studied either in &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; or in &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus&lt;/i&gt; and are absent in all anatomically studied species of &lt;i&gt;Solaropsis&lt;/i&gt; Beck, 1837, their sister genus. The presence of a bursa copulatrix sac reflexed over its duct is a character shared by all &lt;i&gt;Labyrinthus&lt;/i&gt; species in which soft anatomy is known, and it was identified as a synapomorphy in a published phylogeny. &lt;i&gt;Isomeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;awa.&lt;/i&gt; n.sp. differs from other species of the genus mainly in shell morphology and characters of the distal genitalia. The presence of a stimulator-like structure in the vagina as well as the presence of a glandular pouch in the vagina are diagnostic characters of this new species, not present in the closely Camaenid related genera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Morphology; Taxonomy; Stylommatophora; Helicoidea; Colombia; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cuezzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Typhlodromus &lt;/i&gt;Scheuten (Acari: Phytoseiidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of phytoseiid mites is described from Brazil, &lt;i&gt;Typhlodromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moraesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., collected on &lt;i&gt;Tabebuia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alba&lt;/i&gt; (Cham.) Sandwith and &lt;i&gt;Chamaesyce&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirta&lt;/i&gt; (L.) Millsp. in the State of São Paulo. This is the second species of the &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arizonicus&lt;/i&gt; group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phytoseiidae; &lt;i&gt;Typhlodromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arizonicus&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;Typhlodromus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moraesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phytoseiidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lofego</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Feres</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-28</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Chlororithra &lt;/i&gt;Butler, 1889 (Lepidoptera, Geometridae, Geometrinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Chlororithra&lt;/i&gt; Butler, 1889 is revised. Based on an examination of the syntypes of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;missioniaria&lt;/i&gt; Oberthür, we elevate that taxon to species status. Differences between &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fea&lt;/i&gt; Butler and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;missioniaria&lt;/i&gt; and variation within each species are discussed in detail and illustrated. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fea.&lt;/i&gt; Tribal placement of the genus is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geometridae; Geometrinae; &lt;i&gt;Chlororithra&lt;/i&gt;; new status; review</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geometridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Han</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>X.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Li</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>M.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xue</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Y.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-39</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Diversity and distribution of the marine and estuarine shrimps (Dendrobranchiata, Stenopodidea and Caridea) from North and Northeast Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study aimed to evaluate the current state of knowledge of marine and estuarine shrimp species from the suborder Dendrobranchiata and the infraorders Stenopodidea and Caridea, considering their diversity and distribution along the North and Northeast Brazilian coast (N/NE). The number of reported species rose from 124 to 169 since the Paulo S. Young’s Catalogue of Crustacea of Brazil, put out in 1998, which means an increase of 36.3%. Pernambuco (89 species) and Bahia (68 species) are the states that present the highest shrimp diversity, accounting for 53% and 40.5% of the total species registered for the N/NE regions, respectively. On the other hand, the states of Sergipe (21 species) and Piauí (13 species) contributed with only 12.5% and 7.7% of the total species registered at the moment.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">shrimp diversity; shrimp distribution; geographic distribution; North and Northeast Brazil; Crustacea; Decapoda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">shrimp diversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coelho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Almeida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Souza-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>E. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bezerra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giraldes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Dendroseius &lt;/i&gt;Karg from Iran (Acari: Rhodacaridae), with a key to the known species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dendroseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoliensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; collected from soil in northern Iran is described and illustrated. A key is provided for the known species of &lt;i&gt;Dendroseius.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; &lt;i&gt;Dendroseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoliensis&lt;/i&gt;; Gamasina; Iran; key; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Faraji</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sakenin-Chelav</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Karg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
