<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3155.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jan. 2012</title>
    <volume>3155</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-01-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus cultripes &lt;/i&gt;species group, with description of a new related species (Anura, Cycloramphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The revision of the &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cultripes&lt;/i&gt; species group is presented, through the definition and characterization of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cultripes,&lt;/i&gt; theredescription of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi&lt;/i&gt; based on recently collected specimens, and the description of a new species. &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;monachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the headwaters of the São Francisco River, in the Parque Nacional da Serra da Ca-nastra (20o 10'S, 46o 30'W, 1350 m above sea level), Municipality of São Roque de Minas, State of Minas Gerais, Brazil. The geographic distributions of the referred species are described and mapped.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; geographic distribution; &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cultripes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monachus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulisses</firstname>
          <lastname>Caramaschi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>Felgueiras</middlename>
          <lastname>Napoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On sand-bearing myxillid sponges, with a description of &lt;i&gt;Psammochela tutiae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Poecilosclerida, Myxillina) from the northern Moluccas, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sand-bearing sponges belonging to the suborder Myxillina are mainly observed in South Australia. Recent biodiversitysurveys in Indonesia yielded several of these sand-bearing sponges belonging to three different genera, &lt;i&gt;Chondropsis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Des-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;mapsamma&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Psammochela.&lt;/i&gt; These sponges are distributed across three different families and the ecological and evo-lutionary implications for the incorporation of sand and detritus in the skeleton remain unresolved so far. In the presentpaper &lt;i&gt;Psammochela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tutiae&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov. (Poecilosclerida: Myxillina: Myxillidae) is described from the northern Moluccas, In-donesia. The new species is compared with all other (five) &lt;i&gt;Psammochela&lt;/i&gt; species occurring in the Indo-West Pacific. Thenew species differs from the other species by overall morphology, absence of polydentate chelae and presence of thinstrongylote megascleres. The current position of &lt;i&gt;Psammochela&lt;/i&gt; within the Myxillidae and its relation to other arenaceous Myxillina are discussed here, and an identification key to all known species of &lt;i&gt;Psammochela&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; Myxillidae; sand-sponges; Indo-West Pacific; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nicole</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Voogd (The Netherlands)</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-28</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">BRYAN L. STUART (USA), SOMPHOUTHONE PHIMMACHAK (Vietnam), </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twelve species of &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; are known from Vietnam, Laos and Cambodia, most of which have been described toscience in the past twelve years. Our fieldwork on the Dakchung Plateau of southeastern Laos discovered a small &lt;i&gt;Lepto-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;brachium&lt;/i&gt; with a yellow upper iris that resembled &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buchardi,&lt;/i&gt; a species known only by the female holotype from the Bo-laven Plateau of southern Laos. We use our new collections to expand the original description of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buchardi,&lt;/i&gt; and describethe Dakchung species as new. &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xanthops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from its congeners by having small bodysize (males with SVL 44.7, females with SVL 38.8–45.2), the upper one-half of iris and scleral arc pale yellow, a dark venter, and sexually active males without spines on the upper lip.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bolaven Plateau; Dakchung Plateau; Laos; &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buchardi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bolaven Plateau; Dakchung Plateau; Laos; &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buchardi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sengvilay</firstname>
          <lastname>Seateun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Niane</firstname>
          <lastname>Sivongxay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">MASAFUMI MATSUI (Japan), KANTO NISHIKAWA (Japan), DAICUS M. BELABUT (Malaysia),</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new microhylid, &lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limbooliati&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the state of Johor, in the southern part of PeninsularMalaysia. Morphologically, the new species differs from all known congeners in the combination of medium body size;short fourth finger; two subarticular tubercles on fourth finger and none on the fifth toe; presence of light lateral stripe anddark inguinal spot; absence of nuptial pads and outer metatarsal tubercles. Acoustically, the new species clearly differsfrom all congeners whose calls have been reported, and resembles a syntopic ranid &lt;i&gt;Hylarana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laterimaculata&lt;/i&gt; with a long series of high-pitched whistle like notes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt;; advertisement call; cryptic species; new species; Southeast Asia; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ahmad</firstname>
          <lastname>Norhayati</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hoi</firstname>
          <middlename>Sen</middlename>
          <lastname>Yong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3155.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jan. 2012</title>
    <volume>3155</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-01-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new softnose skates of the genus &lt;i&gt;Brochiraja &lt;/i&gt;(Rajoidei: Arhynchobatidae) from the deepwater slopes and banks of the Norfolk Ridge (South-West Pacific)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the softnose skate genus &lt;i&gt;Brochiraja&lt;/i&gt; are described based on material collected from the Norfolk Ridgein the northern Tasman Sea (South-West Pacific). Most of this material was collected in 2003 by the New Zealand vessel,RV &lt;i&gt;Tangaroa,&lt;/i&gt; during the NORFANZ voyage. These species extend the known range of the genus northward along theNorfolk Ridge, and along with &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aenigma,&lt;/i&gt; are the only other representatives of the genus found outside seas adjacentNew Zealand. &lt;i&gt;Brochiraja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heuresa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is known from the western Norfolk Ridge and the Wanganella Bank at 870–1350 m depth, whereas &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittacauda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is known from a smaller area of the western Norfolk Ridge at 629–973 mdepth. These species differ from each other, and from other nominal members of the genus, in morphometrics, meristics, coloration and squamation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arhynchobatidae; skates; new species; &lt;i&gt;Brochiraja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heuresa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Brochiraja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittacauda&lt;/i&gt;; Wanganella Bank; Norfolk Ridge; Tasman Sea; South-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arhynchobatidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Last</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bernard</firstname>
          <lastname>Séret</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-64</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
