<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3158.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jan. 2012</title>
    <volume>3158</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new rhamphorhynchid (Pterosauria: Rhamphorhynchidae) from the Middle/Upper Jurassic of Qinglong, Hebei Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A heavily compressed, but nearly complete fossil skeleton recovered from the Middle/Upper Jurassic Tiaojishan Forma-tion of Mutoudeng, Qinglong County, Hebei Province, China, represents a new genus and species of long-tailed pterosaur,&lt;i&gt;Qinglongopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The holotype and only known specimen has an estimated forelimb length of 0.18m. The new taxon is distinguished by a relatively short skull, a remarkably short pteroid with a distinctive knob-like distalexpansion, and a prepubis with a relatively slender distal process. Phylogenetic analysis demonstrates that &lt;i&gt;Qinglongopter-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; is a member of Rhamphorhynchidae, exhibiting many of the unique character states found in members of this clade.&lt;i&gt;Qinglongopterus&lt;/i&gt; is strikingly similar to &lt;i&gt;Rhamphorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; and more closely related to this taxon than to any other rham-phorhynchine, this pairing is supported by morphometric data and several synapomorphies (short, broad nasal process ofthe maxilla; forelimb length more than four times that of the hind limb; wing-phalanx one more than twice the length ofthe tibia). &lt;i&gt;Qinglongopterus&lt;/i&gt; demonstrates that the highly derived skeletal morphology of &lt;i&gt;Rhamphorhynchus,&lt;/i&gt; known onlyfrom the latest Jurassic (Tithonian) of Europe, had already appeared by the start of the Late Jurassic. This hints at evolu-tionary stasis in Rhamphorhynchinae, a phenomenon seemingly also present in two other clades of basal pterosaurs,Anurognathidae and Scaphognathinae, and contrasting sharply with basal monofenestratans which appear to have undergone extensive evolutionary change during the same interval.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Middle/Upper Jurassic; Tiaojishan Formation; Pterosaur; &lt;i&gt;Qinglongopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Middle/Upper Jurassic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Junchang</firstname>
          <lastname>Lü</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Unwin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bo</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chunling</firstname>
          <lastname>Gao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Caizhi</firstname>
          <lastname>Shen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Indonesian species of &lt;i&gt;Macrophthalmus &lt;/i&gt;Desmarest, 1823, with the description of a new species (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Macrophthalmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fourteen species of &lt;i&gt;Macrophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; Desmarest, 1823, are reported from Indonesia, of which two species, &lt;i&gt;Macrophthal-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;mus&lt;/i&gt; (Macrophthalmus) &lt;i&gt;abbreviatus&lt;/i&gt; Manning &amp; Holthuis, 1981, and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (Macrophthalmus) &lt;i&gt;sulcatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malaccensis&lt;/i&gt; Tweedie,1937, are recorded for the first time from the region, and one new species &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (Mareotis) &lt;i&gt;fusculatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described. Thenew species resembles &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (Mareotis) &lt;i&gt;definitus&lt;/i&gt; Adams &amp; White, 1849, in the relatively narrow male abdomen and mod-erately long, curved tip of the male G1. However, the differences are noticeable in the morphology of the carapace of thenew species which is divergent posterolateraly, the presence of tubercles on the gastric, cardiac and intestinal regions, and the absence of a longitudinal row of granules or setae on the branchial region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Macrophthalmidae; &lt;i&gt;Macrophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new records; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dwi</firstname>
          <middlename>Listyo</middlename>
          <lastname>Rahayu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dharma</firstname>
          <middlename>Arif</middlename>
          <lastname>Nugroho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-36</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A relict new species of &lt;i&gt;Oreobates &lt;/i&gt;(Anura, Strabomantidae) from the Seasonally Dry Tropical Forests of Minas Gerais, Brazil, and its implication to the biogeography of the genus and that of South American Dry Forests</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt; is described from Cavernas do Peruaçu National Park, Januária, Minas Gerais state, in theAtlantic Dry Forests of Brazil. The new species is distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt; by having the following combi-nation of characters: large tympanum, discs broadly enlarged and truncate on Fingers III and IV, smooth dorsal skin, nup-tial pads absent, snout subacuminate, and a very short pulsatile (2–3 pulses) single-noted advertisement call with dominantfrequency of about 3150 Hz, and no harmonic structure. Molecular phylogenetic analyses using partial sequences of themitochondrial genes cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; (cyt &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; and 16S using multiple outgroups recovered the new species within &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt;and sister to &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterodactylus.&lt;/i&gt; The latter species inhabits the Dry Forests of Mato Grosso (Cerrado) and Bolivia (Chiq-uitano forests), and is strictly associated to these habitats, which suggests a preterit connection between Chiquitano andAtlantic Dry Forests. The discovery of a new &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt; in the Atlantic Dry Forest is of great importance for the conservation of these dry forests, as it is known only from this type of habitat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Peruaçu valley; Pandeiros River; Terrarana</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Peruaçu valley</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mauro</firstname>
          <lastname>Teixeira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renata</firstname>
          <middlename>Cecília</middlename>
          <lastname>Amaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renato</firstname>
          <middlename>Sousa</middlename>
          <lastname>Recoder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <middlename>Aurélio</middlename>
          <lastname>De Sena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>Trefaut</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Charinus bromeliaea &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Amblypygi: Charinidae); a new species of bromeliad inhabiting whip spider from French Guyana </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Charinus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1892 is described from French Guyana, raising the number of species in the genus to48 (27 for the Neotropical region and 19 for South America). &lt;i&gt;Charinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bromeliaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from the otherspecies in the genus by morphological characteristics and unique ecology. Adapted to live in &lt;i&gt;Achmea&lt;/i&gt; bromeliads on gran-ite inselbergs, this species is an interesting addition to the wide range of habitats &lt;i&gt;Charinus&lt;/i&gt; species are found in. This is also the first record of the genus from French Guyana and this record extends the geographic distribution of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Guiana; inselberg; &lt;i&gt;Charinus&lt;/i&gt;; identification key; check list; whip spider; bromeliad</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Guiana</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Merlijn</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alessandro</firstname>
          <middlename>Ponce</middlename>
          <lastname>De Leão Giupponi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-59</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">LUCÍLIA S. MIRANDA (Brazil), MARIA A. HADDAD (Brazil), CLAUDIA E. MILLS (USA) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3158.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jan. 2012</title>
    <volume>3158</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathyferula&lt;/i&gt;, a new Caribbean deep-water turrid genus (Gastropoda: Turroidea), with description of a large-sized new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Stahlschmidt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dominique</firstname>
          <lastname>Lamy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Koen</firstname>
          <lastname>Fraussen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
