<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3176.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Jan. 2012</title>
    <volume>3176</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-01-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A cryptic complex of species related to &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema licinum &lt;/i&gt;Manter, 1970 from fishes of the Indo-West Pacific, including descriptions of ten new species of &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema &lt;/i&gt;Witenberg, 1944 (Digenea: Transversotrematidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;licinum&lt;/i&gt; Manter, 1970 was described from two species of fishes from Moreton Bay, Queensland, and sub-sequently reported from 13 further species from six families in the Indo–West Pacific region. This study records specimensmorphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;licinum&lt;/i&gt; from 48 fish species from 11 families. A combined analysis of the second internaltranscribed spacer region (ITS2) of ribosomal DNA and morphological data revealed a complex of at least 15 species andfrom these data ten new species of &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; Witenberg, 1944 are described here. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;licinum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; is char-acterised in terms of morphology, distinct genotype, wide host distribution (Kyphosidae, Lutjanidae, Monodactylidae,Mugilidae, Pomacentridae and Sparidae) and, at present, is known only in Moreton Bay. The following new species areproposed: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atkinsoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from nemipterids from Heron Island (southern GBR) and Ningaloo Reef (Western Australia);&lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borboleta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from chaetodontids and lutjanines (Lutjanidae) from Lizard Island and Heron Island; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cardinalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from lutjanines and a haemulid from Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carmenae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from nemipterids from Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dam-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;sella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from pomacentrids, a labrid and a mugilid from Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;espanola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from lutjanines from Heronand Lizard Islands; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusilieri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from caesionines (Lutjanidae) from Lizard Island; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from caesioninesfrom Lizard Island and Ningaloo Reef; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nova&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from a nemipterid from New Caledonia; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;witenbergi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;from caesionines from Heron Island. &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borboleta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is itself probably a complex of at least three closelyrelated species but these are not yet sufficiently well delineated to allow separate descriptions. Four putative species re-ferred to as Species A–D recognised from molecular analysis have not been described because of insufficient data. Mostspecies are evidently strongly restricted to families or subfamilies of fishes. Only &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;licinum&lt;/i&gt; appears to be genuinely eu-ryxenic. &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borboleta&lt;/i&gt; infects chaetodontids and lutjanids but the nature of the distribution may be an indi-cation that it represents a species complex. Most of the species appear to have restricted ranges, being absent from susceptible host species at some localities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Transversotrematidae; Chaetodontidae; Haemulidae; Kyphosidae; Labridae; Lutjanidae; Monodac-</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Janet</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hunter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptoecia midatlantica&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of the deep-sea quill-worms (Polychaeta: Onuphidae: Hyalinoeciinae) from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leptoecia&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1919, collected from the northern part of the Mid-Atlantic ridge atdepths around 2100–2700 m, is described. &lt;i&gt;Leptoecia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;midatlantica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by the presence of both uni-and bidentate simple falcigers on the first pair of parapodia, presence of dorsal cirri on all chaetigers, dorsoventrally flat-tened organic tube, and appearance of the first subacicular hooks around chaetiger 28–39. The unusually high intraspecificvariability of several morphological characters (dentition of falcigers, shape of prostomium, and number of anal cirri) in the examined material is described. A key for the seven known species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leptoecia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; species key; intraspecific variability; &lt;i&gt;Neonuphis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Parhyalinoecia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paronuphis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nataliya</firstname>
          <lastname>Budaeva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phlegra &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1876, &lt;i&gt;Phintella &lt;/i&gt;Strand 1906 and &lt;i&gt;Yamangalea &lt;/i&gt;Maddison, 2009 (Arachnida: Araneae: Salticidae)— new species and new generic recordsfor Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phlegra&lt;/i&gt; Simon, &lt;i&gt;Phintella&lt;/i&gt; Strand and &lt;i&gt;Yamangalea&lt;/i&gt; Maddison are newly recorded from Australia, each genus beingrepresented here by one new species: &lt;i&gt;Phlegra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proszynskii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Phintella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monteithi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Yamangalea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lubinae.&lt;/i&gt; The diagnoses and descriptions are provided and remarks on distribution are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Salticidae. &lt;i&gt;Phlegra&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phintella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Yamangalea&lt;/i&gt;; jumping spiders; new species; taxonomy; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marek</firstname>
          <lastname>Żabka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
