<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3179.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Feb. 2012</title>
    <volume>3179</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-02-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Attheyella &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Canthosella&lt;/i&gt;) from Colombia and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Attheyella &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Delachauxiella&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;freyi &lt;/i&gt;(Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Canthocamptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Occasional collections of organisms from water bodies of the Andean Region and the Pacific coast of Colombia yieldedtwo species of canthocamptid harpacticoids belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Attheyella&lt;/i&gt; Brady, 1880. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Attheyella&lt;/i&gt;(Canthosella) &lt;i&gt;chocoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; inhabiting phytotelmata of the forest at the Pacific Chocó State is described. &lt;i&gt;Attheyella&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Delachauxiella)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freyi&lt;/i&gt; Löffler, 1963, described from Ecuador, was found in a high mountain pond in the southern Colom-bian Andes, and redescribed here. Both species are illustrated with line drawings and SEM photographs. A special mor-phological structure was discovered on the antenna of male and female &lt;i&gt;Attheyella&lt;/i&gt; (D.) &lt;i&gt;freyi:&lt;/i&gt; it is probably present in otherspecies of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Delachauxiella&lt;/i&gt; Brehm, 1926, as well. An identification key to Colombian species of the family Canthocamptidae is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Colombia; Pacific forest; phytotelmata; “páramo” region; Andes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Santiago</firstname>
          <lastname>Gaviria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Danielle</firstname>
          <lastname>Defaye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of Eutardigrada from Belarus with the description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The list of tardigrade species recorded from Belarus is provided; nine were new records for this geographic area and three,&lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sottilei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paramacrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klymenki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valentinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; were new to science.&lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sottilei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; had smooth cuticle; eye spots present; the dorsal transverse ridges of the buccal armaturejoined to form a continuous arc; pharyngeal bulb with two macroplacoids and microplacoid; eggs with processes in shapeof inverted goblets with indented distal discs; egg shell with a very dense reticular design.&lt;i&gt;Paramacrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;klymenki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; had smooth cuticle; eye spots absent; buccal armature similar to that of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;areolatus;&lt;/i&gt;buccal tube not very wide; stylet supports inserted on the buccal tube at about 80% of its length; pharyngeal bulb withthree macroplacoids; microplacoid absent; eggs with conical processes with a reticular design similar to that of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;areola-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tus;&lt;/i&gt; egg shell areolated; central area of each areola slightly thickened but not subdivided.&lt;i&gt;Hypsibius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valentinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; had smooth cuticle; eye spots present; buccal tube very narrow; pharyngeal bulb with twomacroplacoids and a small septulum, claws of the &lt;i&gt;Hypsibius&lt;/i&gt; type; small, smooth, flexible lunules present; a short cuticular bar is present between the bases of the claws of the hind legs; no cuticular bar on the first three pairs of legs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Tardigrada; East Europe</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yevgen</firstname>
          <lastname>Kiosya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giorgio</firstname>
          <lastname>Sabella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Towards a List of Available Names in Zoology, partim Phylum Rotifera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Many, mostly older, names of animal species are nomenclaturally problematic, either because their orthography is unstable, orthey cannot be linked reliably to a taxonomic identity, due to the lack of recognisable descriptions and/or types. Yet, they repre-sent available (sensu International Code of Zoological Nomenclature) names and must be taken into account in zoologicalworks. This situation, with available senior, yet dubious names confounding nomenclature, is undesirable. It creates uncertain-ties at a time when molecular approaches are revolutionizing our concepts of species diversity, and fails us when the currentextinction crisis calls for efficient, accurate, and constructive approaches to document, monitor, and conserve biodiversity.The International Code of Zoological Nomenclature (The Code) provides a means to address this issue by restricting avail-ability, application and orthography of names to those included in the &lt;i&gt;List&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Available&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Names&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zoology&lt;/i&gt; (LAN). The Code(Art. 79) allows an international body of zoologists in consultation with the Commission to propose a candidate part of theLAN for a major taxonomic field. We explore this possibility for 3570 species-group names of Phylum Rotifera (of which 665are problematic), by presenting such a candidate Rotifera part of the LAN. The web site of the International Commission onZoological Nomenclature (http://www.iczn.org) will hold both the candidate list and a forum to facilitate consultation on thecandidate list, while the list itself also can already be freely downloaded from three other Internet sites: http://fada.biodiver-sity.be, http://rotifer.ansp.org/LAN, and www.hausdernatur.at/rotifera. We give here an overview of the general approach andprocedures applied in preparation of the candidate list, and anticipate that our effort will promote the process as well as result in a standard list of names for use in taxonomy, the Global Names Architecture and other biodiversity information initiatives.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">International Code of Zoological Nomenclature; taxonomy; nomenclature; names standards</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">International Code of Zoological Nomenclature</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hendrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Segers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Willem</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Smet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claus</firstname>
          <lastname>Fischer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Fontaneto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Evangelia</firstname>
          <lastname>Michaloudi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wallace</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jersabek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
