<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3201.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Feb. 2012</title>
    <volume>3201</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-02-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision and phylogenetic analysis of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Aysenia &lt;/i&gt;Tullgren (Ara-neae: Anyphaenidae, Amaurobioidinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Aysenia&lt;/i&gt; Tullgren includes 8 species of spiders endemic to the southern forests of Chile and Argentina. Theyhave an elongated body, recurved posterior eye row and third legs directed forward. There are currently five known speciesof &lt;i&gt;Aysenia.&lt;/i&gt; The study of all the specimens of &lt;i&gt;Aysenia&lt;/i&gt; available in collections showed the existence of three undescribedspecies and the unknown male of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata,&lt;/i&gt; all of which are here described. New geographical records are provided forall species, with illustrations and reviewed diagnosis for the genus and the previously known species. Data from the newspecies and the male of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; are used to test the monophyly of the genus, its relationships with other genera in thefamily, and among its species. The phylogenetic analysis using cladistic methods uses observations from 264 previously defined characters plus three characters that arise from this study, scored for 104 species of Anyphaenidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladistics; new species; South America; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladistics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>E. González</middlename>
          <lastname>Márquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martín</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramírez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Earthworms (Oligochaeta: Glossoscolecidae) of the Amazon region of Colombia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The descriptions of three species of terrestrial oligochaetes, family Glossocolecidae, are added to the catalog of earth-worms of Colombia’s Amazon region: &lt;i&gt;Martiodrilus&lt;/i&gt; (Maipure) &lt;i&gt;huitoto&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (Cordilleroscolex) &lt;i&gt;mirania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Periscolex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coreguaje&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; With these new registries, the earthworms fauna of Colombia now contains 136 spe-cies. A key is included to differentiate species of &lt;i&gt;Periscolex,&lt;/i&gt; and several observations are given related to the distribution of species and the presence of earthworms depending on changes in land use.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caquetá; &lt;i&gt;Martiodrilus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Periscolex&lt;/i&gt;; new species.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caquetá</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>Feijoo</middlename>
          <lastname>M</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Liliana</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Celis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-44</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydrophis donaldi &lt;/i&gt;(Elapidae, Hydrophiinae), a highly distinctive new species of sea snake from northern Australia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of viviparous sea snake, &lt;i&gt;Hydrophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;donaldi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Hydrophiinae), is described from the Gulf of Carpen-taria, northern Australia. Molecular analyses reveal this species as a deeply divergent lineage within the &lt;i&gt;Hydrophis&lt;/i&gt; sub-group, and separate it from all other sampled taxa by fixed nucleotide substitutions at three independent mitochondrial andnuclear loci. The new species is assigned to &lt;i&gt;Hydrophis&lt;/i&gt; based on the current morphological diagnosis of this large but pa-raphyletic genus, and is distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Hydrophis&lt;/i&gt; species and closely allied genera by a combination of mor-phological characters relating to scalation, colour pattern and osteology. Using current keys for sea snakes, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;donaldi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; might be mistaken for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coggeri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sibauensis&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diadema&lt;/i&gt; but it is readily distinguished from thesespecies by a higher number of bands on the body and tail, lower ventral count, strongly spinous body scales, and a wider,more rounded head. Sea snakes have been sampled intensively in the Gulf of Carpentaria due to their vulnerability to by-catch in the region’s commercial prawn-trawl fisheries. That this highly distinctive new species has evaded discovery inthe region until now is surprising, but might be explained by its habitat preferences. All known specimens of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;donaldi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; were found in estuarine habitats that are relatively poorly surveyed and are not targeted by commercial fisheries.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Estuary; Gulf of Carpentaria; &lt;i&gt;Hydrophis&lt;/i&gt;; phylogenetics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Estuary</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kanishka</firstname>
          <middlename>D. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ukuwela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kate</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sanders</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bryan</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Oligodon &lt;/i&gt;Fitzinger, 1826 (Squamata: Colubridae) from Pulau Nias, Indonesia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; Fitzinger, 1826, &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of a singlespecimen originating from Nias Island, off the west coast of Sumatra, Indonesia. It differs from other species of the regionby the combination of a constant number (15) of dorsal scale rows, undivided hemipenes, entire anal plate, form of den-tition, and dorsal pattern of white crossbars alternating with three irregular reticulations. This new species is comparedwith other species of the Greater Sunda Islands with 15 or 17 dorsal scale rows. An updated checklist and key to &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; species of the region of Sumatra is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Colubridae; Indonesia; &lt;i&gt;Oligodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wagneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Pulau Nias; Squamata; taxonomy; Sumatra</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Colubridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <lastname>David</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gernot</firstname>
          <lastname>Vogel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
