<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3210.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Feb. 2012</title>
    <volume>3210</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of two ghost shrimps (Decapoda: Axiidea: Callianassidae) from the Middle Miocene of the Central Paratethys: systematics, intraspecific variation, and &lt;i&gt;in situ &lt;/i&gt;preservation </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A redescription of two Middle Miocene burrowing ghost shrimps of the Central Paratethys, &lt;i&gt;Callianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brocchii&lt;/i&gt;Lőrenthey, 1897 and &lt;i&gt;Callianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudorakosensis&lt;/i&gt; Lőrenthey in Lőrenthey &amp; Beurlen, 1929, is provided. Material form-ing the basis of this study comes from the Studienka Formation (lower 'Sarmatian', Serravallian) of the Slovak part of theVienna Basin and exhibits preservation allowing reassignment of the studied taxa to the genera &lt;i&gt;Neocallichirus&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1988and &lt;i&gt;Eucalliax&lt;/i&gt; Manning &amp; Felder, 1991 respectively. The major cheliped of both species exhibits two distinct morphotypesinterpreted herein as possible sexual dimorpism. Several specimens of both taxa are preserved within the tube structuresand are interpreted as &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; preservation within the burrows. Type material of both studied taxa and additional collections from the roughly coeval strata of Hungary and Austria were also studied.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ghost shrimp; &lt;i&gt;Neocallichirus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brocchii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Eucalliax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudorakosensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Middle Miocene; Central Paratethys; &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; preservation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ghost shrimp</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matúš</firstname>
          <lastname>Hyžný</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Natália</firstname>
          <lastname>Hudáčková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Uropodina (Acari: Mesostigmata) from California, USA </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Jedediella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;horneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of two females and four males collected in California, USA.The new genus is unusual among uropodine mites by the shape and length of chelicerae. A previously described speciesof uropodine of uncertain taxonomic placement, &lt;i&gt;Discourella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sellnicki&lt;/i&gt; Hirschmann &amp; Zirngiebl-Nicol, 1969, is transferredto the new genus as &lt;i&gt;Jedediella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sellnicki&lt;/i&gt; (Hirschmann &amp; Zirngiebl-Nicol, 1969) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Two new &lt;i&gt;Trachytes&lt;/i&gt; species(T. &lt;i&gt;axe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated accompanied with a new key and notes to the &lt;i&gt;Trachytes&lt;/i&gt; species of North America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Uropodina; new genus; new species; taxonomy; California</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Uropodina</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jenő</firstname>
          <lastname>Kontschán</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Josef</firstname>
          <lastname>Starý</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-38</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the African catfish genus &lt;i&gt;Andersonia &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Siluriformes) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fishes of the catfish genus &lt;i&gt;Andersonia&lt;/i&gt; (Amphiliidae, Doumeinae) are distributed widely across the northern sub-Saharanportion of Africa that is called the Nilo-Sudan Bioregion. Recent literature indicated that either one or two species of &lt;i&gt;An-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;dersonia&lt;/i&gt; occur in the four drainage basins (upper Niger, upper Nile, Omo, and Lake Chad) in which the genus has beenfound. Our study failed to find any differences in the samples from those basins, as we therefore treat them as populationsof a single species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leptura,&lt;/i&gt; which is redescribed based on extensive series of specimens from across its range. The ge-nus &lt;i&gt;Andersonia&lt;/i&gt; is retained as valid at this time, based on the lack of clear evidence of the phylogenetic position of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lep-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tura&lt;/i&gt; within the Doumeinae. However, a broader sampling of taxa, especially among species currently placed in the genus &lt;i&gt;Phractura,&lt;/i&gt; may require a change to that assignment.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphiliidae; Doumeinae; Nilo-Sudan Bioregion</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphiliidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carl</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferraris</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-49</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of the salps (Tunicata, Thaliacea) from the Western Caribbean Sea with a key for their identification and comments on other North Atlantic salps </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In waters of the Northwestern Atlantic pelagic tunicates may contribute significantly to the plankton biomass; however, theregional information on the salp fauna is scarce and limited to restricted sectors. In the Caribbean Sea (CS) and the Gulf ofMexico (GOM) the composition of the salpid fauna is still poorly known and this group remains among the less studiedzooplankton taxa in the Northwestern Tropical Atlantic. A revised checklist of the salp species recorded in the North At-lantic (NA, 0–40° N) is provided herein, including new information from the Western Caribbean. Zooplankton sampleswere collected during two cruises (March 2006, January 2007) within a depth range of 0–941 m. A total of 14 species wererecorded in our samples, including new records for the CS and GOM area (Cyclosalpa &lt;i&gt;bakeri&lt;/i&gt; Ritter 1905), for the CS (Cy-&lt;i&gt;closalpa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; (Chamisso, 1819)), and for the Western Caribbean (Salpa &lt;i&gt;maxima&lt;/i&gt; Forskål, 1774). The number of speciesof salps known from the CS and GOM rose to 18. A key for the identification of the species recorded in the region is provided. Studies on the ecological role of salps in several sectors of the NA are scarce and deserve further attention.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">pelagic tunicates; Yucatan Peninsula; North Atlantic; gelatinous zooplankton; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">pelagic tunicates</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Clara</firstname>
          <middlename>María</middlename>
          <lastname>Hereu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Suárez-Morales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-60</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Chactas camposi &lt;/i&gt;Mello–Leitão, 1939 (Scorpiones, Chactidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The true taxonomic status of the chactid scorpion &lt;i&gt;Chactas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camposi&lt;/i&gt; Mello-Leitão, 1939 from Ecuador is established basedin the recently discovered holotype female, until now considered lost, at the Museu Nacional do Rio de Janeiro. In baseon the analysis of the external morphology, we transfer this species to the genus &lt;i&gt;Teuthraustes&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1878. A detailedredescription and diagnosis according to modern standards are provided. &lt;i&gt;Teuthraustes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camposi&lt;/i&gt; comb. n. is closely related with &lt;i&gt;Teuthraustes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whymperi&lt;/i&gt; (Pocock, 1893) from Ecuadorian provinces Pichincha and Cotopaxi.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scorpiones; &lt;i&gt;Teuthraustes&lt;/i&gt;; Ecuador; Andes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scorpiones</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ochoa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Pinto–Da–Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-02-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
