<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3233.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Mar. 2012</title>
    <volume>3233</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Siluriformes: Loricariidae) from the Upper Rio Paraná basin of southeastern Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this study, we describe three new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bandeirante,&lt;/i&gt; from Salesópolis in the stateof São Paulo, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langeanii&lt;/i&gt; from Muzambinho, in the state of Minas Gerais, and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;botucatu&lt;/i&gt; from Botucatu, in the state ofSão Paulo. All of the described species are found in the Upper Rio Paraná basin. The new species are different from eachother and from their nominal congeners in their mitochondrial DNA sequences (COI), morphology and meristic traits, inaddition to their color patterns. Morphologically, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bandeirante&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from all congeners by the presenceof moderate keels throughout the lateral series of plates and by a naked area between each mid-ventral and ventral platethat is greater in size than the length of these plates. &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;botucatu&lt;/i&gt; is morphologically distinguished by a re-duction of the adipose fin and the presence of dark spots that are distributed along the body. &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langeanii&lt;/i&gt;can be morphologically distinguished by the absence of hypertrophied odontodes and a swollen integument on the head, as well as by morphometric characteristics.&lt;b&gt;Key-words:&lt;/b&gt; catfishes, freshwater fishes, molecular identification, Neoplecostominae, Neotropical fishes, taxonomyNo presente estudo, descrevemos três novas espécies do gênero &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bandeirante&lt;/i&gt; de Salesópolis, no estadode São Paulo, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langeanii&lt;/i&gt; de Muzambinho, no estado de Minas Gerais e &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;botucatu&lt;/i&gt; de Botucatu, no estado de São Paulo.Todas as espécies descritas são da bacia do Alto Rio Paraná. As novas espécies são diferenciadas por sequências de DNAmitocondrial (COI), morfologia e caracteres merísticos, adicionalmente por aspectos de coloração. Morfologicamente, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;bandeirante&lt;/i&gt; é diferenciada das congêneres principalmente pela presença de quilhas moderadas ao longo das séries de pla-cas laterais e área nua entre cada placa médio ventral e ventral maior que o comprimento dessas placas. &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;botucatu&lt;/i&gt; é diferenciada morfologicamente pela redução da nadadeira adiposa e presença de pintas escuras em todo o cor-po. &lt;i&gt;Neoplecostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langeanii&lt;/i&gt; pode ser distinguida morfologicamente pela ausência de odontódeos hipertrofiados e pele intumescida na cabeça, tanto quando por caracteres morfométricos.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fábio</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Roxo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cláudio</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zawadzki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gnathia masca &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea, Isopoda, Gnathiidae) from Lizard Island, Great Barrier Reef, Australia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gnathia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;masca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from material collected off Coconut Beach, Lizard Island, Great Barrier Reef, Aus-tralia. Males are characterised by a cephalosome with a shallow dorsal sulcus that stretches half its length, a slightly pro-duced frontal border with two conical superior fronto-lateral processes and a conical inferior medio-frontal process. Malemandibles have 6 processes on the dentate blade and a distinct internal lobe with 6 or 7 crenulations and a single largedistal process. Live males, females and larvae are characterized by brown pigmentation especially in the male where it forms a dark band that stretches between the eyes, giving it the appearance of a mask.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Gnathiidae; &lt;i&gt;Gnathia&lt;/i&gt;; Great Barrier Reef; description; morphology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Charon</firstname>
          <lastname>Farquharson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nico</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandra</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grutter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Angela</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davies</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-36</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">S. HARIKRISHNAN (India), KARTHIKEYAN VASUDEVAN (India), ANSLEM DE SILVA (Sri Landa), V. DEEPAK (India), NILADRI BHUSAN KAR (India), ROHIT NANIWADEKAR (India), ALBERT LALREMRUATA (India), K. REBEKAH PRASOONA (India) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new tree skink species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1830, closely allied to &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haliana,&lt;/i&gt; is described from southern West-ern Ghats of India. The new species named, &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;johnsinghi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from all other congeners bymorphological and molecular data. A related species, &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subcaeruleum,&lt;/i&gt; is re-described based on new material from anew locality in the Western Ghats. Mitochondrial rDNA-based phylogenetic analysis of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; reveals the affin-ities of the south Indian and the Sri Lankan species with Southeast Asian ones. The biogeographic processes that mighthave led to the disjunct distribution of the entities in the genus are discussed. An updated key to the identification of species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dasia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Endemism; Arboreal skink; Western Ghats; re-description; Phylogeny; Disjunct distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Endemism</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ramesh</firstname>
          <middlename>K</middlename>
          <lastname>Aggarwal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3233.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Mar. 2012</title>
    <volume>3233</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Classification of &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx islandicus &lt;/i&gt;(Amphipoda, Crangonyctidae) based on morphological characters and comparison with molecular phylogenies </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; is a groundwater amphipod species endemic to Iceland and a member of the family Crangonyctidaewhich is widespread throughout the Holarctic region. A previous study based on variation in nuclear genes showed that&lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; closest relatives are &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt; species from North America, where most of the species diversity of the genusoccurs. In this study, we aim at describing the morphological affinities of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; with North American &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt;species and two Eurasian species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chlebnikovi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subterraneus.&lt;/i&gt; We used the morphological characters defined byZhang &amp; Holsinger (2003) and scored them for different populations of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; as well as for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chlebnikovi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;subterraneus.&lt;/i&gt; The molecular phylogeny of the Crangonyctidae family and the morphological character states are com-pared in order to detect potential convergence in the morphological traits, common in subterranean species. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt;appears to be close morphologically to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subterraneus&lt;/i&gt; from Europe and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicarpus&lt;/i&gt; from North America. The morphological proximity of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subterraneus&lt;/i&gt; is incongruent with the pattern observed from molecular data.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; groundwater; morphology; RNA; convergence; biogeography; colonization; Iceland</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Etienne</firstname>
          <lastname>Kornobis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Snæbjörn</firstname>
          <lastname>Pálsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jörundur</firstname>
          <lastname>Svavarsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-66</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A &lt;i&gt;nomen novum &lt;/i&gt;for &lt;i&gt;Protechinus &lt;/i&gt;Lavocat, 1961 (Mammalia, Erinaceidae), a junior homonym of the valid name &lt;i&gt;Protechinus &lt;/i&gt;Noetling, 1897 (Echinoidea, Arbacioida) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jelle</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zijlstra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-03-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
