<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3364.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3364</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular phylogenetics of stream treefrogs of the &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus larinopygion &lt;/i&gt; group (Anura: Hylidae), and description of two new species from Ecuador</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We review the systematics of frogs of the &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group. A new phylogenetic tree inferred frommitochondrial DNA (partial sequences of 12S rRNA, valine-tRNA, and 16S rRNA genes; ~2.3 kb) of eleven species ofthe &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group is provided, based on maximum parsimony, maximum likelihood, and Bayesian analyses. Ourphylogeny confirms the close relationship of members of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group with Andean relatives of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; group, which also occurs in the Andes. &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tapichalaca&lt;/i&gt; is placed as sister species to the rest of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group, in which two clades (A+B) are evident. Although ingroup relationships are well supported, themonophyly of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group and placement of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tapichalaca&lt;/i&gt; require additional testing. Genetic divergencesamong species of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group are shallow compared to those observed in many other anurans, with geneticdistance among sister species (H. &lt;i&gt;princecharlesi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ptychodactylus)&lt;/i&gt; as low as 1.31%. However, this pattern isconcordant with radiations in other highland Andean lineages of anurans that show marked morphological or behavioraldifferentiation, but low divergence in mitochondrial markers. Divergence-time analyses (using BEAST) indicate that the&lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; clade is a relatively ancient lineage that appeared in the Eocene, at a minimum age of 51.2 million years ago(MYA), while the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group originated in the Middle-Late Eocene at a minimum age of 40.9 MYA. Ourresults might suggest a rapid radiation of &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; starting in the Miocene into the Pliocene, from at least 14.2 MYA tothe most recent divergence between sister taxa at ~2.6 MYA. We also describe two sympatric new species of &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt;from northwestern Ecuador: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criptico&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princecharlesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. We diagnose them by their phylogeneticposition (they are not sister to each other), genetic divergence, and a unique combination of color patterns, and othermorphological features. Additionally, we describe the suctorial tadpoles and the extreme ontogenic color changes in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;larinopygion,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantostictus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princecharlesi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psarolaimus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrinus.&lt;/i&gt; Furthermore, we describe theosteology of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criptico,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantostictus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princecharlesi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psarolaimus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ptychodactylus,&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staufferorum.&lt;/i&gt; We describe vocalizations of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantostictus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pasarolaimus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;staufferorum,&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tapichalaca.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrinus&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time in Ecuador and its range is extended 62.4 km (airlinedistance), from its southernmost locality record in Departamento de Nariño, Colombia. Most species of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;larinopygion&lt;/i&gt; group are currently severely threatened by extinction, after surviving the catastrophic extinctions in the1980s and 1990s that led to the disappearance of many other sympatric anurans that bred in swiftly flowing water and hadlotic water tadpoles in the Andean highlands. Research and conservation actions are urgently needed for these species. Inorder to better call attention to these conservation issues, we name one of the new species in honor of Prince Charles ofWales, who is contributing significantly to the growth of awareness in the battle against tropical deforestation, climate change, and the catastrophic extinction of rainforest amphibians.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Ecuador; Calls; Conservation; Extinction; Hylidae; &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criptico&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lar-&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura; Ecuador; Calls; Conservation; Extinction; Hylidae; &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;criptico&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Hyloscirtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lar-&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coloma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sofía</firstname>
          <lastname>Carvajal-Endara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dueñas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arturo</firstname>
          <lastname>Paredes-Recalde</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Manuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Morales-Mite</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Almeida-Reinoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elicio</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tapia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carl</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hutter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Toral</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-78</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-04</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
