<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3378.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Jul. 2012</title>
    <volume>3378</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-07-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the geckos of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Oman based on morphology, mitochondrial and nuclear data, with descriptions of eight new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; is one of the most species-rich and widely distributed of all reptile genera, being found in thetropical and subtropical regions of the world and hundreds of continental and oceanic islands. Despite having already 111species, the number of species described in recent years is very high. This has been facilitated, in part, by the use ofmolecular techniques, which in most cases have been employed to confirm the differentiation at the DNA level of somemorphologically variable forms and to discover some cryptic lineages.Preliminary analyses indicate that some &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; species from Oman are quite variable in their morphologyand may include more than one species. In order to test this hypothesis we inferred a molecular phylogeny including 131&lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; (20 species) using 1385 base pairs of mitochondrial DNA (353 bp &lt;i&gt;12S;&lt;/i&gt; 302 bp &lt;i&gt;cytb;&lt;/i&gt; 588 bp &lt;i&gt;nd4&lt;/i&gt; and 142bp &lt;i&gt;tRNAs)&lt;/i&gt; and 1481 bp of nuclear DNA (403 bp c-mos; 668 bp &lt;i&gt;mc1r&lt;/i&gt; and 410 bp &lt;i&gt;rag2)&lt;/i&gt; and analyzed 226 specimens (15species) for several meristic and pholidotic characters of which we took 3103 photographs that have been deposited inMorphoBank (project 483). Our results indicate the presence of eight new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; geckos in Arabia: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;luqueorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hajarensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from North Oman; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;masirahensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Masirah Island; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;inexpectatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from one locality on coastal Central Oman; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alkiyumii&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;festivus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;paucituberculatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Dhofar, Southern Oman; and finally &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;endophis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. probably from North Omanand described on the basis of morphology alone. An identification key to the genus &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; from Oman is alsopresented. With these descriptions, the number of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; species found in Oman increases from 7 to 13 and thenumber of endemic &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; from 0 to 6. The description of three new species endemic to the Hajar Mountains inNorth Oman highlights the importance of this mountain range as a biodiversity hotspot that, up to now, includes 12reptile species that are found nowhere else in the World. Another hotspot of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; biodiversity is the DhofarMountain range, in the extreme Southwestern corner of Oman and East Yemen. As a result of its particular geographicsituation, orography and the effect of the Southwest Monsoons, this mountain range presents a diverse variety of habitatswith different species of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; adapted to them.With the exception of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flaviviridis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leschenaultii,&lt;/i&gt; which belong to the Tropical Asian clade of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus,&lt;/i&gt;all Arabian &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; for which DNA sequence is available are members of the Arid clade of &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus.&lt;/i&gt;Relatively recent dispersal appears to have taken place within Arabia in the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcicus&lt;/i&gt; group, with the South Arabian &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;lemurinus&lt;/i&gt; occurring far from other confirmed members of this assemblage. &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flaviviridis&lt;/i&gt; and a clade of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; are genetically uniform, widespread in Arabia and beyond and occur around human habitations, suggesting thatmuch of their large distributions are anthropogenic, as appears to be so in several other &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; species outsideArabia.The way in which species of Arabian &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; separate ecologically is surprisingly varied. They may occur atsimilar altitudes but replace each other geographically, or if they are sympatric there may be altitudinal separation.Humidity may also be an important factor, and when animals exist within a few meters of each other, structural nichemay be significant. While four native species occur close together in Dhofar, most &lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt; communities in Arabiaconsist of only one or two species, although climbing geckos belonging to other genera, such as &lt;i&gt;Asaccus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ptyodactylus,&lt;/i&gt; may also be present.‫غ‬</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; Arabia; phylogeny; molecular clock; taxonomy; systematics; mtDNA; nDNA; MorphoBank</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hemidactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Salvador</firstname>
          <lastname>Carranza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Edwin</firstname>
          <middlename>Nicholas</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-95</pages>
        <date_published>2012-07-04</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
