<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3531.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Oct. 2012</title>
    <volume>3531</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-10-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus &lt;/i&gt;Lacordaire, the New World hooded shore beetles (Coleoptera: Epimetopidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The New World genus &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus&lt;/i&gt; Lacordaire, 1854, is revised, based on the examination and databasing of 2,470specimens. New collection records are provided for 15 previously described species, and 36 new species aredescribed. The &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus&lt;/i&gt; fauna now comprises 56 species, of which 37 are restricted to South America, 17 are onlyfound north of South America, and only two species are known from both areas. &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus&lt;/i&gt; ranges from Argentinato Arizona and Arkansas, but there are no records from the Amazon basin. The genus is divided into seven speciesgroups, five of which are newly delineated. High resolution digital images of all primary types are presented (onlineversions in color), geographic distributions of all species are mapped, and male genitalia of primary types areillustrated. The morphology of the underside of the pronotal hood is described and illustrated for the first time. Onenew synonomy is proposed, placing &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leechi&lt;/i&gt; Rocha as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balfourbrownei&lt;/i&gt; Rocha. New speciesof &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus&lt;/i&gt; are: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acuminatus&lt;/i&gt; (Guatemala: El Progresso, km. 69 on C. A. 9); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustus&lt;/i&gt; (Ecuador: Napo, Tena);&lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arcuatus&lt;/i&gt; (Paraguay: Dep. Concepcion, Arroyo Toro Paso, Unterlauf ); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arizonicus&lt;/i&gt; (USA: Arizona, Pajarito Mts.,Sycamore Canyon); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ballatoris&lt;/i&gt; (Venezuela: Tachira State, El Tama National Park); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bifidus&lt;/i&gt; (Mexico: Oaxaca,Tapanatepec, 8 mi. W Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clandestinus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Mato Grosso, Caceres); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clypeatus&lt;/i&gt; (Guyana: Region 8,Iwokrama Forest, 1 km W Kurupukan); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coleuncus&lt;/i&gt; (Argentina: Tucuman, Departamento de Burruyacu, Rio Salas);&lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deceptus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Mato Grosso, Caceres); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadorensis&lt;/i&gt; (Ecuador: Napo, 17 km SW Tena); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil:Mato Grosso, São Felix); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inaequalis&lt;/i&gt; (Ecuador: Napo, Tena); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lanceolatulus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Mato Grosso, Caceres); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;lanceolatus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Mato Grosso, Caceres); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latilobus&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica: Puntarenas, Monteverde area); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latisoides&lt;/i&gt;(Panama: Canal Zone, 12.0 mi NW Gamboa); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latus&lt;/i&gt; (Colombia: Cesar, Pueblo Bello, Sierra de Santa Marta); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;lobilatus&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica: Limon, Reventazon, Hamburg Farm); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microporus&lt;/i&gt; (Panama: Panama Province, Rio Mamoniat PanAm Hwy); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mucronatus&lt;/i&gt; (Honduras: Rio Humuya NW Comayagua); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multiportus&lt;/i&gt; (Uruguay: 90 km SWArtigas); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oaxacus&lt;/i&gt; (Mexico: Oaxaca, Tapanatepec, 8 mi. W Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruvianus&lt;/i&gt; (Peru: Ayacucho, La Mar, SantaRosa); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plicatus&lt;/i&gt; (Venezuela: Tachira State, El Tama National Park); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rectus&lt;/i&gt; (Costa Rica: Heredia, OTS La SelvaField Sta., Puerto Viejo de Sarapique, Rio Puerto Viejo); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robustus&lt;/i&gt; (Panama: Canal Zone, 4.1 mi NW Gamboa, RioFrijoles); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spatulus&lt;/i&gt; (Peru: Madre de Dios, Pantiacolla Lodge, Monk Saki Trail, Alto Madre de Dios River); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt;steineri (Ecuador: Napo, Tena); &lt;i&gt;surinamensis&lt;/i&gt; (Suriname: Sipaliwini District, Camp 3, Wehepai); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversoides&lt;/i&gt;(Peru: Madre de Dios, Pantiacolla Lodge, Monk Saki Trail, Alto Madre de Dios River); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversus&lt;/i&gt; (Bolivia: LaPaz, Alcoche); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridens&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Sao Paulo, Campos do Jordão, Parque do Estado Rio Galharada); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trilobus&lt;/i&gt;(Venezuela: Bolivar, Los Pijiguaos); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venezuelensis&lt;/i&gt; (Venezuela: Apure State, ca. 1 km N. Rio Claro); &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vulpinus&lt;/i&gt; (Brazil: Rio Grande do Sul, Pelotas).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Epimetopidae; &lt;i&gt;Epimetopus&lt;/i&gt; Lacordaire; new species; South America; Central America; semiaquatic insects; holotype digital images</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Perkins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-95</pages>
        <date_published>2012-10-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
