<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Table of contents</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 300KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt;  </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3586.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Dec. 2012</title>
    <volume>3586</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2012</year>
    <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Standardized measurements, landmarks, and meristic counts for cypriniform fishes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Standardized measurements and landmarks for traditional morphometrics, landmark-based (partial truss) measurements, and geometric morphometrics for Cypriniformes are described. Standardized meristic counts also are described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Morphology; fishes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Armbruster</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>8-16</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinigarra napoense&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and species of labeonin fishes (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from Guangxi Province, South China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new garrain genus and species are described from the Zuo-Jiang of the Zhu-Jiang (Pearl River) drainage in GuangxiProvince, South China. &lt;i&gt;Sinigarra,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, is characterized by having the lower lip modified into a mental adhesive discposteriorly discontinuous with the mental region. It is distinguished from all other disc-bearing genera, namely &lt;i&gt;Garra,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Placocheilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Discocheilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Discogobio,&lt;/i&gt; by having the anterior edge of the mental adhesive disc not modified to form ananteromedian crescentic fold, an upper lip present, but separated from the upper jaw, and indistinct papillae scarcely scattered over the rostral cap and lower lip or absent.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; Labeonini; Garraina; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-25</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic placements of the barbin genera &lt;i&gt;Discherodontus&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Chagunius&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Hypselobarbus &lt;/i&gt;in the subfamily Cyprininae (Teleostei: Cypriniformes) and their relationships with other barbins</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The barbin genera &lt;i&gt;Discherodontus&lt;/i&gt; Rainboth 1989, &lt;i&gt;Chagunius&lt;/i&gt; Smith 1938 and &lt;i&gt;Hypselobarbus&lt;/i&gt; Bleeker 1860 are distrib-uted in Southeast and South Asia and are among the least studied taxa of the order Cypriniformes. Few morphologicalstudies have been conducted on these genera and only a very limited number of morphological characters were employedto hypothesize or infer their monophyly, inter-relationships, and relationships with other barbins. The main aim of thisstudy is to examine the monophyly of these three genera and propose hypothesis of relationship among these taxa andother barbins based on a molecular phylogeny of the subfamily Cyprininae. A total of 106 cypriniform species were sam-pled, including 64 species and 31 genera of barbins collected from Eurasia and Africa. Partitioned maximum likelihoodanalysis was performed using DNA sequences derived from five mitochondrial genes (5601 bp): cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; oxidasesubunit I (COI), cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; (Cyt &lt;i&gt;b),&lt;/i&gt; 16S ribosomal RNA (16S), NADH dehydrogenase subunits 4 (ND4) and subunits5 (ND5). The resulting phylogeny demonstrates that, under current taxon sampling, &lt;i&gt;Discherodontus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chagunius,&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;Hypselobarbus&lt;/i&gt; are all monophyletic genera. Together they do not form a monophyletic group, as hypothesized in previousstudies, but are instead part of three distinct and unrelated clades. &lt;i&gt;Discherodontus&lt;/i&gt; constitutes the basal lineage of a cladeformed by Southeast Asian barbins (e.g. &lt;i&gt;Poropuntius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hypsibarbus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Balantiocheilos);&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chagunius&lt;/i&gt; is basal to a cladeformed mainly by &lt;i&gt;Puntius&lt;/i&gt; and allies (although this relationship was only weakly supported); &lt;i&gt;Hypselobarbus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Barbus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;carnaticus&lt;/i&gt; formed a clade sister to a clade including &lt;i&gt;Tor,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neolissochilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Labeobarbus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Varicorhinus.&lt;/i&gt; Homoplasy andshared plesiomorphy of some hypothesized important morphological characters employed in previous studies that led researchers to hypothesize earlier relationships are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">homoplasy; mitochondrial; molecular; morphology; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">homoplasy; mitochondrial; molecular; morphology; phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lei</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Vincent</middlename>
          <lastname>Hirt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tetsuya</firstname>
          <lastname>Sado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Arunachalam</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Raja</firstname>
          <lastname>Manickam</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Simons</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsin-Hui</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mayden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masaki</firstname>
          <lastname>Miya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-40</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Bleeker was right: Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys &lt;/i&gt;(Bleeker 1859) and resurrection of the genus &lt;i&gt;Anematichthys &lt;/i&gt;(Bleeker 1859), based on morphological and molecular data of Southeast Asian Cyprininae (Teleostei, Cypriniformes)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy within the order Cypriniformes is subject to frequent changes, thanks to the results coming from recentmolecular phylogenies that help understand the Cypriniformes tree of life previously established through morphologicalcharacters. In this paper, we focus on species belonging to the Cyprininae – the largest sub-family among Cypriniformes– and we present both morphological and phylogenetic arguments to revise the taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys.&lt;/i&gt;For morphological investigations, we characterized external traits as well as the postcranial skeleton and theneurocranium. For molecular phylogenies, we used four markers, both mitochondrial and nuclear, to establish aphylogenetic tree. We studied four species currently assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; as well as the species&lt;i&gt;Cosmochilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmandi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Puntioplites&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcifer&lt;/i&gt; and we show that the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; is non-monophyletic as&lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enoplos&lt;/i&gt; is closer to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmandi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcifer&lt;/i&gt; than &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;apogon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;repasson.&lt;/i&gt; Finally, we revise the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; and we propose to split this genusinto two genera: genus &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; with the species &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enoplos&lt;/i&gt; and genus &lt;i&gt;Anematichthys&lt;/i&gt; with species &lt;i&gt;Anematichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Anematichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apogon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anematichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;repasson.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; taxonomy; morphology; molecular phylogeny; &lt;i&gt;Cyclocheilichthys&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emmanuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Pasco-Viel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Monette</firstname>
          <lastname>Veran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Laurent</firstname>
          <lastname>Viriot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rectoris longibarbus&lt;/i&gt;, a new styglophic labeonine species (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from South China, with a note on the taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;R. mutabilis &lt;/i&gt;(Lin 1933)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rectoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibargus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is here described from the Zuo–Jiang of the Pearl River drainage at Jinxi County,Guangxi Province, China. It is distinct from all other congeners in the rostral barbel length and the structure of the gas-bladder. &lt;i&gt;Rectoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longibarbus&lt;/i&gt; is further distinguished from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posehensis&lt;/i&gt; by having a slightly papillated posteromedianpatch on the median plate of the lower lip, and from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mutabilis,&lt;/i&gt; as here understood, by having a longitudinal black striperunning along the lateral line on the flank. Taxonomic problems with &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mutabilis&lt;/i&gt; are also addressed; it is regarded to bea senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luxiensis.&lt;/i&gt; The type locality of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mutabilis&lt;/i&gt; is likely in the Yuan–Jiang (a tributary of the middleYangtze River drainage) in Guizhou Province. The species currently recognized as &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mutabilis&lt;/i&gt; is previously unnamed, and possibly represents an undescribed genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rectoris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Cyprinidae; taxonomy; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rectoris&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ding-Gui</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jia-Hu</firstname>
          <lastname>Lan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura tenebrosa&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of loach from the Kwai Noi River system, Mae Khlong basin, Thailand (Teleostei: Nemacheilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Kwai Noi, Mae Khlong basin, in the Thong Pha Phum District ofKanchanaburi Province in western Thailand. The species is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; by a uniformdusky brown color pattern without marks on the dorsum or side of body and with many conspicuous supplementaryneuromasts along the lateral line and on the head. It is further distinguished from other species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; lacking markson the body by its dark brown color, an incomplete lateral line extending only to beneath the dorsal fin, and the origin ofthe dorsal fin located above the origin of the pelvic fin. The species is small, reaching only 46.0 mm SL, 55.1 mm TL, and inhabits shallow gravel and rubble riffles in small streams.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">loach; Cypriniformes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">loach</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Punnatut</firstname>
          <lastname>Kangrang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>William H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beamish</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>69-77</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic Relationships of the Genus &lt;i&gt;Homatula &lt;/i&gt;(Cypriniformes: Nemacheilidae), with Special Reference to the Biogeographic History around the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the nemacheilid genus &lt;i&gt;Homatula&lt;/i&gt; are endemic to the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau of China. Herein we provide phy-logenetic inferences of species relationships based on complete sequences of the mitochondrial &lt;i&gt;cytochrome&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene (cyt &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt;and partial sequences of the nuclear &lt;i&gt;recombination&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;activation&lt;/i&gt; gene (RAG 1). Both gene trees (and the concatenated dataset) support the recognition of five clades in the genus. These analyses also support the hypothesis that two of the lineagesresolved represent undescribed species awaiting formal description, and, further, that two previously recognized speciesare junior synonyms; both are genetically indistinguishable from other previously recognized species. Divergence timesof the major clades in &lt;i&gt;Homatula&lt;/i&gt; are inferred to be Late Pliocene and the Early Pleistocene, and are correlated with themassive geological events associated with the uplift of the Qinghai-Tibetan Plateau occurring at these times. The recon-struction of drainage histories suggests that the fish faunas of the Nu and Lancang rivers are basal relative to other riverinefaunas in the region, and that the Nanpan and the Jinsha rivers share a more recent history than with any other river systems included in our study.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">molecular phylogeny; biogeography; molecular divergence times; Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">molecular phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rui</firstname>
          <lastname>Min</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun-Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <lastname>Winterbottom</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mayden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>78-94</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new loach of the genus &lt;i&gt;Physoschistura &lt;/i&gt;Bănărescu &amp; Nalbant (Teleostei: Nemacheilidae) from Chindwin basin, Manipur, India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The paper describes &lt;i&gt;Physoschistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrinum,&lt;/i&gt; a new nemacheilid from the Chindwin basin in Manipur, India. The newspecies is distinguished from congeners in having 9½ branched dorsal-fin rays; 12–14 irregularly arranged light reddishbrown bars on the side, some of which are broken into blotches and short bars; 5–6 dark brown saddles; forked caudal finwith 9+8 branched rays; axillary pelvic lobe well formed but not prominent; 10 pores in preoperculomandibular canal andsuborbital flap in the male. The status of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prashadi&lt;/i&gt; is also discussed, and the species is validated to &lt;i&gt;Physoschistura.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New nemacheilid; Changa River; northeastern India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New nemacheilid</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lokeshwor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vishwanath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>95-102</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic study of the &lt;i&gt;Cobitis striata &lt;/i&gt;complex (Cypriniformes, Cobitidae) in Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species and six new subspecies of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; from the western part of the Japanese archipelago aredescribed: &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaibarai&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnostriata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuchigamii&lt;/i&gt;subsp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hakataensis&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oumiensis&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tokaiensis&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saninensis&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yodoensis&lt;/i&gt; subsp. nov. &lt;i&gt;Cobitis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;striata&lt;/i&gt; Ikeda, 1936 was redescribed on the basis of specimens collected from the type locality. The four striated spinedloaches, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaibarai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnostriata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; were clearly distinguished by the pelvic myotomenumber, shape of the lamina circularis, black spots at the caudal base, body shape, and egg diameter. Although thesesubspecies of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minamorii&lt;/i&gt; are remarkably alike in morphology, the adult males of the subspecies had different longitudinal patterns of pigmentation during the non-spawning season.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Teleostei; striated spined loach; freshwater fish; East Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Teleostei</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jun</firstname>
          <lastname>Nakajima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>103-130</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura maejotigrina&lt;/i&gt;, a new stream loach (Pisces: Nemacheilidae) from northern Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maejotigrina,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from Maechaem River, a tributary of Ping River, in the upper Chao Phra-ya River drainage, Chiang Mai Province, Thailand. It is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; in having 21–24dark tiger-stripe black bars on the side of the body and 6½–7½ branched dorsal soft rays. The species is medium-sized,reaching 53.0 mm SL (69.6 mm TL), and is known only from the Maechaem River system, Ping River drainage, northernChao Phraya River basin, Chiang Mai Province, Thailand. It lives in fast running, clear water over a substrate of mixed gravel, small stone and sand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chiang Mai Province; Maechaem River; nemacheilines; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chiang Mai Province</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Apinun</firstname>
          <lastname>Suvarnaraksha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>131-137</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius signicaudus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of cyprinid fish from Maeklong Basin, western Thailand (Cypriniformes: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;signicaudus,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of cyprinid fish from the Khwae Noi and Khwae Yai branches of the Maeklong River,western Thailand, is described. It is characterized by the combination of a large, elongated blotch at the caudal-fin base(blotch is formed by the fusion of the large caudal spot at the fleshy end of the caudal base and the last vertical bar on theflank) that extends about 1/3 of the distance from the caudal-fin origin beyond the last scale on the caudal base to the mar-gin of the caudal fork; an anal-fin origin opposing the 2nd–4th branched dorsal-fin rays; eight scale rows above the lateralline; dark pigment on the dorsal fin concentrated mainly along the margins of the rays; 36 or more precaudal lateral-linescales; and small dentary tubercles. This species has previously been identified as &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchellus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orna-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;tus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchellus&lt;/i&gt; has no, or a small caudal spot, a dorsal fin with dark pigments concentrated in the middle of theinterradial regions, and much larger dentary tubercles. &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; and similar species have an anal-fin position thatopposes the 5th–7th branched dorsal-fin rays (rarely the 4th), or does not overlap with them at all, and have no, or small caudal spots.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchellus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infrafasciatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt;; Maeklong; Khwae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchellus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anuratana</firstname>
          <lastname>Tejavej</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>138-147</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Barilius ornatus &lt;/i&gt;Sauvage (Cypriniformes: Cyprinidae) with data from a population from the eastern part of the Isthmus of Kra, Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus,&lt;/i&gt; the first described species of &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; from Southeast Asia, is redescribed with data from additional spec-imens from the eastern part of the Isthmus of Kra. The species is characterized by having 37–40 scales (rarely 36) alongthe lateral line, 6–7scale rows above the lateral line, 17–20 (rarely 16 or 21) predorsal scales, 12–14 circumpeduncularscales, anal-fin origin opposite from the 6th branched dorsal-fin ray to behind the last branched dorsal-fin ray, head depth17–21% SL, predorsal length not more than 58% SL, dark pigment on dorsal fin concentrated at the edge of the brancheddorsal-fin rays, generally short and thin rostral and maxillary barbels (if present), 1–2 small caudal spots or no caudal spot,and small dentary tubercles. With data from additional specimens &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; can be clearly differentiated from &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;barnoides&lt;/i&gt; Vinciguerra and &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infrafasciatus&lt;/i&gt; Fowler. The status of &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudiocellatus&lt;/i&gt; Chu, and &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barila&lt;/i&gt; Hamilton are also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barnoides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infrafasciatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudiocellatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barila&lt;/i&gt;; Chumphon</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barnoides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anuratana</firstname>
          <lastname>Tejavej</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>148-159</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acrossocheilus longipinnis &lt;/i&gt;(Wu 1939), a senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Acrossocheilus stenotaeniatus &lt;/i&gt;Chu &amp; Cui 1989 from the Pearl River basin (Teleostei: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A detailed morphological comparison of the currently recognized subspecies, &lt;i&gt;Acrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iridescens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipinnis&lt;/i&gt; and&lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;i.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iridescens,&lt;/i&gt; shows that there are differences in body coloration of juveniles and some osteological characters, inaddition to the structure of the first branched dorsal-fin ray and the shape of the distal edge of the dorsal fin which arecurrently used to distinguish them. These differences support the taxonomic elevation of the two subspecies to species.Based on examination of the type specimens of &lt;i&gt;Acrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenotaeniatus,&lt;/i&gt; and comparison with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipinnis,&lt;/i&gt; it isconcluded that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipinnis&lt;/i&gt; is a senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenotaeniatus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Acrossocheilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipinnis&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed. Thecurrent generic classification of the two species is discussed based on the body coloration of juveniles and ontogenetic color change.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Morphology; ontogenetic changes; subspecies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Le-Yang</firstname>
          <lastname>Yuan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bosco</firstname>
          <middlename>Pui Lok</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>160-172</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Yaoshania &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Erromyzon kalotaenia&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and a new species of balitorid loaches from Guangxi, China (Teleostei: Cypriniformes)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Yaoshania,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, is described with &lt;i&gt;Protomyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachychilus&lt;/i&gt; as type species. &lt;i&gt;Yaoshania&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from othergenera of Balitoridae by its larger gill opening, a lip lamina at angle of mouth, and the rostral fold with four notches toaccommodate rostral barbels. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Y.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachychilus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Erromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kalotaenia,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is de-scribed from Guangxi, China. It is distinguished from other species of &lt;i&gt;Erromyzon&lt;/i&gt; by the very reduced median lobe of therostral fold; the lower lip distinctly covered with melanophores; and the color pattern on the flank. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Erromyzon&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Yaoshania&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Erromyzon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Yaoshania&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maurice</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun-Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>173-186</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa &lt;/i&gt;(Cypriniformes: Nemacheilidae), &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa longliensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov, from Guizhou, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of nemacheilid loach, &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longliensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Yudonghe River, a small tributary of PearlRiver in Guizhou Province, China. It can be distinguished from other valid &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; loaches by the followingcombination of characters: body smooth and scaleless; head tapering; lips thin and smooth; posterior chamber of gasbladder highly developed, long, bag-shaped, tip reaching origin of pelvic fin; intestine short, bending in zigzag shapebehind stomach; insertion of pelvic fin posterior to dorsal-fin origin; dorsal-fin origin closer to snout tip than to caudalfin base; caudal fin deeply forked, upper lobe obviously longer than lower one; pelvic-fin tip reaching to anus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa;&lt;/i&gt; Guizhou; Pearl River; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa;&lt;/i&gt; Guizhou; Pearl River; China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Qiu</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun-Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>187-194</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of suckers (Teleostei: Cypriniformes: Catostomidae): further evidence of relationships provided by the single-copy nuclear gene IRBP2</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The order Cypriniformes and family Catostomidae, the Holarctic suckers, have received considerable phylogeneticattention in recent years. These studies have provided contrasting phylogenies and classifications to historical,morphology-based phylogenetic and prephylogenetic hypotheses of relationships of species and the naturalness ofhypothesized genera, tribes, and subfamilies. To date, nearly all molecular work on catostomids has been done using DNAsequence variation of mitochondrial genes. In this study, we add to our previous investigations to identify single-copynuclear gene markers for diploid and polyploid cypriniforms, and to expand sequences of nuclear IRBP2 gene to 1,933 bpfor 23 catostomid species. This effort expands our previous studies using only partial sequences of 849 bp. The extendedgene fragment consists of nearly the complete gene across exon1 to exon 4 and is used in two analyses to inferphylogenetic relationships of the currently, or formerly, recognized genera, tribes, and subfamilies. One analysis includes23 ingroup species for which the larger fragment of IRBP2 could be obtained; these taxa were also included in a secondanalysis of 67 samples of 52 species for the shorter fragment. As is typical of other nuclear genes examined to date forcypriniform species, variation in IRBP2 provided strong nodal support for some supra-specific groupings and speciesrelationships. The two analyses revealed slightly different relationships, yet are largely consistent with one another. Theresulting tree from variation in the shorter fragment for 52 species is somewhat inferior to the tree derived using theextended fragment in that not as many nodes were resolved, and few have strong support. Relationships from the latteranalysis are, however, consistent with inferred relationships that are more robustly supported in the smaller taxon analysisusing the larger fragment, lending credence to the use of more complete sequence data of genes in phylogenetic analyses.The current classification of the family (e.g., Nelson 2006) is not fully supported herein. The Ictiobinae is monophyletic,but some ambiguity exists as to relationship of this group relative to Cycleptinae and Myxocyprininae, as well as the needto recognize the latter two subfamilies. Catostominae is monophyletic. &lt;i&gt;Catostomus&lt;/i&gt; is clearly not monophyletic;unnaturalness of the genus is supported herein as well as in multiple, consistently repeated and highly supported studiesresolving &lt;i&gt;Deltistes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chasmistes,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Xyrauchen&lt;/i&gt; within &lt;i&gt;Catostomus.&lt;/i&gt; We herein synonymize the former three genera intothe latter genus; their recognition as distinct genera has been based on historical methods of classification based strictlyon “distinctiveness” or anagenesis of each lineage alone and not phylogenetic relationships relative to species of&lt;i&gt;Catostomus.&lt;/i&gt; The monophyly of Erimyzonini is strongly supported within the analysis of the longer sequence data set. Themonophyly of Thoburniini is ambiguous, but Moxostomatini, including “Scartomyzon,” is monophyletic in both analyses.The proposed recognition of &lt;i&gt;Scartomyzon&lt;/i&gt; as a monophyletic group separate from &lt;i&gt;Moxostoma&lt;/i&gt; is again falsified but with evidence from the nuclear gene IRBP2.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">interphotoreceptor retinoid-binding protein gene; IRBP2; molecular systematics; polyploidy; gene duplication</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">interphotoreceptor retinoid-binding protein gene; IRBP2</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wei-Jen</firstname>
          <middlename>Chen</middlename>
          <lastname>)</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mayden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>195-210</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microphysogobio nudiventris&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of gudgeon (Teleostei: Cyprinidae) from the middle Chang-Jiang (Yangtze River) basin, Hubei Province, South China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microphysogobio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nudiventris,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the Du-He, a tributary flowing into the Han-Jiang of themiddle Chang-Jiang (Yangtze River) basin, in Zhushan County, Hubei Province, South China. It belongs in theincompletely scaled group of this genus, but differs from all other species of this group except &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaluensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapidus,&lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wulonghensis&lt;/i&gt; in the presence of a scaleless midventral region of the body extending more than two-thirds of thedistance from the pectoral-fin insertion to the pelvic-fin insertion. This new species differs from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaluensis&lt;/i&gt; in theslightly concave or straight distal edge of the dorsal fin, interorbital width, and snout length; from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapidus&lt;/i&gt; in thenumber of perforated scales on the lateral line and number of pectoral-fin rays, and the placement of the anus; and from&lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wulonghensis&lt;/i&gt; in having the two lateral lobes of the lower lip posteromedially disconnected, the shape of the median mental pad of the lower lip, and the number of circumpeduncular scales.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Cypriniformes; Gobioninae; Middle Chang-Jiang basin</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhong-Guan</firstname>
          <lastname>Jiang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Er-Hu</firstname>
          <lastname>Gao3</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>211-221</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura albirostris&lt;/i&gt;, a new nemacheiline loach (Teleostei: Balitoridae) from the Irrawaddy River drainage of Yunnan Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albirostris,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of nemacheiline loach, is described from the Longchuanjiang, a tributary of theIrrawaddy River of Tengchong County, southwestern Yunnan, China. It differs from all congeners in the combination ofan extremely slender body; a distinctive rectangular unpigmented area on the snout, ethmoid region and anterior rostralbarbels; 5–7 dark dorsal saddles that are confluent with 5–8 lateral bars; lacking a suborbital flap in males; and possessing an incomplete lateral line with 27–51 pores, and a weakly-developed processus dentiformis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Irrawaddy; Ayeyarwaddy; taxonomy; fish; biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Irrawaddy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chen</firstname>
          <lastname>Xiao-Yong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Neely</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>222-227</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thryssocypris wongrati&lt;/i&gt;, a new anchovy-like cyprinid (Cypriniformes) from the Chao Phraya basin, Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thryssocypris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wongrati,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of cyprinid from the Chao Phraya basin, Thailand, is distinguished from all otherspecies of &lt;i&gt;Thryssocypris&lt;/i&gt; by having a combination of the origin of the dorsal fin behind the origin of the anal fin, 37–40lateral-line scales, 16 circumpeduncular scales, and a dark spot at the base of the caudal fin. &lt;i&gt;Thryssocypris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wongrati&lt;/i&gt; oc-cupies the lower part of the Chao Phraya basin where it has been recorded from irrigation canals in Sing-Buri up to the most northern part of the basin in the Nan River in Phitsanulok Province.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fish; teleost; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chaiwut</firstname>
          <lastname>Grudpan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jarungjit</firstname>
          <lastname>Grudpan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>228-235</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the loach species &lt;i&gt;Barbatula nuda &lt;/i&gt;(Bleeker 1865) (Pisces: Balitoridae) from North China, with a description of a new species from Inner Mongolia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Variation in the currently recognized species, &lt;i&gt;Barbatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda&lt;/i&gt; (Bleeker 1865), from North China was studied, and threedistinct species are identified: &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toni,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibba&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.. The name &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda&lt;/i&gt; is presently misapplied; this speciesis distinct from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toni,&lt;/i&gt; a species widely distributed in Northeast China, and occurs only in the Liao-He basin of LiaoningProvince and the Tumen-Jiang basin of Jilin Province. The new species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibba,&lt;/i&gt; is only found in Dali-Nur Lake in Inner Mongolia. Among Chinese &lt;i&gt;Barbatula&lt;/i&gt; species, it is uniquely distinguished by the shape of the predorsal body.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Barbatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda&lt;/i&gt;; new species; North China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liang</firstname>
          <lastname>Cao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Romain</firstname>
          <lastname>Causse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>236-248</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Physoschistura dikrongensis&lt;/i&gt;, a new loach from Arunachal Pradesh, India (Teleostei: Nemacheilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of nemacheilid, &lt;i&gt;Physoschistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dikrongensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Brahmaputra basin in ArunachalPradesh, India. It is easily distinguishable from congeners in having two V-shaped dark brown bars across the caudal fintowards the distal end; 11–15 irregular bars on the body; dark brown mottled markings on the head; 4 simple and 8½branched dorsal-fin rays; 4 simple anal-fin rays; an incomplete lateral line; a forked caudal fin with 8+7 branched rays; a well-developed axillary pelvic lobe; suborbital flap in males, and nine preoperculo-mandibular sensory canal pores.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dikrong River; Doimukh; Brahmaputra basin; New nemacheilid</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dikrong River</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lokeshwor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vishwanath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>249-254</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura obliquofascia, &lt;/i&gt;a new loach from Uttarakhand, India (Cypriniformes: Nemacheilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new nemacheilid loach, &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquofascia,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Kalsa, a stream near Chanfi, tributary of Gola River,Ganga basin in Uttarakhand, India. The new species is readily distinguished from congeners by the following combinationof characters: 12–14 oblique olivaceous dark bars on the body and three rows of black spots on the dorsal fin; lateral linecomplete with 104–112 pores, dorsal fin with 3–4 simple and 8½ branched rays; 8+8 branched rays in caudal fin; dorsaladipose crest prominent; males lacking suborbital flap; and 10–11 pores in preoperculo-mandibular canal. The sequence of the cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene of length 307 base pairs was used for molecular characterization of the species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ganga basin; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny; New nemacheilid</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ganga basin</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lokeshwor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Barat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sati</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Darshan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vishwanath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mahanta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>255-263</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Metzia &lt;/i&gt;(Cypriniformes: Cyprinidae) from Northern Laos</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new cyprinid fish, &lt;i&gt;Metzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bounthobi,&lt;/i&gt; is described on the basis of 18 specimens (including 10 specimens in type series)from the Mekong River basin in Phongsaly and Luang Prabang Provinces, northern Laos. The species is distinguishedfrom congeners by having the following diagnostic traits: 18–20 branched anal-fin rays (vs. 10–18 in the others); 49–55lateral-line scale rows (vs. 35–48); 33–36 predorsal scale rows (vs. 15–20); 20–22 circumpeduncular scale rows (vs.14–18); 8–10 gill rakers on outer surface of first gill arch (vs. 12–18). The new species also resembles species of &lt;i&gt;Hemic-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ulterella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ischikauia&lt;/i&gt; and at least some species of &lt;i&gt;Anabarilius,&lt;/i&gt; in sharing a sharp keel developed only between the base ofthe pelvic fin and anus, soft last unbranched dorsal-fin ray, and air bladder composed of two chambers; however, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;bounthobi&lt;/i&gt; differs in having a considerably rounded snout (vs. pointed in &lt;i&gt;Hemiculterella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ischikauia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anabarilius),&lt;/i&gt;18–20 branched anal-fin rays (vs. 8–17 in &lt;i&gt;Hemiculterella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ischiakuia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anabarilius),&lt;/i&gt; 49–55 lateral-line scale rows (vs.more than 58 in &lt;i&gt;Ischikauia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anabarilius,&lt;/i&gt; except for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transmontana&lt;/i&gt; with 54–57), air bladder with rounded posteriorend (vs. posterior end with a small lobe at least in &lt;i&gt;Hemiculterella)&lt;/i&gt; and 39–40 vertebrae (vs. 40–43, 42–43 and 43–48 in &lt;i&gt;Hemiculterella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ischikauia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anabarilius,&lt;/i&gt; respectively).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; Cyprinidae; &lt;i&gt;Metzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bounthobi&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Laos</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Koichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Shibukawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Phouvin</firstname>
          <lastname>Phousavanh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Koneuma</firstname>
          <lastname>Phongsa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Akihisa</firstname>
          <lastname>Iwata</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>264-271</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triplophysa pseudostenura&lt;/i&gt;, a new nemacheiline loach (Cypriniformes: Balitoridae) from the Yalong River of China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of nemacheiline loach, &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudostenura,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Yalong River, a tributary of theupper Yangtze River drainage in China. Previous collectors misidentified the species as &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenura.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;pseudostenura&lt;/i&gt; can be separated from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenura&lt;/i&gt; and other valid species of &lt;i&gt;Triplophysa&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination ofcharacters: body smooth and without scales; head tapering; lips thin and smooth; trunk and caudal peduncle slender,laterally compressed; depth of caudal peduncle tapering posteroventrally approaching caudal fin; posterior chamber of gasbladder reduced or absent; intestine short, forming a zigzag loop posterior to bottom of ‘U’-shaped stomach; insertion of pelvic fins anterior to dorsal-fin origin; caudal fin deeply concave.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Teleost; new species; Upper Yangtze River; fish</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Teleost</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chunlin</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhaobin</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>272-280</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular systematics of western North American cyprinids (Cypriniformes: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogenetic or evolutionary relationships of species of Cypriniformes, as well as their classification, is in a era offlux. For the first time ever, the Order, and constituent Families are being examined for relationships within aphylogenetic context. Relevant findings as to sister-group relationships are largely being inferred from analyses of bothmitochondrial and nuclear DNA sequences. Like the vast majority of Cypriniformes, due to an overall lack of anyphylogenetic investigation of these fishes since Hennig’s transformation of the discipline, changes in hypotheses ofrelationships and a natural classification of the species should not be of surprise to anyone. Basically, for most taxa noproperly supported phylogenetic hypothesis has ever been done; and this includes relationships with reasonable taxonand character sampling of even families and subfamilies. As such, like others, many western North American cyprinidgenera have had a controversial taxonomic and systematic history.Our effort to better understand the evolutionary history of this artificial geographic grouping of species (Western)surveyed taxa and characters broadly. We analyzed 127 taxa (71 species) from 36 genera, including representative taxafrom all 22 western genera hypothesized to form the Western Clade &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Coburn and Cavender (1992). Our evaluationalso included additional sampling from a heterogeneous array of species from the western genera &lt;i&gt;Algansea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gila,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lepidomeda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ptychocheilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Siphateles.&lt;/i&gt; Resulting phylogenetic inferences, based on one mitochondrial and threenuclear genes (mtDNA: &lt;i&gt;cytb;&lt;/i&gt; nDNA: &lt;i&gt;Rag1,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhod,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S7),&lt;/i&gt; consistently resolved a well-supported Western Clade, but oneinclusive of &lt;i&gt;Chrosomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erythrogaster.&lt;/i&gt; This taxon, always formed the sister group to the extant species of &lt;i&gt;Gila&lt;/i&gt; plus 10other western genera. Our Western Clade is qualitatively different from that of prior studies and does not include thegenera &lt;i&gt;Agosia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Algansea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Iotichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lepidomeda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Meda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mylocheilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Plagopterus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pogonichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhinichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tiaroga&lt;/i&gt;or &lt;i&gt;Yuriria.&lt;/i&gt; All of these taxa were, however, included in Coburn and Cavender´s (1992) Western Clade. Our broader-scalesurvey and increased character sampling were always resolved these latter taxa within one of two different major clades:the OPM Clade (sensu Mayden 1989) and the Creek Chub—Plagopterin Clade (sensu Simons &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2003). Ourhypothesized Western Clade places &lt;i&gt;Orthodon&lt;/i&gt; sister to a Western Chub-Pikeminnow Clade also inclusive of &lt;i&gt;Acrocheilus,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Eremichthys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gila,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hesperoleucus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lavinia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Moapa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mylopharodon,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ptychocheilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Relictus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Siphateles.&lt;/i&gt; The lattertaxa have traditionally been recognized at the generic level, simply on the basis of their morphological distinctivenessand not on the basis of a phylogenetic evaluation of relationships. Composition of our Western Chub-Pikeminnow Cladealso reveals genetic divergences between species of some genera (Gila, &lt;i&gt;Ptychocheilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Siphateles)&lt;/i&gt; comparable to geneticdivergences documented between genera within the Western Clade. Relationships for these 10 genera also highlighttaxonomic inconsistencies relative to recent phylogenetic analysis and, in some cases, are in need of focused attentionusing morphology or additional molecular data to test relationships that will eventually establish a stable classification.Some of these genera are clearly unnatural relative to other genera and their classification or ranking is an obligatory change in modern science of phylogenetics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Western Clade; Phoxinins; sequence analyses; &lt;i&gt;Gila&lt;/i&gt; lineage; controversial taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Western Clade</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Susana</firstname>
          <lastname>Schönhuth</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shiozawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dowling</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mayden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>281-303</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Traccatichthys tuberculum&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of nemacheiline loach from Guangdong Province, South China (Pisces: Balitoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Traccatichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculum,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is herein described from the Jian-Jiang, a coastal river in Guangdong Province,South China. Photo by Bosco P.L. Chan. This new species differs from all other Chinese congeners (i.e., &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulcher&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;zispi)&lt;/i&gt; in interorbital width, caudal-peduncle length, and pectoral-fin length. It, together with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zispi,&lt;/i&gt; lacks the colorpatterns of the dorsal and anal fins in &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulcher,&lt;/i&gt; and differs from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zispi&lt;/i&gt; in preanal length. &lt;i&gt;Traccatichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculum,&lt;/i&gt;together with all other Chinese congeners, is distinct from the Vietnamese species, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taeniatus,&lt;/i&gt; in the shape of the black bar on the caudal-fin base, and the color pattern of the anal fin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Balitoridae; &lt;i&gt;Traccatichthys&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Jian-Jiang; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Balitoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chun-Xian</firstname>
          <lastname>Du</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bosco</firstname>
          <middlename>Pui Lok</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>304-312</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Homatula wuliangensis &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Nemacheilidae)&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;a new loach from Yunnan, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Homatula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Homatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuliangensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Lancang River of the Wuliang Mountain, Pu-Er City, Jingdong County, Yunnan Province, China. &lt;i&gt;Homatula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuliangensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is readily distinguished from otherspecies of &lt;i&gt;Homatula&lt;/i&gt; by the combination of several morphological characters, including a long upper lobe of the caudalfin relative to the lower lobe, high and long dorsal adipose crest, series of 22–26 very closely aligned body markings, bodyscaled, and 41–42 vertebrae. In addition, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wuliangensis&lt;/i&gt; differs from the similar species &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anguillioides&lt;/i&gt; in having short-er barbels, spots on the caudal fin, the origin of the pelvic fin under the last simple dorsal-fin ray, and a pointed axillarypelvic lobe divided from the body. The new species is further distinguished from the similar species &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pysnolepis&lt;/i&gt; in having shorter barbels, lacking a notch on the lower jaw, and lacking vermiform markings on top of the head.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homatula; Paracobitis; Nemacheilidae; Yunnan; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homatula</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rui</firstname>
          <lastname>Min</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jun-Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xiao-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>313-318</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Nemacheilidae) in the Mae Khlong basin in southwestern Thailand with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent fieldwork has revealed the presence of six species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; McClelland 1838 in the Mae Khlong basin in south-western Thailand. These include &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexcauda&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler 1937), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balteata&lt;/i&gt; (Rendahl 1948), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahnerti&lt;/i&gt; Kottelat 1990, therecently described &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantiaca&lt;/i&gt; Plongsesthee &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2011 and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenebrosa&lt;/i&gt; Kangrang &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2012, and a newly discoveredspecies described herein. &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexcauda&lt;/i&gt; previously was the only &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; species known in the Mae Khlong, andit was mis-identified as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmotes&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler 1934). &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pantherina,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., is easily distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; by its distinctive color pattern. It appears to be endemic to the Mae Nam Kwai Noi system.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pisces; Cypriniformes; &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexcauda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmotes&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pisces</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rungthip</firstname>
          <lastname>Plongsesthee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>William H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beamish</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Punnatut</firstname>
          <lastname>Kangrang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zachary</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Randall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Randal</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Singer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zachary</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>319-328</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Resurrection of the genus &lt;i&gt;Homalopteroides &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Balitoridae) with a redescription of &lt;i&gt;H. modestus &lt;/i&gt;(Vinciguerra 1890)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Homalopteroides&lt;/i&gt; Fowler 1905 is resurrected and distinguished from the genus &lt;i&gt;Homaloptera&lt;/i&gt; van Hasselt 1823based on a combination of characters including a unique mouth morphology, dorsal-fin origin over pelvic fin,≤60 lateral-line scales, and≤30 predorsal scales. Species included in &lt;i&gt;Homalopteroides&lt;/i&gt; are &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wassinkii&lt;/i&gt; (Bleeker 1853), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modestus&lt;/i&gt;(Vinciguerra 1890), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rupicola&lt;/i&gt; (Prashad &amp; Mukerji 1929), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smithi&lt;/i&gt; (Hora 1932), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stephensoni&lt;/i&gt; (Hora 1932), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weberi&lt;/i&gt;(Hora 1932), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tweediei&lt;/i&gt; (Herre 1940), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indochinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Silas 1953), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nebulosus&lt;/i&gt; (Alfred 1969), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yuwonoi&lt;/i&gt; (Kottelat1998), and possibly &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manipurensis&lt;/i&gt; (Arunkumar 1999). &lt;i&gt;Homalopteroides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modestus&lt;/i&gt; (Vinciguerra 1890) is a poorlyknown species that was originally described from the Meekalan and Meetan rivers of southern Myanmar. It occurs in theSalween, Mae Khlong, and Tenasserim basins, and can be distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Homalopteroides&lt;/i&gt; by thecombination of caudal-fin pattern (black proximal and distal bars, median blotch), 15 pectoral-fin rays, pectoral-fin lengthgreater than head length, 5½–6½ scales above and 5–6 scales below the lateral line (to the pelvic fin), 39–44 total lateral-line pores, no axillary pelvic-fin lobe, pelvic fin not reaching anus, orbital length less than interorbital width in adult, and maxillary barbel reaching to or slightly past the anterior orbital rim.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Homaloptera&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Balitoropsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Homalopterula&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Chopraia&lt;/i&gt;; loaches</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Homaloptera&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zachary</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Randall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>329-346</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Schistura myrmekia &lt;/i&gt;(Fowler 1935) (Teleostei: Nemacheilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myrmekia&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler 1935) was originally described from a single specimen collected from Keng Sok,southwestern Thailand. It was differentiated from a similar species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmotes&lt;/i&gt; (Fowler 1934), by having four—ratherthan three—dark bands behind the dorsal fin, and the presence of a wart-like suborbital flap. Although &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myrmekia&lt;/i&gt; hassince been placed in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmotes,&lt;/i&gt; it is distinguishable by the size and orientation of the suborbital flap,a much shorter maxillary barbel, and a more slender appearance. The holotype, the only known specimen of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myrmekia,&lt;/i&gt;is redescribed and contrasted with other species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; in southern Thailand. &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myrmekia&lt;/i&gt; is known onlyfrom the holotype, collected in an area that recently has been highly modified by human activities. Recent efforts to find the species have failed, and it is probably extinct.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pisces; Cypriniformes; South Thailand; loach</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pisces</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Randal</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Singer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>347-352</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sexual dimorphism in species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Nemacheilidae) from the Mae Khlong basin and peninsular Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sexually dimorphic characteristics are described for four species of &lt;i&gt;Schistura&lt;/i&gt; from the Mae Khlong basin and peninsularThailand. Males of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahnerti&lt;/i&gt; have a suborbital flap and rows of unculi on the upper surfaces of the pectoral-fin rays.Females of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahnerti&lt;/i&gt; have a suborbital groove. None of the morphological measurements differ significantly betweenmales and females of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahnerti.&lt;/i&gt; In the other three species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantiaca,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;aurantiaca,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexcauda,&lt;/i&gt; all indi-viduals lack the flap or groove, but most males have a conspicuous black botch on the procurrent rays of the upper lobeof the caudal fin, a feature absent in most females. Some morphometric characteristics vary between sexes of these spe-cies. Sexually dimorphic traits presumably have a function related to reproduction; however, little is known about reproduction in &lt;i&gt;Schistura,&lt;/i&gt; and variation in morphology in relation to habitat or other environmental factors has not been studied.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">loaches; suborbital flap; suborbital groove</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">loaches</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rungthip</firstname>
          <lastname>Plongsesthee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>William H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beamish</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>353-358</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cypriniformes of Borneo (Actinopterygii, Otophysi): An Extraordinary Fauna for Integrated Studies on Diversity, Systematics, Evolution, Ecology, and Conservation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Borneo Island is governed by the countries of Brunei Darussalam, Malaysia (Sabah and Sarawak) and Indonesia(Kalimantan) and is part of Sundaland. These countries have a high diversity of freshwater fishes, especially describedand undescribed species of Cypriniformes; together these species and other flora and fauna represent an extraordinaryopportunity for worldwide collaboration to investigate the biodiversity, conservation, management and evolution ofBorneo’s wildlife. Much of the fauna and flora of Borneo is under significant threat, warranting an immediate and swiftinternational collaboration to rapidly inventory, describe, and conserve the diversity. The Sunda drainage appears to havebeen an important evolutionary centre for many fish groups, including cypriniforms (Cyprinidae, Balitoridae andGyrinocheilidae); however, Northwestern Borneo (Brunei, Sabah and Sarawak) is not connected to Sundaland, and thisdisjunction likely explains the non-homogeneity of Bornean ichthyofauna. A previous study confirmed that northernBorneo, eastern Borneo and Sarawak shared a similar ichthyofauna, findings that support the general hypothesis forfreshwater connections at one time between western Borneo and central Sumatra, and south Borneo and Java island.Borneo is drained by five major rivers: (1) Rajang and Baram rivers in Sarawak, and (2) Kapuas, Mahakam and Baritorivers in Kalimantan. The Cypriniformes is the most diverse clade in Borneo, and it is represented by at least 285 speciesin 55 genera and eight major clades (Balitoridae, Cobitidae, Cyprinidae, Gyrinocheilidae, Leptobarbidae, rasborines,cultrines and Paedocyprididae); at least 147 (52%) of these species are endemic to the incredibly diverse habitats ofBorneo. Most fish faunal studies in Borneo have involved inventory and discovery; however, none to date have focusedtheir efforts on the great biodiversity and systematics of Cypriniformes. In this paper we briefly discuss the generalbiodiversity of cypriniforms in Borneo, including recent revisions to the classification of the order through theCypriniformes Tree of Life and Planetary Biodiversity Inventory efforts supported by the USA NSF basic scienceinitiatives, in conjunction with researchers in countries of Borneo. It is our hope that this particular summary willgalvanize individuals to increase worldwide collaborative and integrated efforts on the biodiversity of Cypriniformes,and incite lively discussions among a broad array of interested parties, including those involved in the recent and critically important “Heart of Borneo” initiative funded by all these countries and some NGOs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Borneo; Cypriniformes; Sundaland</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zohrah</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sulaiman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>L</middlename>
          <lastname>Mayden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>359-376</pages>
        <date_published>2012-12-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
