<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">PETER JÄGER, MARTIN PÄCKERT, PETER SCHWENDINGER (EDS) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 20KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt;  </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Foreword</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Jäger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Päckert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Schwendinger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Table of contents</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Open</middlename>
          <lastname>Access</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1325.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1325</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Palaearctic Titmouse Species (Aves: Paridae: Parus sensu lato)  A current survey</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Within the Palaearctic taxa belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Parus&lt;/i&gt; s.l. there are sympatric species at all levels of similarity. However, during the entire 20th Century no other sympatric cryptospecies were discovered, despite the progressive refinement of comparative methods. All the taxonomic changes introduced were related to determining the status of allopatric and parapatric taxa, in particular with respect to either 1. the subspecies or species status or, more rarely, 2. direct systematic relationships in the cases of &lt;i&gt;Parus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lugubris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hyrcanus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;davidi.&lt;/i&gt; This taxonomic survey of Palaearctic titmouse species aims at a synthesis of the results of both classical morphological methods on the one hand and the more recent bioacoustic and molecular studies on the other. Under the assumptions of the biospecies concept 22 Palaearctic titmouse species are distinguished, which at a higher taxonomic level belong to fourteen geospecies. Most species embrace different “population groups”, which represent the smallest bundling of taxa on a morphological-geographical basis. Within Palaearctic Paridae each of the 44 population groups presented in this paper is distinguished by a distinct morphological character set. Mean values of several morphometric measurements, such as wing length, tail length and relative tail length are provided for each population group in the species list (Section VI).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Intraspecific vicariance; geospecies; superspecies; allospecies; tail/wing index; wing/ tip index</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Intraspecific vicariance</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Eck</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>7-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Characterization of a secondary contact zone of the Great Tit Parus major and the Japanese Tit P. minor (Aves: Passeriformes) in Far Eastern Siberia with DNA markers.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Great Tit &lt;i&gt;Parus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; and the Japanese Tit &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; meet and hybridize in a secondary contact zone in Far Eastern Amur River Valley. The genetic characteristics of this hybrid zone were studied by nuclear microsatellites and mitochondrial DNA sequences. Patterns of introgression of nuclear markers, mitochondrial markers and phenotypic characters were found to be different. The possible reasons, such as stronger selection against heterogametic females according to Haldane’s rule, lowered hybrid fitness, assortative mating and factors enforcing introgression, like densitydependent pair-formation, are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Paridae; hybrid zone; Amur; microsatellite; mitochondrial DNA; introgression; Haldane’s rule</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Paridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kvist</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Rytkönen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-73</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Remarks on biology, vocalisations and systematics of Urocynchramus pylzowi Przewalski (Aves, Passeriformes)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Several field studies in the Qinghai Nanshan area (Qinghai Province, China) have added new findings to the scant knowledge about Przewalski´s Rosefinch &lt;i&gt;Urocynchramus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pylzowi&lt;/i&gt; Przewalski, 1876. The hitherto completely unknown vocalisations are described and used to clarify systematic relationships. Although one could argue for a relationship to &lt;i&gt;Uragus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sibiricus&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas), based on nearly identical auditory impression and sonagram structures of their songs, detailed measurements show significant differences in time and frequency parameters. Moreover a mtDNA analysis shows no close phylogenetic relationship to either of three major emberizid clades. These results support the hypothesis that &lt;i&gt;Urocynchramus&lt;/i&gt; belongs in its own family, the Urocynchramidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Urocynchramidae; Przewalski´s Rosefinch; Long-tailed Rosefinch; &lt;i&gt;Uragus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sibiricus&lt;/i&gt;; acoustics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Urocynchramidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gebauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaiser</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wassmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>75-98</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Song dialects as diagnostic characters  acoustic differentiation of the Canary Island Goldcrest subspecies Regulus regulus teneriffae Seebohm 1883 and R. r. ellenthalerae Päckert et al. 2006</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>99-115</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of the Italian Sparrow  Passer italiae (Vieillot 1817): Speciation by stabilised hybridisation? A critical analysis</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since its description the taxonomic status of the Italian Sparrow &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; (Vieillot 1817) has changed repeatedly according to the speciation concepts applied. Due to external similarities with hybrid sparrow individuals the hypothesis that &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; is a stabilised hybrid form between &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domesticus&lt;/i&gt; (L. 1758) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispaniolensis&lt;/i&gt; (Temm. 1820) has deeply influenced the discussion although some authors do not even accept hybrid forms as taxa. Based upon a comprehensive review of the literature it is shown that the postulation of a hybrid origin of &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; is inadmissible, being based on a methodologically circular argument. There is no convincing proof of stabilised hybridisation. Therefore &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; is a real taxon and not a hybrid form. Applying the Biospecies Concept according to current knowledge of distributional facts and the lack of reproductive isolation between &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;hispaniolensis&lt;/i&gt; I argue that these two forms are conspecific. &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domesticus&lt;/i&gt; is not conspecific with them. According to the rules of zoological nomenclature the taxa have to be designated as &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; (Vieillot 1817) and &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;italiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispaniolensis&lt;/i&gt; (Temminck 1820).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Species concept; subspecies; biospecies; &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;domesticus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Passer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispaniolensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Species concept</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Töpfer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>117-145</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Umbopilio species from Assam, NE India (Opiliones: Sclerosomatidae: Gagrellinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Umbopilio&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1956 (Opiliones, Sclerosomatidae) from Burma, originally placed in the Phalangiinae and later transferred to the Sclerosomatinae, is here transferred to the Gagrellinae. A second species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;Umbopilio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Assam, NE India.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Asia; harvestmen; &lt;i&gt;Umbopilio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Umbopilio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxus&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Asia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Klime</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>147-156</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Geographic variation of chromosomes and somatic morphology in the Japanese polymorphic species Leiobunum hiraiwai (Arachnida: Opiliones: Sclerosomatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;hiraiwai-subgroup&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvipalpe-species&lt;/i&gt; group (Opiliones: Sclerosomatidae: Leiobuninae) is revised on the basis of somatic morphology, genitalia and karyotypes. This subgroup is distributed mainly in the mountainous areas of the Japanese Beech (Fagus &lt;i&gt;crenata)&lt;/i&gt; forest zone (usually above 700 m in altitude in the southwestern part of Japan) in the western part of the Japanese Islands and corresponds to a single polytypic species, &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiraiwai&lt;/i&gt; (Sato &amp; Suzuki, 1939) with eight geographic races. &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tamanum&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki, 1957 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tsushimense&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki, 1976 are here synonymized with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiraiwai.&lt;/i&gt; All the races, except for the Tsushima race, were chromosomally analyzed. The number of chromosomes varies geographically from 2n = 18 to 22 eastwards, irrespective of the variation in somatic morphology or male genitalia. Component chromosomes in these karyotypes are invariably metacentric or submetacentric in structure. Some morphological characters show a geographic pattern of variation that conforms to the stasipatric model of speciation. The possible processes of geographical differentiation of the species and direction of character evolution are inferred on the basis of such geographical patterns. The distribution of some character states suggests that the closest relative of the subgroup is the &lt;i&gt;curvipalpe-subgroup&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvipalpe&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1910 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tohokuense&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki, 1976) that inhabits the northeastern part of Honshu, Japan. The &lt;i&gt;hiraiwai-subgroup&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hiraiwai)&lt;/i&gt; shows a mutually exclusive or checkerboard pattern of geographical distribution with regards to the &lt;i&gt;montanum-subgroup&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Leiobunum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanum&lt;/i&gt; Suzuki, 1953) in southwestern Japan, suggesting some possible reproductive interference between these two species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Checkerboard distribution; chromosomes; genital morphology; geographic variation; Japan; new synonymy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Checkerboard distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tsurusaki</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>157-190</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Martensolasma jocheni, a new genus and species of harvestman from Mexico (Opiliones: Nemastomatidae: Ortholasmatinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Martensolasma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jocheni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;g.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Mexican State of Aguascalientes. The new genus is distinct from &lt;i&gt;Dendrolasma&lt;/i&gt; Banks and &lt;i&gt;Ortholasma&lt;/i&gt; Banks in lacking the extensive modifications of the eye tubercle.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aguascalientes; Ortholasma; Crosbycus; Nemastomatinae; Ceratotlasmatidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aguascalientes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shear</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>191-198</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Marayniocus martensi, a new genus and a new species of Peruvian harvestmen (Arachnida: Opiliones: Gonyleptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and a new species of Gonyleptidae (Pachylinae) from the Peruvian Andes, &lt;i&gt;Marayniocus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi,&lt;/i&gt; are described. The generic distinction is primarily based on the male genitalia, especially the ventral process of the stylus, which is fan-shaped and bears an acute ventral apophysis; such a structure has no parallel among other Andean pachylines. Exomorphological and genital differences between &lt;i&gt;Marayniocus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and the Andean genera &lt;i&gt;Acrographinotus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Junicus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Punagraphinotus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Palcapachylus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tarmapachylus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pichitus&lt;/i&gt; are discussed. The new species has been collected in high altitude grasslands south of the Chanchamayo basin, on the eastern Andean slopes of central Peru.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Peru; Andes; Neotropics; Pachylinae; taxonomy; genus diagnosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Peru</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Acosta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>199-210</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Tricommatinae from the montane savanna of São Paulo (Opiliones: Laniatores: Gonyleptidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopachylus&lt;/i&gt; — &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; — is described from São José do Barreiro, São Paulo State, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Olynthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alticola&lt;/i&gt; H. Soares, 1945, from Alto da Serra, also in the São Paulo State, is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Pseudopachylus.&lt;/i&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopachylus&lt;/i&gt; now comprises six species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Harvestmen; neotropical; WWF Ecoregions NT0160; NT0703; Atlantic Forest; Brazilian arachnofauna</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Harvestmen</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>211-217</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Protimesius &lt;/i&gt;from Brazil (Opiliones: Stygnidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of the harvestmen genus &lt;i&gt;Protimesius&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1913 are described from Brazil: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foliadereis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (type-locality: Juruena, Mato Grosso), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;junina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (type-locality: Gruta Califórnia, Pau Brasil, Bahia), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cirio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (type-locality: Ananindeua, Pará), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boimbumba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carnaval&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (type-locality for both: Rio Moa, Parque Nacional da Serra do Divisor, Acre). &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;apiacas&lt;/i&gt; Pinto-da-Rocha, 2000 is recorded from Rondonia State (Brazil) for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Harvestmen; Neotropics; taxonomy; Laniatores</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Harvestmen</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <lastname>Villarreal-Manzanilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pinto-Da-Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>219-233</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the family Fissiphalliidae Martens, 1988, with descriptions of two new Amazonian species (Arachnida: Opiliones: Laniatores)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Brazilian Fissiphalliidae are described. &lt;i&gt;Fissiphallius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chicoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Pará State, Gurupá municipality, whitewater floodplains (várzea), and &lt;i&gt;Fissiphallius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tucupi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Amazonas State, Castanho municipality (paleovárzea). The number of species for this family in the Amazon rainforest increases from one to three. The two new species are closely related to &lt;i&gt;Fissiphallius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; Pinto-da-Rocha, 2004 from Amazonas State, Manaus. Fissiphalliidae and Zalmoxidae show remarkable similarities in somatic and genital morphology. Fissiphalliidae is kept as a family on the basis of its particular shape of the stragulum, but this character should be tested in a phylogenetic framework. A future phylogenetic analysis should determine if Fissiphalliidae is in fact the sister group of Zalmoxidae, or just a junior synonym. A key for identification, a distribution map, and notes on the distribution of the six species of Fissiphalliidae and the biology of the Amazonian species are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropics; Amazonian Rainforest; Amazonian floodplains; Zalmoxidae; taxonomy; BR-319 highway</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tourinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>González</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>235-254</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the family Oncopodidae VI. &lt;i&gt;Martensiellus&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus from Borneo, and the discovery of a tarsal pore organ in Oncopodidae (Opiliones: Laniatores)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Martensiellus,&lt;/i&gt; is established for &lt;i&gt;Martensiellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuipalpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from central Sarawak. The distad-directed, expandable glans penis of this species indicates a close relationship with &lt;i&gt;Biantoncopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscus&lt;/i&gt; Martens &amp; Schwendinger from the Philippines. Females of two other species from eastern Sarawak and southern Kalimantan, which presumably also belong to &lt;i&gt;Martensiellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;g.,&lt;/b&gt; are presented but not formally described. A dorsal pore, similar to the pore organ of Ricinulei, is reported to be present on undivided leg tarsi of mature specimens of &lt;i&gt;Martensiellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuipalpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; ?Martensiellus &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;g.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;spp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Palaeoncopus&lt;/i&gt; spp., &lt;i&gt;Caenoncopus&lt;/i&gt; spp. and &lt;i&gt;Oncopus&lt;/i&gt; spp. This character is considered as apomorphic for Oncopodidae, providing further support for monophyly of this family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; taxonomy; Sarawak; Kalimantan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schwendinger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>255-266</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of harvestmen (Arachnida: Opiliones) in Slovenia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The authors present a short historical faunistic, zoogeographical and ecological review of research on harvestmen (Opiliones) of the territory of presentday Slovenia, and discuss some actual ecological and nature conservational questions. Till recent, 64 species plus two subspecies of Opiliones inhabiting Slovenia are recorded, most of these are Alpine, European, Centraland Western European elements. Taxonomically, there are some open questions, especially in the genus &lt;i&gt;Trogulus.&lt;/i&gt; A small number of further species can be expected in Slovenia, raising the potential final number to 69-71. Some harvestmen are locally and regionally endangered, especially by anthropogenous habitat and ecosystem changes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnids; harvestmen; nature conservation; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Novak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Delakorda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Novak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>267-276</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On some Linyphiidae of China, mainly from Taibai Shan, Qinling Mountains, Shaanxi Province (Arachnida: Araneae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The collection of Prof. J. Martens and, in part, of Dr P. Jäger, mainly from Taibai Shan, Qinling Mountains, Shaanxi Province, China, contains 36 identifiable species of Linyphiidae. Among these, the following nine new species belong to known genera: &lt;i&gt;Agyneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Arcuphantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Indophantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mughiphantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beishanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jaegeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nippononeta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Asthenargus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Dicymbium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinofacetum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Each of the remaining five new species warrants the erection of a new genus: &lt;i&gt;Houshenzinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Houshenzinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rimosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.),&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Shaanxinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Shaanxinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.),&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Shanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Shanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taibaiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.),&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Taibainus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Taibainus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.)&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Taibaishanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Taibaishanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.).&lt;/b&gt; The following new synonym and combinations are proposed (valid names on the right): &lt;i&gt;Gnathonarium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cambridgei&lt;/i&gt; Schenkel 1963 = &lt;i&gt;Gnathonarium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taczanowskii&lt;/i&gt; (O. Pickard-Cambridge 1873) &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Araeoncus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stigmosus&lt;/i&gt; Xia, Zhang, Gao, Fei, Rui &amp; Kim 2001 = &lt;i&gt;Tibioploides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stigmosus&lt;/i&gt; (Xia, Zhang, Gao, Fei, Rui &amp; Kim 2001) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Walckenaeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anguilliformis&lt;/i&gt; Xia, Zhang, Gao, Fei, Rui &amp; Kim 2001 = &lt;i&gt;Shaanxinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anguilliformis&lt;/i&gt; (Xia, Zhang, Gao, Fei, Rui &amp; Kim, 2001) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lepthyphantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huangyuanensis&lt;/i&gt; Zhu &amp; Li 1983 = &lt;i&gt;Tchatkalophantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huangyuanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Zhu &amp; Li 1983) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; The female of &lt;i&gt;Tibioploides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stigmosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spiders; taxonomy; new genera; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tanasevitch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>277-311</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Spatiator martensi &lt;/i&gt;n. sp., a second species of the extinct spider family Spatiatoridae in Eocene Baltic amber (Araneae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Spatiator&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Araneae: Spatiatoridae) is described from the Early Tertiary Baltic amber forest. It is the second known species of this extinct family of spiders. Ants as syninclusions point to a possible ant mimicry or myrmecophagy.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Fossil spiders; Tertiary; new species; mimicry; myrmecophagy; myrmecomorphy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Fossil spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wunderlich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>313-318</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of spiders of the family Zodariidae (Araneae) from eastern Nepal</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Zodariidae of the genus &lt;i&gt;Suffasi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; Jocqué, 1991, obtained from the easternmost part of Nepal are described under the names, &lt;i&gt;Suffasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kanchenjunga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Both new species can be distinguished from each other and from all the known species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;Suffasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tigrina&lt;/i&gt; (Simon, 1893) from India, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tumegaster&lt;/i&gt; Jocqué, 1992 from Nepal, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attiduya&lt;/i&gt; Benjamin &amp; Jocqué, 2000 and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahasumana&lt;/i&gt; Benjamin &amp; Jocqué, 2000 from Sri Lanka by the peculiar shape of male palpal tibia. In both species, the tibia is very thick, and it has a dorsal spine in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kanchenjunga.&lt;/i&gt; The females of both species have an epigynum with a long scape, which is slightly widened in front in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kanchenjunga.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Suffasi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;; alpine fauna; Himalayas; Ilam district; soil dwellers</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ono</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>319-326</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heteropoda schwendingeri &lt;/i&gt;Jäger 2005 (Araneae: Sparassidae)  first description of female with notes on intraspecific variation and evidences supporting species status</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The female of &lt;i&gt;Hete&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ropoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schwe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ndin&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geri&lt;/i&gt; Jäger 2005 is described for the first time. Notes on intraspecific variation are given from two males and three females from the type locality, Than Lod Yai cave. Small variation and consistent combination of both male and female characters confirm its species status.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; systematics; huntsman spiders; Heteropodinae; Thailand; cave-dwelling</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Eusemann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Jäger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>327-334</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Martensopoda &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. from southern Indian mountain ranges, the first genus of huntsman spiders with a cymbial spur (Araneae: Sparassidae: Heteropodinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Martensopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is established for two species from South India with distinct and apomorphic features in their copulatory organs. A cymbial spur in the male copulatory organs is reported the first time in the Sparassidae. The embolus’ loop — unique to Heteropodinae — is oriented transversally to the plane of the alveolus. Females exhibit spirally coiled copulatory openings similar to those of &lt;i&gt;Spariolenus,&lt;/i&gt; but with a posterior pit at the median septum and with lateral loops of the internal duct system. &lt;i&gt;Martensopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Cardamon Hills in Kerala State (male, female), &lt;i&gt;Martensopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula&lt;/i&gt; (Reimoser 1934) comb. nov. is known only from females and is recorded from Palni Hills, Tamil Nadu State.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Martensopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Martensopoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov.; India; Cardamon Hills; Palni Hills</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Jäger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>335-345</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the false-scorpion family Cheliferidae from Thailand, with remarks on &lt;i&gt;Ancistrochelifer &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Metachelifer&lt;/i&gt; (Arachnida: Pseudoscorpiones)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Cheliferidae is described from Thailand: ? &lt;i&gt;Dactylochelifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ancistrochelifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orientalis&lt;/i&gt; (Beier, 1967), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Hysterochelifer&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1932, a subcortical pseudosco rpion from northern Thailand, is redescribed. The status of the genus &lt;i&gt;Metachelifer&lt;/i&gt; Redikorzev, 1938 is briefly discussed in connection with &lt;i&gt;Metachelifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepalensis&lt;/i&gt; (Beier, 1974), nom. revalid. &amp; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Hysterochelifer,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Metachelifer&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrotuberculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Krumpal, 1987), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Dactylochelifer&lt;/i&gt; Beier, 1932.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pseudoscorpions; &lt;i&gt;Dactylochelifer&lt;/i&gt;; new combination; revalidation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pseudoscorpions</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Dashdamirov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>347-362</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the Southeast Asian millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Pacidesmus&lt;/i&gt; Golovatch, with the description of a new troglobitic species from southern China (Diplopoda: Polydesmida: Polydesmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Pacidesmus&lt;/i&gt; is briefly reviewed, with all of its three species keyed, including the clearly troglobitic &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from two caves in Guizhou Province, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Guizhou Province</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Golovatch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Geoffroy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>363-368</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Laena &lt;/i&gt;Latreille (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae) from Southeastern Asia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; Latreille, 1829 (Tenebrionidae: Lagriinae ) are described fro m the Malayan Peninsula (Laena &lt;i&gt;kenyirica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schulzi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.),&lt;/b&gt; Burma (Laena &lt;i&gt;kurbatovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.),&lt;/b&gt; Thailand (Laena &lt;i&gt;inthanonica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;khaolaka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rolandi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.),&lt;/b&gt; Laos (Laena &lt;i&gt;champasaka&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jocheni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiyoshii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.)&lt;/b&gt; and Vietnam (Laena &lt;i&gt;gialaica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moguntia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.).&lt;/b&gt; A check-list of all species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Laena&lt;/i&gt; from the Malayan Peninsula (13), Myanmar/Burma (2), Thailand (13), Laos (3) and Vietnam (9) is added.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Malaysia; Myanmar/Burma; Thailand; Laos; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Schawaller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>369-384</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1320.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1320</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Torpedo formosa &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new species of electric ray (Chondrichthyes: Torpediniformes: Torpedinidae) from Taiwan </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of torpedo ray, &lt;i&gt;Torpedo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from specimens collected from northeastern Taiwan. The new species is placed in the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Tetronarce&lt;/i&gt; based on a uniform purplish dorsal coloration and the absence of papillae around the spiracles. It is distinct from the sympatric &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tokionis,&lt;/i&gt; the only other known &lt;i&gt;Torpedo&lt;/i&gt; (Tetronarce) species from the western North Pacific, by a disc that is wider than long, a shorter tail, a greater number of spiral valve turns, and its dorsal coloration. It has been misidentified as &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nobiliana,&lt;/i&gt; but is distinguished from it by having longer snout and spiracle lengths, a lower vertebral count, and a caudal fin height that is greater than the distance from the first dorsal origin to the caudal fin origin. This new species, at present, is known only from the northeast coast of Taiwan between Keelung and Suao primarily at depths of less than 300m.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Electric ray; Torpedinidae; &lt;i&gt;Torpedo&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Electric ray</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Haas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ebert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Holoparasitus &lt;/i&gt;Oudemans, 1936 from northern Austria and Karavanke (Acari: Parasitidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Witaliñski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-27</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The subgenus&lt;i&gt; Monilearia&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Lyrula&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;Wollaston, 1878 (Gastropoda: Helicoidea: Cochlicellidae) from Lanzarote and Fuerteventura (Canary Islands), with the description of &lt;i&gt;Monilearia&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Lyrula&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;i&gt; tubaeformis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ibáñez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Groh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alonso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Castillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yanes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-41</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lubbockichthys myersi&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of dottyback fish from Guam (Pseudochromidae: Pseudoplesiopinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gill</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Edwards</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The male gonostylus of the orchid bee genus &lt;i&gt;Euglossa&lt;/i&gt; (Apidae: Euglossini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ospina-Torres</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Parra-H</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gonzalez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cranial morphology and karyotypic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Ceratophrys joazeirensis&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Ceratophryidae, Ceratophrynae): taxonomic considerations</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Da Silva Vieira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P. Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Arzabe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1319.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1319</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New genera of Psocoptera (Insecta), from Mexico, Belize and Ecuador (Psoquillidae, Ptiloneuridae, Lachesillidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of Psocoptera are described, each in a new monotypic genus: &lt;i&gt;Rhyopsocoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typhicolus&lt;/i&gt; (Psoquillidae) and &lt;i&gt;Omilneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumvittata&lt;/i&gt; (Ptiloneuridae) from Mexico, &lt;i&gt;Belicania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cervantesi&lt;/i&gt; (Ptiloneuridae) from Belize, and &lt;i&gt;Waoraniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;erwini&lt;/i&gt; (Lachesillidae) from Ecuador. Relationships within each family are discussed, and keys to the genera in each family are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Psocoptera; Psoquillidae; Ptiloneuridae; Mexico; Ecuador; new genera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Psocoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>N. G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Aldrete</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of &lt;i&gt;Palliolatrix&lt;/i&gt; gen.n. and seven new species from Middle America (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Baridinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Palliolatrix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.n.&lt;/b&gt; is erected and distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Peridinetus&lt;/i&gt; Schönherr and &lt;i&gt;Peridinetellus&lt;/i&gt; Champion. Ten Neotropical species are included, with the following seven newly described: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palliolatrix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (type species; Costa Rica and Panama), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;attenuata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Costa Rica and Panama), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Colombia), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infucata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Costa Rica), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.,&lt;/b&gt; (Costa Rica and Panama), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Guatemala, Nicaragua to Colombia) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virgata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; (Colombia). &lt;b&gt;New&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combinations&lt;/b&gt; are &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineola&lt;/i&gt; (Kirsch) (from &lt;i&gt;Megops&lt;/i&gt; Schönherr), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insignis&lt;/i&gt; (Chevrolat) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrimaculata&lt;/i&gt; (Champion) (both from &lt;i&gt;Peridinetus).&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">weevils; taxonomy; Piperaceae; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">weevils</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Prena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-28</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; (Cirripedia: Balanomorpha: Pyrgomatidae) is not a sponge-inhabiting barnacle </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of coral-inhabiting barnacle, &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi,&lt;/i&gt; is described. It was found in a colony of the coral &lt;i&gt;Symphyllia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radians&lt;/i&gt; Milne Edwards &amp; Haime, 1849 from Sulawesi, Indonesia. The barnacles were suspended in the coral tissue and were easily detached. A unique feature of &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; is its membranous basis; in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;youngi&lt;/i&gt; the calcareous basis is reduced to a vestige by which the barnacle is attached to the coral. &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; has been regarded as a genus of spongeinhabiting barnacle, thus unique in the otherwise coral-associated family Pyrgomatidae, but our findings confirm that this genus too comprises coral-inhabiting barnacles. We propose a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pyrgospongia,&lt;/i&gt; to accommodate the sponge-inhabiting barnacle originally described as &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stellula&lt;/i&gt; Rosell, 1973. The relationships of both &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pyrgospongia&lt;/i&gt; within the Pyrogomatidae are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Barnacles; Pyrgomatidae; Corals; &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pyrgospongia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Barnacles; Pyrgomatidae; Corals; &lt;i&gt;Pyrgopsella;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pyrgospongia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Achituv</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Simon-Blecher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-41</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Astiotrema turneri&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Digenea: Plagiorchiidae) from cichlid fishes (Cichlidae: Perciformes) of Lake Malawi, south-eastern Africa </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Astiotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the cichlid species &lt;i&gt;Pseudotropheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emmiltos,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Labeotropheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trewavasae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Melanochromis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermivorus&lt;/i&gt; from Lake Malawi. It differs from &lt;i&gt;Astiotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reniferum&lt;/i&gt; (as described by Yeh &amp; Fotedar 1958) in its distinctly broader body, the much smaller cirrus-sac, its oblique testes, the shorter ventral sucker to ovary distance, the vitellarium reaching into the forebody and the extracaecal uterus; from &lt;i&gt;Astiotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;impletum&lt;/i&gt; in the sucker-ratio, the longer caeca, the smaller cirrus-sac and the extracaecal uterus; and from &lt;i&gt;Glossidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedatum&lt;/i&gt; (and its probable synonyms &lt;i&gt;Astiotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lazeri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Afromacroderoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lazerae)&lt;/i&gt; in its much broader body shape, in its distinct oesophagus, the intestinal bifurcation in the posterior forebody, in the distinctly oblique testes, the extracaecal uterus and the vitellarium reaching well into the forebody.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Plagiorchiidae; &lt;i&gt;Astiotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turneri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Cichlidae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudotropheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebra&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pseudotropheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emmiltos&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Labeotropheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trewavasae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Melanochromis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vermivorus&lt;/i&gt;; Lake Malawi</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Oosterhout</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Blais</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cable</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haliclona (Reniera)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;portroyalensis &lt;/i&gt;n. sp., a new chalinid sponge (Porifera, Demospongiae, Haplosclerida) from the southeast coast of Jamaica </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new demosponge species of the order Haplosclerida, growing on mangrove roots in Port Royal, southeast coast Jamaica, is described as &lt;i&gt;Haliclona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Reniera)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;portroyalensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; A short overview of previous work on Chalinidae and on Jamaican sponges is given, and we discuss how the new species differs from other member of the genus and subgenus. The holotype is purple alive and beige when preserved in alcohol. It has digitate and bulbous processes with scattered oscula, some laterally plush, and measuring 2–3 mm with larger ones up to 6 mm on the bulbous areas. The consistency is soft, and it is easily torn, but resilient. The megascleres, oxeas are straight to slightly curved with short conical points. The only microscleres are toxas which are of varying lengths numerous and distributed throughout the ectosome and choanosome.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chalinidae; Haplosclerida; &lt;i&gt;Haliclona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Reniera)&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Jamaica</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chalinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>P. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jackson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Weerdt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Webber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1318.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1318</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of genera &lt;i&gt;Gaza &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Callogaza &lt;/i&gt;(Vetigastropoda, Trochidae), with description of a new Brazilian species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A revision of the trochid genera &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Callogaza,&lt;/i&gt; inhabiting the deep waters of western Atlantic Ocean and eastern Pacific Ocean, is here provided. Species are separated mainly by shell characters, but anatomical features are also used in some species. The species considered in this study are: &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (SE Brazil), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daedala&lt;/i&gt; Watson, 1879 (Central Pacific), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rathbuni&lt;/i&gt; Dall, 1890 (tropical W Pacific), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri&lt;/i&gt; Dall, 1889 (E Caribbean), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superba&lt;/i&gt; (Dall, 1881) (Gulf of Mexico and Caribbean), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubana&lt;/i&gt; Clench &amp; Aguayo, 1940 (N Caribbean), &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olivacea&lt;/i&gt; Quinn, 1991 (NE South America and SE Brazil), &lt;i&gt;Callogaza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watsoni&lt;/i&gt; Dall, 1881 (Gulf of Mexico), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sericata&lt;/i&gt; (Kira, 1959) (NW Pacific) and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frederici&lt;/i&gt; (Smith, 1906) (S India). Anatomical data are provided for: &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olivacea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superba&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubana.&lt;/i&gt; Both &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Callogaza&lt;/i&gt; are characterized by having iridescent, thin-walled shell, with the outer lip deflected (determined growth), and a flat callus partially or completely covering the wide umbilicus, making it a hollow chamber. Anatomically, the examined &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; spp. have long epipodial tentacles and two series of holes between the propodium and the base of the head. The number of these structures can assist in the differentiation of species. Based on similarities of the shell and comparison with species of other trochid genera, we conclude that &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Callogaza&lt;/i&gt; have some characters in common, which most probably constitute synapomorphies that support a monophyletic branch of the family. &lt;i&gt;Microgaza&lt;/i&gt; is not regarded as part of this trochid branch, but may rather belong to Solariellinae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trochidae; &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Callogaza&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gaza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compta&lt;/i&gt; new species; Anatomy; Brazil; revision</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trochidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>R. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Simone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cunha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Haploblepharus kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt;, a new catshark (Chondrichthyes: Scyliorhinidae) from South Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of catshark, &lt;i&gt;Haploblepharus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Class Chondrichthyes, Order Carcharhiniformes, Family Scyliorhinidae) is described from kwaZulu-Natal, South Africa. The type series includes the holotype, RUSI 39835, and two paratypes, RUSI 6075 and RUSI 6077. This species was previously recognised as a variant of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; (Schinz 1822), which occurs along the southern coast of South Africa. The colour pattern of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt; is superficially similar to &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;edwardsii&lt;/i&gt; although distinct; however &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Haploblepharus&lt;/i&gt; in having a stockier build compared to its congeners, a less depressed head and trunk, and a compressed caudal peduncle.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploblepharus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Scyliorhinidae; Carcharhiniformes; taxonomy; South Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haploblepharus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kistnasamyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Scyliorhinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Human</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Compagno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of the Dollmans tree mouse (&lt;i&gt;Prionomys batesi;&lt;/i&gt; Mammalia: Nesomyidae) in the Republic of Congo and additional description of this rare Central African rodent</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We present new data on the poorly known rodent &lt;i&gt;Prionomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batesi&lt;/i&gt; Dollman, 1910. Recently, five specimens of this species were collected in Odzala National Park, which represent the first record of this species in Republic of Congo. These new captures, combined with the preparation of 15 specimens from Central African Republic allowed us to complete the morphological description of the species as well as, for the first time, to document intraspecific variability. This species is actually known from three countries (Cameroon, Central African Republic and Republic of Congo) and four localities (Bitye, Obala, La Maboké and Odzala). It seems to be restricted to areas of forest-savannah mosaic where the forest is actually colonising the savannah.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Prionomys&lt;/i&gt;; Dendromurinae; Biogeography; Morphometry; Africa; Rodentia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Prionomys&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Denys</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Colyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nicolas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1317.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1317</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First description of deep-sea polyclad flatworms from the North Pacific: &lt;i&gt;Anocellidus&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. &lt;i&gt;profundus &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Anocellidae, n. fam.) and &lt;i&gt;Oligocladus voightae &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Euryleptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two deep-sea polyclad species are described. Both species were found in association with woodboring bivalves on oak and fir wood blocks that had been deployed on heavy sediment in the Cascadia Basin and Escanaba Trough in the North Pacific Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Anocellidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profundus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; warrants erection of Anocellidae, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; because of the unique position and orientation of the male copulatory apparatus. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profundus&lt;/i&gt; lacks eyes but has long, nuchal tentacles and a ventral, arrowhead-shaped organ of putative sensory function. The male copulatory apparatus is located posterior to the male gonopore and is directed anteriorly. Highly muscularized spermiducal bulbs are present, a prostatic vesicle is lacking. A large Lang’s vesicle characterizes the female reproductive system. &lt;i&gt;Oligocladus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;voightae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is defined by the presence of a mouth located anterior to the brain. Few and minute tentacular eyes are present. The seminal vesicle is connected to an auxiliary sperm storage vesicle, and a posterior anal pore is present in the main median branch of the intestine. All type material is deposited at the Field Museum of Natural History, Chicago, Illinois, USA.Se describen dos nuevas especies de policládidos de la profundidad marina. &lt;i&gt;Anocellidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profundus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; garantiza el establecimiento de la nueva familia Anocellidae, n. fam. debido a la posición y orientación única del aparato copulatorio masculino. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;profundus&lt;/i&gt; carece de ojos pero presenta tentáculos largos y un órgano ventral con forma de punta de flecha cuya función se presume es sensorial. El aparato copulatorio masculino esta localizado posterior al gonoporo masculino y dirigido anteriormente. En lugar de vesícula seminal dos bulbos espermiducales musculares están presentes y el sistema femenino se caracteriza por una vesícula de Lang de gran tamaño. La boca de &lt;i&gt;Oligocladus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;voightae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; esta localizada anterior al cerebro. Pocos diminutos ojos están presentes. La vesícula seminal esta conectada con una vesícula auxiliar que almacena esperma y un poro anal esta presente en la rama media del intestino. Todo el material tipo esta</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Quiroga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bolaños</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Litvaitis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus darwinii&lt;/i&gt; group (Iguania: Liolaemidae) from Catamarca Province, Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We provide the description for a new species from Catamarca province, Argentina that belongs to the &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darwinii&lt;/i&gt; group. The new species was previously considered as a population of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus,&lt;/i&gt; but it can be distinguished from that species mainly because of differences on coloration pattern, and its geographic distribution, which is disjunct from the populations of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is characterized for having males with a dorsal background coloration of light brown to ferrous red, the head darker than the rest of the body, paravertebral markings rounded and never in contact, dorsolateral strips lightly marked, small dark brown spots on the throat, and a belly that is white or light red.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darwinii&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt;; Catamarca; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Abdala</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gómez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-33</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the knowledge of the "Staphylinus-complex" (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylinini) of China. Part 14. The genus &lt;i&gt;Ocychinus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana 2003. Section 2</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the second paper dealing with the Chinese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ocychinus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003. Two species are described as new: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustiarum&lt;/i&gt; (from Yunnan) and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kalabi&lt;/i&gt; (from Sichuan). New distributional records for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xizangensis&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sichuanensis&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003 and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003 are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; &lt;i&gt;Ocychinus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic; taxonomy; new species; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Smetana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the knowledge of the "Staphylinus-complex" (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylinini) of China. Part 13. The genus &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobulbus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana 2003. Section 3</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the third paper dealing with the Chinese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobulbus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003. Two species are described as new: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biplagiatus&lt;/i&gt; (from Yunnan) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; (from Shaanxi). New distributional records for &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bisinuatus&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003 and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abdominalis&lt;/i&gt; Smetana, 2003 are given. &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobulbus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; is the first member of the genus to occur in the province of Shaanxi.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; &lt;i&gt;Sphaerobulbus&lt;/i&gt;; Palaearctic; taxonomy; new species; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Smetana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on the genus &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt; Stål 1873 (Heteroptera: Aradidae) from China, with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two aradid species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt; from China are recognized. &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kormilevi&lt;/i&gt; Bai, Heiss &amp; Cai is described as new to science. The female of &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bhoutanensis&lt;/i&gt; Usinger &amp; Matsuda 1959 is redescribed. A key to the Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt; is given, and diagnostic morphological features of new species are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Aradidae; Mezirinae; &lt;i&gt;Barcinus&lt;/i&gt;; China; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Heiss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of Semaphore gecko &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Mauretania, represents a 4700km range extension for genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new Semaphore gecko, &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adrarensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Adrar Atar region of central Mauritania. It is most closely related to the geographically nearest member of the genus, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavipunctatus&lt;/i&gt; of northeast Africa and southwest Arabia. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adrarensis&lt;/i&gt; shows an 18% divergence from this species in mitochondrial DNA (cytochrome b) and also differs in being smaller, more depressed and more slender, with the dorsal crest of enlarged scales on the tail not extending forwards beyond the vent. The localities of the new species lie 4700km west of the previously known distribution of &lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt; and the phylogenetic topology of the genus indicates that it represents a westward range extension. The degree of genetic divergence suggests &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adrarensis&lt;/i&gt; separated from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavipunctatus&lt;/i&gt; as much as seven million years ago.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt;; Semaphore gecko; Gekkonidae; range extension; Mauritania; new species; mtDNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pristurus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Geniez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arnold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1316.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1316</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rails (Rallidae: &lt;i&gt;Gallirallus&lt;/i&gt;) from prehistoric archaeological sites in Western Oceania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kirchman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Steadman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to the knowledge of the "Staphylinus-complex" (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae, Staphylinini) of China. Part 11. The genus &lt;i&gt;Wasmannellus&lt;/i&gt; Bernhauer, 1920 and &lt;i&gt;Nelmanwaslus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Wasmannellus&lt;/i&gt; Bernhauer, 1920 is redescribed and reevaluated; its relationship with the relevant genera of Staphylinini is briefly discussed; the appropriate portion of the key to genera in Smetana &amp; Davies (2000) is modified to allow the inclusion of the genus. The genus &lt;i&gt;Nelmanwaslus&lt;/i&gt; is described as new, with &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. as the type species and another included species: &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stevensi&lt;/i&gt; (Cameron, 1932) (comb. nov., from &lt;i&gt;Wasmannellus).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nelmanwaslus&lt;/i&gt; is the genus that was misidentified as &lt;i&gt;Wasmannellus&lt;/i&gt; in Smetana &amp; Davies (2000).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Staphylinidae; Staphylininae; Palaearctic; &lt;i&gt;Wasmannellus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nelmanwaslus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Smetana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt; species (Gastropoda: Helicoidea: Hygromiidae) of the new subgenus &lt;i&gt;Majorata&lt;/i&gt;, both endemic to the Jandía Peninsula (Fuerteventura, Canary Islands)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jandiaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt; (Majorata) &lt;b&gt;subgen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Jandía Peninsula mountains (Fuerteventura Island). The new subgenus, which includes &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jandiaensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutropis,&lt;/i&gt; is characterized mainly by the following synapomorphies: The shell is without hairs and there is a large penial papilla present arising from all the five epiphallar folds. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jandiaensis&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutropis&lt;/i&gt; in the unkeeled, almost globular shell, which is smaller but taller than that of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutropis&lt;/i&gt; and has more numerous but smoother radial ribs. Also, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jandiaensis&lt;/i&gt; has a pseudopapilla in the distal penial cavity instead of the thick longitudinal pilaster present in &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eutropis.&lt;/i&gt; The range of &lt;i&gt;Majorata&lt;/i&gt; is small, declining from 30,000 years ago and the new species should be classified as “Critically Endangered” based on the very small size of its distribution area (smaller than 1 km 2 ) and the very abundant and free-range livestock present. Mainly goats, grazing freely destroy the habitat in the entire Jandía mountains. Protection of their habitat is recommended, mainly by means of strict livestock control.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gastropoda; Hygromiidae; &lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jandiaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Majorata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;subgen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; conservation; Jandía Peninsula; Fuerteventura; Canary Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gastropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alonso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ponte-Lira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Castillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yanes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Groh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ibáñez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Ponsadenia&lt;/i&gt; (Gastropoda: Helicoidea, Bradybaenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three &lt;i&gt;Ponsadenia&lt;/i&gt; species, including &lt;i&gt;Ponsadenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhongdianensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Yunnan, are reported from China. In addition to describing &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhongdianensis,&lt;/i&gt; the genitalia of the two previously known species are re-described and illustrated. The distribution pattern of &lt;i&gt;Ponsadenia&lt;/i&gt; and many other endemic bradybaenid genera suggests that the belt encircling the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau is important in the formation of the bradybaenid diversity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bradybaenidae; &lt;i&gt;Ponsadenia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bradybaenidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1315.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1315</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the catshark genus &lt;i&gt;Holohalaelurus&lt;/i&gt; Fowler 1934 (Chondrichthyes: Carcharhiniformes: Scyliorhinidae), with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper examines the alpha level taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Holohalaelurus&lt;/i&gt; Fowler 1934 (Chondrichthyes: Carcharhiniformes: Scyliorhinidae), which is endemic to southern and east Africa. A novel species identification key is presented for &lt;i&gt;Holohalaelurus,&lt;/i&gt; and a comprehensive review of the taxonomy (including type material and synonyms) and distribution of all taxa is presented. &lt;i&gt;Holohalaelurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regani&lt;/i&gt; (Gilchrist 1922) is restricted to southern Africa and the taxa that occur in tropical east Africa are discrete taxonomic units, resulting in the resurrection of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanostigma&lt;/i&gt; Norman 1939, and two new species, which are described here. &lt;i&gt;Holohalaelurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polystigma&lt;/i&gt; (Regan 1921) is shown to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Gilchrist 1914), the</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Human</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Luidia changi&lt;/i&gt;, a new sea star species (Echinodermata: Asteroidea: Luidiidae) from the Yellow Sea, with a review of two related species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In the collections of the Institute of Oceanology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, a new species, &lt;i&gt;Luidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;changi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. was discovered mixed in with two closely allied species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quinaria&lt;/i&gt; von Martens, 1865 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yesoensis&lt;/i&gt; Goto, 1914. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;changi&lt;/i&gt; is described herein; it differs from the two known species in details of abactinal plates, abactinal spinelets, body proportions, and in geographic distributions of the three species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Yellow Sea; Asteroidea; Luidiidae; &lt;i&gt;Luidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;changi&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Yellow Sea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Liao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1314.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1314</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Aleiodes &lt;/i&gt;Wesmael (Part 8): the &lt;i&gt;coxalis &lt;/i&gt;(Spinola) Species-Group (Hymenoptera: Braconidae, Rogadinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Aleiodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coxalis&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola) species-group is defined as including the following previously described species: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coxalis&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola) 1808, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; (Spinola) 1808, &lt;i&gt;signatus&lt;/i&gt; (Nees) 1812, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alternator&lt;/i&gt; (Nees) 1834, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tristis&lt;/i&gt; Wesmael 1838, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aciculatus&lt;/i&gt; Cresson 1869, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctihyacinthi&lt;/i&gt; (Provancher) 1880, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arcticus&lt;/i&gt; (Thomson) 1891, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incertus&lt;/i&gt; (Kokoujev) 1898, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jakolewi&lt;/i&gt; (Kokoujev) 1898, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coxator&lt;/i&gt; (Telenga) 1941, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incertoides&lt;/i&gt; (Telenga) 1941, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;satanus&lt;/i&gt; (Telenga) 1941, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nunbergi&lt;/i&gt; (Noskiewicz) 1956, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;negativus&lt;/i&gt; (Tobias) 1961, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hellenicus&lt;/i&gt; (Papp) 1985, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moldavicus&lt;/i&gt; (Tobias) 1986, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itamevorus&lt;/i&gt; Shaw and Marsh 2004, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maritimus&lt;/i&gt; Shaw and Marsh 2004. Nine new North American species are described in this paper: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquilonius&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevis&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cultrarius&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dichromatus&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;floridensis&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadratus&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shenefelti&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whartoni&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wyomingensis&lt;/i&gt; NEW SPECIES. The &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coxalis&lt;/i&gt; species group is regarded as monophyletic as distinguished by the rugose vertex and sculptured fourth metasomal tergum. An identification key, descriptions, illustrations, distribution and biological information are provided for thirteen North American species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hymenoptera; Braconidae; Aleiodes; parasitoids; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hymenoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marsh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fortier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Amphimedon&lt;/i&gt; (Porifera, Demospongiae, Haplosclerida, Niphatidae) from the Capricorn-Bunker Group of Islands, Great Barrier Reef, Australia: target species for the sponge genome project</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new niphatid demosponge, &lt;i&gt;Amphimedon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Heron and One Tree Islands, southern Great Barrier Reef, Queensland, Australia. The new species is of particular significance as it is currently the subject of the first sponge genome project. The species is characterized within the globally distributed genus &lt;i&gt;Amphimedon&lt;/i&gt; by its distinctive blue-green colour, and the combination of encrusting-lobate growth form, spongin-rich spiculofibres and feeble spicule size, The new species is compared and contrasted with known or suspected &lt;i&gt;Amphimedon&lt;/i&gt; species of Australia and adjacent territories of Papua New Guinea, New Caledonia and Indonesia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; Demospongiae; Haplosclerida; Niphatidae; &lt;i&gt;Amphimedon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Heron Island; One Tree Island; Capricorn-Bunker Group; Great Barrier Reef; Queensland; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>N. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hooper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Soest</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-39</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt; (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae: Empoascini) from northern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated from Ecuador and Colombia. The species are placed in a previously published key and relationships to other species of the genus are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Empoasca&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Southern</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of three new species of Odonata from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species are described here: &lt;i&gt;Oxyagrion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zielmae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Coenagrionidae) from one male collected at Costa Rica, Mato Grosso do Sul state; &lt;i&gt;Lestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Lestidae) from a pair from Imperatriz, Maranhão state and &lt;i&gt;Perithemis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capixaba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Libellulidae) from one male from Mutum Preto, Espírito Santo state, all deposited at Museu Nacional, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Oxyagrion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zielmae&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavidum&lt;/i&gt; Selys, 1876 but differs by having cerci and paraprocts the same size, pterostigma long and narrow and terminal segment of genital ligula with the two lobes larger than in &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavidum.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; is compared with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auritus&lt;/i&gt; Hagen in Selys, 1862; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bipupillatus&lt;/i&gt; Calvert, 1909; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dichrostigma&lt;/i&gt; Calvert, 1909; &lt;i&gt;Lestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcifer&lt;/i&gt; Sjöstedt, 1918; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficula&lt;/i&gt; Rambur, 1842; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; Selys, 1862 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulistus&lt;/i&gt; Calvert, 1909. The new species is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Lestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falcifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulistus,&lt;/i&gt; but differ by the peculiar color of pterothorax, caudal appendages and genital ligula. &lt;i&gt;Perithemis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capixaba&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mooma&lt;/i&gt; Kirby, 1889 but differs by having the first segment of vesica spermalis slowly rounded, in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mooma&lt;/i&gt; this structure is trapezoidal. Illustrated keys to new species are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Odonata; &lt;i&gt;Lestes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Oxyagrion&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Perithemis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; identification key; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Odonata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>O. I.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Souza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Muzón</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1313.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1313</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Varanus &lt;/i&gt;Merrem (Squamata: Varanidae) from the Pilbara region of Western Australia, with observations on sexual dimorphism in closely related species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Aplin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fitch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>King</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Free-living Platyhelminthes of the Pacaya-Samiria National Reserve, a Peruvian Amazon floodplain</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty-one free-living species of turbellaria (Platyhelminthes) were found in the Pacaya-Samiria National Reserve (Loreto, Peru), a Peruvian Amazon floodplain. The total 21 observed taxa comprise five species of Catenulida, two species of Macrostomida, two species of "Lecithoepitheliata", 10 species of Rhabdocoela and two species of Tricladida. Most of the species are cosmopolitan and occur in freshwater habitats worldwide. Of the species collected, only &lt;i&gt;Mesostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ehrenbergi&lt;/i&gt; was previously known from this region, whereas five species of Rhabdocoela were only recently described from the Pacaya-Samiria Reserve. Some morphological, distributional and ecological remarks are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;“Turbellaria”,&lt;/b&gt; Amazon floodplain; free-living Platyhelminthes; distribution; Peru; Pacaya-Samiria Reserve</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;“Turbellaria”,&lt;/b&gt; Amazon floodplain</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Noreña</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Damborenea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brusa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Escobedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Edotia tangaroa &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Isopoda: Idoteidae) from the western Ross Sea, Antarctica </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Edotia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tangaroa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the western Ross Sea, Antarctica, the first record of the genus from that region. It is characterised by the dorsal ornamentation, consisting of numerous small, blunt tubercular, structures from the head to the tip of pleotelson, as well as short, blunt dorsal spines on basis of pereopods 1–7. Antenna 1 is slightly longer and more robust than antenna 2. An annotated species list is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ross Sea; Southern Ocean; taxonomy; Valvifera; Idoteidae; &lt;i&gt;Edotia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ross Sea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brandt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1312.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1312</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cliona minuscula&lt;/i&gt;, sp. nov. (Hadromerida : Clionaidae) and other bioeroding sponges that only contain tylostyles </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new bioeroding sponge belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Australian Great Barrier Reef, &lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; As the sponge lacked microscleres, comparison with existing clionaid species was difficult. We considered 15 other species of &lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; with only tylostyles: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alderi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenosa.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caesia&lt;/i&gt; nov. comb., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californiana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delitrix,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dissimilis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecaudis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insidiosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janitrix,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kempi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laticavicola,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macgeachii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;millepunctata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peponaca.&lt;/i&gt; Characters of all species are presented in table-form to facilitate comparison during future studies. We listed additional species of &lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; that were not directly compared to the new species, because they were either invalid, insufficiently described, or they may not be obligate bioeroders. The form and dimensions of the megascleres of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; indicated that it is distinct from all considered species. Its mean tylostyle dimensions were 225.3 µm length, 4.5 µm shaft width and 6.8 µm tyle width, which is comparatively small. Because other morphological features were small as well (erosion chambers, papillar diameter), this species was named &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula.&lt;/i&gt; The species record for sponges of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; reported from Australia is now 11.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula&lt;/i&gt;; Porifera; new species; description; taxonomy; faunistics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cliona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schönberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Grass</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heiermann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;i&gt; brethesi&lt;/i&gt; Dyar, 1919 (Diptera: Culicidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt; (Culex) &lt;i&gt;brethesi&lt;/i&gt; Dyar is redescribed in the adult, pupal and fourth-instars larvae and the male genitalia. The paper includes available information on the taxonomy and distribution of the species. The taxonomy and identification of &lt;i&gt;Cx.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brethesi&lt;/i&gt; are reviewed in light of current knowledge of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Culex.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Culicidae; &lt;i&gt;Culex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brethesi&lt;/i&gt;; male; female; larva; pupa; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>Gustavo</middlename>
          <lastname>C.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new American species of &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; (Collembola: Hypogastruridae) and ecological notes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated, &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Cuba and &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Peru. The species &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mangle&lt;/i&gt; (Murphy, 1965) &lt;b&gt;stat.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is revalidated and recombined. &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenosa&lt;/i&gt; (Uchida &amp; Tamura, 1967) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oceanica&lt;/i&gt; (Yosii, 1960) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are transferred from &lt;i&gt;Xenylla.&lt;/i&gt; A key for the 8 species known in the genus is also given and detailed information about the ecology of &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peruensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Collembola; Hypogastruridae; &lt;i&gt;Paraxenylla&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Collembola</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Palacios-Vargas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Janssens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Iberorhyzobius &lt;/i&gt;Raimundo &amp; Canepari gen. nov., for &lt;i&gt;Coccidula rondensis&lt;/i&gt; Eizaguirre (Coleoptera: Coccinellidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of Coccidulinae from the Iberian Peninsula, &lt;i&gt;Iberorhyzobius&lt;/i&gt; Raimundo &amp; Canepari, is described for the species &lt;i&gt;Coccidula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rondensis&lt;/i&gt; Eizaguirre, 2004. Description and illustrations of the adult and larva are presented. Differences between &lt;i&gt;Iberorhyzobius&lt;/i&gt; and other European Coccidulini are discussed. Adults and larvae of this species were collected in maritime pine stands, &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinaster&lt;/i&gt; Aiton. Larvae were found preying upon ovisacs of the pine bast scale &lt;i&gt;Matsucoccus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feytaudi&lt;/i&gt; Ducasse. Both adults and larvae were lured by the sex pheromone of this prey. Our findings support the hypothesis that the new genus is endemic to the Iberian Peninsula.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coccinellidae; Coccidulini; &lt;i&gt;Iberorhyzobius&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Pinus&lt;/i&gt;; Iberian Peninsula; pine bast scale</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coccinellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Raimundo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Canepari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Z.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mendel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Branco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Franco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Acyphus&lt;/i&gt; Heller (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) with comments on infraspecific variation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acyphus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1921 is a monotypic genus of Entiminae, Naupactini, ranging in north-central Argentina, southern Brazil, Paraguay and Uruguay. Its single species is mainly associated to trees of the genus &lt;i&gt;Prosopis&lt;/i&gt; (Leguminosae), with several species ranging throughout the xerophytic forests of the Chacoan subregion. The genus is easily recognized by the presence of 20 elytral striae and the robust antennae, with strongly dilated scape, compressed from near base onwards. &lt;i&gt;Acyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;renggeri&lt;/i&gt; (Labram &amp; Imhoff) -senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Acyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;funicularis&lt;/i&gt; Hellershows variation in the distribution and density of the scaly vestiture of the elytra. There is a morphotype devoid of distinct scales and two squamose morphotypes with different irregular nebulose pattern. The paper includes descriptions of the genus and its only species, habitus photographs, line drawings of genitalia and mouth parts, and a map of distribution.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; weevils; Naupactini; &lt;i&gt;Acyphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;renggeri&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lanteri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Guadalupe</middlename>
          <lastname>Del Rio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1311.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1311</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new bathyal &lt;i&gt;Fusinus&lt;/i&gt; (Mollusca: Gastropoda: Fasciolariidae) from New Caledonia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new bathyal species of &lt;i&gt;Fusinus&lt;/i&gt; is described from New Caledonia. &lt;i&gt;Fusinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laviniae&lt;/i&gt; new species is distinguished from other New Caledonia &lt;i&gt;Fusinus&lt;/i&gt; by its long siphonal canal and angular sculpture. This new species is compared to &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colus&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1758), &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nicobaricus&lt;/i&gt; (Röding, 1798), &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nobilis&lt;/i&gt; (Reeve, 1847), &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salisburyi&lt;/i&gt; Fulton, 1930, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; (Baird, 1873), and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;undatus,&lt;/i&gt; (Gmelin, 1791). A range extension for &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nobilis&lt;/i&gt; to New Caledonia is noted.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gastropoda; Fasciolariidae; &lt;i&gt;Fusinus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; New Caledonia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gastropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Snyder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hadorn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of lady beetles in the &lt;i&gt;Cycloneda germainii&lt;/i&gt; species complex (Coleoptera; Coccinellidae: Coccinellinae: Coccinellini) with descriptions of new and unusual species from Chile and surrounding countries</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A complex of lady beetle species including &lt;i&gt;Cycloneda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;germainii&lt;/i&gt; (Crotch) is reviewed and seven valid species recognized, including &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;germainii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eryngii&lt;/i&gt; (Mulsant), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sicardi&lt;/i&gt; (Brèthes), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviana&lt;/i&gt; (Mulsant), and three new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrimosa&lt;/i&gt; González &amp; Vandenberg, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;disconsolata&lt;/i&gt; Vandenberg &amp; González, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonica&lt;/i&gt; González &amp; Vandenberg, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>González</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vandenberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>13-50</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Proboscis ornamentation as a diagnostic character for the &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californicus-digitatus&lt;/i&gt; complex (Arthropoda: Pycnogonida) with an example from the &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus eroticus &lt;/i&gt;female</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Females of the Indo-Pacific species &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eroticus&lt;/i&gt; (Arthropoda: Pycnogonida: Phoxichilidiidae) are described for the first time. The presence of peculiar ventral outgrowths or protuberances on the female proboscis of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eroticus&lt;/i&gt; and 13 other &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; species motivates an evaluation of a &lt;i&gt;californicus-digitatus&lt;/i&gt; complex, based on external morphology and species distribution. The anatomy and development of proboscis protuberances is assessed using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), Nomarski optics, and flourescence microscopy. External morphology of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eroticus&lt;/i&gt; is compared to that of apparently related species. An identification key for the 14 species of &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; with females bearing a proboscis with ventral protuberances is provided here as an identification tool.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pycnogonida; &lt;i&gt;Anoplodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; proboscis; dimorphism; Indo-Pacific; Phoxichilidiidae; sea spiders</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pycnogonida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arango</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Maxmen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-64</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1310.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1310</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Tetramorium forte&lt;/i&gt; Forel, 1904 (Insecta: Hymenoptera: Formicidae), a western Mediterranean ant species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The western Mediterranean ant species &lt;i&gt;Tetramorium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forte&lt;/i&gt; Forel, 1904 is redescribed and a lectotype is designated. Taxonomic controversy surrounding the application of the name and its synonymy is thereby resolved: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ruginode&lt;/i&gt; Stitz, 1917 (with its junior synonym &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispanicum&lt;/i&gt; Bondroit, 1918), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tingitanum&lt;/i&gt; Santschi, 1929 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maroccanum&lt;/i&gt; De Haro &amp; Collingwood, 1994 are relegated to synonymy with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forte.&lt;/i&gt; Lectotypes are designated for &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispanicum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maurum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tingitanum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maroccanum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silvestrianum&lt;/i&gt; Emery, 1924. The latter taxon, previously regarded as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forte,&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Myrmica&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Güsten</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sanetra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of sepiolid squid from the waters around Tonga in the central South Pacific (Mollusca: Cephalopoda: Sepiolidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Choneteuthis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the waters around Tonga in the central South Pacific Ocean. The new genus does not clearly fit in any of the currently recognized subfamilies of the family Sepiolidae, justifying a reconsideration of the subfamilial subdivision of the family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; Cephalopods; Sepiolidae; taxonomy; new genus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; Cephalopods</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Boucher-Rodoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new &lt;i&gt;Fridericia&lt;/i&gt; species (Oligochaeta: Enchytraeidae) and its molecular comparison with two morphologically similar species by PCR-RFLP</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Fridericia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassiductata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; was described and compared by DNA fragment analyses (PCR-RFLP), with two similar species, &lt;i&gt;Fridericia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ratzeli&lt;/i&gt; (Eisen,1872) sensu Nielsen &amp; Christensen (1959) and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eiseni&lt;/i&gt; Dózsa-Farkas, 2005. The main characteristics of the new species are: 13–20 mm long, 0.5–0.7 mm wide, segment number: (38)–40–56, spermatheca with 9–10 large, sessile, globular diverticula, long and thick ectal duct, and two very large (80–130 µ m long) egg shaped ectal glands. Maximum ten chaetae per bundle, typical brown reticulate epidermal gland cells noticeable on the body surface. The oesophageal appendage is variable between type-a and type-c (according to Möller 1971) the branches are located proximally. The seminal vesicle is large, the penial slit is longitudinal with more transverse components. Three subneural glands in XIV–XVI. The new species was collected only in the Zemplén Mountains in Hungary, in similar biotopes (between and under the leaf-litter) to those of the common &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ratzeli.&lt;/i&gt; It may be hypothesized that it fills the ecological role of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ratzeli&lt;/i&gt; because, although all three compared species occurred in this area, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ratzeli&lt;/i&gt; was very seldom found and never together with the new species. The three species were also examined by molecular methods. Which confirmed the existence of three distinct species. Both morphological and molecular studies indicate that &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ratzeli&lt;/i&gt; is still not a homogeneous species. It seems that the applied molecular methods help distinguish morphologically very similar species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oligochaeta; Enchytraeidae; new &lt;i&gt;Fridericia&lt;/i&gt; species; ITS; PCR-RFLP</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oligochaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Dózsa-Farkas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cech</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1309.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1309</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Camerobia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neophyllobius&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Prostigmata: Camerobiidae) from Australia, with the descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We review the mites of the genera &lt;i&gt;Camerobia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Neophyllobius&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Prostigmata: Camerobiidae) from Australia and propose two new species, &lt;i&gt;Neophyllobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;variegata&lt;/i&gt; from soil under rocks in The Northern Territory, and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;womersleyi&lt;/i&gt; from under bark in Adelaide, South Australia. Two known species, &lt;i&gt;Camerobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; Southcott and &lt;i&gt;Neophyllobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; Womersley, are redescribed and new data are provided. A key to the described species of Camerobiidae known from Australia and an updated list of &lt;i&gt;Neophyllobius&lt;/i&gt; species described since 1991 are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Raphignathoidea; systematics; taxonomic key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Raphignathoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Q.-H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Walter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species in the &lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;candens&lt;/i&gt; (Panzer, 1793) species-group from Iran and Turkey, with taxonomic notes on the group (Coleoptera: Buprestidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species in the &lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt; (Anthaxia) &lt;i&gt;candens&lt;/i&gt; (Panzer, 1793) species-group: &lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt; (Anthaxia) &lt;i&gt;jenisi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; from southern Iran and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (A.) &lt;i&gt;pyrosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; from eastern Turkey, are described, illustrated and compared with related species. &lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urens&lt;/i&gt; Abeille de Perrin, 1882 is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucens&lt;/i&gt; Küster, 1852 and is treated as a wellcharacterized subspecies. A key to the species of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candens&lt;/i&gt; species-group is provided and short comments on the taxonomic history, distribution and bionomy of the group are given</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coleoptera; Buprestidae; &lt;i&gt;Anthaxia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Palaearctic Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bílý</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new Asian Scaphytopiini leafhoppers (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Deltocephalinae) with description of a new genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The following new leafhopper taxa of the deltocephaline tribe Scaphytopiini are described: &lt;i&gt;Grammacephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcatus&lt;/i&gt; Dai &amp; Zhang &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from China, and &lt;i&gt;Sikhamani&lt;/i&gt; Viraktamath &amp; Webb &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; with type species &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delicatula&lt;/i&gt; Viraktamath &amp; Webb &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Nepal and China. Detailed morphological descriptions and illustrations of the new species are given and a checklist to the species of &lt;i&gt;Grammacephalus&lt;/i&gt; Haupt is provided. The type specimens are deposited in the Entomological Museum of Northwest A&amp;F University, The Natural History Museum, London, the B.P. Bishop Museum, Hawaii, U.S.A. and the University of Agricultural Sciences, Bangalore, India.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Cicadellidae; Deltocephalinae; &lt;i&gt;Grammacephalus;&lt;/i&gt; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Cicadellidae; Deltocephalinae; &lt;i&gt;Grammacephalus;&lt;/i&gt; new species; China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Dai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Viraktamath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Webb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes manihine &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new pontoniine shrimp of the &lt;i&gt;P. alcocki&lt;/i&gt; species group (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of pontoniine shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manihine,&lt;/i&gt; is described and illustrated. It is a member of the little known deep-water &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alcocki&lt;/i&gt; species group. Collected from Kenyan waters, from about 250 m, it is the shallowest depth from which species of this group have been recorded.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manihine&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Kenya; Indian Ocean; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Hylidae: Phyllomedusinae) from northwestern Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarsius&lt;/i&gt; group (Anura: Hylidae: Phyllomedusinae) from northwestern Venezuela can be differentiated from other species in the group by its small size, white and pink bars on the concealed surfaces of legs, and distinctive mating call; it is known only from xeric areas in the vicinity of Serranía de San Luis, Estado Falcón, Venezuela. The call is described, and some natural history data is also provided. The &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarsius&lt;/i&gt; group includes five species and is defined by morphological characters (with one putative synapomorphy).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Hylidae; &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tarsius&lt;/i&gt; group; Falcón state; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrio-Amorós</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1308.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1308</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the species of Ardistomina (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Clivinini) in America north of Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bousquet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllodesmium rudmani&lt;/i&gt; (Mollusca: Nudibranchia: Aeolidoidea), a new solar powered species from the Indo-West Pacific with data on its symbiosis with zooxanthellae </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Phyllodesmium&lt;/i&gt; species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudmani&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described from North Sulawesi, Indonesia and from Luzon Island, the Philippines. The new species is associated with the octocoral &lt;i&gt;Xenia&lt;/i&gt; sp. Its external morphology is similar to other &lt;i&gt;Xenia&lt;/i&gt; associated &lt;i&gt;Phyllodesmium&lt;/i&gt; species, except the unique morphology of the cerata, that mimic closed polyps of &lt;i&gt;Xenia.&lt;/i&gt; The digestive glandular branching system within the cerata is similar to that of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jakobsenae&lt;/i&gt; Burghardt &amp; Wägele, 2004, a species that was found associated with the same species of &lt;i&gt;Xenia&lt;/i&gt; and at the same locality in Indonesia as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudmani.&lt;/i&gt; The masticatory border of the jaw with a few large denticles is similar to several other species of &lt;i&gt;Phyllodemium&lt;/i&gt; that feed on &lt;i&gt;Xenia,&lt;/i&gt; as are the radular teeth with numerous small denticles. The lobate receptaculum seminis is similar to that described for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnum&lt;/i&gt; Rudman, 1991, whereas the remaining species have a smooth pyriform receptaculum. Behavioural notes of the new species are given and active photosynthesis due to zooxanthellae (Dinophyceae of the genus &lt;i&gt;Symbiodinium)&lt;/i&gt; in the digestive gland was measured &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; with a Diving-PAM (Pulse Amplitude Modulated Fluorometer). Experiments with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudmani&lt;/i&gt; indicate a symbiotic relationship with zooxanthellae, at least for three weeks. These results are compared to the ones of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jakobsenae.&lt;/i&gt; Histological investigation of the cerata of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rudmani&lt;/i&gt; suggests relatively high efficiency of the symbiosis for the new species because of the high grade of branching of the digestive gland.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllodesmium&lt;/i&gt;; symbiosis; solar powered; zooxanthellae ; &lt;i&gt;Symbiodinium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Xenia&lt;/i&gt;; photosynthesis; Diving-PAM</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllodesmium&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Burghardt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gosliner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Chaunus dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; (Duméril &amp; Bibron) (Anura, Bufonidae).</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae&lt;/i&gt; are the southernmost taxa of the &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; species group (formerly &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group). The biology of these species has been scarcely studied. In this sense, larval external morphology of &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; is described for the first time and compared with other species of the &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group, particularly with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae.&lt;/i&gt; The tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; at stages 31–35 are about 15 mm, and belong to the benthic ecomorphological guild. They have a depressed body, a slightly truncated snout, and the spiracle is placed on the posterior third of the body. The tail axis is straight, the dorsal fin begins at tail-body junction and ends broadly rounded. The vent tube is medial, it starts at midline and opens usually to the right, but in some specimens it opens to the left. The oral disc has a single row of marginal papillae, large dorsal gap, medium-sized ventral gap, and labial tooth row formula 2(2)/2. A multivariate analysis of morphometric variables provided differentiation from tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae,&lt;/i&gt; based on interorbital, eye-nostril and fronto-nasal distances, body maximum height and width, and dorsal gap length. However, the general aspect of both species is quite similar, and comparable to the tadpole of a related species, &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaeus.&lt;/i&gt; Other known tadpoles of the &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group are those of &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beebei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Chaunus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major,&lt;/i&gt; which differ from the above mentioned species in having a more depressed snout and body, and labial tooth row formula 2(2)/3. The observed variability in the vent tube opening of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorbignyi&lt;/i&gt; (and also in &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae)&lt;/i&gt; seems to depend on how the beginning of the ventral fin is folded, which is attached to the tube. This fact may have lead to different interpretations of vent tube configuration in the &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group, and must be taken into account in between-species comparisons.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bufo;&lt;/i&gt; larval morphology; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bufo;&lt;/i&gt; larval morphology; &lt;i&gt;granulosus&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Borteiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolenc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tedros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Prigioni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Euros &lt;/i&gt;Hy. Edwards (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae: Apameiini) with description of one new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Nearctic members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Euros&lt;/i&gt; Hy. Edwards, 1881 are revised to include three species, with &lt;i&gt;Euros&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osticollis&lt;/i&gt; described as new. The adults and male genitalia are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euros&lt;/i&gt;; new species; California; Oregon</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Euros&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Troubridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1307.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Sep. 2006</title>
    <volume>1307</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Bostrichidae (Coleoptera) of Taiwan: a key to species, new records, and a lectotype designation for &lt;i&gt;Sinoxylon mangiferae &lt;/i&gt;Chujo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A key to the species of Bostrichidae from Taiwan is provided. Twelve species are recorded from Taiwan for the first time. Twenty-one species are believed to be established in Taiwan. A further seven species are recorded, but are not definitely known to be established. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Sinoxylon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mangiferae&lt;/i&gt; Chujo.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bostrichidae; Bostrichinae; Dinoderinae; Lyctinae; key; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bostrichidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beaver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Canopyana vateriae&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. and sp. nov.A leafhopper breeding on &lt;i&gt;Vateria indica&lt;/i&gt; and a new record of &lt;i&gt;Bhatia distanti&lt;/i&gt; (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Selenocephalinae) from south India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Canopyana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Canopyana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vateriae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; as type species is described and illustrated. The new species was collected on &lt;i&gt;Vateria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indica&lt;/i&gt; L. (Dipterocarpaceae) while canopy was being sampled in Karnataka. The new genus is similar to &lt;i&gt;Kutara&lt;/i&gt; Distant but differs in differently placed antennal bases, shape of the head and the male genitalia. &lt;i&gt;Bhatia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distanti&lt;/i&gt; Zhang and Webb previously known only from Sri Lanka is recorded for the first time from Western Ghats of India.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cicadellidae; Selenocephalinae; Canopy sampling; &lt;i&gt;Canopyana&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cicadellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Viraktamath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Srinivasa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-39</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Napaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lajaensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Gastropoda: Pulmonata: Enidae) from a Quaternary Aeolian Deposit of Northeast Tenerife, Canary Islands </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Napaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lajaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the oldest &lt;i&gt;Napaeus&lt;/i&gt; species found in the Canary Islands, with more than 130 ka. It is described from a Pleistocene aeolian deposit intercalated between two basaltic lava flows located at Mancha de La Laja (Tenerife Island). The new species is characterized mainly by the presence of two very prominent, spiral, semicylindrical ribs on the body whorl shell. The stratigraphic setting and taphonomic features of the land snail association to which &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lajaensis&lt;/i&gt; belongs, were also shown.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gastropoda; &lt;i&gt;Napaeus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Pleistocene; Canary Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gastropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Castillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yanes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alonso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ibáñez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Kamimuria&lt;/i&gt; (Plecoptera, Perlidae) from the Russian Far East</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Kamimuria,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lyubaretzi&lt;/i&gt; (Plecoptera, Perlidae) from the Russian Far East is described and illustrated for the first time. The description includes all life stages and both sexes. Distributional data are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Plecoptera; Perlidae; &lt;i&gt;Kamimuria&lt;/i&gt;; Russian Far East; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Plecoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Teslenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tonsilla&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Amaurobiidae) from mountains of Sichuan, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Coelotinae from mountains of Sichuan, China, &lt;i&gt;Tonsilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;defossa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated. The new species can be distinguished from other &lt;i&gt;Tonsilla&lt;/i&gt; species by the thick patellar apophysis and the fishtail-shaped conductor in male, and by the strongly reduced atrium and the hidden spermathecal heads in female.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coelotinae; epigynum; pedipalpus; biodiversity hotspots</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-09-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
