<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1369.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1369</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus &lt;/i&gt;Sharp and &lt;i&gt;Derallus &lt;/i&gt;Sharp of North America, Central America, and the Caribbean (Coleoptera: Hydrophilidae: Berosini) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of the New World genera &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus&lt;/i&gt; Sharp and &lt;i&gt;Derallus&lt;/i&gt; Sharp that occur outside continental South America are reviewed; three and five species are recorded respectively. &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;selva&lt;/i&gt; Short, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Costa Rica. &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toxillus&lt;/i&gt; d’Orchymont is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exilis&lt;/i&gt; (LeConte). A key to the genera of Berosini and the species of &lt;i&gt;Derallus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus&lt;/i&gt; occurring outside South America is presented with diagnostic features illustrated. New locality records are provided for all species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydrophilidae; Berosini; &lt;i&gt;Derallus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hemiosus&lt;/i&gt;; Central America; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>Ed. Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Short</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Torres</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of Cnemaspis (Sauria: Gekkonidae) from Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ranwellai&lt;/i&gt; is described from Gannoruwa in the Central Province of Sri Lanka. This species differs from all other &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; species by having 12–15 femoral pores and having spine-like tubercles on the body and tail. Males have a distinct yellow colour in the throat area. It is similar to &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jerdoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scalepensis&lt;/i&gt; Ferguson, 1877, but differs from the former by having spine-like tubercles in the tail, a fewer number of ventral scales at mid ventral region, presence of dorsal tubercles in the mid body area and by having completely different colour patterns in the throat and dorsal neck region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sri Lanka; &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;; Gannoruwa; &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ranwellai&lt;/i&gt;; New species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sri Lanka</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wickramasinghe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-33</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura &lt;/i&gt;from East China (Collembola: Onychiuridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new onychiurid species, &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;qixiaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is reported from Jiangsu Province of East China. Morphologically, it is very similar to the widely-spread and definitely parthenogenetic species &lt;i&gt;Th.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;encarpata&lt;/i&gt; (Denis, 1931). The new species is gamogenetic and differs from the latter in labial palp and proximal setae. A key to the Chinese species of the genus is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Collembola; Onychiuridae; &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;qixiaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Collembola</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>X.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-41</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella cearense &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. from sandstone reefs off Fortaleza (Ceara State, Brazil) (Desmacellidae, Mycalina, Poecilosclerida, Demospongiae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cearense&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described here on the basis of a single specimen collected in 2004 at Parque Estadual Marinho da Pedra da Risca do Meio, off Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil. This is the first record of &lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella&lt;/i&gt; for the Atlantic Ocean. The new species differs from the other eleven &lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella&lt;/i&gt; species by the absence of raphides/microxea, and is the only species with a single category of styles as megascleres (mean length 435µm, mean width 12µm), and sigmas (mean length 21µm). The new species appears to be closer to Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella,&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of overall spicule morphology (mainly dimensions and categories of megascleres). This could be suggestive of a transpacific track for the colonization of the South Atlantic, instead of the shorter Agulhas track.Key words: &lt;i&gt;Sigmaxinella,&lt;/i&gt; taxonomy, Parque Estadual da Pedra da Risca do Meio, sponge, new species, sandstone reef, Brazil</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Salani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. D. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lotufo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajdu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lopharcha moriutii&lt;/i&gt;, sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Polylopha cassiicola &lt;/i&gt;Liu &amp; Kawabe (Lepidoptera, Tortricidae, Chlidanotinae, Polyorthini) from Thailand and Hong Kong</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lopharcha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moriutii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Thailand and Hong Kong; the genus is recorded from China for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Polylopha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cassiicola&lt;/i&gt; is recorded from Hong Kong. Adults and genitalia are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Oriental fauna; Southeast Asia; China; genitalia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nasu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tardigrada nova: a bibliographic analysis and catalogue of new species described in Zootaxa before 2006</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During 2002 to 2005, 35 papers on Tardigrada were published in &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt; by 22 authors from nine countries with descriptions of 33 new species. A bibliographic analysis of these papers is presented here along with a catalogue of new species of Tardigrada described in these papers.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; biodiversity discovery; species description; historical pattern; zoological nomenclature; dating</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Z.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1368.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1368</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sensiava longiseta &lt;/i&gt;(Copepoda, Calanoida): a new genus and species from the abyss of the Weddell Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sensiava&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longiseta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from male specimens collected at abyssal depths above the seabed in the Weddell Sea (Southern Ocean). Segmentation and setation of the swimming legs of the new species are typical of the superfamily Clausocalanoidea. Although the new genus shares the presence of sensory setae on the maxilla with the Bradfordian families of the Clausocalanoidea, it does not fit the diagnosis of any of these families. &lt;i&gt;Sensiava&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longiseta&lt;/i&gt; shares with the ancestral group of Bradfordian genera a 1,2,3 setal pattern on the praecoxal endites of the maxilliped and, therefore is provisionally placed within Diaixidae. &lt;i&gt;Sensiava&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longiseta&lt;/i&gt; shows marked asymmetry in the antennule; the right limb is geniculated with ancestral segments XIX–XXIII morphologically modified. The presence of this well pronounced, geniculated antennule is up to now the most striking example of this feature and regarded as an ancestral character in the advanced superfamily Clausocalanoidea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Calanoida; &lt;i&gt;Sensiava&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; benthopelagic; Weddell Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Markhaseva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Schulz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of mites in the genera &lt;i&gt;Uropoda&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Crinitodiscus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Uroobovella&lt;/i&gt; from Turkey (Acari: Mesostigmata: Uropodidae, Urodinychidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new mite species of the cohort Uropodina, &lt;i&gt;Uropoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Crinitodiscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ayyildizi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Uroobovella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated on the basis of specimens collected from Turkey. &lt;i&gt;Uropoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Crinitodiscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ayyildizi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Uropodidae) were collected from the Eastern Black Sea Region, and &lt;i&gt;Uroobovella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; was collected from Eastern Anatolia. All new species presented here are endemic, and have not been collected from any other regions or habitats in Turkey. Adults and deutonymphs of &lt;i&gt;Uropoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Crinitodiscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ayyildizi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and adults of &lt;i&gt;Uroobovella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described, and ecological information for the new species is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; Acari; Uropodina; &lt;i&gt;Uropoda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Uroobovella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Crinitodiscus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brasilaccoderus&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Eurypinae (Coleoptera: Mycteridae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Brazilian genus &lt;i&gt;Brasilaccoderus&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed and described as new, comprising &lt;i&gt;Brasilaccoderus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scaber&lt;/i&gt; (Champion), &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plaumanni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species.&lt;/b&gt; Important characters are illustrated, and habitus photographs and a key to species are provided. Some preliminary thoughts on a phylogenetic placement of the new genus are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Mycteridae; Eurypinae; Brazil; new genus; new species; classification</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pollock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rivulus kayapo &lt;/i&gt;n. sp.&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cyprinodontiformes: Rivulidae): a new killifish from the serra dos Caiapos, upper rio Araguaia basin, Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kayapo,&lt;/i&gt; new species, a member of the &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; species group from the rio Caiapó drainage, upper rio Araguaia basin, is described. It is similar to &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinima&lt;/i&gt; by the absence of bars on the caudal fin and flank in both sexes, in having longitudinal rows of red dots along the entire flanks in both sexes, and in having longitudinally elongated white mark above the caudal spot in females. &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kayapo&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinima&lt;/i&gt; in having more caudal-fin rays, the dorsal-fin origin more posteriorly placed, and fewer scales in the longitudinal and transverse series; and differs from all congeners of the &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; species group by possessing a unique reticulate color pattern on the flanks in males. A key for identification of species of &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; from the rio Araguaia-Tocantins basin is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Killifish; Cyprinodontiformes; Rivulidae; &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt;; rio Araguaia; systematics; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Killifish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. E. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; from Mindoro Island, Philippines: &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris distincta &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Parastenocarididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of harpacticoid, &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distincta&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described and discussed. The new species was collected in a freshwater interstitial habitat near the mouth of a river in Western Mindoro Province, the Philippines. This is the second species of &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt; described from this country. The medial ornamentation of P1 basis, the morphology of male P3 and the number and distribution of the integumental pores in the new species differ from those previously reported in other species of &lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris.&lt;/i&gt; We review and discuss the more common arrangements of these features in recently described species, emphasizing the taxonomic discriminative value of their variations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt;; Philippines; interstitial habitat; Harpacticoida; groundwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parastenocaris&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cottarelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Berera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1367.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1367</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; Curtis, with distributional records, and taxonomic and biological notes for Agrilinae and Trachyinae (Coleoptera: Buprestidae) of Mexico and Central America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper treats 225 species of Buprestidae in the genera &lt;i&gt;Agrilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Brachys,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Callimicra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cyphothorax,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dismorpha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hylaeogena,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leiopleura,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Omochyseus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachyschelus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paragrilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Taphrocerus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Trypantius.&lt;/i&gt; New country records are recorded for Mexico and all Central American countries. &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vandenberghei&lt;/i&gt; Westcott and Hespenheide, new species, from Central America and Mexico, and the male of &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eyai&lt;/i&gt; Westcott and Noguera are described and figured. Rational is provided for changing &lt;i&gt;Agrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurilatera&lt;/i&gt; Waterhouse to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurilaterus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catherinae&lt;/i&gt; Chevrolat is shown to be a justified emendation of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catharinae;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;complexus&lt;/i&gt; (Waterhouse) is a new combination; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;consobrinus&lt;/i&gt; Dugès is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;correctus&lt;/i&gt; Thompson.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Buprestidae; Agrilinae; Mexico; Central America; distribution; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Buprestidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Westcott</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hespenheide</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Picicola &lt;/i&gt;Clay and Meinertzhagen (Phthiraptera: Philopteridae) from jacamars and puffbirds (Piciformes: Galbulidae, Bucconidae), with descriptions of five new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The three species of previously named &lt;i&gt;Picicola&lt;/i&gt; Clay and Meinertzhagen from jacamars and puffbirds are redescribed and five new species are described and illustrated. These new species and their type hosts are: &lt;i&gt;Picicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valquii&lt;/i&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Notharchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tectus&lt;/i&gt; (Boddaert), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;naokii&lt;/i&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Bucco&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capensis&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osheai&lt;/i&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Malacoptila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusca&lt;/i&gt; (J.F. Gmelin), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;faucetti&lt;/i&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Chelidoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenebrosa&lt;/i&gt; (Pallas), and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oneilli&lt;/i&gt; ex &lt;i&gt;Notharchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrorhynchos&lt;/i&gt; (J.F. Gmelin). We collected partial cytochrome oxidase I (COI) sequences for all of the species in this group, and these data support the genetic distinctiveness of these new species. A key is provided for the identification of all eight species of &lt;i&gt;Picicola&lt;/i&gt; from jacamars and puffbirds.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">chewing lice; phylogeny; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">chewing lice</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Price</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Weckstein</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-50</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Associations, new records, and a new species of &lt;i&gt;Atopsyche&lt;/i&gt; from northwestern Argentina and southern Bolivia (Trichoptera: Hydrobiosidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larva, pupa, and the adult male of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Atopsyche&lt;/i&gt; (Trichoptera: Hydrobiosidae) from northwestern Argentina and southern Bolivia are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Atopsyche&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Atopsaura)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunguensis&lt;/i&gt; new species, is close to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Atopsaura)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobosa&lt;/i&gt; Ross and King 1952 and &lt;i&gt;A.(Atopsaura)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; Navás 1930. In the new species the parapods are large, broadened at the tip, and dorsally curved toward the midline, the apical segment of the inferior appendages is curved toward the midline, and the phallotheca bears a dorsal bilobed lobe with lateral spines. Preimaginal stages of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;callosa&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated and represent new records from Bolivia. In addition, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Atopsyche) &lt;i&gt;kamesa&lt;/i&gt; is newly recorded from Argentina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Hydrobiosidae; &lt;i&gt;Atopsyche&lt;/i&gt;; new species; associations</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>A. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of the genus&lt;i&gt; Euepedanus&lt;/i&gt; from China, with the description of a new species (Opiliones: Laniatores: Epedanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The opilionid genus &lt;i&gt;Euepedanus&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time from China and a new species, named &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., is described and illustrated from specimens collected in the Diaoluo Nature Reserve on Hainan Island, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Epedaninae; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.-S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.-G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1366.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1366</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the Malagasy &lt;i&gt;Pachypanchax &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cyprinodontiformes, Aplocheilidae), with descriptions of four new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loiselle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Scolymia cubensis&lt;/i&gt; in Brazil: revising the problem of the Caribbean solitary mussids</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Identification of scleractinian corals is traditionally based upon morphological analysis of skeleton traits. However, due to the influence of the environment on coral development, and the pattern highly variable of most diagnostical characters, additional information related to anatomy of soft parts, reproductive behavior and ecological interactions have been argued to support the distinction among similar morphotypes. Caribbean and South Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Scolymia&lt;/i&gt; comprise a small group of solitary zooxanthellate corals: &lt;i&gt;Scolymia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacera,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wellsii&lt;/i&gt; have been far subject of taxonomical misunderstandings. Aggressive interactions bewteen &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacera&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubensis&lt;/i&gt; were useful to validate their specific status. Nevertheless, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wellsii&lt;/i&gt; has been erroneously suggested to be synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubensis.&lt;/i&gt; Following Laborel, Lang and Wells’ studies, we reinforce the individuality of the Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Scolymia&lt;/i&gt; species, confirming the occurrence of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubensis&lt;/i&gt; to Brazil. Supporting newly-reported occurrences of Caribbean species along the Brazilian littoral, this finding is likely to contribute with a new perspective to assess the ‘variability’ among scleractinian corals. A key for the identification of the &lt;i&gt;Scolymia&lt;/i&gt; species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scleractinia; Mussidae; &lt;i&gt;Scolymia&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; South Atlantic; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scleractinia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Neves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Johnsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sampaio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pichon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Neoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Phytoseiidae) from the Macaronesian Region, Canary Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of mesostigmatid mite, &lt;i&gt;Neoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferraguti&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. collected from soil, litter and lichens of natural ecosystems on Tenerife island, Canary Islands is described. &lt;i&gt;Neoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferraguti&lt;/i&gt; has two pairs of setae on the sternal shield, four pairs of preanal setae and two distinct pointed macrosetae on genu and basitarsus IV, macroseta on tibia IV slightly longer than other setae. A key for females of &lt;i&gt;Neoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; species in the Canary Islands is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Mesostigmata; &lt;i&gt;Neoseiulella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferraguti&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; Canary Islands; Tenerife; Spain</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moraza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Estévez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Sinothomisus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. with a new species from Yunnan Province, China (Araneae, Thomisidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper reports a new thomisid spider genus &lt;i&gt;Sinothomisus&lt;/i&gt; with type species, &lt;i&gt;Sinothomisus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., from Gaoligong Mountains, Yunnan Province, China. Photos of bodies, SEM photos of male palpal organ, illustrations of copulatory organs and the detailed morphological characteristics are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; crab spider; new genus; Gaoligong Mountains</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.-M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Griswold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.-J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Peng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1365.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1365</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crangonyx islandicus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a subterranean freshwater amphipod (Crustacea, Amphipoda, Crangonyctidae) from springs in lava fields in Iceland </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Crustacea, Amphipoda, Crangonyctidae) is described from Iceland. This is the second species of freshwater, subterranean, gammaridean amphipods found in Iceland and the first species of the family Crangonyctidae. &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;islandicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from other species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt; by combination of the following characters: the number of spines on the outer and inner lobes of the maxillipedal palp, the presence of a spine at the base of the unguis of the dactylus of gnathopods 1 and 2, stout and short uropod 3, and by a short and wide telson. The species was recorded in South, Southwest, West and Northeast Iceland from numerous springs emerging from relatively young (&lt;10 000 years), porous lavas. The species has apparently survived Pliocene and Pleistocene glaciations in groundwater of porous lava fields and may have persisted in Iceland for several million years.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Crangonyx&lt;/i&gt;; Crangonyctidae; Crangonyctoidea; Iceland; glaciations; subterranean; groundwater; subarctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Svavarsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kristjánsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Aulacid wasps (Hymenoptera: Aulacidae) of New Guinea, with descriptions of five new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The little known aulacid fauna of New Guinea comprises six geographically isolated, endemic species. Previously known from a single species, &lt;i&gt;Aulacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pterostigmatus&lt;/i&gt; (Szépligeti), three new species of &lt;i&gt;Aulacus&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enarotadi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedlaceki&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wau.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, &lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus&lt;/i&gt; is recorded from New Guinea for the first time with the descriptions of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kiunga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laloki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A key to the New Guinea species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Evanioidea; &lt;i&gt;Aulacus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristaulacus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; parasitic wasps</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Evanioidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jennings</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Austin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on Acanthoderini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae) described by Ernst Fuchs, now in the Herbert Schmid Collection, Vienna, Austria</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A study of the species of the tribe Acanthoderini (Coleoptera, Cerambycidae, Lamiinae) described by Ernst Fuchs and deposited in the Herbert Schmid private collection is presented. Four new synonyms are established: &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Psapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvistriatus&lt;/i&gt; Tippmann, 1960 = &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Psapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griseofasciata&lt;/i&gt; Fuchs, 1958; &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Psapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; Fuchs, 1958 = &lt;i&gt;Idiomerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;difficilis&lt;/i&gt; Melzer, 1934; &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Psapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexmaculatus&lt;/i&gt; Fuchs, 1961 = &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schmithi&lt;/i&gt; Melzer, 1935; and &lt;i&gt;Sorelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cervina&lt;/i&gt; Lane, 1965 = &lt;i&gt;Oreodera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferruginea&lt;/i&gt; Fuchs, 1964. Two new combinations are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Oreodera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hassenteufeli&lt;/i&gt; (Fuchs, 1958) from &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Pasapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sorelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferruginea&lt;/i&gt; (Fuchs, 1964) from &lt;i&gt;Oreodera.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Acanthoderes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Psapharochrus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virescens&lt;/i&gt; Fuchs, 1962 is transferred to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Scythropopsis&lt;/i&gt; Thomson, 1864. Notes on the type-material and the geographical distribution are added for each species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acanthoderini; Cerambycidae; Coleoptera; Ernst Fuchs; Lamiinae; new combinations; synonyms; transferences</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acanthoderini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Monné</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Monné</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;the genus &lt;i&gt;Coelotes&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Amaurobiidae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new Coelotinae species are reported: &lt;i&gt;Coelotes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capacilimbus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conversus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov., &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indistinctus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;introhamatus&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. A detailed description and illustrations of each new species are presented and differences with related species are discussed. A distribution map of all four new species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Coelotinae; epigynum; pedipalpus; spider</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; (Monogenoidea, Platyhelminthes) from the gills of Southern Atlantic marine catfishes (Siluriformes, Ariidae) of the Neotropical region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; Bychowsky &amp; Nagibina, 1969 (Dactylogyridae: Ancyrocephalinae) are described from the gills of marine catfishes from the Southwestern Atlantic: &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropicalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Aspistor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luniscutis&lt;/i&gt; (Valenciennes, 1840), and &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boegeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Genidens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbus&lt;/i&gt; (Lacepède, 1803) and &lt;i&gt;Genidens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genidens&lt;/i&gt; (Cuvier, 1829). This is the first report of species of &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; in the Atlantic waters and the Neotropical region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Monogenoidea; Dactylogyridae; Ancyrocephalinae; &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neotropicalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chauhanellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boegeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; Siluriformes; &lt;i&gt;Aspistor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luniscutis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Genidens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barbus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Genidens&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genidens.&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Monogenoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Domingues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fehlauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1364.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1364</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Caridea (Crustacea, Decapoda) collected on the Brazilian (13&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;/22&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;S) continental shelf and slope</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The REVIZEE (Survey of the live resources from the Economic Exclusive Zone) Program collected 158 benthic samples, in Brazilian continental shelf and slope, in latitudes ranging from 13 o 00´S to 22 o 30´S, and depths ranging from 50 to 500m. In these samples, ten caridean species, distributed in six families were identified: &lt;i&gt;Latreutes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fucorum&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1798), &lt;i&gt;Trachycaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;restricta&lt;/i&gt; (A. Milne Edwards, 1878) (Hippolytidae); &lt;i&gt;Anchistioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antiguensis&lt;/i&gt; (Schmitt, 1924) (Anchistioitidae); &lt;i&gt;Brachycarpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biunguiculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Lucas, 1849), &lt;i&gt;Leander&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Say, 1818) (Palaemonidae, subfamily Palaemoninae); &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bermudensis&lt;/i&gt; (Armstrong, 1940), &lt;i&gt;Pontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manningi&lt;/i&gt; Fransen, 2000 (Palaemonidae, subfamily Pontoniinae); &lt;i&gt;Leptochela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratorbita&lt;/i&gt; Bate, 1888 (Pasiphaeidae); &lt;i&gt;Processa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; Christoffersen, 1979 (Processidae) and &lt;i&gt;Pseudocheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; Kensley, 1983 (Bresiliidae). Nine of these species are herein redescribed and compared with data from the literature. Of these, &lt;i&gt;Pseudocheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; is a new record for the Brazilian coast. &lt;i&gt;Anchistioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antiguensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manningi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratorbita&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; had their latitudinal distribution expanded to the study area.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; Brazil; continental shelf; slope</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cardoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Xysticus&lt;/i&gt; C. L. Koch from Turkey (Araneae: Thomisidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Xysticus&lt;/i&gt; C. L. Koch, 1835 is described from Turkey. Differences between the new species and related species are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Araneae; Thomisidae; new species; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Demir</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Topcu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Turkes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-49</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Idaea&lt;/i&gt; Treitschke and the female of &lt;i&gt;Scopula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vojnitsi&lt;/i&gt; Inoue (Lepidoptera: Geometridae, Sterrhinae) from the Russian Far East</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Idaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;khankaensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and the female of &lt;i&gt;Scopula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vojnitsi&lt;/i&gt; Inoue from Primorsk Territory (southern Russian Far East) are described and illustrated. The taxonomic positions of both species are discussed briefly.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Geometridae; Sterrhinae; new species; female description; Russian Far East</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beljaev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agelanius burgeri,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of horse fly from south Chile (Diptera: Tabanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The female and male of &lt;i&gt;Agelanius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burgeri,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from Nueva Imperial, Cautín Province, Chile are described and illustrated. Its relationship to other &lt;i&gt;Agelanius&lt;/i&gt; species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agelanius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burgeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; Tabanidae; Diachlorini; Neotropical Region; Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agelanius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burgeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; Tabanidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>González</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Corrections to "&lt;i&gt;A checklist of the butterflies of Melanesia, Micronesia, Polynesia and some adjacent areas&lt;/i&gt;" published in &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 1178 (2006)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tennent</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-66</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic notes on the genus &lt;i&gt;Gonycentrum&lt;/i&gt; Bergroth (Hemiptera: Tingidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1363.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1363</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the North Atlantic amphipod genus &lt;i&gt;Normanion &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Amphipoda: Lysianassoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Members of the lysianassoid genus &lt;i&gt;Normanion&lt;/i&gt; have previously been difficult to identify, due to uncertainty regarding synonymies and validity among members of the taxon. Here, the genus is reviewed and a full description with illustrations is provided for the four eyed-species. Species are compared and synonymies are resolved.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Normanion&lt;/i&gt;; Amphipoda; Lysianassoidea; Northeast Atlantic; Mediterranean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Normanion&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kilgallen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Myers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mcgrath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the systematics of the genus &lt;i&gt;Bradypodion&lt;/i&gt; (Sauria: Chamaeleonidae), with the description of two new genera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic history and composition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Bradypodion&lt;/i&gt; as construed by Klaver &amp; Böhme (1986) and new morphological and molecular data relevant to the taxonomy of the group is reviewed. The combined evidence strongly supports a formal rearrangement of the group into three distinct genera. &lt;i&gt;Bradypodion,&lt;/i&gt; type species &lt;i&gt;Chamaeleo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; Daudin 1802, is retained for the southern African species. Two new genera are erected to accommodate additional well-diagnosed clades within central and east African species previously referred to &lt;i&gt;Bradypodion.&lt;/i&gt; Species of the “fischeri complex” are assigned to &lt;i&gt;Kinyongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gen.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nova,&lt;/i&gt; whilst the endemic Mulanje chameleon is placed in the monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Nadzikambia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gen.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nova.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chamaeleonidae; &lt;i&gt;Bradypodion&lt;/i&gt;; Phylogeny; new genera; mitochondrial and nuclear DNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chamaeleonidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tilbury</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tolley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Branch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Parapagurapseudopsis carinatus &lt;/i&gt;(Tanaidacea: Apseudomorpha) and remarks about the male form</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapagurapseudopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinatus&lt;/i&gt; Brum, 1973 (Apseudomorpha, Pagurapseudidae) is previously known from an incomplete female description. This study presents the female redescription and a description of the male, unknown up to now. Sexual dimorphic aspects are discussed and a key to the Brazilian Pagurapseudidae is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapagurapseudopsis&lt;/i&gt;; Pagurapseudidae; Apseudomorpha; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapagurapseudopsis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pires-Vanin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on identity, new synonymy and larva of &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt; Jacoby (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae) with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Genus &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt; Jacoby is characterized morphologically, and &lt;i&gt;Amphimeloides&lt;/i&gt; Jacoby &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Taizonia&lt;/i&gt; Chen &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are junior synonyms with it. Several &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt; species are figured, including &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bella&lt;/i&gt; (Chen) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; (Jacoby) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridipennis&lt;/i&gt; Jacoby. A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt; from the Nilgiri Hills in south India, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;korakundah&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated, including the larvae. Larvae were associated with adults by sequencing a fragment of the mitochondrial gene cytochrome oxidase I. Larval morphology is discussed and compared with that of other flea beetles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae; &lt;i&gt;Ivalia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Taizonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Amphimeloides&lt;/i&gt;; moss feeding; larval sensilla; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duckett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prathapan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Konstantinov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1362.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1362</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Convolutidae (Acoela) from Tanzania</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of Convolutidae, including a new genus and species, from shallow marine sediments in Tanzania are described: &lt;i&gt;Convoluta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;enelitta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Convoluta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Heterochaerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Picola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;renei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The species &lt;i&gt;Conaperta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Conaperta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thela&lt;/i&gt; are reassigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Convoluta.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Confocal microscopy; turbellarians; meiofauna; Rupert Riedl</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Confocal microscopy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Achatz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hooge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Key to conifer-infesting species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt; Shimer worldwide (Hemiptera: Coccoidea: Diaspididae), with descriptions of two new species and a redescription of &lt;i&gt;L. pallidula &lt;/i&gt;(Williams)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt; are described, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caribaeae&lt;/i&gt; Williams and Miller from Trinidad and Jamaica and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;murreeana&lt;/i&gt; Williams and Miller from Pakistan. &lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidula&lt;/i&gt; (Williams), a non-conifer infesting species, is redescribed so that it can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallida&lt;/i&gt; (Maskell), a species commonly detected on conifers. A dichotomus key is presented for the identification of the adult females of the 25 species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt; that occur on conifers worldwide and a matrix is provided containing 23 characters considered important in distinguishing the 25 conifer-infesting species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt;; conifer; armored scale; Trinidad; Jamaica; Pakistan; worldwide</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidosaphes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davidson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-42</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the immature stages of &lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guahybae&lt;/i&gt; Huamantinco &amp; Nessimian, 2004 (Trichoptera: Odontoceridae), with a new record for the genus and keys to larvae and pupae of Neotropical genera</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larva and pupa of &lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guahybae&lt;/i&gt; Huamantinco &amp; Nessimian from tributaries of the Rio Aiuruoca, Minas Gerais, Brazil, are described, illustrated and compared with other Odontoceridae. The larva is characterized by a reduced lateral carina on the head, a membranous metanotum, a distinctive pattern of ventral setae on abdominal segment I and by the presence of a conspicuous dorsal spine on the anal claw. The larva of &lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; is similar to those of the neartic genera &lt;i&gt;Nerophilus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Namamyia&lt;/i&gt; principally by the undivided mesonotal plates, and by the position and form of setal areas on the metanotum. The pupa is very similar to other odontocerids. The specimens were collected from sandy substrates in small order streams. Animal parts, plant fragments and detritus were observed in the larval gut contents. The genus &lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; is for the first time recorded from the State of São Paulo, Brazil. Keys to larvae and pupae of known Neotropical genera of Odontoceridae are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guahybae&lt;/i&gt;; Odontoceridae; larva; pupa; Brazil; taxonomy; new record; keys to Neotropical genera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anastomoneura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guahybae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dumas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nessimian</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Definition of &lt;i&gt;Doriclytus&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;stat. rev. as a subgenus of &lt;i&gt;Polynema &lt;/i&gt;and redescription of its type species, &lt;i&gt;P. (Doriclytus) vitripenne &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Mymaridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Doriclytus&lt;/i&gt; Foerster is redescribed and treated as a subgenus of the common, diverse, and widespread genus &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; Haliday (Mymaridae). Its type species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitripenne&lt;/i&gt; (Foerster), is redescribed based on the holotype as well as more recently collected specimens from Russia, Sweden, and Belgium. The Neotropical genera &lt;i&gt;Restisoma&lt;/i&gt; Yoshimoto and &lt;i&gt;Formicomymar&lt;/i&gt; Yoshimoto, both &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; are synonymized under &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus)&lt;/i&gt; and their type species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; as, respectively, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;howdeni&lt;/i&gt; (Yoshimoto) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venezuelaense&lt;/i&gt; (Yoshimoto), both &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Barypolynema&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Notopolynema&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; are synonymized under &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus);&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tarphypolynema&lt;/i&gt; Ogloblin, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; described originally as a subgenus of &lt;i&gt;Barypolynema,&lt;/i&gt; is synonymized under the nominate subgenus &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Polynema).&lt;/i&gt; A key to the three presently recognized subgenera of &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; s. l. is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mymaridae; &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Doriclytus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Polynema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Doriclytus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitripenne&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mymaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Triapitsyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fidalgo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1361.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1361</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new &lt;i&gt;Episemion&lt;/i&gt; species (Cyprinodontiformes: Nothobranchiidae) from northern Gabon and southeastern Equatorial Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Episemion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krystallinoron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; the second species in this formerly monotypic genus, is described from the Monts de Cristal in northwestern Gabon and adjacent areas in Equatorial Guinea. It is clearly distinguished from its congener by the coloration pattern of adult males. Species status is also supported by mitochondrial DNA data. &lt;i&gt;Episemion&lt;/i&gt; Radda &amp; Pürzl, 1987 is regarded as a valid genus, distinct from all other nothobranchiid genera and probably most closely related to &lt;i&gt;Diapteron&lt;/i&gt; Huber &amp; Seegers, 1977 and &lt;i&gt;Kathetys&lt;/i&gt; Huber, 1977. It is the third described endemic nothobranchiid species from the Monts de Cristal and adjacent areas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Episemion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krystallinoron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; systematics; phylogeny; color patterns; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Episemion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krystallinoron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sonnenberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Blum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Misof</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the taxonomy and conservation status of the Ecuadorian Glassfrog &lt;i&gt;Centrolenella puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; Flores &amp; McDiarmid (Amphibia: Anura: Centrolenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Glassfrog &lt;i&gt;Centrolenella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; Flores &amp; McDiarmid is a taxon known only from the female holotype, and recently placed in the genus &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; due to its supposed close relationship with &lt;i&gt;Centrolene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mariae&lt;/i&gt; (Duellman &amp; Toft). Herein we report new material of &lt;i&gt;puyoensis,&lt;/i&gt; including adult male specimens previously unknown. We propose the new combination &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; (Flores &amp; McDiarmid) n. comb., in recognition of the state of the humeral &lt;i&gt;crista&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventralis&lt;/i&gt; in males of this species, which lack a humeral spine. The hypothesis of relationships between three species, including &lt;i&gt;puyoensis,&lt;/i&gt; proposed as the &lt;i&gt;mariae&lt;/i&gt; species-group is questioned as it was based on phenetic rather than derived characters. We present new data that extend the distributional range of &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis,&lt;/i&gt; and define its range along the Foothill Evergreen forests from 400 m to 1000 m above sea level in the provinces of Napo, Orellana, and Pastaza. New data presented herein also permit a re-evaluation of the conservation status of the species, previously classified under the IUCN category of Critically Endangered. We recommend that &lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; be reclassified as “Endangered”: EN B1ab(i,ii,iii)+2ab(i,ii,iii); based on a better understanding of the presence of the species, its occupancy area, number of known localities, and habitat quality status.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; n. comb.; distributional range; conservation status; Ecuador</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cochranella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puyoensis&lt;/i&gt; n. comb.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cisneros-Heredia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdiarmid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Iguanidae) from San Guillermo National Park, western Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Iguanidae Liolaemini lizard from the San Guillermo National Park in western Argentina, is described. The new species is a member of the &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darwinii&lt;/i&gt; complex within the monophyletic &lt;i&gt;boulengeri&lt;/i&gt; species group. It is distinguished by its small body size, relatively long tail, low number of scales around midbody, dorsal scales moderately keeled, precloacal pores only in male, bulged patch of enlarged scales on the proximal posterior surface of the thigh in both sexes, dorsal pattern lacking of light vertebral or dorsolateral stripes, antehumeral fold without black pigment in female but greyish in male, a prescapular dark dot dorsal to antehumeral fold in both sexes, and postscapular spot absent. The new species is terrestrial, living in habitats with gravel and sandy soil in an Andean Monte landscape with sparse vegetation, above 2270 meters of altitude.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Iguanidae; Squamata; Reptilia; Andean fauna; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Monguillot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cabrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Acosta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Villavicencio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of Neocoelidiinae Oman (Hemiptera: Auchenorrhyncha: Cicadellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of Neocoelidiinae, &lt;i&gt;Xenocoelidiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and its type-species, &lt;i&gt;Xenocoelidiana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from the state of Amazonas, Brazil. This new genus is similar to genera with species lacking a distinct carina in the transition between the crown and front (Chinchinota Kramer, &lt;i&gt;Deltocoelidia&lt;/i&gt; Kramer, &lt;i&gt;Chinaia&lt;/i&gt; Bruner &amp; Metcalf, &lt;i&gt;Xenocoelidia&lt;/i&gt; Kramer, and &lt;i&gt;Paraphysiana&lt;/i&gt; Chiamolera &amp; Cavichioli). The genus can be distinguished from these other genera mainly by the long coronal suture at the basal half of the crown, the antennal ledges which in lateral view are straight and strongly carinate, and the rectangular clypeus with parallel lateral margins.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">leafhoppers; Neocoelidiinae; new genus; new species; &lt;i&gt;Xenocoelidiana&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">leafhoppers</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques-Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cavichioli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Robackia&lt;/i&gt; Saeher from China (Diptera: Chironomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Robackia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parallela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Oriental China is described and illustrated as male. It differs from other known species of the genus by having a low antennal ratio, a parallel-sided superior volsella, and abdomen with dark brown marks. Chinese males of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilicauda&lt;/i&gt; Sæther are examined and figured. A key to all males of &lt;i&gt;Robackia&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chironomidae; &lt;i&gt;Robackia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chironomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the unknown stages of &lt;i&gt;Simulium &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Aspathia&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;i&gt; sandyi&lt;/i&gt; Coscaron, Ibanez-Bernal &amp; Coscaron-Arias (Diptera: Simuliidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The pharate male and the larva of &lt;i&gt;Simulium&lt;/i&gt; (Aspathia) &lt;i&gt;sandyi&lt;/i&gt; Coscarón, Ibáñez-Bernal &amp; Coscarón-Arias, 1999, are described for the first time, and the female and pupa are redescribed. The most important features of the larva, pupa, male, and female are illustrated, and the previously reported type locality is corrected.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera: Simuliidae; black flies; &lt;i&gt;Simulium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aspathia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Simulium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sandyi&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; description; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera: Simuliidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sandoval-Ruiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ibanez-Bernal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1360.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1360</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Fossil flower bugs (Heteroptera: Cimicomorpha: Cimicoidea) from the Late Jurassic of Northeast China, including a new family, Vetanthocoridae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An extinct new family of flower bugs, Vetanthocoridae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; with 2 new tribes, Vetanthocorini and Crassicerini, 8 new genera, and 9 new species (Byssoidecerus &lt;i&gt;levigatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Collivetanthocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Vetanthocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Vetanthocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Curvicaudus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mecopodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xanthos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pustulithoracalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gloriosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Curticerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venustus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Crassicerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furtivus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; are described from the Late Jurassic Yixian Formation in western Liaoning Province, China. These fossil records suggest there was an important diversity of flower bugs in the earlier Late Jurassic of northern China. A key to four flower-bug families and a key to the known fossil flower bugs are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Cimicoidea; Vetanthocoridae; flower bugs; new family; new tribe; new genus; new species; late Jurassic; Yixian Formation; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus henselii&lt;/i&gt; (Peters) (Anura: Leiuperidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Although &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; frogs are prominent members of Neotropical herpetofauna, larval stages are not known from more than half of the species in this genus. Herein, we describe the tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henselii&lt;/i&gt; based on samples collected in Departamento de Rivera, northern Uruguay. General aspect and major external morphological features are similar to most of other known tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus.&lt;/i&gt; Remarkable character states are a medial vent tube and the presence of dorsal and ventral gaps in the row of marginal oral papillae. &lt;i&gt;Physalaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henselii&lt;/i&gt; has been successively assigned to the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuvieri&lt;/i&gt; and to the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henselii&lt;/i&gt; species groups, but no conclusions can be drawn in support of these associations from external larval morphology. Instead, we found that some character states may contribute to relate species, like the presence of a ventral gap in the marginal row of oral papillae which is shared by &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albonotatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuqui,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuvieri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henselii.&lt;/i&gt; This character state is unique among non-bufonid anurans, although it is also present in some species of the related genus &lt;i&gt;Pseudopaludicola.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albonotatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuqui&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuvieri&lt;/i&gt; tadpoles can be differentiated from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandezae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henselii&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of two small ventrolateral gaps, which are absent in the latter.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; larval morphology; Leptodactylidae; Uruguay</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia; larval morphology; Leptodactylidae; Uruguay</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolenc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Borteiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tedros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nunez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Maneyro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lentireduvius&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of Peiratinae from Brazil, with a key to the New World genera (Hemiptera: Reduviidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lentireduvius&lt;/i&gt; Cai &amp; Taylor, new genus, and one new species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliensis&lt;/i&gt; Cai &amp; Taylor, are described in the subfamily Peiratinae based on a single male specimen from Brazil. The dorsal habitus, antennal segments, male genitalia, and other diagnostic morphological features are illustrated with 25 figures. A key to the genera of Peiratinae of the Western Hemisphere is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Peiratinae; &lt;i&gt;Lentireduvius&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; Brazil; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Substituting time-consuming pencil drawings in arthropod taxonomy using stacks of digital photographs</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The most time-consuming part of a taxonomic description is making the illustrations. This contribution shows how to save time by omitting the pencil drawings of arthropod appendages and replacing them by stacks of microphotographs. These are imported into a drawing software package on a computer in order to make a publication-ready line drawing, a technique described in detail in Coleman (2003). The photographic method requires a special treatment of the appendages which is also shown.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">method; drawing; taxonomy; arthropods; microphotography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">method</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coleman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1359.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1359</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematic notes on tribes in the family Caliscelidae (Hemiptera: Fulgoroidea) with the description of new taxa from Palaearctic and Oriental Regions</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A diagnosis of the family Caliscelidae Amyot et Serville, 1843 is given. The system of higher taxa of the family is revised. The genus &lt;i&gt;Coinquenda&lt;/i&gt; Distant, 1916 is transferred to the subfamily Ommatidiotinae from the family Issidae. Coinquendini &lt;b&gt;trib.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type genus: &lt;i&gt;Coinquenda&lt;/i&gt; Distant, 1916) is erected in the subfamily Ommatidiotinae. &lt;i&gt;Coinquenda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigroclavata&lt;/i&gt; Distant, 1916 is redescribed. The tribe Adenissini Dlabola, 1980 is recharacterized and transferred to the subfamily Ommatidiotinae from the subfamily Caliscelinae. The rank of the tribe Bocrini Emeljanov, 1999 is reduced to the subtribe of the tribe Adenissini. As a result the genera &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; Metcalf, 1952, &lt;i&gt;Pterilia&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1859, and &lt;i&gt;Pterygoma&lt;/i&gt; Melichar, 1903 are transferred to the Adenissini from the family Issidae. Pteriliina &lt;b&gt;subtrib.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type genus: &lt;i&gt;Pterilia&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1859) is erected in the tribe Adenissini. &lt;i&gt;Distantina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Elidiptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimlivata&lt;/i&gt; Walker, 1851) is erected in the subtribe Pteriliina &lt;b&gt;subtrib.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Keys to the subfamilies, tribes, and subtribes of the Caliscelidae, the genera of the tribe Adenissini, and species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; Metcalf are given. &lt;i&gt;Anissus&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1980 and &lt;i&gt;Denissus&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1980 are placed in synonymy under &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; Metcalf, 1952. &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jakowleffi&lt;/i&gt; (Puton, 1890) is redescribed. &lt;i&gt;Adenissus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circularis&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1980 and &lt;i&gt;Anissus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bispinatus&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1980 are transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Perissana.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dlabolai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed as a replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Adenissus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circularis&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1980 (secondary homonym). &lt;i&gt;Raunolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;subgen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Perissus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circularis&lt;/i&gt; Linnavuori, 1952) is erected in the genus &lt;i&gt;Perissana.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Perissana&lt;/i&gt; (Raunolina) &lt;i&gt;arabica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Saudi Arabia. 5 th instar larva of &lt;i&gt;Adenissus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;riadicus&lt;/i&gt; Dlabola, 1985 is described. New faunistic records for 5 species of the family are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Caliscelidae; Ommatidiotinae; Adenissini; Perissana; taxonomy; Palaearctic and Oriental Regions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gnezdilov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Tarsonemus&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Tarsonemidae) associated with bark beetles (Coleoptera: Scolytidae) from Crimea, Ukraine</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tarsonemus&lt;/i&gt; Can. &amp; Fanz., 1876: &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fraxini&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bistridentati&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. are described and illustrated based on material from instars associated with bark beetles in Ukraine. The systematic position of new species and their host relationships are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tarsonemus&lt;/i&gt;; Scolytidae; Ukraine; systematics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tarsonemus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Magowski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Khaustov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the largest ice bug, &lt;i&gt;Namkungia magnus&lt;/i&gt; com. nov. (Grylloblattodea, Grylloblattidae) from Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The largest ice bug species, &lt;i&gt;Namkungia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnus&lt;/i&gt; (Namkung, 1986) from Balgudeuk cave at Jeongseon, Gangwon-do, Korea is transferred from the genus &lt;i&gt;Galloisiana&lt;/i&gt; and redescribed with setae and trichobothria patterns, and with mouthpart, basisternum and genital structure descriptions based on the morphological characters. This species resembles &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biyongensis&lt;/i&gt; (Namkung, 1974) by its large size (longer than 30 mm), eyeless condition, more than 47antennomeres, and 12 cercomeres but is distinguished by asymmetrical supra-anal plate of the bulging 9th abdominal tergite with truncate projection, 52 antennomeres, the cervical sclerite with nine setae (11 on right) on the lateral margin of the left, and copulatory sclerites of the genital structure.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; ice bug; Grylloblattodea; &lt;i&gt;Namkungia&lt;/i&gt;; cave; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.-W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1358.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1358</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biodiversity "hotspots", patterns of richness and endemism, and distribution of marine sponges in South Africa based on actual and interpolation data: A comparative approach</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">“Hotspots” of biodiversity at a meso-scale diversity were examined for marine sponge populations throughout the temperate, subtropical and tropical South Africa. Actual and interpolated (predicted) data sets are presented in a comparative manner to compare the diversity patterns of South African Demospongiae species and their distribution in contiguous 5°grid sections, to demonstrate current knowledge of the sponge fauna in various coastal regions. Richness and endemism varied considerably between marine areas and grid sections, for species at all spatial scales. Richness and endemism were equally effective indicators of biodiversity “hotspots”, but differed in patterns between the two datasets. Species richness appears to be fairly unevenly distributed along the coast, and marked peaks occur in the south of the country, the greatest being in the area surrounding Cape Town (Sector 11); almost certainly the consequence of a disproportionately intense sampling effort at these locations. Levels of apparent endemism varied considerably between sectors, ranging from zero (Sector 1) to 71 species (Sector 11), with an average of 57% apparent endemic species recorded for all 35 regions based on the actual data, vs. 20% apparent endemics for the predicted data. The Bray-Curtis analysis (without transformations) showed no clear pattern of faunal relationships between the 35 selected sectors for the actual dataset, but the predicted data set showed three distinct faunal groups, the West Coast fauna extending from Cape Point northwards, a South Coast fauna, and an East Coast fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; sponges; Demospongiae; species richness; endemism; biogeography; South Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Samaai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Calappa&lt;/i&gt; Weber, 1795 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Calappidae) from East and South Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of box crab, &lt;i&gt;Calappa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africana,&lt;/i&gt; new species (Brachyura: Calappidae) is described from East and South Africa. The species, previously misidentified as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Ortmann, 1892, differs from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; by its live colouration, carapace shape, and the morphologies of the manus and merus of the cheliped and male first gonopod. In addition, a new lectotype for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exanthematosa,&lt;/i&gt; a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica,&lt;/i&gt; is selected.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Calappidae; &lt;i&gt;Calappa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; East Africa; South Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Calappidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Psammocora albopicta&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a new species of Scleractinian Coral from the Indo-West Pacific (Scleractinia; Siderastreidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new scleractinian coral species, &lt;i&gt;Psammocora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopicta,&lt;/i&gt; is described. The species forms encrusting colonies which can attain large sizes and has very small corallites with a styliform columella. Calice and columella diameter, colline shape and corallite density on the skeleton surface are the morphological characters that separate the species from the other species in the genus. A high degree of variation in septa shape and ornamentation, as well as collines development can be found within the same specimen. Living colonies are dark brown to dark green and present white patterns on all, or part, of the surface. Type material was collected in the Arabian Gulf, additional specimens were collected in the Gulf of Aden, and the study of museum collections allows extension of the species distribution to the western Indo-Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Anthozoa; Scleractinia; &lt;i&gt;Psammocora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopicta&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Indo-Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Benzoni</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Agadasys&lt;/i&gt; Whittington&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Platystomatidae, Plastotephritinae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agadasys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xizangensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from China (type locality: Motuo, Xizang Province) is described. The subfamily Plastotephritinae and the genus &lt;i&gt;Agadasys&lt;/i&gt; are recorded from China for the first time. The previously monotypic concept of &lt;i&gt;Agadasys&lt;/i&gt; is revised, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hexablepharis&lt;/i&gt; Whittington is briefly redescribed and a key to two species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Platystomatidae; Plastotephritinae; &lt;i&gt;Agadasys&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whittington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Retropluma solomonensis&lt;/i&gt; nom. nov., a replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Retropluma laurentae&lt;/i&gt; McLay, 2006 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Retroplumidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1357.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1357</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Spongillaflies (Neuroptera: Sisyridae) of North America with a key to the larvae and adults</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The distributions of the two genera (Climacia and &lt;i&gt;Sisyra)&lt;/i&gt; and six species of spongillaflies known to occur in Canada, Mexico and the United States are reviewed and summarized. Several new and significant distribution records are presented for states or provinces in these countries. Species diagnoses and a revised, illustrated key to the third instar larvae and adults of all species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spongillaflies; Neuroptera; Sisyridae; &lt;i&gt;Climacia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sisyra&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spongillaflies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bowles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the larva and pupa of &lt;i&gt;Potamyia phaidra &lt;/i&gt;Malicky and Chantaramongkol (Trichoptera: Hydropsychidae) from southern Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Larvae and pupae of &lt;i&gt;Potamyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phaidra&lt;/i&gt; Malicky and Chantaramongkol (Trichoptera: Hydropsychidae) were collected from montane streams in southern Thailand. Pupal identifications were based on genitalic features in common with described adults, and larvae were associated with the pupae. Herein, the final larval instar and pupa are described, diagnosed, and figured.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Hydropsychidae; &lt;i&gt;Potamyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phaidra&lt;/i&gt;; larva; pupa; description; Thailand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prommi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Permkam</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-29</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic studies of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus&lt;/i&gt; Chaudoir (Coleoptera: Carabidae: &lt;i&gt;Pterostichus&lt;/i&gt;), with description of a new species sympatric&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;with &lt;i&gt;P. thunbergi&lt;/i&gt; Morawitz</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on the structures of the male genitalia, the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus&lt;/i&gt; Chaudoir is redefined, and five subgenera, viz., &lt;i&gt;Euryperis&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky, &lt;i&gt;Morphnosoma&lt;/i&gt; Lutshnik, &lt;i&gt;Euferonia&lt;/i&gt; Casey, &lt;i&gt;Feroperis&lt;/i&gt; Lafer, and &lt;i&gt;Moritapterus&lt;/i&gt; Berlov, are synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus.&lt;/i&gt; Phylogenetic analyses based on eighteen morphological characters revealed that the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus&lt;/i&gt; is monophyletic, whereas most traditional subgenera synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus&lt;/i&gt; are non-monophyletic. &lt;i&gt;Pterostichus&lt;/i&gt; (Petrophilus) &lt;i&gt;tuberifer&lt;/i&gt; Sasakawa, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a sympatric species with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thunbergi&lt;/i&gt; Morawitz, is described from Japan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">endophallic structures; new synonymy; &lt;i&gt;Petrophilus&lt;/i&gt;; morphological phylogeny; &lt;i&gt;Pterostichus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberifer&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">endophallic structures</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sasakawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kubota</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; Chevrolat, 1837 (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Cassidinae: Omocerini), with key to &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; s. str.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The following new species of &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; s. str. (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Cassidinae) are described: &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;howdenorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Venezuela), &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atahualpai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Peru), &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;putamayoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Peru), and &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giganteensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Colombia). Colour photos of the dorsal and lateral habitus of all new species are provided. A key to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; s. str. is given. &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nevermanni&lt;/i&gt; (Spaeth, 1928) is transferred from the nominotypical subgenus to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Vulpia&lt;/i&gt; Spaeth, 1913.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Chrysomelidae; Cassidinae; Omocerini; &lt;i&gt;Discomorpha&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Borowiec</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Brazilian &lt;i&gt;Holepyris&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera, Bethylidae), with description of a new species from Amazonian forest</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Brazilian fauna of &lt;i&gt;Holepyris&lt;/i&gt; is investigated. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eminentus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Amazonian rain forest is described and illustrated. It is recognized by having large and bulging eyes. New geographic records and taxonomic variation data for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coriaceus&lt;/i&gt; Evans, 1977; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micidus&lt;/i&gt; Evans, 1977; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subtilis&lt;/i&gt; Evans, 1977; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt; Evans, 1977; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turrialbae&lt;/i&gt; Evans, 1977 are provided. A key to Brazilian species is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Hymenoptera; Bethylidae; &lt;i&gt;Holepyris&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical region; Amazonian forest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gobbi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1355.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1355</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision and phylogenetic analysis of &lt;i&gt;Chilicola sensu stricto &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Colletidae) with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gibbs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Packer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydroporus neclae&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from north-eastern Turkey, a new member of the &lt;i&gt;memnonius&lt;/i&gt;-group of &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; Clairville (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neclae&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. is described from the Erzurum province in north-eastern Turkey. The species belongs to the &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;memnonius-group.&lt;/i&gt; Its habitus and the shape of the median lobe are similar to those of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; Sharp, but the shape of the hind margins of the metacoxal processes are similar to those of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanarius&lt;/i&gt; Sturm. The male and female genitalia as well as several other characters of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neclae&lt;/i&gt; sp.n. are figured and compared with those of these two other species. The key to species of the &lt;i&gt;memnonius-group&lt;/i&gt; given in Fery (1999) is modified to include the new species and the relevant parts are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; &lt;i&gt;Hydroporus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;memnonius-group&lt;/i&gt;; new species; species key; Turkey.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Erman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fery</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Contulma&lt;/i&gt; from South America (Trichoptera: Anomalopsychidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species in the caddisfly genus &lt;i&gt;Contulma&lt;/i&gt; Flint 1969 (Trichoptera: Anomalopsychidae) are described from Bolivia and southeastern Brazil: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Bolivia), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluminensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Brazil), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meloi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Brazil), and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tripui&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Brazil). The Bolivian species represents the first record of the genus and family for Bolivia. The Brazilian species form a closely related group of species also including &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tijuca&lt;/i&gt; Holzenthal &amp; Flint 1995.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Anomalopsychidae; &lt;i&gt;Contulma&lt;/i&gt;; South America; Neotropics; new species; Bolivia; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holzenthal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Robertson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt; (Ephemeroptera: Caenidae) from Florida, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eglinensis&lt;/i&gt; new species is described from nymph and adults, and its relationships with other North American species of the genus are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt;; Ephemeroptera; Caenidae; Eglin Air Force Base; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caenis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pescador</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Richard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1354.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1354</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A synopsis of the fleas (Insecta: Siphonaptera) parasitizing New World species of Soricidae (Mammalia: Insectivora)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A synopsis of the 57 species and 24 genera of New World fleas parasitizing species of Soricidae is provided, with synonymical lists, and distributional and host data. Species analyzed belong to the families Ceratophyllidae (10 genera), Ctenophthalmidae (10 genera), Hystrichopsyllidae (two genera), and Leptopsyllidae (two genera). Three subspecies are elevated to species: &lt;i&gt;Corrodopsylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lira,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nearctopsylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hygini.&lt;/i&gt; Soricid hosts include 17 species of &lt;i&gt;Sorex,&lt;/i&gt; four species of &lt;i&gt;Cryptotis,&lt;/i&gt; two species of &lt;i&gt;Blarina,&lt;/i&gt; and one species of &lt;i&gt;Crocidura.&lt;/i&gt; The species hosting the highest number of flea species is &lt;i&gt;Blarina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicauda&lt;/i&gt; (19 flea species), followed by &lt;i&gt;Sorex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereus&lt;/i&gt; (16), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacificus&lt;/i&gt; (9), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trowbridgii&lt;/i&gt; (8), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fumeus&lt;/i&gt; (7), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palustris&lt;/i&gt; (7), and &lt;i&gt;Cryptotis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva&lt;/i&gt; (7). Most of the flea species analyzed are polyxenous, and belong mainly to genera associated to small rodents and marginally present on Soricidae. The association with Soricidae seems to be more evident in species of &lt;i&gt;Corrodopsylla,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Corypsylla,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ctenophthalmus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Doratopsylla,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hystrichopsylla,and&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nearctopsylla.&lt;/i&gt; Only &lt;i&gt;Corrodopsylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lira,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrerai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ctenophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cryptotis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;expansus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myodosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hystrichopsylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cryptotis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guatemalensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nearctopsylla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgiana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pfitzeri,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;princei&lt;/i&gt; are apparently stenoxenous or monoxenous. Taxa analyzed belong to the Nearctic biotic element and are specially diversified in the Mexican Transition Zone.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fleas; parasites; Soricidae; Insectivora; Nearctic; Holarctic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fleas</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morrone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Acosta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Dirt-encrusted and dragon millipedes (Diplopoda: Polydesmida: Paradoxosomatidae) from Queensland, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three unusual new Paradoxosomatidae are described from tropical north Queensland. &lt;i&gt;Desmoxytoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hasenpuschorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; closely resembles the dragon millipedes &lt;i&gt;Desmoxytes&lt;/i&gt; of southeast Asia, but differs in gonopod details. &lt;i&gt;Tholerosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monteithi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corrugatum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are remarkable for their tightly attached coating of soil particles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diplopoda; Polydesmida; Paradoxosomatidae; dragon millipede; Queensland; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diplopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mesibov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-44</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Acentropinae and Musotiminae (Lepidoptera, Pyralidae) of the Galapagos Islands, Ecuador</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Acentropinae and Musotiminae (Lepidoptera, Pyralidae) are recorded for the Galapagos Islands, Ecuador for the first time. They are represented by one species each: &lt;i&gt;Parapoynx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluctuosalis&lt;/i&gt; (Zeller, 1852) and &lt;i&gt;Undulambia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindbladi&lt;/i&gt; Landry &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; respectively. The latter has been reared from the fern &lt;i&gt;Pteridium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquilinum&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;arachnoideum&lt;/i&gt; Herter (Polypodiaceae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Pyralidae; Acentropinae; Musotiminae; new species; Polypodiaceae; Galapagos Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Landry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Roque-Albelo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stigmaeus&lt;/i&gt; Koch (Acari: Stigmaeidae) from Northwest of Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stigmaeus&lt;/i&gt; Koch (Acari: Stigmaeidae), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malekii&lt;/i&gt; Haddad, Bagheri &amp; Khanjani, is described and illustrated from Northwestern (East Azarbaijan) Iran. The materials of new species were collected from apple litter. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Stigmaeus&lt;/i&gt; found in Iran is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Stigmaeidae; &lt;i&gt;Stigmaeus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Iran</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Irani-Nejad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bagheri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Khanjani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kamali</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new sibling species of &lt;i&gt;Halyzia straminea &lt;/i&gt;(Hope) (Coleoptera: Coccinellidae: Halyziini) from the Indian subcontinent</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halyzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dejavu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; a sibling species of &lt;i&gt;Halyzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;straminea&lt;/i&gt; (Hope), is described from India and Nepal. The distinguishing characters, including the male and female genitalia, are described in detail and illustrated in comparison with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;straminea.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coccinellidae; &lt;i&gt;Halyzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;straminea&lt;/i&gt;; new sibling species; &lt;i&gt;Halyzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dejavu&lt;/i&gt;; Indian subcontinent</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coccinellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Poorani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Booth</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1353.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1353</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and biology of &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt; species (Polychaeta: Spionidae) boring into oyster shells in South America, with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt; species boring into oyster shells in South America are described based on museumand new material collected mainly in Brazil. These include &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;haswelli&lt;/i&gt; newly recorded for South America, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadoriana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rickettsi&lt;/i&gt; newly recorded for the Atlantic coast of South America, and a new species described from Brazil. Extension of the distribution of these oyster-associated species may have resulted from transportation of oysters to South America for aquaculture. In all species, females deposit eggs into capsules which are joined to each other in a string and attached to the inner wall of the burrow. In &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadoriana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;haswelli&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rickettsi,&lt;/i&gt; larvae develop inside the capsules until the 3-chaetiger stage and then are released into the water column where they feed and develop until the 16–18-chaetiger stage. &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinhosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; exhibits lecithotrophy; larvae develop inside the capsules until the 14-chaetiger stage, then hatch and settle after a short planktonic stage. Newly settled individuals of all species construct a small silty tube on the shell surface before boring into the shell. &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ecuadoriana&lt;/i&gt; forms mud blisters on the inner side of oyster shells. Heavy infestation by this species poses a threat to oyster aquaculture in Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">oyster disease; worm infestation; mud blister; boring; &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">oyster disease</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Radashevsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nalesso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Notes on &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; Kirkaldy, 1902 (Heteroptera: Gerridae), with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilicaudatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; from northeastern India and &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luaae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; from China (Hainan Island); both are closely related to &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pingae&lt;/i&gt; Andersen, 1998 from China (Guangdong). The occurence of &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kalidasa&lt;/i&gt; Kirkaldy, 1902 in northeastern India is confirmed. &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrestris&lt;/i&gt; Andersen, 1982 is recorded from Nepal for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gerridae; &lt;i&gt;Eotrechus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new record; descriptive notes; China; India; Nepal</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gerridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zettel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Bennarellini from Costa Rica (Hemiptera: Fulgoromorpha: Cixiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Noabennarella&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. and a new species, &lt;i&gt;Noabennarella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costaricensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Costa Rica, are described. Considering &lt;i&gt;Noabennarella&lt;/i&gt; as an example, general descriptions of Bennarellini characters, including first detailed descriptions of male and female genitalia, are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; planthoppers; Cixiidae; new species; morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Holzinger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kunz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tadpole and advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis albopunctata&lt;/i&gt; (Anura, Microhylidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopunctata&lt;/i&gt; is known from specimens from Bolivia, the tadpole is unknown. Here we present data on tadpole and the advertisement call of a Brazilian population of this species. Tadpoles and calls are from Uberlândia (Minas Gerais, Brazil). Tadpoles are 18.3-21.5 mm TL. Body length about 47% total length; tail triangular, flagellar-tipped. Oral apparatus with two symmetrical semicircular flaps pending over the mouth; flaps border wartyornamented. The tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopunctata&lt;/i&gt; differ in color from that of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shudikarensis.&lt;/i&gt; Different from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ventrimaculata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvalhoi,&lt;/i&gt; tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albopunctata&lt;/i&gt; do not possess a pair of parentheses-like mottles between eyes. Calls from the Brazilian population were consistently characterized by nine pulses per notes and two harmonic frequency bands, while calls from Bolivia have 5-8 pulses per note and no harmonics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole morphology; vocalization; Cerrado; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giaretta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1351.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1351</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The larvae of &lt;i&gt;Amarodytes duponti&lt;/i&gt; (Aube (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae: Hydroporinae), with comments on Bidessini larval morphology and chaetotaxy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Larval morphology of the Neotropical endemic dytiscid genus &lt;i&gt;Amarodytes&lt;/i&gt; Régimbart is investigated. All three larval instars of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duponti&lt;/i&gt; (Aubé) are described and illustrated with particular emphasis on morphometry and chaetotaxy. Larvae of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duponti&lt;/i&gt; share with those of other Bidessini studied in detail the absence of the primary pore ABc. Contrary to other first instar Bidessini, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duponti&lt;/i&gt; characterizes by the presence of an occipital suture and the absence of pores PAj and PAk. &lt;i&gt;Amarodytes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duponti&lt;/i&gt; is related to &lt;i&gt;Allodessus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bistrigatus&lt;/i&gt; (Clark) by the presence of secondary setae on the first urogomphomere, a unique feature among the Bidessini.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diving beetles; Bidessini; &lt;i&gt;Amarodytes&lt;/i&gt;; larval morphology; chaetotaxy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diving beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Michat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Alarie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-13</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hydara&lt;/i&gt; (Hemiptera: Coreidae: Coreinae: Hydarini) from Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hydara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kmenti&lt;/i&gt; new species, collected in Madagascar is described. The relationships with &lt;i&gt;Hydara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Westwood) and &lt;i&gt;Hydara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrofasciata&lt;/i&gt; Garcia Varela are discussed. The adult dorsal habitus, and drawings of pronotum, male genital capsule, and female genital plates are included, as is a key to the Madacascar Hydarini.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Coreidae; Hydarini; &lt;i&gt;Hydara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kmenti&lt;/i&gt; new species; Madagascar; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brailovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres &lt;/i&gt;(Copepoda, Siphonostomatoida, Asterocheridae) associated to &lt;i&gt;Placospongia cristata &lt;/i&gt;Boury-Esnault (Porifera) in Bahia State, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The siphonostomatoid fauna associated with the sponge, &lt;i&gt;Placospongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristata&lt;/i&gt; Boury-Esnault, is studied for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimbarrensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is characterized by having two spines distally on the third endopod of P4 instead of a seta and a spine, is described and compared with its congeners. Another species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neptunei&lt;/i&gt; Johnsson, is also found associated with this sponge, however, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristata&lt;/i&gt; may not be its main host since it is scarce. &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neptunei&lt;/i&gt; has previously been recorded associated with an undetermined sponge in the southeast region of Brazil thus the present record extends its distribution to the northeast. This study is the first record of the sponge &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristata&lt;/i&gt; in Bahia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Asterocheridae; Siphonostomatoida; &lt;i&gt;Asterocheres&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Copepoda; &lt;i&gt;Placospongia&lt;/i&gt;; Porifera</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Asterocheridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bispo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Johnsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Neves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-34</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of&lt;i&gt; Plinachtus &lt;/i&gt;Stal (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Coreidae: Coreinae: Gonocerini) from Aldabra Atoll and Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Plinachtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aldabrensis&lt;/i&gt; new species, collected in Aldabra Atoll, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contortus&lt;/i&gt; new species, collected in Madagascar are described, and included in the &lt;i&gt;dubius-group.&lt;/i&gt; The relationships with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubius&lt;/i&gt; Herrich-Schaeffer, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schoutedeni&lt;/i&gt; van Reenen are discussed. The adult dorsal habitus, and drawings of pronotum, and male genital capsule are provided, as is a key to the known species from Madagascar and Aldabra Atoll.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; Coreidae; Gonocerini; &lt;i&gt;Plinachtus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Aldabra Atoll; Madagascar</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brailovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Barrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Isotomodes&lt;/i&gt; Linnaniemi, 1907 of the Ibero-balearic fauna, with description of two new species (Collembola: Entomobryomorpha: Isotomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Isotomodes&lt;/i&gt; Linnaniemi, 1907 is represented by 14 species in the Ibero-balearic fauna, two of which are new to the science. The two new Spanish species, &lt;i&gt;Isotomodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Picos de Europa (Cantabria, Northern Spain) and &lt;i&gt;Isotomodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rafaeli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Murcia (Southeastern Spain), are both here described. Drawings of the diagnostic structures of the new species and a key for the identification of Ibero-balearic species of &lt;i&gt;Isotomodes&lt;/i&gt; are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Collembola; Isotomidae; new species; Iberian Peninsula; Balearic Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Collembola</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Arbea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of the frog parasite genus &lt;i&gt;Batrachomyia&lt;/i&gt; Krefft from New Guinea (Diptera: Chloropidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Batrachomyia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krausi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; from Oya Tabu, Fergusson Island off the southeastern coast of Papua New Guinea is described and illustrated. It marks the first record of this genus of frog parasites outside of Australia. The larva of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krausi&lt;/i&gt; was found parasitizing the frog &lt;i&gt;Rana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;supragrisea,&lt;/i&gt; the first record of the fly genus from the frog family Ranidae. The biology of this species is summarized and a table of known hosts for the genus is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chloropidae; &lt;i&gt;Batrachomyia&lt;/i&gt;; frogs; Ranidae; systematics; Papua New Guinea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chloropidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Evenhuis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Ptychopteridae -a family of flies (Diptera) new to the Neotropical Region and description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ptychoptera&lt;/i&gt; Meigen (Diptera: Ptychopteridae) is described from cloud forest in southern Mexico, representing the first definitive record of the family in the Neotropical Region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ptychopteridae; new species; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ptychopteridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hancock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M-A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Marcos-Garcia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rotheray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1350.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1350</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Study of two species groups of &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt; Robineau-Desvoidy (Diptera: Muscidae) from China, with the description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species groups of &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt; from China were studied, the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nymphaearum-group&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscicoxa-group.&lt;/i&gt; Three new species are described, &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolorantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nymphaearum-group,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirtiorbitalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrifuscicoxa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscicoxa-group.&lt;/i&gt; A key to the species groups and subgroups of Chinese &lt;i&gt;Phaonia,&lt;/i&gt; and keys to the species of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nymphaearum-group&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscicoxa-groups,&lt;/i&gt; are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Muscidae; &lt;i&gt;Phaonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;nymphaearum-group&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;fuscicoxa-group&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Du</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnesterodon holopteros &lt;/i&gt;(Cyprinodontiformes: Poeciliidae: Poeciliinae), a new species from the Republic of Uruguay</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnesterodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holopteros&lt;/i&gt; new species is described from the río Uruguai drainage. The new species is distinguished from its congeners by: (1) a series of small dark brown dots along predorsal portion of first, second or third lateral scale row, associated with vertical bars along body sides; (2) eight or nine (rarely seven) dark brown vertical bars (from one to three scales in depth) along lateral surface of body in females, which may extend nearly down to belly (i.e., at level of ventral profile); (3) bony style at male gonopodium tip long and gently arched, narrowing towards tip to form a distal filament and bearing a V-shaped membrane restricted to its proximal third; (4) four branchiostegal rays in females; and (5) unbranched pelvic-fin rays.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical Ichthyofauna; taxonomy; phylogeny; live-bearing killifishes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical Ichthyofauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>H. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lucinda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Litz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Recuero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the type specimens of the &lt;i&gt;Elachista freyerella&lt;/i&gt; species-group (Lepidoptera: Elachistidae: Elachistinae) from India and Sri Lanka</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five species of the &lt;i&gt;Elachista&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freyerella&lt;/i&gt; species-group from India and Sri Lanka are redescribed based on their types; their genitalia are figured for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lepidoptera; Elachistidae; &lt;i&gt;Elachista&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;freyerella&lt;/i&gt; species-group; types; India; Sri Lanka</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lepidoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sruoga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Diskus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Epanerchodus&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1901 in the Korean Peninsula, with a description of a new species (Diplopoda, Polydesmida, Polydesmidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diplopod genus &lt;i&gt;Epanerchodus&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1901 appears to be represented in the Korean Peninsula by eight species, i.e. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreanus&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1937, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kimi&lt;/i&gt; Murakami &amp; Paik, 1968, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavisetosus&lt;/i&gt; Murakami &amp; Paik, 1968, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polymorphus&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova &amp; Golovatch, 1981, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beroni&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova &amp; Kim, 1993, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gangwonus&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova &amp; Lim, 2001, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multiprocessus&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova, 2001, and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacilliferus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; A description of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bacilliferus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is presented. All currently known &lt;i&gt;Epanerchodus&lt;/i&gt; species from Korea are keyed, including the new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diplopoda; Polydesmida; &lt;i&gt;Epanerchodus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; key; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diplopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The species of &lt;i&gt;Larinus &lt;/i&gt;Dejean, 1821 (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) described by J. Desbrochers : lectotype designations and new synonymies</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on a study of the types of species described by J. Desbrochers in the genus &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; Dejean, several nomenclatural changes are proposed. Lectotypes are designated (or Holotypes recognized) for the following species names: &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricticollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interruptus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;breviusculus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villosiventris&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villosicollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distinguendus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senilis&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius) var. &lt;i&gt;rubripes&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassiusculus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obesulus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacer&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hierolosymae&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cribricollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;densicollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;akbesianus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugithorax&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tauricus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers. Eight new synonymies are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ursus&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius, 1792) [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senilis&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius) var. &lt;i&gt;rubripes&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1892 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ]; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fucatus&lt;/i&gt; Faust, 1891 [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacer&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers,1896 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ]; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brenskei&lt;/i&gt; Faust, 1890 [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;akbesianus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1897 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.];&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassiusculus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1895 [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;khnzoriani&lt;/i&gt; Ter-Minassian, 1962, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.];&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lederi&lt;/i&gt; Faust, 1889 [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cribricollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1896, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.];&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sturnus&lt;/i&gt; (Schaller, 1783) [= &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugithorax&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1897, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.];&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sibiricus&lt;/i&gt; Gyllenhal, 1836 [=Larinus &lt;i&gt;distinguendus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1892 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.];&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cardopatii&lt;/i&gt; Lucas, 1849 [=Larinus &lt;i&gt;densicollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1897 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; ]. The name of &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hierolosymae&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1896 is corrected and become &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hierosolymae&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1896 [emendation]. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obesulus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1896 is assigned to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Cryphopus&lt;/i&gt; Petri, 1907. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;villosicollis&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1892 and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hierosolymae&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1896 are placed in the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Phyllonomeus&lt;/i&gt; Gistel, 1856. &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tauricus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1897 belongs to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Larinomesius&lt;/i&gt; Reitter, 1924. At the present time, the types of three species are not located : &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rufipes&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1870, &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;numidicus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1892 and &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; Gyllenhal var. &lt;i&gt;minutissimus&lt;/i&gt; Desbrochers, 1891.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curculionidae; Lixinae; &lt;i&gt;Larinus&lt;/i&gt;; holotypus; lectotypus; Desbrochers; new synonymies; emendation.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curculionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gultekin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Perrin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1349.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Nov. 2006</title>
    <volume>1349</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hyla vigilans &lt;/i&gt;Solano, 1971, a second species for the genus &lt;i&gt;Scarthyla&lt;/i&gt;, redescription and distribution in Venezuela and Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vigilans,&lt;/i&gt; a poorly known hylinae from Venezuela and Colombia, is redescribed and assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Scarthyla&lt;/i&gt; based on external morphology and osteology. The call is analysed from localities from both sides of the Andes. When adult, &lt;i&gt;Scarthyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vigilans&lt;/i&gt; is indistinguishable externally from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;goinorum;&lt;/i&gt; only calls and larvae distinguish the two species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vigilans;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scarthyla;&lt;/i&gt; Hylidae; Hylinae; redescription; distribution; Venezuela; Colombia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vigilans;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scarthyla;&lt;/i&gt; Hylidae; Hylinae; redescription; distribution; Venezuela</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrio-Amoros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Pascual</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mueses-Cisneros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Infante</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Chacon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new genera and species of Eriococcidae (Hemiptera: Coccoidea) from southern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera of Eriococcidae, &lt;i&gt;Intecticoccus&lt;/i&gt; Kondo and &lt;i&gt;Orafortis&lt;/i&gt; Hardy, each with a new species (I. &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; Kondo and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luma&lt;/i&gt; Hardy), are described and illustrated based on the adult females. &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; was collected on &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; (Nothofagaceae) in Argentina and Chile, and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luma&lt;/i&gt; was collected in Chile on &lt;i&gt;Amomyrtus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luma&lt;/i&gt; (Myrtaceae). Based on a phylogenetic analysis of SSU rDNA (18S) sequence data, &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luma&lt;/i&gt; are placed within the Gondwanan group of eriococcids (sensu Cook &amp; Gullan 2004), which also includes other &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus-feeding&lt;/i&gt; genera such as &lt;i&gt;Chilechiton&lt;/i&gt; Hodgson &amp; Miller, &lt;i&gt;Chilecoccus&lt;/i&gt; Miller &amp; González and &lt;i&gt;Madarococcus&lt;/i&gt; Hoy. Major genera within the Gondwanan group that feed on other plant groups include &lt;i&gt;Lachnodius&lt;/i&gt; Maskell, &lt;i&gt;Opisthoscelis&lt;/i&gt; Schrader and some species currently assigned to &lt;i&gt;Eriococcus&lt;/i&gt; Targioni Tozzetti. We consider that &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luma&lt;/i&gt; are each sufficiently distinct from other named taxa to warrant erection of two new genera. DNA data do not support a relationship of &lt;i&gt;Chilechiton&lt;/i&gt; with the New Zealand genus &lt;i&gt;Eriochiton&lt;/i&gt; Maskell. A revised taxonomic key to the adult females of Eriococcidae known from Chile is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amomyrtus&lt;/i&gt;; Argentina; Chile; Eriococcidae; &lt;i&gt;Intecticoccus&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; &lt;i&gt;Nothofagus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Orafortis&lt;/i&gt;; scale insects; phylogenetic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amomyrtus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kondo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hardy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cook</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gullan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-36</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus&lt;i&gt; Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; Hong (Hemiptera: Palaeontinidae), with description of a new species from the Middle Jurassic of China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diagnostic characters for &lt;i&gt;Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; Hong, 1983, belonging to the Palaeontinidae Handlirsch, 1906, are revised. This genus is remarkably different from others in the fore wing, whose branches of Sc are obscure and antenodal region is square; and in the hind wing, whose M 3+4 is unbranched and arises from stem M, whose M 1+2 fork is more distal and A 1 is absent. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trinervus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described based on two well preserved specimens from the Middle Jurassic of Daohugou, Inner Mongolia, China; this is the first palaeontinid specimen with complete fore and hind wings articulated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; Hong; 1983; &lt;i&gt;Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trinervus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Hemiptera; Palaeontinidae; Middle Jurassic; Daohugou; China; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sinopalaeocossus&lt;/i&gt; Hong</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Fang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Duan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-45</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Zora&lt;/i&gt; from China (Araneae: Zoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Zora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acuminata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described in both sexes from Mt. Baihua, Beijing City, China. The genital organs suggest its close relationship with &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lyriformis&lt;/i&gt; Song, Zhu &amp; Gao, 1993.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Baihua Mountain; Beijing; diagnosis; taxonomy; species description</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Baihua Mountain</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.-S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.-S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Puelchesia gracilis&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and species of Pachydemini endemic to the Monte biogeographic province in Argentina (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae: Melolonthinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new scarab beetle genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Puelchesia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on specimens collected in the Monte biogeographic province of west central Argentina. This genus is placed in the tribe Pachydemini based on an evaluation of the characters within the context of the current classification of the subfamily Melolonthinae. The distribution and natural history of the taxon is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Argentina; new species; Pachydemini; Melolonthinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Argentina</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ocampo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>B. T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first fossil Myopsocidae (Psocoptera) in Dominican amber</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myopsocus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Dominican amber (Miocene?). This first fossil Myopsocidae shows some similarities with the recently described Australian genus &lt;i&gt;Nimbopsocus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Psocoptera; Myopsocidae; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; first fossil record; Dominican amber</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Psocoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Waller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Poinar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-11-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
