<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1119.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1119</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cladocera (Crustacea: Ctenopoda, Anomopoda) from southern Mexico, Belize and northern Guatemala, with some biogeographical notes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Different surveys in the Campechano–Petenense biogeographical province, including a part of Yucatan Peninsula, Belize, and North of Guatemala (Departments of Peten and Alta Verapaz), produced a list of 56 species of the Cladocera. Studied water bodies included small temporary pools, sinkholes (named cenotes), permanent lagoons, wetlands, and Peten Lake. We increase the number of known cladoceran species from Mexico by adding eight new records, and provide the first published species list for Belize, as well as for the Mayan Mountains and intermittent rivers from Guatemala. Interesting taxa found are &lt;i&gt;Diaphanosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bergamini&lt;/i&gt; Paggi &amp; da Rocha, 1999; &lt;i&gt;Macrothrix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; King, 1853; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; Sars, 1901; &lt;i&gt;Grimaldina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brazzai&lt;/i&gt; Richard, 1892; &lt;i&gt;Picripleuroxus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quasidenticulatus&lt;/i&gt; Smirnov, 1996; &lt;i&gt;Ephemeroporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentatus&lt;/i&gt; (Bergamin, 1939); &lt;i&gt;Graptoleberis&lt;/i&gt; sp.; &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;ossiani&lt;/i&gt; Sinev, 1998; &lt;i&gt;Oxyurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliata&lt;/i&gt; Bergamin, 1939, and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicaudis&lt;/i&gt; (Birge, 1910). The majority of these species are Neotropical representatives, and the Mexican records are the northernmost. Few other taxa, such as the recently described &lt;i&gt;Leydigia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;louisi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mexicana&lt;/i&gt; Kotov, Elías-Gutiérrez &amp; Nieto, 2003, are related to African species or widely distributed, like &lt;i&gt;Ilyocryptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinifer&lt;/i&gt; Herrick, 1882. Some species, as &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentatus&lt;/i&gt; (Bergamin) and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliata&lt;/i&gt; Bergamin were rare in the samples.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New record; distribution; neotropics; Branchiopoda; freshwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New record</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Elias-Gutierrez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kotov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Garfias-Espejo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Anatomical investigation of the slender catshark &lt;i&gt;Schroederichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis &lt;/i&gt;Springer, 1966, with notes on intrageneric relationships (Chondrichthyes: Carcharhiniformes: Scyliorhinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The slender catshark &lt;i&gt;Schroedericthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt; Springer, 1966, originally described from two immature males, is redescribed on the basis of 12 specimens of both sexes, juveniles and adults (as well as the holotype and paratype). The supplementary specimens were collected off the northern coast of Brazil between Amapá and Pará states. Aspects of its external morphology, color pattern, dermal denticles, dentition, vertebral counts, and the cephalic, clasper and pectoral fin skeleton are described in detail and fully illustrated. These features are compared with those of congeneric species. Our observations support preliminary results of work in progress that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatus&lt;/i&gt; Springer, 1966, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saurisqualus&lt;/i&gt; Soto, 2003 form a monophyletic group, mostly on the basis of neurocranial morphology, and that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bivius&lt;/i&gt; (Smith, 1838) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; (Guichenot, 1848) should be removed from &lt;i&gt;Schroederichthys.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schroedericthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt;; Scyliorhinidae; anatomical description; phylogenetic relationships; western South Atlantic Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Schroedericthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>U.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gomes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peters</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>B. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gadig</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Loandalia &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Pilargidae) from Queensland, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; are described from Queensland, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fredrayorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from Moreton Bay, south eastern Queensland and is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of singular palpostyles; uniramous parapodia at chaetiger 1; an emergent notopodial spine at chaetiger 9; neurochaetae numbering 20–24; ventral cirri begin on chaetiger 7 and the pygidium with two lateral papillae-like anal cirri. &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gladstonensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from Gladstone Harbour, central eastern Queensland and is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of bifid palpostyles; chaetiger 1 uniramous with remaining chaetigers biramous; an emergent notopodial spine from chaetiger 7–8; ventral cirri present from chaetiger 5 and neurochaetae numbering 5–6.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fredrayorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gladstonensis&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov.; Pilargidae; Queensland; Australia; new species; systematics.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Loandalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fredrayorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Marks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hocknull</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1118.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1118</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Atypus &lt;/i&gt;in China (Araneae: Atypidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Thirteen species of &lt;i&gt;Atypus&lt;/i&gt; known from China are described, including seven species new to science: &lt;i&gt;Atypus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flexus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;largosaccatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ledongensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedicellatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacculatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yajuni&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. The zoogeography of &lt;i&gt;Atypus&lt;/i&gt; is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Atypidae; &lt;i&gt;Atypus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; identification key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.-S.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>X.</middlename>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Qu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of freshwater mussel (Bivalvia: Unionidae), &lt;i&gt;Pleurobema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;athearni&lt;/i&gt;, from the Coosa River Drainage of Alabama, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Mobile Basin historically supported one of the most diverse freshwater mussel (Bivalvia: Unionidae) assemblages in North America. More than 65 species of mussels are known from the Basin, but it is difficult to determine how many species were present historically. The drainage's unique physical habitat was largely destroyed between the late 1800s and mid-1900s by impoundment and channel modifications of most of the larger rivers. Many species that were once common are now restricted to small headwater rivers and mid-sized tributaries. Recent Coosa River tributary surveys revealed a new, undescribed species of &lt;i&gt;Pleurobema.&lt;/i&gt; This new species, &lt;i&gt;Pleurobema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;athearni,&lt;/i&gt; is distinctive in outward appearance, shell morphometry and reproductive morphology, and can be distinguished from other Coosa River drainage unionids. Our analysis indicates that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;athearni&lt;/i&gt; is morphologically different from other similar taxa. It differs both in shell width/length and width/height ratios and thus provides a simple, quantitative means to differentiate this species from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;georgianum&lt;/i&gt; (Lea, 1841) &lt;i&gt;Fusconaia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barnesiana&lt;/i&gt; (Lea, 1838), and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerina&lt;/i&gt; (Conrad, 1838), which it superficially resembles and that also occur in the area. Our morphological diagnosis of this species is supported by recent molecular analyses that suggest this species is a &lt;i&gt;Pleurobema&lt;/i&gt; and one closely related to other endemic Coosa River drainage unionids. The discovery of a new species of large, long-lived macroinvertebrate from a relatively well-sampled drainage in a populated region of the southeast United States underscores the need for more detailed surveys in isolated stretches of tributary streams. It should also serve as a reminder that almost 40 species of aquatic mollusks have been extirpated from the Mobile Basin before anything could be learned about their habitat or life history requirements.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Big Canoe Creek; freshwater mussel; Mobile Basin; mollusk biodiversity; Unionoida; endemic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Big Canoe Creek</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gangloff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Feminella</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of high intertidal barnacle (Cirripedia, Tetraclitidae) from Baja California Sur, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species, &lt;i&gt;Lissaclita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melaniae&lt;/i&gt; (Tetraclitidae), is described from the Gulf of California, Baja California Sur, Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Lissaclita&lt;/i&gt; has a secondarily divided single row of parietal tubes without septa, lack of tubes in the radii, diametric shell growth, and a membranous basis. This combination of characters does not agree with any currently described subfamily within the Tetraclitidae. Lacking a detailed phylogenetic analysis of the entire family, we place the new genus in the Tetraclitidae without assigning it to a subfamily.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tetraclitidae; &lt;i&gt;Lissaclita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melaniae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; et &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Gulf of California; barnacles</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tetraclitidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gomez-Daglio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Syoc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1117.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1117</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Balitoridae) from the Temburong River basin, Brunei Darussalam, Borneo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; from Brunei Darussalam, on the island of Borneo, are described from recent collections and from older museum specimens. &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cranbrooki,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is superficially similar to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis,&lt;/i&gt; but differs in having a distinct secondary rostrum; body brown with 9–10 grey bars, head dorsum dark brown with thin grey reticulate pattern; and 56–60 scales on lateral line. &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aeroides,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is similar to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctulatus,&lt;/i&gt; but differs in having the body uniform brown, dorsum uniform brown; head dorsum with very fine cream reticulate pattern (similar to a cream head with brown spots and blotches); dorsal, caudal and anal fins blue in life; and 47–65 scales in lateral line. &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venustus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is similar to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pariclavis,&lt;/i&gt; but differs in having both the body and head dorsum plain brown; dorsal, caudal and anal fins red in life; and 58–63 scales in lateral line.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cranbrooki&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aeroides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venustus&lt;/i&gt;; biodiversity; Borneo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gastromyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cranbrooki&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Z.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sulaiman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Paraeupolymnia&lt;/i&gt;, and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Nicolea uspiana&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov. (Terebellidae: Polychaeta)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Paraeupolymnia&lt;/i&gt; Young &amp; Kritzler, 1987 is redefined and its type species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carus&lt;/i&gt; Young &amp; Kritzler, 1987, is redescribed. It is easily recognized by the presence of two pairs of branchiae on segments two and three, and one pair of lateral lappets on segments two/three; its distribution is expanded to include localities in Florida, the Gulf of Mexico, Lesser Antilles and Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Paraeupolymnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;garciagomezi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from the Florida Keys; it differs from its congeners by the presence of a region with many tubercles on the thoracic dorsal surface, and a rounded emergent papillae between the notoand neuropodia. Finally, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uspiana&lt;/i&gt; Nogueira, 2003, is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Nicolea&lt;/i&gt; Malmgren, 1866, because of the lack of lateral lappets, and variation in the number of thoracic chaetigers.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Grand Caribbean; Mexican Caribbean; Panama; Polychaetes; Terebellids; Taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Grand Caribbean</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mario</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Londono-Mesa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new records of Tingidae (Insecta: Heteroptera) of New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nine new species of Tingidae (Heteroptera) are described from New Guinea, and new localities are recorded for 23 known species, with comments on their distribution and systematic affinities. An identification key to genera and species is provided for all the New Guinean species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Identification key; New Guinea; new species; new records; Systematics; Taxonomy; Tingidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Guilbert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1116.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1116</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Pygolabis &lt;/i&gt;Wilson, 2003 (Isopoda, Tainisopidae, Crustacea) from Western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new isopod species of the hypogean genus &lt;i&gt;Pygolabis&lt;/i&gt; (family Tainisopidae) are described from the Pilbara and Gascoyne regions of Western Australia. The species appear to be restricted to small areas in the ground waters below single or neighbouring creek beds. These species are similar in overall morphology, and are primarily identified using features of the pleotelson, uropods and the shape of the appendix masculina on the male pleopod 2.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tainisopidae; &lt;i&gt;Pygolabis&lt;/i&gt;; Western Australia; hypogean; taxonomy; narrow range endemics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tainisopidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Keable</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>D. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus nephelion &lt;/i&gt;(Siluriformes, Loricariidae)&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;a new and endangered species of suckermouth armored catfish from the Tuy River, north-central Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of suckermouth armored catfish, &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nephelion,&lt;/i&gt; is described from seven specimens collected in tributaries of the Tuy River in the Caribbean Sea basin of north-central Venezuela. &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nephelion&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from the other species assigned to its genus by its unique color pattern, the head and body being marked with irregular white spots. &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nephelion&lt;/i&gt; is the third species of the genus described from Venezuela: &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torbesensis&lt;/i&gt; (Schultz 1944) from the Mérida mountain range (Cordillera de Mérida), Orinoco River basin; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perijae&lt;/i&gt; Pérez and Provenzano 1996 from Perijá mountain range (Sierra de Perijá), Maracaibo Lake basin; and now &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nephelion&lt;/i&gt; from the La Costa mountain range (Cordillera de La Costa). These three species inhabit isolated foothill rivers and have very restricted geographic distributions. The extreme alteration of the Tuy River basin by humans may threaten &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nephelion&lt;/i&gt; and the other fish species endemic to the basin with extinction. An artificial key for the species assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt; is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt;; Loricariidae; Ancistrini; Venezuela; Tuy River; endangered species; suckermouth armored catfish</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cordylancistrus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Provenzano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Milani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-41</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Reassessment of the taxonomic status of the genera &lt;i&gt;Ischnocnema&lt;/i&gt; Reinhardt and Lutken, 1862 and &lt;i&gt;Oreobates &lt;/i&gt;Jimenez-de-la-Espada, 1872, with notes on the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Leiuperus verrucosus&lt;/i&gt; Reinhardt and Lutken, 1862 (Anura: Leptodactylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic status of two leptodactylid frog genera is reevaluated. &lt;i&gt;Ischnocnema&lt;/i&gt; Reinhardt and Lütken, 1862 is considered a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Duméril and Bibron, and the combination &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verrucosus&lt;/i&gt; (Reinhardt and Lütken, 1862) is proposed. &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt; Jiménez-de-laEspada, 1872 is revalidated, and the combinations &lt;i&gt;Oreobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quixensis&lt;/i&gt; Jiménez-de-la-Espada, 1872, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simmonsi&lt;/i&gt; (Lynch, 1974), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saxatilis&lt;/i&gt; (Duellman, 1990), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctaecrucis&lt;/i&gt; (Harvey and Keck, 1995), and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanderi&lt;/i&gt; (Padial, Reichle and De la Riva, 2005) are proposed. &lt;i&gt;Epsophus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verrucosus&lt;/i&gt; Miranda-Ribeiro, 1937 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verrucosus&lt;/i&gt; (Reinhardt and Lütken, 1862).&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Key&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;words:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Amphibia; Anura; Leptodactylidae; &lt;i&gt;Ischnocnema;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oreobates;&lt;/i&gt; Taxonomy</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>U.</firstname>
          <lastname>Caramaschi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Canedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus with two new species of hermit crabs (Crustacea, Decapoda, Paguroidea, Paguridae) from an unique habitat</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Pteropagurus,&lt;/i&gt; is proposed for two new species of hermit crabs that are described and illustrated herein. These species, &lt;i&gt;Pteropagurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spina&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. are unique in that their shelter of choice is empty pteropod mollusk shells. The taxon can be categorized as a deepwaters genus, with a bathymetric range of 285 to 700 meters. Although both species are presently known only from New Caledonia, it is quite possible that their occurrence in other areas has been overlooked because their unique habitat has been neither expected nor heretofore considered a resource for hermit crabs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Paguroidea; Paguridea; new genus; new species; pteropod shells</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclaughlin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Rahayu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1115.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1115</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three species of the isopod crustacean genus &lt;i&gt;Antennuloniscus&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1962 (Asellota: Haploniscidae) from the Southern Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Antennuloniscus&lt;/i&gt; is rediagnosed and discussed. &lt;i&gt;Antennuloniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornatus&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1962 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1962 are redescribed and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latoperculus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from material obtained from the Southern Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Isopoda; Haploniscidae; &lt;i&gt;Antennuloniscus&lt;/i&gt;; deep sea; Southern Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Brökeland</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Chone infundibuliformis &lt;/i&gt;Kroyer, 1856 (Polychaeta: Sabellidae) and histology of the branchial crown appendages, collar and glandular ridge</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fifty-three species have been formally described in &lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt; Krøyer, 1856, showing wide variation in the shapes of dorsal lips, peristomium, and posterior abdominal uncini. Previous studies indicate that such variation could result in splitting of the genus; however, the original description of the type species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infundibuliformis&lt;/i&gt; did not include critical details and illustrations, and for other species, incomplete or misleading information has been provided. In order to redescribe the species &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infundibuliformis&lt;/i&gt; and delineate the genus, type and topotype materials were reviewed, and histological sections of the appendages of the branchial crown, collar and glandular ridge are described. The redescription points out that in &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infundibuliformis:&lt;/i&gt; 1) insertion of the branchial lobes is not exposed beyond the collar; 2) radioles have a paired series of pinnules of different sizes; 3) radiolar flanges are broad; 4) dorsal lips are broadly rounded, as long as wide, without mid-rib; they have hyaline cartilage, but there is no extension of the branchial skeleton; 5) dorsal lips are vascularized by a plexus of small blood vessels derived from the basal branchial blood vessels, which further back communicate with the dorsal vessel; 6) thoracic uncini have teeth above the main fang of unequal size, median tooth of basal row larger than teeth in subsequent rows; 7) uncinus shape shows variation within each torus, but no intersegmental gradation is appreciable; 8) females with oocytes distributed in all thoracic and abdominal segments; males with sperm in abdomen, with barrel-shaped nucleus and mushroom-shaped acrosome. The collar is supported by a dense mass of hyaline cartilage and covered by glandular epithelium composed of basophile glands. Acidophil glands, tubular-shaped with granulose secretions, constitute the glandular ridge. Size of teeth in thoracic uncini, presence or absence of abdominal uncini variation, latero-ventral posterior abdominal depression, dorsal lips internal construction and glandular ridge are compared among some species of &lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt; and close genera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sabellidae; &lt;i&gt;Chone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infundibuliformis&lt;/i&gt;; histology; glandular ridge</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sabellidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tovar-Hernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sosa-Rodriguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Megaphobema teceae &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Araneae, Theraphosidae), a new theraphosine spider from Brazilian Amazonia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species from Juruti River Plateau, Juruti, Pará, Brazil that fits the generic characters of &lt;i&gt;Megaphobema&lt;/i&gt; is described. &lt;i&gt;Megaphobema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;teceae&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. differs from the other four species known in this genus mainly by the presence of a conspicuous post-ocular process. This is the first record of the genus to both oriental Amazon and Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Theraphosidae; &lt;i&gt;Megaphobema&lt;/i&gt;; Brazilian Amazon; Neotropical; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Perez-Miles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miglio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonaldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1114.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1114</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phytoseiid mites of the subtribes Typhlodromalina and Euseiina (Acari: Phytoseiidae: Euseiini) from sub-Saharan Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twenty-four phytoseiid species of the subtribe Typhlodromalina Chant &amp; McMurtry are reported in this paper. They refer to all species of this subtribe now known to occur in sub-Saharan Africa, and they belong to the genera &lt;i&gt;Amblydromalus&lt;/i&gt; Chant &amp; McMurtry (5 species), &lt;i&gt;Prasadromalus&lt;/i&gt; Chant &amp; McMurtry (1 species), &lt;i&gt;Typhlodromalus&lt;/i&gt; Muma (7 species) and &lt;i&gt;Ueckermannseius&lt;/i&gt; Chant &amp; McMurtry (11 species). Ten of these species are described for the first time and 11 species are redescribed. All of these were collected in cassava habitat, in an effort to determine the mites of that agro-ecosystem in that region. Redescriptions are based mostly on specimens collected in this study; for 6 species, redescriptions are also based on type specimens. A key to help in the separation of Typhlodromalina presently known to occur in sub-Saharan Africa is included. The morphological relation between a group of sub-Saharan species of &lt;i&gt;Euseius&lt;/i&gt; (2 of which first described in this paper) and &lt;i&gt;Ueckermannseius&lt;/i&gt; is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biological control; predator; cassava; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biological control</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Moraes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zannou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yaninek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of &lt;i&gt;Syntormon &lt;/i&gt;from Singapore with the description of a new species (Insecta, Diptera, Dolichopodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Syntormon&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time from Singapore. &lt;i&gt;Syntormon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singaporensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described and illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Syntormon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Southeast Asia; Singapore; rain forest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Syntormon&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Grootaert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Q.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Heterocoelia &lt;/i&gt;Dahlbom from China, with a key to the Oriental species (Hymenoptera: Bethylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The males of two new species of &lt;i&gt;Heterocoelia&lt;/i&gt; from China: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhaoi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. are described and illustrated. A key to Chinese &lt;i&gt;Heterocoelia&lt;/i&gt; is provided. The type specimens are deposited in the Department of Plant Protection, Zhejiang University, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hymenoptera; Bethylidae; &lt;i&gt;Heterocoelia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hymenoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Z.</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1113.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1113</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Hybridization in Umbridae in the Hudson River, New York, with Designation of Neotypes for &lt;i&gt;Umbra limi &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Umbra pygmaea&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We document the occurrence of a natural hybrid between the Eastern Mudminnow, &lt;i&gt;Umbra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; (DeKay 1842) and the Central Mudminnow, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limi&lt;/i&gt; (Kirtland 1840). Hybrid individuals were collected in a supratidal pool in a fresh-tidal marsh in the Hudson River, New York. ANOVA, ANCOVA, principal components analysis, and discriminant function analysis of meristics and morphometrics showed that the hybrids were distinguishable from the parental species and were generally intermediate between them. The tidal Hudson River is the only place these species are sympatric, and hybridization must have occurred within the last several decades. We designate neotypes for &lt;i&gt;Umbra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pygmaea&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Umbra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limi.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Central Mudminnow; Champlain Canal; Eastern Mudminnow; Erie Canal; fish dispersal; James DeKay; Jared Kirtland; type locality; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Central Mudminnow</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schmidt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Daniels</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Villa &lt;/i&gt;Lioy (Bombyliidae, Diptera) from Egypt, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Villa&lt;/i&gt; Lioy in Egypt was carried out. Seven species were found, two of them are described as new, namely: &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;efflatouni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenozoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aegyptiaca&lt;/i&gt; Engel is raised to species level (stat. &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and a lectotype designated; and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bivirgata&lt;/i&gt; Austen and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paniscoides&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi are recorded for the first time from Egypt. Another two species, &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cana&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen) and &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micrargyra&lt;/i&gt; (Walker) were previously recorded in Egypt. The study of type specimens showed that &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senecio&lt;/i&gt; (Loew), wrongly recorded from Egypt, is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ixion&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius) &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A key, diagnoses, and illustrations of genitalia and wings of some species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Villa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;efflatouni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;V.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenozoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Egypt; Bombyliidae; Diptera; taxonomy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Villa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>El-Hawagry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Greathead</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-32</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and infraciliature of the oligotrich ciliate &lt;i&gt;Strombidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapulum &lt;/i&gt;(Yagiu, 1933) Kahl, 1934 (Protozoa, Ciliophora, Oligotrichida) from the intestine of sea urchin &lt;i&gt;Hemicentrotus pulcherrimus &lt;/i&gt;Agassiz</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology and infraciliature of a poorly known endocommensal ciliate, &lt;i&gt;Strombidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapulum&lt;/i&gt; (Yagiu, 1933) Kahl, 1934, isolated from the intestine of the sea urchin &lt;i&gt;Hemicentrotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulcherrimus&lt;/i&gt; Agassiz, was investigated based on observations of specimens from living cells and fixed protargol impregnated cells. An improved diagnosis is given based on previous and current studies: large sized marine &lt;i&gt;Strombidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo&lt;/i&gt; 50–130 × 25–65 µm; dorsoventrally slightly flattened; outline ovate and turnip-shaped, tapering posteriorly and terminating in an elongate tail; apical protrusion about 5 µm long in live cells; one elongated macronucleus; girdle kinety equatorial composed of about 57 monokinetids; ventral kinety located subcaudally on right margin, composed of about 5 dikinetids; on average 16 anterior and 29 ventral membranelles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Endocommensal ciliate; morphology; &lt;i&gt;Strombidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapulum;&lt;/i&gt; sea urchin; redescription</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Endocommensal ciliate; morphology; &lt;i&gt;Strombidium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rapulum;&lt;/i&gt; sea urchin; redescription</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-40</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new marine cyrtophorid ciliate, &lt;i&gt;Brooklynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. from the China Sea with a new definition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Brooklynella &lt;/i&gt;(Protozoa, Ciliophora, Cyrtophorida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology and infraciliature of the new marine ciliate, &lt;i&gt;Brooklynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., collected from the coastal water off Qingdao, China, have been investigated using live observation and protargol impregnation method. The new species is characterized by: size 40–50 × 20–30 µm &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vivo,&lt;/i&gt; body highly flattened, reniform to oval in outline; 15–17 ventral kineties, of which the rightmost three to four rows extend apically; five postoral kineties without cilia; about six nematodesmal rods; podite about 6 µm long; two contractile vacuoles diagonally positioned; freeliving, marine habitat. The new species can be distinguished from the type form &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hostilis&lt;/i&gt; Lom &amp; Nigrelli, 1970 in having smaller body size, fewer somatic kineties and contractile vacuoles, and a distinct finger-like podite. Based on the present as well as previous work, an improved diagnosis for the genus &lt;i&gt;Brooklynella&lt;/i&gt; is suggested: Hartmannulidae with a definitive podite, of which the base is located at posterior ventral portion of cell, but not surrounded by somatic kineties; postoral and left kineties considerably shorter than right ones, terminating at about the same level of post-equator rather than progressively posteriorly shortened. The characteristics of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. namely the continuous ventral ciliature like hartmannulids and non-ciliated postoral kineties and the reduced number of nematodesmal rods like dysteriids, suggests it could be an intermediate form between families Hartmannulidae Poche, 1913 and Dysteriidae Claparède &amp; Lachmann, 1859.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brooklynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt;; Ciliophora; new species; morphology; infraciliature</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brooklynella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Gong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-49</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Evidence of full species status of the neotropical leaf-frog &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri bahiana &lt;/i&gt;(A. Lutz, 1925) (Amphibia, Anura, Hylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The full species status of &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt; was investigated based on tadpoles and vocalizations characteristics. We found distinct characteristics between the tadpoles and advertisement and territorial calls of the former and that of &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri.&lt;/i&gt; The main tadpole differences are related with a skin projection protecting the spiracle, origin of dorsal fin, morphology of ventral fin and distribution of papillae on the oral disc. The advertisement call and territorial call of &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt; were different from the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; calls especially for the structure and temporal characteristics (pulses/second principally). The color of newly metamorphosed &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt; suggests that the color pattern of the internal sides of the thigh of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; can be related to a neotenic pattern of development. We elevate &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt; to species level based on morphological and acoustical traits decribed here.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burmeisteri&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole; advertisement call; territorial call; taxonomic status</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phyllomedusa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bahiana&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <middlename>S. N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Junca</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-64</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1111.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">20 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1111</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-20</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of Southern Hemisphere &lt;i&gt;Austronanus &lt;/i&gt;Hodgson, 1910, with two new genera and five new species of Paramunnidae (Crustacea: Isopoda: Asellota)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Paramunnid species of Southern Hemisphere cold-water &lt;i&gt;Austronanus&lt;/i&gt; Hodgson, 1910 and related genera are characterised by simple, smooth, flattened, rather elongate oval bodies, a broadly projecting frontal head margin, well-developed, short, mostly distally bulging eyestalks with ommatidia, pereonites with lateral margins contiguous, rounded or truncate, and dorsally visible coxae V–VII. Just and Wilson (2004) rejected synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Austronanus&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Paramunna&lt;/i&gt; Sars proposed by Nordenstam (1933), following a revision of the latter genus. The type species, &lt;i&gt;Austronanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glacialis&lt;/i&gt; Hodgson, 1910, is re-described based on topotypic material from McMurdo Sound, Antarctica, (the holotype is a small manca). The types of &lt;i&gt;Paramunna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentata&lt;/i&gt; Nordenstam, 1933 and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia&lt;/i&gt; Hale, 1937 are re-described and the two species referred to &lt;i&gt;Austronanus&lt;/i&gt; together with three new Antarctic and subantarctic species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aucklandensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gelidus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mawsoni.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paramunna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagoniensis&lt;/i&gt; Winkler, 1994 is redescribed and made the type species of a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Xigonus.&lt;/i&gt; A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Stephenseniellus,&lt;/i&gt; is established for two new species from the subantarctic islands south of New Zealand and Australia, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palliolatipes&lt;/i&gt; (type species) from Macquarie Island, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serraticornis&lt;/i&gt; (originally reported by Stephensen, 1927 as “Paramunna (serrata (Richardson) ?”) from Auckland Island.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Asellota; Paramunnidae; &lt;i&gt;Austronanus&lt;/i&gt; complex; southern hemisphere.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Just</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>D. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-58</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-20</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Natarsia &lt;/i&gt;Fittkau (Diptera: Chironomidae: Tanypodinae) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The chironomid genus &lt;i&gt;Natarsia&lt;/i&gt; is recorded from the Oriental Region for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Natarsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nugax&lt;/i&gt; (Walker) is redescribed and &lt;i&gt;Natarsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;qinlingica&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. is described from males. A key to adult males is presented and the generic description is emended.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chironomidae; Tanypodinae; &lt;i&gt;Natarsia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chironomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Cheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-20</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first five years of &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Z.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-20</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1110.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1110</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on the Zoarcidae of the southern hemisphere. X. New records from western Antarctica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions and some range extensions are given for 10 species of eelpouts ranging from the Ross to Weddell seas, Antarctica. The new specimens, from eight sampling cruises, broaden descriptive data previously reported by Anderson (1988) for &lt;i&gt;Dieidolycus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leptodermatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lycenchelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aratrirostris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Oidiphorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mcallisteri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ophthalmolycys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bothriocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachycara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachycephalum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Seleniolycus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevifasciatus.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, &lt;i&gt;Bothrocara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;molle,&lt;/i&gt; previously known from Japan to Chile, is reported from off South Georgia in 1286–2187 m.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Antarctica; subantarctic; Zoarcidae; eelpouts; Ross Sea; Scotia Sea; Weddell Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Antarctica</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Anderson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapionosyllis &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Syllidae: Exogoninae) from Tenerife (Canary Islands, Spain) with description of a new species and new records</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of &lt;i&gt;Parapionosyllis:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; (Pierantoni, 1903), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macaronesiensis&lt;/i&gt; Brito, Núñez &amp; San Martín, 2000 and a new species &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abriguensis,&lt;/i&gt; were recorded from shallow subtidal sandy substrates of Tenerife. The new species is characterized by having bidentate ventral simple chaetae and a marked dorso-ventral gradation in the length of the compound chaetae. Data on the ecology of these species, as well as a key for all &lt;i&gt;Parapionosyllis&lt;/i&gt; known from the Canary Islands are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polychaeta; Syllidae; Exogoninae; &lt;i&gt;Parapionosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; soft-bottoms; Tenerife; Canary Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polychaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Riera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nunez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>D. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new acuariid species (Spirurida, Acuariidae) and other nematodes from &lt;i&gt;Hydromys &lt;/i&gt;(Muridae, Hydromyinae) from Papua, Indonesia and Papua New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">From a survey of the intestinal helminths of 8 common water rats, &lt;i&gt;Hydromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysogaster,&lt;/i&gt; and 1 Shaw Mayer’s water rat, &lt;i&gt;Hydromys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shawmayeri,&lt;/i&gt; from Papua New Guinea and 1 &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysogaster&lt;/i&gt; from Papua Indonesia, an acanthocephalan, &lt;i&gt;Porrorchis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hydromuris,&lt;/i&gt; a cestode &lt;i&gt;Hymenolepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diminuta,&lt;/i&gt; a notocotylid and a psilostomid trematode and the nematodes &lt;i&gt;Heterakis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fieldingi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Subulura&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Toxocara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mackerrasae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Trichuris&lt;/i&gt; sp., &lt;i&gt;Uncinaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hydromyos&lt;/i&gt; were found, all being new records for &lt;i&gt;Hydromys&lt;/i&gt; in the Island of New Guinea. &lt;i&gt;Tikusnema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intersedis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Acuariidae), differing from its congenors in the number of teeth on the leaves of the pseudolabia and the length and morphology of the left spicule, was described from &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysogaster.&lt;/i&gt; Similar life styles and diets provide a common link between the rodents hosts of &lt;i&gt;Tikusnema&lt;/i&gt; spp. The commonalities between the helminth communities of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysogaster&lt;/i&gt; in northern Australia and New Guinea support the hypothesis that &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chrysogaster&lt;/i&gt; originated in New Guinea and subsequently migrated south.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acanthocephala; Cestoda; Trematoda; Nematoda; water rat; rodent; Muridae; Australia; Papua New Guinea; Papua Indonesia &lt;i&gt;Tikusnema&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acanthocephala</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-37</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of freshwater leech of the genus &lt;i&gt;Haementeria&lt;/i&gt; (Annelida: Glossiphoniidae) from Jalisco State, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Haementeria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lopezi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described based on the examination of 11 specimens collected in northern Jalisco state, Mexico. Leeches were found feeding on blood of &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marinus&lt;/i&gt; (Bufonidae) and &lt;i&gt;Smilisca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baudinii&lt;/i&gt; (Hylidae). Diagnostic characters are: undivided annuli and absence of conspicuous papillae on dorsal surface. Specimens measure 22–59 mm length and 6-9 mm wide.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Annelida; Hirudinea; Glossiphoniidae; &lt;i&gt;Haementeria&lt;/i&gt;; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Annelida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Oceguera-Figueroa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-45</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Homology of the gonostylus parts in crane flies, with emphasis on the families Tipulidae and Limoniidae (Diptera, Tipulomorpha)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The study of the morphology of the gonostylus – a structure of major importance for the taxonomy and systematics of crane flies – has shown that the terminology currently applied to the branches of this organ in Tipulomorpha and its implied primary homology hypothesis are inconsistent in the different families. In this paper, such inconsistencies are discussed, some basic criteria for the proper recognition of the homologous parts are given, and a revised nomenclatural system is proposed. The terms “clasper of gonostylus” and “lobe of gonostylus” are proposed for the gonostylar branches on the basis of the known functions of these structures.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Tipulomorpha; Limoniidae; Tipulidae; gonostylus; homology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new dendrobatid frog (Anura: Dendrobatidae: &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt;) from Aprada tepui, southern Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Venezuelan Guayana. It inhabits the slopes of Aprada tepui, a sandstone table mountain in southern Venezuela. The new species is distinguished from close relatives by its particular pattern, absence of fringes on fingers, presence of a lingual process, and yellow and orange ventral coloration. It is the 18 th described species of &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; from Venezuelan Guayana.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Dendrobatidae; &lt;i&gt;Colostethus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;breweri&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Venezuelan Guayana</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrio-Amoros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1109.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1109</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of the clawed lobsters (Crustacea: Decapoda: Homarida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The generic and familial structure of the clawed lobsters, Homarida, was studied by cladistic analysis. Previous phylogenetic studies of the clawed lobster genera have focussed on the putative nephropoid families: Nephropidae, Thaumastochelidae, and Chilenophoberidae. Recent high-level studies of decapod phylogeny, however, show that in addition to Nephropidae and Thaumastochelidae (both Nephropoidea), the Enoplometopidae (Enoplometopoidea) are ingroup homaridans. Conversely, the homaridan placement of Chilenophoberidae has been questioned, instead possibly having astacidan affinities. This study, building on previous analyses, incorporates additional taxa and data to examine phylogenetic relationships of the genera and families. Analyses were conducted including both extant and extinct taxa (analysis A), and with extant taxa only (analysis B). The resulting topologies from analyses A &amp; B were largely compatible indicating that the phylogenetic signal among homaridan genera was not significantly impacted by fossil taxa. Results support recognition of Nephropoidea, comprising Thaumastochelidae and Nephropidae, and Enoplometopoidea, comprising Enoplometopidae and Uncinidae. Affinities of Chilenophoberidae were found to lie with Astacida rather than Homarida, albeit with weak jackknife support. Thaumastochelidae is strongly supported as monophyletic, with two extant genera and the extinct &lt;i&gt;Oncopareia.&lt;/i&gt; Present data, however, are equivocal about an independently monophyletic Nephropidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Homarida; Nephropoidea; Chilenophoberidae; Enoplometopoidea; Nephropidae; Thaumastochelidae; Enoplometopoidea; Uncinidae; phylogeny; lobster</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the sharpshooter genus &lt;i&gt;Desamera &lt;/i&gt;from northern Brazil (Insecta: Hemiptera: Cicadellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the Neotropical sharpshooter genus &lt;i&gt;Desamera&lt;/i&gt; Young are described and illustrated from Brazil: &lt;i&gt;Desamera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eliasi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Amazonas and Rondônia States and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paraensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Pará State. &lt;i&gt;Desamera&lt;/i&gt; is for the first time recorded from northern and westcentral Brazil. The two new species can be recognized mainly by the aedeagal morphology. The female genitalia in &lt;i&gt;Desamera&lt;/i&gt; are for the first time described in detail. Additional notes on the only other known species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intersecta&lt;/i&gt; (Germar), are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropics; Auchenorrhyncha; Cicadellinae; Proconiini; leafhopper; morphology; taxonomy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mejdalani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of &lt;i&gt;Hypogastrura crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; (Stach, 1949) (Collembola, Hypogastruridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The polytypic species &lt;i&gt;Hypogastrura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; (Stach, 1949) is revised, mostly based on types. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dobsinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Stach, 1949) is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; sensu nov. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;estaranhensis&lt;/i&gt; Cassagnau, 1959 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burgundiana&lt;/i&gt; Gisin, 1960 are synonymized with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franconiana&lt;/i&gt; stat. nov. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carpatica&lt;/i&gt; Nosek, 1962 is recognized as a distinct species. &lt;i&gt;Achorutes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schäfferi&lt;/i&gt; Carl, 1901 (= &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; Schäffer, 1900), suspected as identical with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franconiana,&lt;/i&gt; is considered as a probable synonym of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurescens&lt;/i&gt; (Lubbock, 1867). Redescriptions are provided and lectotypes are designated for &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassaegranulata&lt;/i&gt; (Stach, 1949) sensu nov. and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franconiana&lt;/i&gt; (Stach, 1949) stat. nov.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">redescriptions; lectotypes designation; synonymy; springtails</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">redescriptions</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Skarzynski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-37</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Orisaltata&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus of flea beetles from the Oriental Region (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Orisaltata,&lt;/i&gt; with the type species &lt;i&gt;Aphthona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;azurea&lt;/i&gt; Jacoby (the only known species) from the Oriental Region is described and illustrated. Comparative notes and host plant information are provided. &lt;i&gt;Aphthona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;babai&lt;/i&gt; Kimoto is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Orisaltata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;azurea.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae; new genus; synonymy; Oriental Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prathapan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Konstantinov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus rigidus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., new species of eutardigrade from New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rigidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a new species of eutardigrade from New Zealand very similar to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coronatus&lt;/i&gt; de Barros, 1942. It is characterized by having a smooth cuticle, lacking eye spots, having three macroplacoids and a microplacoid, and eggs with conical processes (with reticular sculpture and an evident ring of basal digitations) and egg shell with dots that seem to continue the basal digitations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rigidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Philippine record of south american sailfin catfishes (Pisces: Loricariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic and biogeographic study of the introduced suckermouth armored catfishes locally known as “janitor fish” is briefly described. Specimens were collected from five sites in the Laguna de Bay basin and were examined for 19 meristic and 37 morphometric characters and other external features including coloration. Results were compared with existing literature on fishes in the family Loricariidae. Examination revealed that specimens of janitor fish, previously reported as &lt;i&gt;Hypostomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plecostomus,&lt;/i&gt; actually belong to the genus &lt;i&gt;Pterygoplichthys,&lt;/i&gt; family Loricariidae. Collected specimens consisted of two species—Pterygoplichthys &lt;i&gt;disjunctivus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pterygoplichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pardalis.&lt;/i&gt; Both species were collected from the five sites except in Pasig River where only &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;disjunctivus&lt;/i&gt; was collected.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Janitor fish; &lt;i&gt;Pterygoplichthys&lt;/i&gt;; sailfin catfishes; Laguna de Bay; Philippines; introduced species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Janitor fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chavez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>De La Paz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Manohar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pagulayan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>R. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1108.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1108</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Shallow water tanaidaceans (Crustacea: Peracarida: Tanaidacea) from New Caledonia and the Loyalty Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Pacific collections by the MUSORSTOM campaigns of the Paris Museum over the last twenty years include a total of four species of Tanaidacea from shallow waters of the New Caledonia region and all new to science. These species are described herein, one in the family Tanaidae, &lt;i&gt;Zeuxo&lt;/i&gt; (Parazeuxo) &lt;i&gt;cloacarattus,&lt;/i&gt; and three in the family Leptocheliidae, viz. &lt;i&gt;Pseudoleptochelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bulbus,&lt;/i&gt; the second Pacific species recorded for this genus, a species of the &lt;i&gt;Leptochelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; agg. represented only by males, and a species with unusual cheliped carpus morphology which is placed in a new genus as &lt;i&gt;Konarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cheiris.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New Caledonia; Tanaidacea; tanaids; &lt;i&gt;Konarus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leptochelia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pseudoleptochelia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zeuxo&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New Caledonia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sialis &lt;/i&gt;from Oriental China (Megaloptera: Sialidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt; from Oriental China are revised. The following three species are described as new to science: &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kunmingensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;versicoloris&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt; from Oriental China is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sialidae; &lt;i&gt;Sialis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Oriental realm; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sialidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of &lt;i&gt;Microtendipes &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer from China (Diptera: Chironomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Microtendipes&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer from China are described and illustrated as males: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quasicaducus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaanensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhamensis.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;britteni&lt;/i&gt; (Edwards), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confines&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedellus&lt;/i&gt; (De Geer), and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatus&lt;/i&gt; Kawai and Sasa are recorded from China; the record of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confines&lt;/i&gt; (Meigen) is the first for China. A key to the males of &lt;i&gt;Microtendipes&lt;/i&gt; in China is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chironomidae; &lt;i&gt;Microtendipes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chironomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <lastname>Qi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microchironomus &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer from China (Diptera: Chironomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus&lt;/i&gt; Kieffer from China is reviewed and one new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavus,&lt;/i&gt; is described and illustrated on the basis of the male. &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tabarui&lt;/i&gt; Sasa is recorded for the first time from China. &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tener&lt;/i&gt; (Kieffer) and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deribae&lt;/i&gt; (Freeman) from China are redescribed. A world key to males is given. &lt;i&gt;Parachironomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trisetifer&lt;/i&gt; Hashimoto &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; is transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clarilatus&lt;/i&gt; Guha &amp; Chaudhuri is transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Demicryptochironomus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">China; Chironomidae; &lt;i&gt;Microchironomus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">China</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1107.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1107</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of Reduviidae (Hemiptera: Heteroptera) from Colombia and other Neotropical countries</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">One subfamily, 27 genera, and 48 species of Reduviidae are recorded for the first time from Colombia and other Neotropical countries. Comments on those taxa, and new localities and notes for other previously known species, are given. For the first time, the female of &lt;i&gt;Opisthacidius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;picturatus&lt;/i&gt; is described and its pronotum figured. Morphological details on &lt;i&gt;Orbella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lugubris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pessoaia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limai,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Phasmatocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spectrum,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pothea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulipes&lt;/i&gt; are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical region; Costa Rica; Panama; Colombia; Ecuador; Venezuela; Trinidad and Tobago; Peru; Bolivia; Brazil; Paraguay; new records; taxonomy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical region</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Forero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new &lt;i&gt;Tityus &lt;/i&gt;species (Scorpiones: Buthidae) from Sierra de Portuguesa, western Venezuela, based on morphological and mitochondrial DNA evidence</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new scorpion species, &lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described, representing the first record of the genus for the southern foothills of Sierra de Portuguesa in the western Venezuelan state of Portuguesa. The species is morphologically related to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanarensis,&lt;/i&gt; from the state of Lara, and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boconoensis,&lt;/i&gt; from state of Trujillo. &lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. can be distinguished by the array of dorsal trichobothria in the pedipalp femur (d &lt;i&gt;3&lt;/i&gt; , &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;4&lt;/i&gt; , &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;5&lt;/i&gt; ) and by the following combination of female metasomal segment II characters: (i) ventral keels double and parallel up to two thirds of the segment, whereupon they converge into a single keel and separate again in the base; (ii) full, parallel ventral keels, including a well defined central keel in the second half of the segment. A molecular approach was undertaken to estimate the genetic relationship between the new species, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanarensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boconoensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;discrepans.&lt;/i&gt; Sequencing of a 562 bp-segment encoding sectors M6 to M11 of the cytochrome oxidase subunit I revealed that &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;imei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. diverges from &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanarensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boconoensis,&lt;/i&gt; particularly in the polymorphic sector I4, sharing more overall sequence similarity with the northcentral Venezuelan species, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;discrepans.&lt;/i&gt; The new species is of potential medical importance given the presence of venom components whose mass resembles that of scorpion neurotoxins affecting voltage-sensitive sodium channels, as indicated by MALDI-TOF MS analyses.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt;; Scorpiones; Buthidae; cytochrome oxidase subunit I; Portuguesa Range; new species; mass spectrometry; Venezuela.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Borges</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Sousa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Manzanilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1106.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1106</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An annotated checklist of mites (Arachnida: Acari) of Zambia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Published literature on the mites of Zambia (formerly Northern Rhodesia) is scanty and fragmentary. As a baseline for further work to enhance knowledge of this fauna, an annotated list of the taxa reported to date is presented. Data for 90 species or incompletely identified species (representing four orders, 42 families and 57 genera) are given. The mites originated from vertebrates, invertebrates, plants, bat guano, house dust and freshwater habitats. Seventeen species are either introduced predators that have evidently not established or are concluded to be incorrect records. A host/habitat–mite checklist is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Northern Rhodesia; Zambia; mites; checklist; Acari</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Northern Rhodesia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mwase</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Baker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Strigeid parasites of the roadside hawk, &lt;i&gt;Buteo magnirostris&lt;/i&gt; (Aves: Falconiformes), from Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An examination of four specimens of the roadside hawk, &lt;i&gt;Buteo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnirostris&lt;/i&gt; (Accipitridae) from Formosa Province, Argentina revealed the presence of three strigeid species: &lt;i&gt;Ophiosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microcephalum&lt;/i&gt; Szidat, 1928, &lt;i&gt;Strigea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falconis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliana&lt;/i&gt; Szidat, 1929 and &lt;i&gt;Strigea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magniova&lt;/i&gt; Dubois, 1988. All three species are redescribed and illustrated. The reports of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falconis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magniova&lt;/i&gt; represent the first records of the genus &lt;i&gt;Strigea&lt;/i&gt; Abildgaard, 1790 from Argentina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Buteo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnirostris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ophiosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microcephalum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Strigea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falconis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Strigea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magniova&lt;/i&gt;; Strigeidae; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Buteo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnirostris&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lunaschi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Drago</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-33</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Andean species of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus &lt;/i&gt;of the &lt;i&gt;darwinii &lt;/i&gt;Complex (Reptilia: Iguanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Iguanidae Liolaeminae from the Parque Nacional San Guillermo, San Juan province in western Argentina, is described. The new species is member of the &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;darwinii&lt;/i&gt; complex within the monophyletic &lt;i&gt;boulengeri&lt;/i&gt; species group. It is characterized by small body size, long tail, relatively low number of scales around midbody, dorsal scales keeled, precloacal pores only in male, bulged patch of enlarged scales on the proximal posterior surface of the thigh in both sexes, and a dorsal color pattern in the male of 12–13 pairs of dark paravertebral spots and irregularly scattered light blue and white scales “speckled” on reddish brown ground. Both sexes lack of light vertebral or dorsolateral stripes. &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is terrestrial, dwelling on rocky gravel and sandy soil in a Monte landscape with sparse vegetation, and seems to have low population density.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanezi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Iguanidae; Squamata; Reptilia; Taxonomy; Parque Nacional San Guillermo; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanezi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mario</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cabrera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Monguillot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new records of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ribautia&lt;/i&gt; Brölemann, 1909 (Chilopoda: Geophilomorpha: Geophilidae) from South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Neotropical Geophilomorpha are described: &lt;i&gt;Ribautia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;combinata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Peru and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;donatellae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil. New records from Amazonia are given for &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ducalis&lt;/i&gt; Pereira, Minelli &amp; Barbieri, 1995. &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proxima&lt;/i&gt; Pereira, Minelli &amp; Barbieri, 1994 is recorded for the first time from Guyane française. &lt;i&gt;Schizoribautia&lt;/i&gt; Brölemann, 1912 is synonymized under &lt;i&gt;Ribautia&lt;/i&gt; Brölemann, 1909, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myriapoda; Chilopoda; Geophilomorpha; Geophilidae; &lt;i&gt;Ribautia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new records; Neotropical Region; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myriapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pereira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Uliana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Minelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1105.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jan. 2006</title>
    <volume>1105</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Bryofauna of Remote Coastal Labrador: including a review of current Canadian records</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nematodes, tardigrades and bdelloid rotifers were identified from moss samples collected from sites near three remote towns in northern, coastal Labrador, Canada. Twenty-three nematode genera, 18 tardigrade species and six rotifer species were identified. All findings were new records for Labrador and many were new records for Canada including three nematode genera (Zeldia Thorne, &lt;i&gt;Daptonema&lt;/i&gt; Cobb and &lt;i&gt;Steineria&lt;/i&gt; Mikoletzky) and two species of rotifer (Macrotrachela &lt;i&gt;punctata&lt;/i&gt; Murray and &lt;i&gt;Macrotrachela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculata&lt;/i&gt; Murray). Canadian bryofaunal studies are reviewed and distributional patterns for Canadian taxa are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nematoda; Tardigrada; Rotifera; range extensions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nematoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Boeckner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Collins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Finney-Crawley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bateman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Cicada orni &lt;/i&gt;Linnaeus (Hemiptera, Cicadidae) from Lesbos island in Greece</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A male of &lt;i&gt;Cicada&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orni&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 from the island of Lesbos (Greece) was found in a recent study to be different from the typical species on the basis of longer echemes and a higher peak frequency. As such it was described as the new subspecies &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lesbosiensis&lt;/i&gt; Boulard, 2000. The present study is a more thorough analysis of the calling song of further material of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orni&lt;/i&gt; collected in the island of Lesbos as well as in the surrounding area, i.e., other Aegean islands and the Greek and Turkish mainlands. This acoustic signal was recorded, comparatively analysed in time and frequency domains and no significant differences were found between this Lesbos sample with nearby populations. Therefore, the present results do not support the designation of the Lesbos material as an independent subspecies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hemiptera; &lt;i&gt;Cicada&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orni&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomic status; acoustic signals; bioacoustics; Lesbos; Greece</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hemiptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Simoes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Boulard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Quartau</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Exaerete &lt;/i&gt;Hoffmannsegg (Hymenoptera: Apidae: Euglossini) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper describes males of a new species of the cleptoparasitic euglossine genus &lt;i&gt;Exaerete&lt;/i&gt; Hoffmannsegg. &lt;i&gt;Exaerete&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guaykuru&lt;/i&gt; Anjos-Silva and Rebêlo &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; was found in the moist forest of Planalto dos Guimarães, located in the Chapada dos Guimarães National Park in southern Mato Grosso, Brazil. Three males were captured using methyl salycilate baits in November 2004, at the beginning of the wet season. Illustrations of male features, including genitalia, and a key to species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Apinae; &lt;i&gt;Exaerete&lt;/i&gt;; orchid bees; cleptoparasitic euglossine; new species; taxonomy; moist forest; Brazil; Neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Apinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>J. D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Anjos-Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rebelo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclature and type material of the marine gastropod &lt;i&gt;Euplica scripta &lt;/i&gt;(Lamarck, 1822) (Sorbeoconcha: Buccinoidea: Columbellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This contribution stabilises the species-level nomenclature of a very common and widespread IndoPacific species of dove snail (Columbellidae). This species has had a confused nomenclature through uncertainty over secondary homonymy. Despite bearing the same epithet, the scientific names &lt;i&gt;Murex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scriptus&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 and &lt;i&gt;Colombella&lt;/i&gt; (sic) &lt;i&gt;scripta&lt;/i&gt; Lamarck, 1822 are not, and never have been, secondary homonyms because the species they represent are located in separate genera (and subfamilies) in the Columbellidae (i.e., presently in &lt;i&gt;Mitrella&lt;/i&gt; (Pyreninae) and &lt;i&gt;Euplica&lt;/i&gt; (Columbellinae), respectively) and the Lamarckian epithet has never been formally or intentionally replaced on the grounds of homonymy. A case of secondary homonymy would only arise in the future if an author considered them congeneric which, given the current trend for greater generic splitting in the family to accommodate monophyletic clades, appears highly unlikely. In order to settle the nomenclature unambiguously and avoid possible future taxonomic difficulties with species related to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scripta&lt;/i&gt; i.e., &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;varians&lt;/i&gt; (G.B. Sowerby 1, 1822), &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bidentata&lt;/i&gt; (Menke, 1843) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borealis&lt;/i&gt; (Pilsbry, 1904), a specimen from the Philippine Islands is herein selected as neotype for &lt;b&gt;both&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Columbella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scripta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;versicolor&lt;/i&gt; G.B. Sowerby 1, 1832, the most frequently used junior synonym, in the absence of any definite syntypes. In other words, the names &lt;i&gt;Colombella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scripta&lt;/i&gt; Lamarck and &lt;i&gt;Columbella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;versicolor&lt;/i&gt; G.B. Sowerby 1 are henceforth objective synonyms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gastropoda; Columbellidae; &lt;i&gt;Columbella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euplica&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mitrella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;scripta&lt;/i&gt;; nomenclature; type material</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gastropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Willan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus microtis &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;M. microtympanum,&lt;/i&gt; and a comparison with other large Madagascan stream frogs (Anura: Mantellidae: Mantellinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We revise two stream frogs, &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum,&lt;/i&gt; providing data on its known distribution and life history traits, based upon observations in nature. For &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtis&lt;/i&gt; we show for the first time photographs of the live individuals, while for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum&lt;/i&gt; we also describe its putative tadpoles. The transfer of &lt;i&gt;microtis&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; is formally justified by morphological and ecological traits, e.g., the lack of nuptial pads, the torrenticolous life style and the low number of eggs. &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtis&lt;/i&gt; shares some characters with &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum:&lt;/i&gt; distribution (both live in south-eastern Madagascar), natural history (both are stream frogs), morphology (wide digital expansions, lack of femoral glands, presence of a mostly unforked omosternum, cryptic dorsal colouration, small tympanum, and presence of a derived cloacal structure). &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum&lt;/i&gt; differs from the species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; (M. &lt;i&gt;grandidieri&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guttulatus),&lt;/i&gt; to which it was so far ascribed, for the lack (vs. presence) of femoral glands, and presence of expanded (vs. moderately expanded) fingertips. Whether &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtympanum&lt;/i&gt; are phylogenetically related, or their overall similarity is due to convergence, is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Boophis&lt;/i&gt;; Madagascar; Ecology; Generic attribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Andreone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nussbaum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-01-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
