<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1277.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1277</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Copepods of the family Dirivultidae (Siphonostomatoida) from deep-sea hydrothermal vent fields on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge at 14ºN and 5ºS</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five species of three genera of Dirivultidae Humes and Dojiri, 1980 were found at deep-sea hydrothermal vent fields on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, at the Logachev-1 field at 14ºN and at two new sites (Turtle Pits and Red Lion) explored at 5ºS. The copepods were collected with a Remotely Operated Vehicle (ROV Quest 4000) and Video Controlled Grab, operated from the &lt;i&gt;R/V&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Meteor&lt;/i&gt; during two cruises (M60/3 and M64/1) conducted in 2004 and 2005 at depths 2992–3048 m. The male of &lt;i&gt;Stygiopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lomonosovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the Logachev field shares a medioventrally prolonged syncoxa of the maxilliped with &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirus&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1996 and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latulus&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1996 from the Snake Pit at 23ºN of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, but differs from them in having two, instead of three, outer spines on the distal exopodal segment of leg 4. &lt;i&gt;Aphotopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanteus&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1996 previously known from the Lucky Strike and the Menez Gwen sites at 37°N and &lt;i&gt;Rimipontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediospinifer&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1996 known from three sites (Logachev, Snake Pit, and Broken Spur at 29°N) are recorded from the Logachev field. &lt;i&gt;Stygiopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectinatus&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1987 previously recorded from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge hydrothermal vent fields TAG (26°N), Snake Pit, Broken Spur (29°N), and from the Mariana Back-Arc Basin of the Pacific Ocean and &lt;i&gt;Stygiopontius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cladarus&lt;/i&gt; Humes, 1996 previously known only from Snake Pit and Broken Spur, were found associated with alvinocaridid shrimps (Rimicaris sp.) from the hydrothermal vent field at 5ºS. The discovery of dirivultids at 5ºS represents the first record of copepods from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent southward of the Logachev field in the Atlantic Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Siphonostomatoida; Dirivultidae; deep-sea hydrothermal vents; MidAtlantic Ridge; symbiosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ivanenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Arbizu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Stecher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Losdolobus &lt;/i&gt;Platnick &amp; Brescovit, 1994 (Araneae: Dysderoidea: Orsolobidae) from southern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Losdolobus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xarruanus&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. from Palmas, Bagé, state of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, is described as new, based on one male and one female collected in pitfall traps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spider; taxonomy; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spider</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Almeida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-27</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Kalliapseudes obtusifrons &lt;/i&gt;(Haswell, 1882), from Southeast Australia (Crustacea: Tanaidacea: Apseudomorpha: Kalliapseudidae), with the designation of a lectotype</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusifrons&lt;/i&gt; (Haswell) is redescribed and referred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Kalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto.&lt;/i&gt; It can be distinguished from the other members of the genus by the nature of the ventral spines on the propodus of pereopods IV and V, the dorsal setation of the merus and the armature on the dactylus of pereopod VI. A key to the four species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Kalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; known from Australian waters is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Tanaidacea; Apseudomorpha; &lt;i&gt;Kalliapseudes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusifrons&lt;/i&gt;; redescription; Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Drumm</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An overview of the South African tangle-veined flies (Diptera: Nemestrinidae), with an annotated key to the genera and a checklist of species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The South African Nemestrinidae are reviewed. Regional family characteristics, biology and the importance of long-proboscid species in pollination biology are discussed. Long-proboscid species (proboscis 15 mm or longer) are important pollinators in most provinces, but particularly in the Western Cape; all have specialised pollination interactions with long-tubed flower species. Five pollination guilds centered on long-proboscid species are briefly discussed. A detailed, annotated key to the six genera is presented; in it particular attention is given to the problematic distinction between &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca&lt;/i&gt; Schiner and &lt;i&gt;Stenobasipteron&lt;/i&gt; Lichtwardt. A checklist of all described species considered to have a South African provenance is provided. A total of 43 described species is recorded in the following genera: &lt;i&gt;Moegistorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; Macquart (4 species); &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca&lt;/i&gt; (35 species); &lt;i&gt;Stenobasipteron&lt;/i&gt; (1 species); &lt;i&gt;Atriadops&lt;/i&gt; Wandolleck (1 species); &lt;i&gt;Nycterimyia&lt;/i&gt; Lichtwardt (1 species); &lt;i&gt;Trichopsidea&lt;/i&gt; Westwood (1 species). &lt;i&gt;Moegistorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to the west coast (Western Cape, Northern Cape). Three of its species have a remarkably elongate proboscis, the best known and most widespread being &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longirostris&lt;/i&gt; (Wiedemann, 1819). Its proboscis reaches 90 to 100 mm in length in some specimens, this being the longest proboscis of all known Diptera. Two new species have been identified in the fauna. &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca&lt;/i&gt; dominates the fauna, and is the only genus likely to be represented in all nine provinces. It appears to occur in all habitats except closed-canopy forest. &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi, 1924 is newly synonymised with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robusta&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi, 1924. The likely South African provenance of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripes&lt;/i&gt; (Macquart, 1840) is confirmed. &lt;i&gt;Nemestrina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; Westwood, 1835, previously referred to &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca,&lt;/i&gt; is considered not to be an Afrotropical species. &lt;i&gt;Prosoeca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhodesiensis&lt;/i&gt; Bequaert, 1925a, is recorded from South Africa for the first time. Although &lt;i&gt;Stenobasipteron&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to only one named South African species, namely &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wiedemanni&lt;/i&gt; Lichtwardt, 1910 from the Eastern Cape and KwaZulu-Natal, several undescribed species occur in Mpumalanga and Limpopo. &lt;i&gt;Stenobasipteron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wiedemanni&lt;/i&gt; occurs in closed-canopy forest, but species from Mpumalanga may occur in other habitats such as grassland and savanna. There are at least two species of &lt;i&gt;Atriadops,&lt;/i&gt; one almost certainly being &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vespertilio&lt;/i&gt; (Loew,</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barraclough</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-63</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First description of the adult male of &lt;i&gt;Epeorus aculeatus &lt;/i&gt;Braasch (Ephemeroptera: Heptageniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male imago of the southeast Asian species &lt;i&gt;Epeorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeatus&lt;/i&gt; Braasch is described for the first time, based on reared material from Thailand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ephemeroptera; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Epeorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeatus;&lt;/i&gt; Heptageniidae; stage description; Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ephemeroptera; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Epeorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeatus;&lt;/i&gt; Heptageniidae; stage description; Asia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Webb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccafferty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Crinoidea and Holothuroidea (Echinodermata) of the abyssal Angola BasinResults of the DIVA-1 expedition of FS "Meteor" (Cruise M48/1)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Agassiz trawl and epibenthic sledge samples taken at abyssal depths in the Angola Basin (southeastern Atlantic Ocean) during the expedition DIVA-1 with FS "Meteor" in July 2000 yielded a rich variety of Echinodermata: inter alia one stalked crinoid (Bathycrinus cf. &lt;i&gt;aldrichianus&lt;/i&gt; Wyville Thomson, 1876) and altogether nine holothurian species, two of which are subspecies. One of these, &lt;i&gt;Achlyonice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is new to science, while all others have been described earlier: &lt;i&gt;Deima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;validum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;validum&lt;/i&gt; Théel, 1879, &lt;i&gt;Psychropotes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semperiana&lt;/i&gt; Théel, 1882, &lt;i&gt;Peniagone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurea&lt;/i&gt; (Théel, 1882), &lt;i&gt;Molpadiodemas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticus&lt;/i&gt; (R. Perrier, 1898), &lt;i&gt;Molpadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liska&lt;/i&gt; Pawson, 1977, &lt;i&gt;Protankyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brychia&lt;/i&gt; (Verrill, 1885), &lt;i&gt;Siniotrochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;myriodontus&lt;/i&gt; Gage &amp; Billett, 1986 and &lt;i&gt;Neolepidotrochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvidiscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angolensis&lt;/i&gt; Bohn, 2005. All species collected are described and their known distributions are given. Finally, two crinoids and 21 holothurian species, so far known from the abyssal Angola Basin, are listed and their zoogeographical relationships are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Echinodermata; Crinoidea; Holothuroidea; South Atlantic Ocean; Angola Basin; deepsea; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Echinodermata; Crinoidea; Holothuroidea; South Atlantic Ocean; Angola Basin; deepsea; taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bohn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1276.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1276</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helobdella nahuelhuapensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Hirudinea, Glossiphoniidae), from Bariloche, Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new freshwater leech species &lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nahuelhuapensis&lt;/i&gt; is described based on the examination of 17 specimens collected near Nahuel Huapi Lake, Bariloche, Argentina with following diagnostic characters. Body thin and lanceolate. Chitinoid scute absent. Unpigmented region (nuchal gland) at somite VIII. Annuli subdivided dorsally. Dorsum surface lacking both papillae and tubercles. One pair of eyes on somite III; mouth pore in the anterior margin of the oral sucker; proboscis base at XII/XIII, diffuse parenchymal salivary tissue; oesophagus simple; crop with gastric chambers; postcaeca or diverticula extending posteriorly; intestine with four caeca. Six pairs of spherical testisacs; sperm ducts reach to somite XV/XVI. Atrium pyriform without preatrial loops. Ovisacs simple, reaching XIV.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Argentina; leech; freshwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helobdella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gullo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the male of &lt;i&gt;Pikelinia tambilloi&lt;/i&gt; (Mello-Leitão, 1941) and its synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Pikelinia toba &lt;/i&gt;Ramírez &amp; Grismado, 1997 (Araneae: Filistatidae: Prithinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male and female of &lt;i&gt;Pikelinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tambilloi&lt;/i&gt; (Mello-Leitão, 1941) is redescribed from specimens recently collected in Santiago del Estero and Córdoba, Argentina. We report on variability in the internal female genitalia, and newly synonymize &lt;i&gt;Pikelinia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toba&lt;/i&gt; Ramírez &amp; Grismado with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tambilloi.&lt;/i&gt; The known range of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tambilloi&lt;/i&gt; is thus widely extended. New records of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolla&lt;/i&gt; Ramírez &amp; Grismado from Argentina are also reported.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spiders; taxonomy; new synonymy; Neotropics; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramírez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-45</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Some zerconid mites (Acari: Mesostigmata: Zerconidae) from Kosovo (Serbia-Montenegro) with description of &lt;i&gt;Zercon kosovina &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three Zerconid mite species were collected in Kosovo (Serbia and Montenegro). Two of them, &lt;i&gt;Zercon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moravicus&lt;/i&gt; Halaškova, 1970 and &lt;i&gt;Prozercon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriatus&lt;/i&gt; (C. L. Koch, 1839), are known species, but the third, &lt;i&gt;Zercon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kosovina&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., proved to be new to science.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Zerconidae; new species; Kosovo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Kontschán</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-53</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval morphology of &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus cuspidifer &lt;/i&gt;Piersig, &lt;i&gt;A. claviger&lt;/i&gt; Koenike, and &lt;i&gt;A. latus &lt;/i&gt;Barrois &amp; Moniez (Acari: Hydrachnidia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The larva of &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latus&lt;/i&gt; is re-described and the larvae of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuspidifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;claviger&lt;/i&gt; are described for the first time. The larvae of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuspidifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;claviger&lt;/i&gt; share characters, such as shape of dorsal plate, shape of excretory pore plate and ratios of medial margins of coxal plates, which they also share with other &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus&lt;/i&gt; s. str. species. In constrast, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latus,&lt;/i&gt; a member of &lt;i&gt;Micrarrenurus,&lt;/i&gt; lacks these characters. Instead, it closely resembles other members of &lt;i&gt;Micrarrenurus&lt;/i&gt; such as &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albator,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbraitus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassicaudatus&lt;/i&gt; in having similar shape of dorsal plates, similar shape of excretory pore plates and pectinate setae on the PV3 and PV4 of the pedipalps. Therefore, the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Micrarrenurus&lt;/i&gt; is further supported by characters of larval morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Parasitengona; water mite; &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus&lt;/i&gt; s. str.; &lt;i&gt;Micrarrenurus&lt;/i&gt;; larvae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Parasitengona</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zawal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1275.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1275</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Simulium &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Inaequalium&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;petropoliense &lt;/i&gt;Coscarón (Diptera: Simuliidae) from Brazil, with the first description of the male and larva</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe the male and larva of &lt;i&gt;Simulium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petropoliense&lt;/i&gt; for the first time and redescribe the female and pupa. All morphological characters are fully illustrated and comparisons with closely related species are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">black fly; Neotropical region; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Inaequalium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petropoliense&lt;/i&gt;; Brazil; Simuliidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">black fly</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Luna Dias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Maia-Herzog</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shelley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rivulus sape&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of killifish (Cyprinodontiformes: Rivulidae) from the Paragua River system, Caroní River drainage, Guyana Shield, Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sape,&lt;/i&gt; is described from two tributaries of the upper Paragua River, Caroní River drainage, of the Guyana Shield in Venezuela. It is a small (all specimens examined less than 50 mm SL), apparently non-annual species that is distinguished from congeners in having the dorsal, anal, and pelvic fins short; adult males with a truncate caudal fin with the upper and lower borders black; and an iridescent blue, ovate spot on sides of the body above the pectoral fins. Neither adults nor juveniles have an ocellus at the dorsal junction of the caudal peduncle and caudal fin. Only one contact organ per scale on some scales along the sides of the body was observed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Fish; Killifish; &lt;i&gt;Rivulus&lt;/i&gt;; Rivulidae; Caroní River drainage; Orinoco River basin; Guyana Shield; Venezuela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lasso-Alcalá</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Taphorn</middlename>
          <lastname>B.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lasso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>O.</firstname>
          <lastname>León-Mata</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-29</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and three new species of Phyllocoptini (Acari: Eriophyidae: Phyllocoptinae) from the Qinling Mountains, Shaanxi Province, northwestern China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and three new species of eriophyid mites from the Qinling Mountains, Shaanxi Province, northwestern China are described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Calvittacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Juglans&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;regia&lt;/i&gt; L. (Juglandaceae); &lt;i&gt;Calepitrimerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dendrobenthamiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Dendrobenthamia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;var.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Osborn) Fang (Cornaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Calepitrimerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fopingi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Lindera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glauca&lt;/i&gt; (Sieb. et Zucc.) Blume (Lauraceae). All the species are vagrant on the undersurface of leaves. No apparent damages were found on the host plant. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Calepitrimerus&lt;/i&gt; from China is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">eriophyid mite; taxonomy; key; &lt;i&gt;Calvittacus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Calepitrimerus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">eriophyid mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Z.-W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-41</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the pollen-beetle genus &lt;i&gt;Meligethes &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera: Nitidulidae) of the &lt;i&gt;M. aeneus &lt;/i&gt;group from Greece, with review of the &lt;i&gt;M. subaeneus &lt;/i&gt;complex</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A morphological analysis was performed, combined with field data on insect/host-plant associations to clarify the taxonomic scenario of the Palaearctic &lt;i&gt;Meligethes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subaeneus&lt;/i&gt; complex (Coleoptera, Nitidulidae, Meligethinae), including three European and Caucasian species (M. &lt;i&gt;subaeneus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matronalis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;epeirosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.)&lt;/b&gt; that are associated with flowers of Brassicaceae for larval development. The analysis was focused on the diagnosis and formal description of a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;epeirosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.&lt;/b&gt; from NW Greece (Pindo Chain), which develops on &lt;i&gt;Cardamine&lt;/i&gt; (s.str.) &lt;i&gt;glauca&lt;/i&gt; Sprengel. The morphological variation of the true &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subaeneus&lt;/i&gt; in Europe was also analysed; the combined morphological and ecological evidence suggests that this species is structured in three main groups of European populations, which are probably the result of Pleistocene differentiation, suggesting an ongoing process of incipient speciation within this taxon.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Nitidulidae; &lt;i&gt;Meligethes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Greece; Brassicaceae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Audisio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mancini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Biase</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-60</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of two new spider genera of Trechaleidae (Araneae: Lycosoidea) from Northern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera of Trechaleidae are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Amapalea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; type species &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brasiliana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from Amapá, and &lt;i&gt;Magnichela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; type species &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santeremensis&lt;/i&gt; from Pará, both states located in Northern Brazil region. &lt;i&gt;Amapalea&lt;/i&gt; presents a tegular projection not found in any other Trechaleidae genera, like &lt;i&gt;Paratrechalea&lt;/i&gt; Carico, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;Paradossenus&lt;/i&gt; F.O.P.Cambridge, 1903. &lt;i&gt;Magnichela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from the other genera and from &lt;i&gt;Amapalea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; by the enlarged and apically expanded chelicerae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spiders; taxonomy; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>L. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1260.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1260</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A genus level revision of the Thamnocephalidae (Crustacea: Branchiopoda: Anostraca)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Thamnocephalidae, especially the genus &lt;i&gt;Branchinella,&lt;/i&gt; has become a mélange of genera and species with unclear affinities. A genus level revision of the family, using modern taxonomic standards, is presented. Two distinct subfamilies are recognized, consisting of six genera (including one new genus): &lt;i&gt;Thamnocephalus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Carinophallus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. in the Thamnocephalinae, and; &lt;i&gt;Dendrocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Phallocryptus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gurneya,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt; in the Branchinellinae. Three genera are each composed of two subgenera: &lt;i&gt;Thamnocephalus&lt;/i&gt; (Thamnocephalus and &lt;i&gt;Simplicephalus),&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Dendrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; (Dendrocephalus and &lt;i&gt;Dendrocephalinus&lt;/i&gt; subgen. nov.), and &lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt; (Branchinella and &lt;i&gt;Branchinellites&lt;/i&gt; stat. nov.). A key to the genera is presented coupled with a checklist of all described species in the family, and &lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hardingi&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed from presumed paratype material.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Branchinellites&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Carinophallus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dendrocephalinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dendrocephalus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gurneya&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phallocryptus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thamnocephalus&lt;/i&gt;; fairy shrimp; new genus; new subgenus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Branchinella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rogers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the male of &lt;i&gt;Tityus martinpaechi &lt;/i&gt;Lourenço, 2001 (Scorpiones, Buthidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinpaechi&lt;/i&gt; Lourenço, 2001 was described based on a single adult female collected in the state of Ceará, Brazil. Subsequently, several scorpions of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; were collected in the Chapada de Ibiapaba, Ceará, and sent to the Instituto Butantan in São Paulo, Brazil. One female and one male of these scorpions were identified as belonging to the species &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinpaechi.&lt;/i&gt; Since the male of this species is yet unknown, it is described in this paper.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scorpiones; &lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martinpaechi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tityus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stigmurus&lt;/i&gt; complex; Chapada de Ibiapaba; Ceará; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scorpiones</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Souza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Candido</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lourenço</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new European species of &lt;i&gt;Pegomya &lt;/i&gt;Robineau-Desvoidy (Diptera: Anthomyiidae) near &lt;i&gt;P. testacea &lt;/i&gt;(De Geer)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pegomya&lt;/i&gt; Robineau-Desvoidy, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prisca&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described from Europe (Sweden, Czech Republic and Slovakia). It belongs to a species group together with the widespread West Palaearctic &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; (De Geer) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hamata&lt;/i&gt; Wei described from China. Differential descriptions and illustrations of the terminalia are given for the two species of the &lt;i&gt;Pegomya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; species group found in Europe. Morphological and other evidence suggests that saprophagous larval habits persist in a few species of &lt;i&gt;Pegomya&lt;/i&gt; represented by the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ruficeps&lt;/i&gt; species groups.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Anthomyiidae; Pegomya; new species; Europe</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Michelsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-46</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Referral of the Halocypridina &lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris &lt;/i&gt;(Miocene, Australia) to the Cladocopina (Ostracoda, Halocyprida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">B. K. Nadeau in 1955 identified as &lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris&lt;/i&gt; ostracodes from the middle Miocene Glenample Clay of Victoria, southeastern Australia. Nadeau’s collection of Ostracoda from the Glenample Clay was located in the collections of the Museum of Victoria, Melbourne. Examination of that material indicates that the Glenample Clay specimens attributed by Nadeau to &lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris&lt;/i&gt; belong to &lt;i&gt;Polycope&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctacatherinae&lt;/i&gt; Whatley &amp; Downing 1983. As a result, it is concluded that &lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris&lt;/i&gt; has not been collected in the Miocene of Australia. Furthermore, in a broader biostratigraphic/palaeobiogeographic context, the result confirms that no member of the Suborder Halocypridina has been reported so far from the Tertiary Period.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Polycope&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctacatherinae&lt;/i&gt;; Ostracoda; Miocene; southeastern Australia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thaumatocypris&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Warne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jones</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kornicker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ptychognathus &lt;/i&gt;Stimpson, 1858 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Varunidae) from the Ryukyu Islands, southwestern Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new varunid crab, &lt;i&gt;Ptychognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insolitus,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Izena Island, the Ryukyu Islands, southwestern Japan. This new species is unique among congeners in having a very broad carapace, long and slender ambulatory legs, and stout male first gonopods. Although these characters are diagnostic to &lt;i&gt;Orcovita&lt;/i&gt; Ng &amp; Tomascik, 1994, the new species belongs to &lt;i&gt;Ptychognathus&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858 based on the lack of a distinct frontal median triangle on the carapace and the short dactyli of the fifth pereopods.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Varunidae; &lt;i&gt;Ptychognathus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Ryukyu Islands; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Osawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-66</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1259.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1259</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Astacilla boreaphilis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Isopoda: Valvifera) from shallow and deep North Atlantic waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Astacilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boreaphilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from shallow and deep waters off Iceland and Greenland. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boreaphilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is easily distinguished from all but one of the &lt;i&gt;Astacilla&lt;/i&gt; species recorded from the North Atlantic by the absence of eyes and from all other &lt;i&gt;Astacilla&lt;/i&gt; species by the pattern of the spines on the body. The species shows pronounced sexual dimorphism. The species occurs at depths between 219 and 1809 m and at temperatures between 2.4°C and 7.2°C. The species is therefore restricted to Atlantic Water (AW), characterizing the area south of the Greenland–Iceland–Færoe Ridge and to Atlantic Water presumably diluted by cold water masses from the Nordic Seas. The depth range in the area differs locally and may be limited by cold water currents crossing the Ridge.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Arcturidae; &lt;i&gt;Astacilla&lt;/i&gt;; Iceland; Greenland</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Stransky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Svavarsson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-23</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Richardiidae (Diptera) from Hispaniola</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of richardiid flies are described from the Neotropical biotic region (Johnrichardia Perez-Gelabert &amp; Thompson, type species, &lt;i&gt;vockerothi&lt;/i&gt; Perez-Gelabert &amp; Thompson (Dominican Republic)).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Richardiidae; Neotropical Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Perez-Gelabert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Thompson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Symphytognathidae (Araneae), a spider family newly recorded from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Symphytognathidae is reported from China for the first time. A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Anapistula&lt;/i&gt; Gertsch, 1941, named &lt;i&gt;Anapistula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;appendix&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described and figured. The spider was recorded in a cave in Hainan, the second-largest island in southern China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anapistula&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Hainan; cave</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anapistula&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Y.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Tong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-38</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new and exceptional poison dart frogs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dendrobates &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Dendrobatidae) from the Northeastern Flank of the cordillera Central of Colombia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We name and describe two new species of poison dart frogs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dendrobates,&lt;/i&gt; from the northeastern flank of the cordillera Central in the departamentos de Tolima and Caldas. Those frogs share an exceptional synapomorphy within the family, which consists of a first toe reduced and fused with the second toe, allowing only four toes to be seen externally. Perhaps this unusual characteristic is reason to create a new genus within the Dendrobatidae, however, this must await a period of further investigation of the phylogeny of these two species, including a molecular and anatomic analysis. Elucidating the taxonomic position of these species and the naming a new genus, if found to be appropriate and applicable, will be the subject of a future manuscript.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Colombia; cordillera Central; Dendrobatidae; &lt;i&gt;Dendrobates&lt;/i&gt;; digital reduction; new species; digital reduction</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rueda-Almonacid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Rada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sánchez-Pacheco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Á.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Velásquez-Álvarez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Quevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-54</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cryptalyra &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera, Megalyridae) from Brazil with a key to species of the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cryptalyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dep&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ressa&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described and illustrated based on a specimen from state of Pará, Brazil. This species is easily recognizable by having a wide longitudinal depression along the propodeum. A key to species based on females is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Wasps; Neotropical region ; Taxonomy; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Wasps</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Azevedo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tavares</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of &lt;i&gt;Simognathus &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Halacaridae) from Mexico, including the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Simognathus&lt;/i&gt; and of the subfamily Simognathinae from Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Simognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cramerae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Mexican tropical Pacific Ocean. The principal diagnostic features are dorsal setae 2 outside of ocular plate, dorsal setae 3 on anterodorsal plate, and second segment of pedipalp with a ventral bristle and without a ventral apophysis. This species resembles &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscus&lt;/i&gt; Viets, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; Bartsch, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hulingsi&lt;/i&gt; Newell.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Halacaridae; Simognathinae; &lt;i&gt;Simognathus&lt;/i&gt;; Mexico; Mexican tropical Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Halacaridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gerardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Rivas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1258.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1258</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contribution to the knowledge of the preimaginal stages of the genus &lt;i&gt;Smicridea &lt;/i&gt;McLachlan in South America (Trichoptera: Hydropsychidae: Smicrideinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species of &lt;i&gt;Smicridea&lt;/i&gt; occur in South and Central America, the major islands of the Antilles, and in the southwestern United States. Of the 172 known species in the genus, the preimaginal stages of only 16 have been described. In the present work, the larvae and pupae of 5 species of &lt;i&gt;Smicridea&lt;/i&gt; are described from South America: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (Smicridea) &lt;i&gt;annulicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Blanchard), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (Rhyacophylax) &lt;i&gt;dithyra&lt;/i&gt; Flint, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (S.) &lt;i&gt;frequens&lt;/i&gt; (Navás), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (R.) &lt;i&gt;pampeana&lt;/i&gt; Flint and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; (R.) &lt;i&gt;spinulosa&lt;/i&gt; Flint. &lt;i&gt;Smicridea&lt;/i&gt; (R.) &lt;i&gt;dithyra&lt;/i&gt; Flint is recorded for the first time from South America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Hydropsychidae; &lt;i&gt;Smicridea&lt;/i&gt;; larva; pupa; South America; Argentina; Neotropics; new record</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sganga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fontanarrosa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Rhacophoridae) from Guangxi Province, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Guangxi Province, China. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minimus,&lt;/i&gt; is the smallest of the known green species of &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus,&lt;/i&gt; with a SVL averaging only 28.1 mm for males and 37.0 mm for females. Other characters that separate it from other green &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; species include a smooth bright green dorsum, lacking tubercles and pattern; a white stripe from tip of snout along the upper lip and shoulder to insertion of hind limbs; reduced webbing, less than a third of the length of outer fingers; and disc of the 3 rd finger smaller than the diameter of the tympanum.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minimus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Polypedates&lt;/i&gt;; Guangxi; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.-Q.</firstname>
          <lastname>Rao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wilkinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.-N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-31</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two &lt;i&gt;Canariella &lt;/i&gt;species (Gastropoda: Helicodea: Hygromiidae) endemic to the Northwest Tenerife (Canary Islands)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giustii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and morphological data for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pontelirae&lt;/i&gt; Hutterer, 1994, previously believed extinct, are added. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giustii&lt;/i&gt; differs from all the other known species of the genus mainly by the broadened penis, with a lateral-proximal epiphallar opening and the extension of the two epiphallar folds in the penial cavity without merging in a penial papilla. Both species are endemic to Teno massif (Tenerife Island). The range of the living population of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pontelirae&lt;/i&gt; is very small, only of about 0.4 km 2 , and tourism has significant effect over the entire area. Thus, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pontelirae&lt;/i&gt; is seriously threatened. It is recommended that the species be classified as “Critically Endangered”, that it be included in the Habitats Directive Annex II and IV of the European Union, and to increase the legal protection level of its relic distribution area to the category of "Site of Scientific Interest". Nine other endemic land snail species also live at that site (among them, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giustii)&lt;/i&gt; and they would benefit from this new level of protection.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gastropoda; Hygromiidae; &lt;i&gt;Canariella&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Tenerife Island; endangered species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gastropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ibáñez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Siverio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alonso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ponte-Lira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-45</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Rhinella proboscidea &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Bufonidae) with notes on adult reproductive behavior</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proboscidea&lt;/i&gt; are described and compared with other tadpoles of the &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margaritifer&lt;/i&gt; group. The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proboscidea&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by small size (17.8 mm), tooth row formulae 2(2)/3, oral papillae only on lateral margins, jaw sheath V-shaped, spiracle sinistral, vent tube medial, body oval in dorsal view and depressed in lateral view, and color in life light brown. Tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proboscidea&lt;/i&gt; are morphologically similar to other species within this group and closely resemble those of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margaritifer&lt;/i&gt; from Cusco Amazónico and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castaneotica&lt;/i&gt; from Pará, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proboscidea&lt;/i&gt; is an explosive breeder and reproduction occurs in temporary pools or small headwaters of streams or soaks, during the rainy season.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margaritifer&lt;/i&gt; group; tadpole morphology; Central Amazonia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margaritifer&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Menin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-56</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon chilensis &lt;/i&gt;Hartlaub, 1905 (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa) from Comau Fiord, southern Chile</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; Hartlaub, 1905, a poorly known species considered as of doubtful validity, is redescribed. Material examined was collected in Comau Fiord (Chile), situated a short distance from Calbuco, the original site where the type material was collected. Morphological features of living specimens of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; are fully described and illustrated, and data are provided on the cnidome. A table that compares polyp and medusa stages of species assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; L. Agassiz, 1862 is presented. The systematic position of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; amongst the other members is discussed, and an identification key for the medusae is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Hydrozoa; Tubulariidae; redescription; &lt;i&gt;Hybocodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt;; hydroid; medusa; Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Galea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1257.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1257</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neverita delessertiana &lt;/i&gt;(Récluz &lt;i&gt;in &lt;/i&gt;Chenu, 1843): a naticid species (Gastropoda: Caenogastropoda) distinct from &lt;i&gt;Neverita duplicata&lt;/i&gt; (Say, 1822) based on molecular data, morphological characters, and geographical distribution</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The members of the caenogastropod family Naticidae show highly conserved morphological characters, which in many cases complicate species separation. In such cases DNA sequence analysis may help to distinguish between species. In this work partial sequences from the small mitochondrial ribosomal RNA (16S rRNA) gene, the small nuclear ribosomal RNA (18S rRNA) gene, a short intron of the nuclear calmodulin (Cal) gene, and the mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) gene are shown to differ significantly between the genomes of what generally had been considered to be merely two morphological variants of the common Western Atlantic naticid &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt; (Say, 1822). Sequence differences between the two forms of &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt; are similar to differences between either of these two forms and the Eastern Pacific &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reclusiana&lt;/i&gt; (Deshayes, 1839), the Indopacific &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;didyma&lt;/i&gt; (Röding, 1798), and the Mediterranean &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;josephinia&lt;/i&gt; (Risso, 1826). The COI sequences divergence between the two forms of &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt; is in the range of the average COI sequences divergence reported for congeneric species of Mollusca (Hebert 2003). We conclude that in addition to &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt; a second shallow water species of &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; exists along the US Atlantic and Gulf coasts for which the name &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delessertiana&lt;/i&gt; (Récluz, 1843) is available.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delessertiana&lt;/i&gt;; 18S rRNA; 16S rRNA; COI; calmodulin intron; molecular phylogeny; Naticidae; Polinicinae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Neverita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duplicata&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hülsken</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Clemmensen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hollmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhabdias lamothei &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Nematoda: Rhabdiasidae) from &lt;i&gt;Leptodeira maculata &lt;/i&gt;(Colubridae) in Mexico, including new records of &lt;i&gt;R. fuscovenosa &lt;/i&gt;(Railliet, 1899) Goodey, 1924</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamothei&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Nematoda: Rhabdiasidae) from the lungs of &lt;i&gt;Leptodeira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; (Colubridae) is described and illustrated. This is the 53 rd species assigned to the genus and the first species described from an endemic snake in Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamothei&lt;/i&gt; differs from all other species by having the combination of the following characters: body coiled, truncated anterior end, 6 lips, equatorial vulvae, esophagus length /body length ratio 8.36–12.46 (10.31%), tail length / body length ratio 4.49–12.28 (6.98 %), and principally by the markedly elongated tail with a sharp terminal point. The geographical distribution of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscovenosa&lt;/i&gt; is expanded in 13 localities and 6 new host records are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamothei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscovenosa&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Nematoda; Rhabdiasidae; &lt;i&gt;Leptodeira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt;; Colubridae; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamothei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhabdias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscovenosa&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martinez-Salazar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>León-Règagnon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-48</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new European species of &lt;i&gt;Pegomya &lt;/i&gt;Robineau-Desvoidy (Diptera: Anthomyiidae) near &lt;i&gt;P. flavoscutellata &lt;/i&gt;(Zetterstedt)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pegomya&lt;/i&gt; Robineau-Desvoidy is described from Europe (Sweden, Denmark and Finland) by the name of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curviphall&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;is.&lt;/i&gt; It belongs, together with the Holarctic &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavoscutellata&lt;/i&gt; (Zetterstedt) and the Nearctic &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flaviante&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nnat&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; Griffiths, in a species group defined by a sickleshaped distiphallus. Differential descriptions are given for the two European species of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavoscutel&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lata&lt;/i&gt; species group, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curviphall&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scute&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;llata.&lt;/i&gt; Larvae of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavoscutel&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lata&lt;/i&gt; are known to feed on bolete mushrooms (Leccinu &lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt; spp.), and a similar larval diet can be expected in other species of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scutellata&lt;/i&gt; species group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">: Diptera; Anthomyiidae; Pegomya; new species; Europe</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">: Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <lastname>Michelsen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Evidence for cryptic species in the tadpole shrimp &lt;i&gt;Triops granarius&lt;/i&gt; (Lucas, 1864) (Crustacea: Notostraca)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We used three ribosomal DNA markers to investigate the genetic divergence of &lt;i&gt;Triops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granarius&lt;/i&gt; (Lucas, 1864) populations from Tunisia, Namibia and Japan. The comparison of the genetic distances between these samples and those found among other species of Notostraca (both &lt;i&gt;Triops&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Lepidurus)&lt;/i&gt; strongly suggests that the three &lt;i&gt;Triops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granarius&lt;/i&gt; populations investigated belong to different, possibly cryptic species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;numidicus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lepidurus&lt;/i&gt;; molecular phylogeny; 16S; 12S; 28S; ribosomal gene</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Triops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;numidicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Korn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hundsdoerfer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1256.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1256</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic notes on the genus &lt;i&gt;Epidaus &lt;/i&gt;Stål (Heteroptera: Reduviidae: Harpactorinae) from Vietnam, with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of &lt;i&gt;Epidaus&lt;/i&gt; Stål from Vietnam are recognized and keyed. &lt;i&gt;Epidaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexspinus&lt;/i&gt; Hsiao and &lt;i&gt;Epidaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispinus&lt;/i&gt; Hsiao are reported for the first time from Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Epidaus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bachmaensis&lt;/i&gt; Truong, Zhao &amp; Cai, sp. nov. is described and its dorsal habitus, head, pronotum, male genitalia, and other diagnostic morphological features are illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reduviidae; Harpactorinae; &lt;i&gt;Epidaus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Vietnam; new species; new records; key.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reduviidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Truong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-9</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Botryllus &lt;/i&gt;(Ascidiacea) from the Red Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new ascidian species was discovered during a study of the ecology of ascidians off the Red Sea coast of Israel. This species has been provisionally assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Botryllus&lt;/i&gt; as complete details of its life cycle are not available to confirm Botrylloides as a junior synonym. The species displays characteristics of Botryllinae, in which growth is associated with active replication of zooids. The species is distinguished by the opaque pale pigmentation of the colonies, the zooid arrangement in regular double rows converging to common cloacal openings at the top of low lobes, the large number of stigmata rows, and ovary lateral to the testes. We name the new species &lt;i&gt;Botryllus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eilatensis,&lt;/i&gt; after the collecting site, the coral reef of Eilat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; synonym; ascidian; Red Sea; Gulf of Aqaba; Botrylloides</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Shenkar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Monniot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>11-19</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Engelimyia &lt;/i&gt;Lopes, 1975 (Diptera: Sarcophagidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Engelimyia&lt;/i&gt; Lopes, 1975 is revised and found to consist of four species: the already named &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bosqi&lt;/i&gt; (Blanchard, 1939) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inops&lt;/i&gt; (Walker, 1849), with the former nominal species herewith resurrected from synonymy with the latter; and two new species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;qibos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psino&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Sarcophaga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cassidifera&lt;/i&gt; Engel, 1931 [= &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inops&lt;/i&gt; (Walker, 1849)]. Male terminalia of all species are illustrated, and a key to the species is provided. The four species appear to form two sister-group pairs: &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inops&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psino&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bosqi&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;qibos,&lt;/i&gt; both of which show a South American—Central American Isthmian disjunction, which here is considered to reflect the same vicariance event and a maximum age of the four species of about 3 My.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pape</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Mello-Patiu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Curius &lt;/i&gt;Newman (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) from Venezuela with notes on sexual dimorphism within the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Curius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chemsaki&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae: Cerambycinae: Curiini), from Venezuela is described. Features distinguishing the new species from its congeners as well as a key to the four species are presented. Sexual dimorphism in pronotal and prosternal morphology within the genus is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerambycinae; Curiini; South America; taxonomy; key; long-range attractant; pheromone gland pores</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerambycinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nearns</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-57</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of the milliped order Polyzoniida from Korean Peninsula, with a redescription of &lt;i&gt;Kiusiozonium okai&lt;/i&gt; (Takakuwa &amp; Miyosi, 1949) (Diplopoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Both the genus &lt;i&gt;Kiusiozonium&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1941 and the species &lt;i&gt;Kiusiozonium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okai&lt;/i&gt; (Takakuwa &amp; Miyosi, 1949) are recorded in the fauna of Korea for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Angarozonium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;munsunum&lt;/i&gt; Mikhaljova, Golovatch, Wytwer, 2000 is new to the fauna of South Korea. &lt;i&gt;Kiusiozonium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okai&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed based upon fresh material from South Korea and Japan. Remarks are provided for the two species encountered, including notes on the variation of latter species as well as on the position of the penes in Nearctic and Palaearctic representatives of the family Polyzoniidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diplopoda; faunistics; Polyzoniidae; Hirudisomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Angarozonium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Kiusiozonium&lt;/i&gt;; Korean Peninsula</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diplopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1255.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1255</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of zerconid mites from southern Europe and the Macaronesian region (Acari: Mesostigmata: Zerconidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Prozercon&lt;/i&gt; and three new species of &lt;i&gt;Zercon&lt;/i&gt; (Acari: Zerconidae) are described and illustrated on the basis of material collected from different habitats (natural, reforested and felled habitats) in Navarra (northern Spain) and Tenerife (Canary Islands).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Mesostigmata; Zerconidae; taxonomy; Iberian peninsula; Macaronesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moraza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New lapsiine jumping spiders from Ecuador (Araneae: Salticidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera and three new species of salticid spider from eastern Ecuador are described, belonging to a group informally called "lapsiines". The new genus &lt;i&gt;Galianora&lt;/i&gt; is based on &lt;i&gt;Galianora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sacha,&lt;/i&gt; new species, and also contains &lt;i&gt;Galianora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bryicola,&lt;/i&gt; new species. The new genus &lt;i&gt;Thrandina&lt;/i&gt; includes the single new species &lt;i&gt;Thrandina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parocula.&lt;/i&gt; These genera share the ancestral salticid traits, rare among neotropical salticids, of a tarsal claw on the female palpus and a median apophysis on the male palp. &lt;i&gt;Galianora&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from other lapsiines by the round tegulum with peripheral embolus. The strikingly large posterior median eyes of &lt;i&gt;Thrandina&lt;/i&gt; are unique among New World salticids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Araneae; Salticidae; &lt;i&gt;Thrandina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Galianora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lapsias&lt;/i&gt;; lapsiines; jumping spider; new species; Ecuador</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-28</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New lyssomanine and hisponine jumping spiders from Africa (Araneae: Salticidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of salticid spider from Africa are described and illustrated. These are &lt;i&gt;Goleba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lyra,&lt;/i&gt; new species, a lyssomanine from Madagascar, &lt;i&gt;Massagris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schisma,&lt;/i&gt; new species, a hisponine from South Africa, and &lt;i&gt;Tomocyrba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andasibe,&lt;/i&gt; new species, a hisponine from Madagascar.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">: Araneae; Salticidae; &lt;i&gt;Goleba&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Massagris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tomocyrba&lt;/i&gt;; Hisponinae; Lyssomaninae; jumping spider; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">: Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>X.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lapsiines and hisponines as phylogenetically basal salticid spiders (Araneae: Salticidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Increased phylogenetic resolution of the basal lineages of salticid spiders will help us understand their early evolution and provide better outgroups for phylogenetic studies within the major clades. We gathered sequences of nuclear and mitochondrial gene regions (28S, 18S, Histone 3, 16S-ND1, CO1) and used them to reconstruct salticid phylogeny by parsimony, likelihood and Bayesian methods. Our results confirm that lapsiines and hisponines are among the basal salticids, i.e. outside the major clade Salticoida. The lapsiines are resolved as sister group to the spartaeines. The precise placement of hisponines is unclear, but they may represent a deep-branching lineage independent from the spartaeines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">: Araneae; Salticidae; &lt;i&gt;Thrandin&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; ; &lt;i&gt;Galian&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hisp&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;o&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sagris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tom&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocyrb&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; ; &lt;i&gt;Goleb&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;; lapsiines; Hisponinae; Spartaeinae; Lyssomaninae; jumping spider; basal groups; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">: Araneae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maddison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Needham</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-55</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Mursia &lt;/i&gt;Desmarest, 1823 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Calappidae) from the Andaman Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An examination of a series of calappid crabs collected from the Andaman Sea and deposited in the Zoological Reference Collection of the Raffles Museum, Singapore, revealed a new species, &lt;i&gt;Mursia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xianshengi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; It differs from the closely related &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buwaya&lt;/i&gt; Galil &amp; Takeda, 2004, in its larger size, wider carapace, and the anteriorly curved lateral spines of the carapace.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Calappidae; &lt;i&gt;Mursia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Andaman Sea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Calappidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>C. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Galil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic note on &lt;i&gt;Eupithecia cupressata &lt;/i&gt;Pearsall (Lepidoptera: Geometridae: Eupitheciini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male of &lt;i&gt;Eupithecia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cupressata&lt;/i&gt; Pearsall is described, and illustrations of adults and genitalia of both sexes are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">California; &lt;i&gt;cupressata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Eupithecia&lt;/i&gt;; Eupitheciini; Geometridae; &lt;i&gt;satyrata&lt;/i&gt; species group; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">California</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferris</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1254.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1254</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New families and subfamilies of amphipod crustaceans</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cleonardopsis&lt;/i&gt; K.H. Barnard, 1916, has been incorrectly placed in the Eusiridae. Based on mouthpart morphology, body carination and the shape of the gnathopods it is reassigned to the Amathillopsidae in the new subfamily Cleonardopsinae. Cleonardopsinae is cosmopolitan in the deep sea. &lt;i&gt;Parepimeria&lt;/i&gt; Chevreux, 1911, has been incorrectly placed in the Epimeriidae. Coleman &amp; Barnard (1991) suggested that it be moved to the Pleustidae. Bousfield &amp; Hendrycks (1994) rejected this suggestion. It is excluded from the Pleustidae because of the progressively larger and ventrally acute coxae 1 to 4, simple first and second gnathopods and carinate urosomites. &lt;i&gt;Parepimeria&lt;/i&gt; appears to be a sister taxon of &lt;i&gt;Amathillopsis&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1875, and forms the basis of a new monotypic subfamily, Parepimeriinae, within the Amathillopsidae. Parepimeriinae appears to be a Southern Ocean endemic. &lt;i&gt;Miramarassa&lt;/i&gt; Ortiz, Lalana &amp; Lio (1999) was originally placed in the Aristiidae mainly because it has an elongate ischium on gnathopod 2. It is excluded from the aristiids and the lysianassoids, because of the slender antenna 1 which is characteristically nonlysianassoid, the mandibular incisor which is curved and serrate and the lacinia mobilis which occurs on both mandibles. A monotypic family, Miramarassidae, is established which may have affinities with iphimedioid taxa. Miramarassidae is currently known only from Cuba. &lt;i&gt;Regalia&lt;/i&gt; K.H. Barnard (1930) has generally been considered as a calliopiid amphipod, although some workers have discussed its similarity to the Pleustidae. A fresh evaluation of the genus has shown that characters not considered by earlier workers, such as a callynophore on antenna 1, brush setae on antenna 2 and a straight, minutely serrate incisor on the mandible, indicate that &lt;i&gt;Regalia&lt;/i&gt; cannot be a calliopiid or a pleustid. &lt;i&gt;Regalia&lt;/i&gt; appears to be most similar to members of the Pardaliscidae, but a number of characters such as the lack of an accessory flagellum, the presence of a left and right lacinia mobilis, a well developed molar and lateral ridging on the pleosome exclude it from this family. Consequently Regaliidae is established as a new monotypic family for &lt;i&gt;Regalia,&lt;/i&gt; with an Indo-West Pacific distribution. &lt;i&gt;Sancho&lt;/i&gt; Stebbing, 1897, has most recently been placed in the Eusiridae (sensu &lt;i&gt;lato),&lt;/i&gt; but might be more suited to the Calliopiidae (sensu &lt;i&gt;stricto)&lt;/i&gt; because of its entire telson. Unlike eusirids or calliopiids, species of &lt;i&gt;Sancho&lt;/i&gt; have a non-recessed head and a dorsoventrally flattened urosome. Sanchoidae is established as a new monotypic family for &lt;i&gt;Sancho,&lt;/i&gt; currently known from shallow water in south-eastern Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; new families; new subfamilies; taxonomy; Amathillopsidae,</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Dorypetalum &lt;/i&gt;Verhoeff, 1900 (Diplopoda: Callipodida: Dorypetalidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new millipede species, &lt;i&gt;Dorypetalum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae&lt;/i&gt; (Callipodida: Dorypetalidae), is described from the Kuru Dağ Mts, European Turkey. The species is morphologically close to &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bulgaricum&lt;/i&gt; from the Rhodope Mts, SE Bulgaria but is well distinguished by the particular, racket-shaped mesal coxosternal process of gonopods. All hitherto described species in the genus are reviewed, and new illustrations are provided for &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bosniense&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trispiculigerum.&lt;/i&gt; A new key for identification of the species in the genus is made to accommodate the new findings.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">millipedes; Diplopoda; Callipodida; &lt;i&gt;Dorypetalum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Dorypetalum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helenae&lt;/i&gt; sp. n.; Turkey</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">millipedes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <lastname>Stoev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Enghoff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-43</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis sulcata &lt;/i&gt;(MClelland, 1842), with descriptions of two new species of rheophilic catfish (Teleostei: Sisoridae) from Nepal and China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The identity of &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcata&lt;/i&gt; is clarified in this study, and the species is redescribed. &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcata&lt;/i&gt; (from the Brahmaputra River drainage) can be distinguished from congeners in having a unique combination of the lack of a prominent bony spur on the anterodorsal surface of the first dorsal-fin pterygiophore, presence of a first dorsal-fin element, bifid neural spines on the complex vertebra, the neural spines of the last 2–3 preanal and first 6–7 postanal vertebrae gradually increasing in height, separate pelvic fins, a less convex snout when viewed laterally, presence of pale spots on the body, 36–39 vertebrae, 12–14 transverse laminae on the thoracic adhesive apparatus, pelvic-fin length 21.2–28.7% SL, pectoral-fin length 121.6–156.3 % HL, length of adipose-fin base 17.8–22.7% SL, length of caudal peduncle 25.0–28.3% SL, depth of caudal peduncle 4.0–5.2% SL, and eye diameter 8.8–10.6% HL. &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eddsi,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from tributaries of the Ganges River in Nepal. &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eddsi&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from congeners by a unique combination of the presence of a prominent bony spur on the anterodorsal surface of the first dorsal-fin pterygiophore, presence of a first dorsal-fin element, bifid neural spines on the complex vertebra, the neural spines of the last 2–3 preanal and first 6–7 postanal vertebrae gradually increasing in height, separate pelvic fins, gently rounded snout when viewed dorsally, presence of pale spots on the body, 36–39 vertebrae, pelvic-fin length 18.0–20.9% SL, pectoral-fin length 114.9–156.0% HL, length of adipose-fin base 19.5–24.3% SL, length of caudal peduncle 25.2–27.8% SL, depth of caudal peduncle 3.5–5.3% SL, and eye diameter 9.6–12.8% HL. &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenura,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is also described from the Irrawaddy River drainage in southwestern China. &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenura&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from congeners by a unique combination of the presence of a prominent bony spur on the anterodorsal surface of the first dorsal-fin pterygiophore, presence of a first dorsal-fin element, bifid neural spines on the complex vertebra, the neural spines of the last 2–3 preanal and first 6–7 postanal vertebrae gradually increasing in height, separate pelvic fins, presence of pale spots on the body, 38–40 vertebrae, pelvic-fin length 20.4–24.3% SL, pectoral-fin length 160.4–196.9% HL, length of adipose-fin base 18.8–23.7% SL, length of caudal peduncle 30.3–34.5% SL, depth of caudal peduncle 2.9–3.6% SL, and eye diameter 9.2–12.8% HL. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudecheneis&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1253.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1253</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A chronological catalog of the New World species of &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; L., 1758 (Chilopoda: Scolopendromorpha: Scolopendridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since 1758, 140 names have been erected for, transferred into, or assigned to species of &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; occurring in the New World. One hundred sixteen are from definite, though sometimes vague, type localities; 18 are for nominal species without type localities; three lack standing in nomenclature and are invalid; and three are &lt;i&gt;nomina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuda.&lt;/i&gt; To facilitate future studies and determining synonymies, these names are cataloged in chronological order in four listings plus a summary roster of senior names and junior subjective synonyms. Additional rosters cite primary homonyms needing rectification and species needing neotypes — ones with revisitable type localities, ones with unknown or overly generalized type localities that cannot be rechecked, and ones whose type specimens may still exist. The Mexican species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robusta&lt;/i&gt; Kraepelin, 1903,inadvertently reduced to subspecific status under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigantea&lt;/i&gt; L., 1758, in a popularized booklet, is returned to full specific status and deleted from Colombia, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiscuta&lt;/i&gt; Wood, 1861, is placed in synonymy under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heros&lt;/i&gt; Girard, 1853, which is deleted from India. &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumichrasti&lt;/i&gt; Saussure, 1860, &amp; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olmeca&lt;/i&gt; Humbert &amp; Saussure, 1969, are possible synonyms of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pomacea&lt;/i&gt; C. L. Koch, 1847. The synonymy of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridilimbata&lt;/i&gt; Daday, 1891, under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polymorpha&lt;/i&gt; Wood, 1861, is accepted, and the following established synonymies are confirmed: under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alternans&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1815 — &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sagraea&lt;/i&gt; Gervais, 1837, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cubensis&lt;/i&gt; Saussure, 1860, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;complanata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multispinata,&lt;/i&gt; &amp; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grayi,&lt;/i&gt; all by Newport, 1844, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquata&lt;/i&gt; &amp; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;testacea,&lt;/i&gt; both by Wood, 1861; under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subspinipes&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1815 — &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sexspinosa&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;placea&lt;/i&gt; &amp; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutea,&lt;/i&gt; both by Newport, 1845; under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;morsitans&lt;/i&gt; L., 1758, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brandtiana&lt;/i&gt; Gervais, 1837, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pella&lt;/i&gt; Wood, 1861; and under &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridicornis&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctidens&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844. The following generic assignments are confirmed: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lobidens&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844, in &lt;i&gt;Cormocephalus&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1845; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cormocephalina&lt;/i&gt; Kohlrausch, 1878, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipleura&lt;/i&gt; Silvestri, 1895, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chilensis&lt;/i&gt; &amp; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallida,&lt;/i&gt; both by Gervais, 1847, in &lt;i&gt;Hemiscolopendra&lt;/i&gt; Kraepelin, 1903. &lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridicornis&lt;/i&gt; Newport, 1844, a plausible inhabitant of Guyana, is deleted from Cuba and the Lesser Antilles. The publication date of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alternans&lt;/i&gt; Leach, previously thought to be 1813, is corrected to 1815, and that of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthrorhabdoides&lt;/i&gt; Ribaut, previously cited as both 1912 and 1914, is established as 1913.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropical; North America; South America; Central America; West Indies/Antilles.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scolopendra&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shelley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-50</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New distribution records for &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia americana &lt;/i&gt;(Baker) and &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia ponera &lt;/i&gt;Traub and Johnson (Siphonaptera: Ctenophthalmidae) with a review of records from the Southwestern United States</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia&lt;/i&gt; is represented in the United States by &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americana&lt;/i&gt; (Baker) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ponera&lt;/i&gt; Traub and Johnson. &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americana&lt;/i&gt; is widely distributed from the eastern seaboard of the United States to the eastern slopes of the Rocky Mountains. The western extreme of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americana&lt;/i&gt; is reported for the first time in Utah, a new state record is given for South Dakota, and additional unpublished records are provided for Arkansas, Colorado, Florida, Georgia, Indiana, Iowa, Kentucky, Montana, New Mexico, and North Carolina. The presence of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ponera&lt;/i&gt; was confirmed in SW Colorado, extending the distribution north by 480 km, additional records are provided for Arizona, and the first record of this species is documented for Texas. A distribution map for &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia&lt;/i&gt; in the southwestern United States and a discussion of their ecology is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">geographical distribution; Siphonaptera; &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Stenoponia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ponera&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">geographical distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hastriter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Haas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Sciophila &lt;/i&gt;Meigen (Diptera: Mycetophilidae) from Turkey, with a key to the Western Palaearctic species of the &lt;i&gt;S. lutea &lt;/i&gt;Macquart group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Sciophila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muglolutea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turkolutea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from southeastern Turkey are described and illustrated. The second record of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delphis&lt;/i&gt; Chandler, previously known only from the holotype, is reported. A key to the Western Palaearctic species of the &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutea&lt;/i&gt; Macquart group is provided, and data on the distribution of the Palaearctic species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mycetophilidae; &lt;i&gt;Sciophila&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Mediterranean refugium; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mycetophilidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bechev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Koç</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1252.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1252</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the Atlantic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Abyssianira &lt;/i&gt;Menzies, 1956 (Isopoda: Asellota: Paramunnidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new Atlantic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Abyssianira&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutilobi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lingula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from off Argentine and Brazilian coasts, respectively. In order to facilitate comparisons the descriptions of two previously known Atlantic species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentifrons&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1956 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentenensis&lt;/i&gt; Menzies, 1962, are completed. Four groups of dorsolateral wart-like elevations are herein described for the first time. These “warts” are present in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acutilobi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lingula&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentifrons&lt;/i&gt; and they seem to consist of agglutinated sand and detritus. The diagnosis of the genus &lt;i&gt;Abyssianira&lt;/i&gt; is emended, and a dichotomous key for these four species is offered.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Doti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Roccatagliata</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new feather mite, &lt;i&gt;Aetacarus elanoides &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Acari: Gabuci-niidae), from the Swallow-tailed Kite &lt;i&gt;Elanoides forficatus&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus) (Falconiformes: Accipitridae; Perninae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the feather mite genus &lt;i&gt;Aetacarus&lt;/i&gt; Gaud &amp; Atyeo, 1975 from the norther n subspecies of the Swallow-tailed Kite, &lt;i&gt;Elanoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficatus&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus) (Falconiformes: Accipitridae) from the southeastern U.S.A. &lt;i&gt;Aetacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elanoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other described species in the genus by the following combination of features: male with terminal membranes as wide as or wider a t base than long and seta e &lt;i&gt;h1&lt;/i&gt; slightly spatulate a t tip; female with spatulate-mucronate seta e &lt;i&gt;e2&lt;/i&gt; and thick spine-like setae &lt;i&gt;h1.&lt;/i&gt; This represents the first described feather mite from &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficatus,&lt;/i&gt; and the first &lt;i&gt;Aetacarus&lt;/i&gt; species described from a New World host.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Astigmata; Pterol ichoidea; host-mite relationships; bird; rapto r; North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Astigmata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Proctor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Zimmerman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Meyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-47</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sympagus &lt;/i&gt;Bates, 1881 (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae: Lamiinae: Acanthocinini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Sympagus&lt;/i&gt; Bates, 1881, is redescribed and redefined, with two species described as new, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cedrelis,&lt;/i&gt; from Mexico and Guatemala, and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monnei,&lt;/i&gt; from Panama. The genus &lt;i&gt;Stenopsilus&lt;/i&gt; Gilmour, 1959, is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Sympagus,&lt;/i&gt; creating &lt;i&gt;Sympagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bimaculatus,&lt;/i&gt; new combination. Comparisons are discussed between &lt;i&gt;Sympagus&lt;/i&gt; and other related genera in the tribe Acanthocinini. Characterizations, color images, and a key to all &lt;i&gt;Sympagus&lt;/i&gt; species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerambycidae; Acanthocinini; &lt;i&gt;Sympagus&lt;/i&gt;; Mexico; Central America; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerambycidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hovore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Toledo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-61</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new flightless trechodine genus and species from the South African Cape region (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Trechitae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scaurotrechodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Cape province. It is the first endemic flightless representative of the tribe Trechodini from southern Africa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trechitae; Trechodinae; Trechodini; South Africa; Cape region; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trechitae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Geginat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1250.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1250</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of deep-sea demosponges (Porifera) from the Aleutian Islands (Alaska, USA)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Deep-sea sponge habitat of the Aleutian Islands was investigated with the ROV &lt;i&gt;Jason&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;II.&lt;/i&gt; Identification of the more than 60 specimens collected at depths between 179 and 2827 m revealed nine new species of demosponges. &lt;i&gt;Megaciella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anisochela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stelodoryx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oxeata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Monanchora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laminachela&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.nov,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Echinoclathria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vasa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Euchelipluma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Esperiopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flagrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mycale&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jasoniae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Latrunculia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;velera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Latrunculia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occulta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described and compared with congeners of the area.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; Poecilosclerida; new species; taxonomy; Aleutian Islands; N-Pacific; deepsea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lehnert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Stone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Heimler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Mycteridae, Boridae, Pythidae, Pyrochroidae, and Salpingidae (Coleoptera: Tenebrionoidea) of the Maritime Provinces of Canada CHRISTOPHER G. MAJKA (Canada) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Abstract</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Excerpt</firstname>
          <lastname>Free</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Order</middlename>
          <lastname>Pdf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-51</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Echinolaophonte armiger &lt;/i&gt;(Gurney) (Copepoda: Harpacticoida) from the Gulf of Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Echinolaophonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger&lt;/i&gt; (Gurney, 1927) is redescribed from the Texas coast (Gulf of Mexico). The species has a simple but strong dorsal spinous process on the cephalosome and the pairs of minute, spiny processes along the posterodorsal margins of the prosomites and urosomites. This is the first full description of the species since Gurney’s (1927) original report from the Suez Canal. The previous reports of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger&lt;/i&gt; are reconsidered based on new morphological characters revealed in the present study. As a result, &lt;i&gt;Echinolaophonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hystrix&lt;/i&gt; (Brian, 1928) is revived as a valid species, and the status of closely related species, formerly known as &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger,&lt;/i&gt; is also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Echinolaophonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger&lt;/i&gt;; Laophontidae; marine harpacticoid copepods; Gulf of Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Echinolaophonte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ho</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Soh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Montagna</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.1249.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Jul. 2006</title>
    <volume>1249</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2006</year>
    <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic study of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tetra &lt;/i&gt;Keifer (Acari: Eriophyidae: Phyllocoptinae: Anthocoptini) from Shaanxi Province, China with descriptions of nine new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nine new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; Keifer (Acari: Eriophyidae: Anthocoptini) from Shaanxi Province, northwestern China are described and illustrated, namely &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;louguantais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Pistacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; Bunge (Anacardiaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnatifidae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Crataegus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnatifida&lt;/i&gt; Bunge (Rosaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorbusis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Sorbus&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Rosaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acerii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Acer&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Aceraceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smilaxis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Smilax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;china&lt;/i&gt; L. (Liliaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucidi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Ligustrum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucidum&lt;/i&gt; Ait. (Oleaceae); &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ningshanis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuihuae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Populus&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Salicaceae); and &lt;i&gt;Tetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salixis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;i&gt;Salix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;babylonica&lt;/i&gt; L. (Salicaceae). All species described here are vagrant on the undersurface of host leaves.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">eriophyid mites; key; classification; vagrant; northwestern China; Palaearctic region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">eriophyid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>X.-F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Xue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Z.-W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Song</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>X.-Y.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Brazilian sharpshooters of the genus &lt;i&gt;Homalodisca &lt;/i&gt;Stål, 1869 (Hemiptera, Cicadellidae): notes, new records, key to species, first description of the male of &lt;i&gt;H. ignota &lt;/i&gt;Melichar, 1924, and a new Northeastern species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of the sharpshooter genus &lt;i&gt;Homalodisca&lt;/i&gt; Stål are known to occur in Brazil: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignota&lt;/i&gt; Melichar; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignorata&lt;/i&gt; Melichar; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucernaria&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus), a senior synonym of the type-species &lt;i&gt;Cicada&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triangularis&lt;/i&gt; Fabricius; and the new species &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spottii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; described from Bahia and Sergipe states. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spottii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is probably involved in the transmission of &lt;i&gt;Citrus&lt;/i&gt; variegated chlorosis in Northeastern Brazil and is easily distinguished from other &lt;i&gt;Homalodisca&lt;/i&gt; species by the (1) dark dorsum mottled with yellow; (2) contrasting yellow mesoscutellum; (3) broadly concave female sternite VII; and (4) aedeagal atrium not expanded dorsally and with 2 pairs of straight spiniform processes. Males and the female genitalia of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignota&lt;/i&gt; are described and illustrated for the first time (including an undistorted view of the female sternite VII). A sclerotized female internal sternite VIII in &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignota&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spottii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is newly recorded for this genus. &lt;i&gt;Homalodisca&lt;/i&gt; species are newly recorded for following Brazilian states: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignota&lt;/i&gt; from Rio de Janeiro and São Paulo; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignorata&lt;/i&gt; from Minas Gerais, Paraná, Rio de Janeiro, and Santa Catarina; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucernaria&lt;/i&gt; from Pará and Roraima. A taxonomic key and notes on Brazilian species are also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; Cicadellinae; Proconiini; new species; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Citrus&lt;/i&gt; variegated chlorosis; vectors</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Takiya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cavichioli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mckamey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-36</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pediobius sasae &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Eulophidae), a new species from galls on dwarf bamboo (&lt;i&gt;Sasa nipponica&lt;/i&gt;) in Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pediobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sasae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Hymenoptera: Eulophidae) is described from Japan. This new species belongs to the “eubius-complex” of species and is compared to the species of that group. It was reared from galls induced by an unidentified gall midge of the tribe Oligotrophini (Diptera: Cecidomyiidae). The galls are formed on stems of dwarf bamboo (Sasa &lt;i&gt;nipponica).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pediobius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sasae&lt;/i&gt; is a solitary primary parasitoid on the gall midge, but possibly also acts as a secondary parasitoid of another parasitoid reared from the same host, an unidentified species of &lt;i&gt;Torymus&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Torymidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pediobius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Torymus&lt;/i&gt;; Eulophidae; Torymidae; Oligotrophini; Cecidomyiidae; &lt;i&gt;Sasa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nipponica&lt;/i&gt;; Japan; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pediobius&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hansson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-45</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Notarius &lt;/i&gt;(Siluriformes: Ariidae) from the Colombian Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Notarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armbrusteri&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described from specimens purchased in the fish market of Buenaventura, Valle del Cauca, Colombia. The species is distinguished from other eastern Pacific species of &lt;i&gt;Notarius&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination of features: mouth small, width 11.1–11.8% SL; eye large, diameter 4.3–4.9% SL; distance between anterior nostrils 6.1–6.9% SL, distance between posterior nostrils 5.9–6.9% SL; short maxillary barbels, length 20.5–22.2% SL; and gill rakers on first arch 3–4+8–9 (total 11–13). Based on mitochondrial evidence (cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and ATP synthase 8/6, total 1937 base pairs), the new species is closely related to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insculptus,&lt;/i&gt; from the Pacific Panama. An updated key to identify the eight described species of &lt;i&gt;Notarius&lt;/i&gt; from the eastern Pacific is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Notarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armbrusteri&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; Ariidae; sea catfishes; eastern Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Notarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armbrusteri&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Betancur-R.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>Acero</middlename>
          <lastname>P.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-59</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematic review of Neotropical genera of Lauxaniidae: 3. The genus &lt;i&gt;Paracestrotus &lt;/i&gt;Hendel, 1925 (Diptera: Schizophora)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of the Neotropical Lauxaniidae genus &lt;i&gt;Paracestrotus&lt;/i&gt; Hendel, 1925 is presented with redescription of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbosus&lt;/i&gt; Hendel, 1925 and the description of a new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pulchripennis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil, Pará, including illustrations and a key.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Lauxaniidae; &lt;i&gt;Paracestrotus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Neotropical Region; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2006-07-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
