<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2732.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2732</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Freshwater Bryozoa of Okinawa, Japan, with descriptions of &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. (Phylactolaemata: Plumatellidae) and two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We identified nine species of phylactolaemate bryozoans collected from ponds and dams on Okinawa Island, Japan. This is the first report on freshwater bryozoans from Okinawa and includes the first record of &lt;i&gt;Plumatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanica&lt;/i&gt; from Japan. Phylactolaemate species were identified on the basis of colony and statoblast morphology and are illustrated by light microscopy and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). We detected two new plumatellid species that, like &lt;i&gt;Plumatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Plumatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vorstmani,&lt;/i&gt; have a transparent, weakly chitinized colony and hypertubercles on the floatoblast fenestra. A previous molecular study showed these four species to form a clade separate from &lt;i&gt;Plumatella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hyalinella.&lt;/i&gt; We here establish the new genus &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; to accommodate these species and describe &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gusuku&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yanbaruensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; We discuss the dispersal of bryozoans to and from Japan by birds carrying statoblasts and provide a key to the Phylactolaemata of Japan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Freshwater Bryozoa; new species; Okinawa; Phylactolaemata; Plumatellidae; &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gusuku&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yanbaruensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rumarcanella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vorstmani&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Freshwater Bryozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masato</firstname>
          <lastname>Hirose</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shunsuke</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mawatari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Odiomarinae nov. subfam., a new subfamily for two primitive genera of Hymenosomatidae MacLeay, 1838, with preliminary remarks on the family (Crustacea, Decapoda, Brachyura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new subfamily Odiomarinae &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; is erected to receive two primitive genera of the eubrachyuran family Hymenosomatidae MacLeay, 1838: &lt;i&gt;Odiomaris&lt;/i&gt; Ng &amp; Richer de Forges, 1996, and &lt;i&gt;Amarinus&lt;/i&gt; Lucas, 1980, mostly from fresh and estuarine waters of the Indo-West Pacific region. The new subfamily is characterised by the presence of “intercalated platelets” on the male abdomen, either articulated and moveable or relatively less well demarcated. The hymenosomatid platelets are actually vestigial uropods that are similar to those, also showing as dorsal plates, of the podotreme Dynomenidae Ortmann, 1892, and Dromiidae De Haan, 1833. The hymenosomatid uropod differs from the podotreme ones by the deep socket that is excavated at its ventral side and thus corresponds to the typical eubrachyuran press-button system. The odiomarine socket is particularly interesting because it provides morphological and phylogenetic criteria for identifying podotreme uropods and eubrachyuran sockets as homologues. In addition to several other plesiomorphic characters, the retention of dorsal uropods in the Hymenosomatidae, a unique known case in the Eubrachyura Saint Laurent, 1980, and evidence of an ancient lineage, allows re-defining and preliminarily interpreting the exclusive combination of characters of the family and to reconsider its status within the Eubrachyura.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Eubrachyura Hymenosomatidae; Odiomarinae &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;subfam.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Odiomaris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Amarinus&lt;/i&gt;; Dorippidae; Inachoididae; uropod; pleotelson; socket; abdominal-locking mechanism; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danièle</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon &lt;/i&gt;Yeo &amp; Ng, 2007 (Crustacea: Brachyura: Potamoidea: Potamidae) from Vietnam, with a redescription of &lt;i&gt;Ranguna&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Ranguna&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;kimboiensis &lt;/i&gt;Dang, 1975</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon&lt;/i&gt; Yeo &amp; Ng, 2007, are described from Vietnam. The poorly known Vietnamese species &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kimboiense&lt;/i&gt; (Dang, 1975) is redescribed. The holotype of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kimboiense&lt;/i&gt; is lost, and a topotypic specimen is designated as the neotype. &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bavi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Ba Vi National Park, Ha Tay Province, and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phongnha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Phong Nha, Quang Binh Province, are allied to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kimboiense,&lt;/i&gt; but can be distinguished by the characters of the carapace, chela and male first pleopod. &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dangi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is allied to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lipkei&lt;/i&gt; (Ng &amp; Naiyanetr, 1993) [type locality northern Thailand], but can be distinguished by characters of the carapace, telson, and male first pleopod.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Brachyura; Potamoidea; Potamidae; Potamiscinae; &lt;i&gt;Indochinamon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; freshwater crab; Vietnam; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tohru</firstname>
          <lastname>Naruse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nguyen</firstname>
          <middlename>Xuan</middlename>
          <lastname>Quynh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Darren</firstname>
          <middlename>C. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Yeo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first earthworm collections from Nicaragua with description of two new species (Oligochaeta)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In August 2009 the Natural History Museum London, Hungarian Natural History Museum and Systematic Zoology Research group, Entomological Museum in Leon and The Society for Environmental Exploration, mounted the first earthworm collection expedition to Nicaragua. No native earthworm species had previously been recorded for this country. This paper lists 18 new species records for the Country with the description of two new taxa to science: &lt;i&gt;Eutrigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Graffia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;azul&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Eutrigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Graffia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nicaraoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; New data on the species &lt;i&gt;Eutrigaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Eutrigaster)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oraedivitis&lt;/i&gt; Cognetti, 1904 is also presented here.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Earthworms; Nicaragua; &lt;i&gt;Eutrigaster&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Earthworms</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Emma</firstname>
          <lastname>Sherlock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stewart</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sally</firstname>
          <lastname>Mcphee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Steer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <middlename>Michel</middlename>
          <lastname>Maes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Csaba</firstname>
          <lastname>Csuzdi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of protoplophorid mites (Acari: Oribatida: Protoplophoridae) from Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the oribatid mite family Protoplophoridae (Acari: Oribatida), &lt;i&gt;Arthrhoplophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adjacentis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Protoplophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;takensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; collected from leaf litter of dry evergreen forest, are described and illustrated from Thailand. &lt;i&gt;Arthrhoplophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adjacentis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is unique in having the long ciliated rostral setae which are closely paired and bidactylous claws on pretarsi I, whereas pretarsi II–IV are tridactylous. &lt;i&gt;Protoplophora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;takensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from its congeners by the presence of notogastral setae &lt;i&gt;cp,&lt;/i&gt; seven pairs of genital setae and four-segmented palpi. Identification keys to species of &lt;i&gt;Arthrhoplophora&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Protoplophora&lt;/i&gt; are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oribatid mites; Enarthronota; Protoplophoridae; &lt;i&gt;Arthrhoplophora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Protoplophora&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oribatid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marut</firstname>
          <lastname>Fuangarworn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comments on the nomenclatural status of two subgeneric names for marine gastrotrichs (Gastrotricha: Xenotrichulidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shushi</firstname>
          <lastname>Abukawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kajihara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
