<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2734.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2734</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new infaunal decapod crustaceans (Caridea: Alpheidae and Gebiidea: Axianassidae) from Lizard Island, Australia, one of them also occurring in Moorea, French Polynesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of marine infaunal decapod crustaceans are described from Lizard Island, Great Barrier Reef, Australia. Three of them belong to the caridean shrimp family Alpheidae, viz. &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shawnsmithi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daviei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Athanopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.;&lt;/b&gt; all three were collected from burrows of unknown hosts. The fourth species, &lt;i&gt;Axianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heardi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the burrowing mud-shrimp family Axianassidae, is described based on a male holotype from Lizard Island and an additional female specimen from Moorea, Society Islands, French Polynesia. The presence of a toothed diaeresis on the uropodal exopod and a well-developed epipod on the second maxilliped in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heardi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are new characters for the genus &lt;i&gt;Axianassa.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Caridea; Alpheidae; Gebiidea; Axianassidae; shrimp; mud-shrimp; Australia; French Polynesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Megophrys &lt;/i&gt;Kuhl &amp; van Hasselt (Amphibia: Megophryidae), from western Thailand and southern Cambodia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Megophrys&lt;/i&gt; are described from historical collections presented by Malcolm A. Smith to The Natural History Museum, London, in the early twentieth century. These specimens were previously misidentified as &lt;i&gt;Megophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parva,&lt;/i&gt; a widespread Asian species apparently comprised of a species complex. &lt;i&gt;Megophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;damrei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Bokor Plateau in the Cardamom Mountains of southern Cambodia and &lt;i&gt;Megophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;takensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Ban Pa Che, Tak Province, in western Thailand, are herein distinguished morphologically from all congeners from their respective and neighbouring countries. These, or further specimens representing either species, do not appear to have been reported on by other authors in the past and the conservation status of the two new species remains to be assessed. An attempt to locate both species at and near their respective type localities was successful for &lt;i&gt;Megophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;takensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; allowing the documentation of observations in the wild and live colouration. This study highlights the importance of examining historical museum collections often overlooked in recent decades by modern taxonomists.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Xenophrys&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; Thailand; Cambodia; amphibian</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Xenophrys&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <lastname>Mahony</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-39</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Fish fauna of Baía da Babitonga (southern Brazil), with remarks on species abundance, ontogenic stage and conservation status</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Basic data on species composition and abundance are essential to subsidize the development of effective actions for conservation of biological diversity and to identifying the effects arising from these actions. This work provides an updated checklist of the fish species occurring in the proposed Baía da Babitonga marine protected area (southern Brazil) as well as their abundance, ontogenic stage and conservation status, based on multi-site data collected in shallow water and deeper zones of the main channel and from published literature. A total of 152 fish species belonging to 18 orders and 53 families were registered, with 29 species being reported for the first time in Baía da Babitonga. Among the registered species, the exotic blenny &lt;i&gt;Omobranchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctatus&lt;/i&gt; (Valenciennes) was the most unexpected. The most species-rich families were Sciaenidae (18), Carangidae (15), Engraulidae (9), Paralichthyidae (8), Epinephelidae (8) and Gobiidae (7). Nine species inhabiting Baía da Babitonga are classified as globally threatened, and 17 species are classified as nationally overexploited; four of these species are on both global and national red lists.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fish assemblage; ichthyofauna; Santa Catarina; species list; southwestern Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fish assemblage</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ciro</firstname>
          <middlename>Colodetti</middlename>
          <lastname>Vilar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Henry</firstname>
          <middlename>Louis</middlename>
          <lastname>Spach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lilyane</firstname>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-52</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the milliped genus &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopus &lt;/i&gt;with commentary on the so-called “Charactopygus-Bildung” modification of spirostreptid paraprocts (Diplopoda: Spirostreptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The status of the monotypic taxon &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopus&lt;/i&gt; (Verhoeff, 1941), proposed for a disjunct Tanzanian spirostreptoid, is reviewed in light of two additional species, which despite different peripheral appearances, are referable to this genus on the basis of genitalic features. &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inflatannulus&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff is redescribed from topotypic material, the nominal species &lt;i&gt;Charactopygus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeanneli&lt;/i&gt; (Brolemann, 1920) is relocated in &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopus&lt;/i&gt; (n. &lt;b&gt;comb.),&lt;/b&gt; and the &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;cin-&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;gulatus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Rondo Plateau in southeastern Tanzania. A terminology for the modified paraproct structure (“Charactopygus-Bildung”) of spirostreptids is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spirostreptidae; &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopinae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Haplogonopus&lt;/i&gt;; paraprocts; Tanzania; Kenya</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spirostreptidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoffman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The alpheid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus &lt;/i&gt;Anker, Poddoubtchenko &amp; Wehrtmann, 2006 in the Western Atlantic, with description of a new species from Tobago (Crustacea, Decapoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A miniature alpheid shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caribbaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of a single female specimen collected in Sandy Bay, Tobago, in 1992. The new species is closely related to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coibita&lt;/i&gt; Anker, Poddoubtchenko &amp; Wehrtmann, 2006 from the Pacific coast of Panama, the type species and the only other known species of &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus&lt;/i&gt; Anker, Poddoubtchenko &amp; Wehrtmann, 2006, differing from it in several morphological characters. With the discovery of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caribbaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus&lt;/i&gt; becomes a genus with transisthmian (= amphi-American) distribution. In addition, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coibita&lt;/i&gt; is reported for the first time since original description and its range is extended by 400 km southwards. The generic diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus&lt;/i&gt; is slightly emended.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Caridea; Alpheidae; shrimp; new species; &lt;i&gt;Leslibetaeus.&lt;/i&gt; Caribbean; Atlantic Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
