<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2737.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2737</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Catalogue of Naidinae and Pristininae (Annelida: Oligochaeta: Naididae) with twenty species new for Montenegro</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Oligochaeta occurring in Montenegrin freshwaters were studied in order to contribute to a better knowledge of this group in the region. The oligochaetes from rivers, lakes, reservoirs, creeks, and springs, belonging to the Black Sea and the Adriatic Sea drainage basins, were investigated. Samples of sediments were taken from 54 sampling sites during three years of research (2005–2008). We confirmed the presence of formerly reported species and found 20 species new for the Montenegrin oligochaete fauna: &lt;i&gt;Chaetogaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristallinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diaphanus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;langi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setosus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Nais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;behningi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bretscheri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elinguis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolci,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ophidonais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serpentina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paranais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frici,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litoralis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Piguetiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blanci,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pristina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bilobata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenkinae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longiseta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osborni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proboscidea,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Slavina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;appendiculata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Uncinais&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uncinata.&lt;/i&gt; Accordingly, the fauna of Naidinae and Pristininae in Montenegro now consists of 36 species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clitellata; Oligochaeta; Naidinae; Pristininae; new records; Montenegro</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clitellata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danijela</firstname>
          <lastname>Šundić</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Branko</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Radujković</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jasmina</firstname>
          <lastname>Krpo–Ćetković</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cycloramphus &lt;/i&gt;Tschudi (Anura: Cycloramphidae) from the Parque Nacional da Serra dos Órgãos, Southeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We report here the discovery of a new species of frog associated to the open areas of the highlands of the Parque Nacional da Serra dos Órgãos. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Cycloramphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;organensis&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by a unique skin texture, medium size (maximum male and female SVL 26.4 mm and 33.3 mm respectively), dorsal surfaces uniformly brick red colored, uniformly areolate skin on dorsum, pupil horizontal, iris with a menisc on upper margin; no fleshy tubercles on eyelid, tympanic annulus concealed beneath skin, macroglands not visible externally, fingers and toes without fringes and webs; supernumerary palmar and plantar tubercles absent, nuptial spines absent. Despite the presence of an iris menisc, a character shared by frogs of both genera &lt;i&gt;Cycloramphus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Zachaenus&lt;/i&gt; Cope, the combination of morphological characters is so unique that the allocation of the species to any of these genera remains ambiguous. Consequently, we used additional molecular-based phylogenetic analyses to ascertain the position of the new taxon. The new species proved to be embedded within the genus &lt;i&gt;Cycloramphus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; &lt;i&gt;Cycloramphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;organensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Atlantic Forest; open highlands; Osteology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>Norberto</middlename>
          <lastname>Weber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vanessa</firstname>
          <middlename>Kruth</middlename>
          <lastname>Verdade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <lastname>De Oliveira Lula Salles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antoine</firstname>
          <lastname>Fouquet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <middlename>Potsch</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho-E-Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pele ramseyi&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and new species of anchialine swimming crab (Crustacea: Brachyura: Portunidae) from the Hawaiian Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of anchialine portunid crab is described from lava pools in Maui, Hawaiian Islands. &lt;i&gt;Pele&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramseyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;genus,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; resembles species of &lt;i&gt;Libystes&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1867, but differs markedly in its reduced and almost immovable eyes, as well as the distinctive structures of the mouthparts, chelipeds, male abdomen and gonopods.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Crustacea; Brachyura; Portunidae; &lt;i&gt;Pele&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new genus; new species; Hawaiian Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new karst-dwelling species of &lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Microhylidae) from Gunung Mulu National Park, Borneo, Malaysia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Gunung Mulu National Park in East Malaysia. The species is endemic to the karst hills and mountains of the Melinau Limestone Formation where it occurs at elevations between 70 and at least 1200 m. It differs from all other species of the genus by the combination of the following morphological characters: medium size (SVL of adult males 29.7–30.1 mm, adult females 35.5–38.8 mm), snout obtusely pointed, tympanum diameter slightly larger than half the eye diameter, upper jaw with weak dentition, fore limbs slender, Finger IV shorter than Fingers I and II, subarticular tubercles prominent, numbering one on Fingers I, II, and IV, and two on Finger III, a smaller, supernumerary metacarpal tubercle present between each finger and palmar tubercle, nuptial pads or asperities absent, heel reaching to posterior margin of eye when legs are adpressed to body, foot shorter than tibiofibula, Toe III longer than Toe V, toes webbed, inner and outer metatarsal tubercle prominent, dorsum and flanks black in life, separated from each other by white dorsolateral line running on both sides of body, chin and chest black, abdomen and proximal third of thigh grey in life, iris red to reddish-orange in life, advertisement call a single note consisting of 7 pulses and lasting 161 ms on average, with dominant frequency at 2250–2650 Hz.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calciphilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; sticky frog; Melinau Limestone; Gunung Api; advertisement call; endemism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Kalophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calciphilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; sticky frog</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Maximilian</middlename>
          <lastname>Dehling</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-60</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Bachia &lt;/i&gt;Gray, 1845 (Squamata: Gymnophthalmidae) from the Cerrado of Midwestern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Bachia&lt;/i&gt; is described from two localities in the states of Mato Grosso and Rondônia, in Midwestern Brazil. The new species mostly resembles &lt;i&gt;Bachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bresslaui&lt;/i&gt; in pholidosis and biometry, differing from this and from all other taxa from &lt;i&gt;bresslaui&lt;/i&gt; group by the presence of two clawed digits in the forefeet.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bachia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Mato Grosso State; Rondônia State; two digits; &lt;i&gt;bresslaui&lt;/i&gt; group</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bachia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joseana</firstname>
          <middlename>Luisa</middlename>
          <lastname>De Freitas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christine</firstname>
          <lastname>Strüssmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcos</firstname>
          <middlename>André</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>Alexandre</middlename>
          <lastname>Kawashita-Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tamí</firstname>
          <lastname>Mott</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
