<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2749.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2749</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New semionotiform (Neopterygii) from the Tlayúa Quarry (Early Cretaceous, Albian), Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new semionotiform fish, &lt;i&gt;Tlayuamichin&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itztli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Early Cretaceous (Albian) of Mexico, which constitutes one of the youngest semionotid articulated remains. The new taxon is represented by five well-preserved specimens from the Tlayúa Quarry near Tepexi de Rodríguez in Puebla State, central Mexico. A series of paraethmoid bones anterior to the supraorbital series, supraorbital bones extending beyond the anterior rim of the orbit, the presence of a large pentagonal supraorbital closing the anterior rim of the orbit, seven anterior infraorbitals, dorsally expanded infraorbitals at the ventral border of the orbit, and the most dorsal suborbital separating the preoperculum from the dermopterotic are potential autapomorphic features of the new taxon. The very long frontals, a dermopterotic that does not contact the anterodorsal corner of the operculum and the presence of a modified pectoral scale are additional features that help to diagnose the taxon. &lt;i&gt;Tlayuamichin&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itztli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; resembles most closely “Lepidotes” &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; from the Middle Purbeck Beds (early Berriasian), England. These two taxa share similarity with other species of &lt;i&gt;Semionotus&lt;/i&gt; from the Early Jurassic of North America and the Triassic of Europe, suggesting interesting biogeographic relationships.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Semionotiformes; new taxon; anatomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Semionotiformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <lastname>López-Arbarello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jesús</firstname>
          <lastname>Alvarado-Ortega</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Sangiorgioichthys &lt;/i&gt;Tintori and Lombardo, 2007 (Neopterygii, Semionotiformes) from the Anisian of Luoping (Yunnan Province, South China)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We report on a new species of the neopterygian genus &lt;i&gt;Sangiorgioichthys&lt;/i&gt; Tintori and Lombardo, 2007, from middle Anisian (Pelsonian) deposits in South China (Luoping County, Yunnan Province). &lt;i&gt;Sangiorgioichthys&lt;/i&gt; was previously known from a single species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aldae,&lt;/i&gt; from the late Ladinian of the Monte San Giorgio (Italy and Switzerland). The recognition of the new species helped to improve the diagnosis of the genus, which is mainly characterized by the presence of broad posttemporal and supracleithral bones, one or two suborbital bones occupying a triangular area ventral to the infraorbital bones and lateral to the quadrate, and elongate supramaxilla fitting in a an excavation of the dorsal border of the maxilla. &lt;i&gt;Sangiorgioichthys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the type species in having two pairs of extrascapular bones, the medial pair usually fused to the parietals, maxilla with a complete row of small conical teeth, long supramaxilla, more than half of the length of the maxilla, only two large suborbital bones posterior to the orbit, and flank scales with finely serrated posterior borders. With the discovery of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; the number of fish genera shared by the Anisian/Ladinian deposits in the Alps and the Anisian deposits in South China increases, including not only the cosmopolitan &lt;i&gt;Birgeria&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Saurichthys,&lt;/i&gt; but also, among others, the subholosteans &lt;i&gt;Colobodus&lt;/i&gt; (so far only in Panxian), &lt;i&gt;Luopingichthys&lt;/i&gt; (so far only in Luoping), &lt;i&gt;Peltopleurus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Habroichthys,&lt;/i&gt; and the very specialized neopterygians &lt;i&gt;Placopleurus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Marcopoloichthys&lt;/i&gt; (only in Luoping). Therefore, although several fish taxa remain to be studied in the Chinese faunas, the so far available evidence indicates close biogeographic relationship between the Middle Triassic marine faunas of the Western Tethys region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Actinopterygii; Middle Triassic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <lastname>López-Arbarello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zuo-Yu</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Emilia</firstname>
          <lastname>Sferco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <lastname>Tintori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guang-Hui</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuan-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fei-Xiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Da-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Jiang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-39</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Astyanax pirapuan&lt;/i&gt;: a new characid species from the upper Rio Paraguay system, Mato Grosso, Central Brazil (Characiformes, Characidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new characid fish is described herein from tributaries of the Rio Aricá-Mirim, Rio Cuiabá basin, Chapada dos Guimarães, Mato Grosso State, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Astyanax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pirapuan&lt;/i&gt; better conforms to the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabripinnis&lt;/i&gt; species complex and it can be distinguished from other species of this complex by a combination of characters, including 8–9 gill rakers on the upper limb of first branchial arch, 0–1 tooth on the maxillary, 17 to 21 branched anal-fin rays, 35–37 perforated lateral line scales and two humeral spots.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical; &lt;i&gt;Astyanax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabripinnis&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Victor</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tagliacollo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Britzke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gabriel</firstname>
          <middlename>S. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Benine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-46</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Akodon oenos &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia, Sigmodontinae), an obscure species from West Central Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oenos&lt;/i&gt; Braun, Mares, and Ojeda, 2000 was described on a large sample of individuals collected from two localities near Mendoza city, Argentina. This sample was obtained in the 1980’s by Julio R. Contreras and María I. Rossi and labeled, but never published, as “Akodon &lt;i&gt;minoprioi&lt;/i&gt; new species.” The description provided by Braun and collaborators was limited to craniodental and color pelage traits compared with those of five individuals of the sympatric form &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;molinae&lt;/i&gt; Contreras, 1968. &lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oenos&lt;/i&gt; was proposed as new and presumptively allied to the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;varius&lt;/i&gt; species group of &lt;i&gt;Akodon.&lt;/i&gt; In February 2009 we collected an individual of &lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; in Llancanelo Natural Reserve, southern Mendoza, that morphologically fits the original description of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oenos.&lt;/i&gt; Further study of some individuals of the type series of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oenos&lt;/i&gt; reinforces this taxonomic hypothesis for the Llancanelo specimen. However, comparisons with other &lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; species overlooked by Braun and collaborators, reveals striking similarities with the widespread and phenotypically variable species &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spegazzinii&lt;/i&gt; Thomas, 1897. The evidence at hand, including morphological, karyological, and genetical traits, allows us to propose a new taxonomic scenario. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oenos&lt;/i&gt; is considered here a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spegazzinii&lt;/i&gt; and therefore belongs to the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviensis&lt;/i&gt; species group of &lt;i&gt;Akodon,&lt;/i&gt; extending the known geographic distribution for this species at least to southern Mendoza piedmont in the ecotone between the Monte and Patagonia eco-regions. More generally, this situation highlights the necessity when working with complex genera (as many sigmodontines are) to perform extensive comparisons and to use several sets of evidence in order to reduce the probability of generating biologically redundant names and more taxonomic confusion.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spegazzinii&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny; &lt;i&gt;boliviensis&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;varius&lt;/i&gt; group; Mendoza</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Akodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spegazzinii&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulyses</firstname>
          <middlename>F. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pardiñas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <lastname>Teta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>D’Elía</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gabriela</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-61</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Branchinecta &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Anostraca) with comments on the large branchiopod crustaceans of Kansas</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Branchinecta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediospinosa,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of fairy shrimp, is described from a single artificial temporary pool in Kansas, USA. The type locality has since been destroyed. The new species shares several characters with &lt;i&gt;Branchinecta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindahli&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;constricta&lt;/i&gt; including the general form of the male second antennal distal antennomere. However, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediospinosa&lt;/i&gt; males are readily separated from all other &lt;i&gt;Branchinecta&lt;/i&gt; species by the presence of an apically spiniform projection on the second antenna proximal antennomere medial surface. Female &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediospinosa&lt;/i&gt; also strongly resemble female &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindahli,&lt;/i&gt; however &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mediospinosa&lt;/i&gt; has hemispherical dorsolateral projections on thoracic segments IV to X, whereas in &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lindahli&lt;/i&gt; they occur on IV to XI, and in &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;constricta&lt;/i&gt; they appear on IV to XII. The Anostraca of Kansas and the Great Plains are briefly discussed, and new large branchiopod records are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Fairy Shrimp; Great Plains; Branchinectidae; new records; &lt;i&gt;Lynceus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cyzicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Fairy Shrimp</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>Christopher</middlename>
          <lastname>Rogers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Don</firstname>
          <lastname>Dasis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Murrow</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
