<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2754.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2754</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Deep-sea ophiuroids (Echinodermata: Ophiuroidea: Ophiurida) from the Gulf of Cadiz (NE Atlantic)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Ophiuroidea collected from mud volcanoes and adjacent bathyal environments from the Gulf of Cadiz are reviewed. Thirteen species from six families—Ophiacanthidae, Ophiactidae, Amphiuridae, Amphilepididae, Ophiuridae and Ophiolepididae—were identified. A direct relationship to the chemosynthetic assemblages has not been established as the ophiuroids found in the mud volcanoes do not appear to have novel morphological adaptations and also occur in non-reducing environments. The ophiuroid fauna from the Gulf of Cadiz differs from other cold seep regions not only by the high species richness but also because members of Amphiuridae are dominant both in number of species and abundance. One species previously unknown, &lt;i&gt;Ophiopristis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gadensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; (Ophiacanthidae) was collected from a dead cold-water coral thicket at the flank of a mud volcano and differs from its congeners in the type of disk spines which are more rugose and not smooth as in most of the other species, the presence of the thickened integument in larger specimens and the distinct separation between the oral papillae and the second oral tentacle scales.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mud volcanoes; reducing environments; macrofauna; biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mud volcanoes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Clara</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gordon</firstname>
          <middlename>L. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Paterson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Cabrinovic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marina</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cunha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the &lt;i&gt;Pyura stolonifera &lt;/i&gt;species complex (Tunicata, Ascidiacea), with a description of a new species from Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pyura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolonifera&lt;/i&gt; is a large solitary ascidian found in Africa, Australasia and South America. The taxonomic status of different populations of this species is disputed, especially since there is evidence for several distinct morphological and genetic units that point towards the existence of multiple cryptic species. While some researchers still recognize &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolonifera&lt;/i&gt; as a single species, others treat the different populations as distinct species. Here, we present a revision of the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolonifera&lt;/i&gt; species complex based on the examination of samples from all regions where there are reliable reports of this taxon. We recognize four species that are both morphologically and genetically distinct, one of which is new to science and is formally described here. This species is morphologically distinct from the other three members of the species complex in terms of the colour and texture of the tunic, the arrangement of the gonads within the gut and the shape of the dorsal tubercle, among other characters. We name the new species &lt;i&gt;Pyura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dalbyi&lt;/i&gt; after Dr. J.E. Dalby Jr., whose research on its ecology and distribution provided the incentive for examining this species more closely.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pyuridae; &lt;i&gt;Pyura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dalbyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; ascidian; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Pyura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;herdmani&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pyura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;praeputialis&lt;/i&gt;; disjunct distribution; southern Africa; Chile; Morocco</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pyuridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <lastname>Rius</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Teske</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An overview of &lt;i&gt;Neogovea &lt;/i&gt;species (Opiliones: Cyphophthalmi: Neogoveidae) with the description of &lt;i&gt;Neogovea virginie &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. from French Guiana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Cyphophthalmi is a group of small to medium sized opilionids with a circumglobal distribution that have often been overlooked in biodiversity surveys due to their small size, cryptic life style and general resemblance to mites. We present an overview of the described species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Neogovea&lt;/i&gt; (Neogoveidae), an identification key to the species and the description of a new species based on the material from a biodiversity survey of an inselberg in French Guyana. &lt;i&gt;Neogovea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;virginie&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is morphologically most similar to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;immsi&lt;/i&gt; Hinton occurring in Brazil, but differentiated by the structure of the “crown” of the spermatopositor.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Guiana; inselberg; &lt;i&gt;Neogovea&lt;/i&gt;; identification key; check list</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Guiana</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Merlijn</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocqué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudy</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocqué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new deep-sea squat lobsters of the genus &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis &lt;/i&gt;Whiteaves, 1874 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Munidopsidae) from Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new deep-sea munidopsids, &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevisquama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from Taiwan. &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; closely resembles &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serricornis&lt;/i&gt; (Lovén, 1852), but differs in lacking an antennal spine, cheliped with fingers longer than palm and merus bearing distal spines but without a row of dorsal spines. &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevisquama&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other congeners by its carapace being densely covered with squamae but without dorsal spines, eyes that are subglobular and lacking spines or papillae, the basal antennal segment bearing a cylindrical process, and the cheliped and walking legs all lacking distal spines. Altogether 36 species of &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt; are now known from the deep waters off Taiwan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Munidopsidae; &lt;i&gt;Munidopsis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Munidopsidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chia-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oreoglanis majusculus&lt;/i&gt;, a new glyptosternine catfish from Arunachal Pradesh, India (Teleostei: Sisoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Oreoglanis&lt;/i&gt; is reported for the first time from India. &lt;i&gt;Oreoglanis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;majusculus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from the Kameng River at Rupa (Brahmaputra basin), in Arunachal Pradesh, India, differs from all its congeners in having the posterior margin of the maxillary barbel with villiform projections, vs. entire, crenulate, laciniate or lobulate in all other species of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new catfish; &lt;i&gt;Oreoglanis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;siamensis&lt;/i&gt; group; Kameng River; Brahmaputra; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new catfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <lastname>Linthoingambi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vishwanath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-66</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Designation of a lectotype for &lt;i&gt;Notiomystis cincta hautura &lt;/i&gt;Mathews, 1935 (Aves: Passeriformes: Meliphagidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>George</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Angehr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
