<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2767.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2767</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Steinernema pui &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Rhabditida, Steinernematidae), a new entomopathogenic nematode from Yunnan, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of entomopathogenic nematode, herein described as &lt;i&gt;Steinernema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; was recovered from a soil sample collected from Xiao-jie town, Jing-hong city, Xi-shuang-ban-na district in Yunnan province, the People’s Republic of China in December 2002. Both morphological and molecular evidence show congruently that &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; belongs to the &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glaseri&lt;/i&gt; group. It can be separated from all described &lt;i&gt;Steinernema&lt;/i&gt; species by a combination of morphological and morphometrical characters of adult and juvenile stages, including spicule and gubernaculum shape of the first generation males (spicule bearing an aperture on the tip and an irregular-shaped concave on ventral side of the lamina close to the tip; gubernaculum with a short needle-shaped cuneus); the tail and vulva shape of the first generation females (tail conoid and pointed with a mucron; vulva with a short double flapped epiptygma) and the body and tail length, distance from anterior end to excretory pore and to the base of pharynx of infective juveniles. The new species can also be distinguished from other &lt;i&gt;Steinernema&lt;/i&gt; species by DNA sequences of either a partial 28S rDNA or the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) regions of rDNA, and from the closely related species &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicaudum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guangdongense&lt;/i&gt; by cross-breeding tests.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">28S rDNA sequence; entomopathogenic nematode; identification; rDNA ITS sequence; &lt;i&gt;Steinernema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pui&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">28S rDNA sequence</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lihong</firstname>
          <lastname>Qiu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jingxiu</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhongdao</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhiyue</firstname>
          <lastname>Lv</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yi</firstname>
          <lastname>Pang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-13</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The systematics of &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula fischeri &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Gymnophiona: Caeciliidae) based on morphological and molecular data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight new specimens are reported for the caecilian amphibian &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri,&lt;/i&gt; a species known in detail previously only from its holotype collected in 1987. The new material was collected at the type locality in Rwanda in 2009, and is used to expand and refine the morphological characterization of the species. Mitochondrial and nuclear gene sequences were used to assess the phylogenetic position of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri&lt;/i&gt; in the context of a recent molecular phylogeny of six of the seven other species of &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula&lt;/i&gt; (from Kenya and Tanzania). Among nominal species, only &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denhardti&lt;/i&gt; remains to be included in molecular phylogenetic studies of &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula&lt;/i&gt; is recovered as monophyletic, with either &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri&lt;/i&gt; or (more probably) &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boulengeri&lt;/i&gt; sister to all other sampled species. There are at least three deep lineages within &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula:&lt;/i&gt; (1) &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boulengeri,&lt;/i&gt; (2) &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fischeri,&lt;/i&gt; and (3) all other Eastern Arc Mountain and Coastal Forest species from Kenya and Tanzania. The status of &lt;i&gt;Afrocaecilia,&lt;/i&gt; a genus erected by Taylor in 1968 to contain all &lt;i&gt;Boulengerula&lt;/i&gt; except &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boulengeri,&lt;/i&gt; is not yet resolved.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Africa; &lt;i&gt;Afrocaecilia&lt;/i&gt;; Albertine Rift; caecilian; DNA; Eastern Arc Mountains; phylogenetics; Rwanda</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gower</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <lastname>Papadopoulou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Doherty-Bone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <lastname>Pupin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>San Mauro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Simon</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Loader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilkinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>14-24</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Inter- and intra-island divergence in &lt;i&gt;Odorrana ishikawae &lt;/i&gt;(Anura, Ranidae) of the Ryukyu Archipelago of Japan, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The endangered frog, &lt;i&gt;Odorrana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawae&lt;/i&gt; (Anura, Ranidae), is a species endemic to the Amami and Okinawa Islands of the Ryukyu Archipelago, Japan. Segmentation of these islands has been considered to occur middle or upper Pleistocene. Our morphometric analyses revealed obvious differences between the Amami and Okinawa populations. Two distinct morphotypes were also recognized from the Amami Island (Amami common and Amami large types). Furthermore, the Amami and Okinawa populations could be distinguished clearly by coloration and dorsal tuberculation. Based on 16S rRNA gene data, the Okinawa and Amami populations were phylogenetically separated but the genetic divergence (1.44– 2.16%) was lower than the value suggested as species threshold in anurans (&gt; 3% in &lt;i&gt;16S).&lt;/i&gt; Individuals of the Amami common and large types were nested within a single clade. Artificial hybridization experiments revealed normal hybrid viability between the two Amami types, with one exception. By contrast, between Okinawa females and two Amami type males, complete hybrid inviability was observed at early embryonic stages in the hybrids contrary to expectations from their low divergence in &lt;i&gt;16S.&lt;/i&gt; The reciprocal hybrids between two Amami type females and Okinawa males were viable, but spermatogenesis in the hybrid males showed some degree of abnormality. These results strongly indicate specific separation of the Amami population from the Okinawa population of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawae.&lt;/i&gt; Thus, we describe the Amami population as a new species, which is readily distinguishable from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawae&lt;/i&gt; by smaller ruggedly edged dorsal spots and an immaculate ventral surface.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odorrana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;splendida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Odorrana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawae&lt;/i&gt;; Ranidae; Ryukyu Archipelago; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odorrana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;splendida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Odorrana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ishikawae&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mitsuru</firstname>
          <lastname>Kuramoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Naoki</firstname>
          <lastname>Satou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shohei</firstname>
          <lastname>Oumi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Atsushi</firstname>
          <lastname>Kurabayashi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masayuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Sumida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species within the &lt;i&gt;Eurytemora affinis &lt;/i&gt;complex (Copepoda: Calanoida) from the Atlantic Coast of USA, with observations on eight morphologically different European populations</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eurytemora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carolleeae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Crustacea: Copepoda: Calaniformes) is described from the Chesapeake Bay, USA. The new species belongs to the Atlantic clade of the &lt;i&gt;Eurytemora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; complex outlined by previously published molecular work but poorly characterized morphologically. To discriminate &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carolleeae&lt;/i&gt; we compare specimens from the Atlantic USA clade with specimens from the type population of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; (Poppe, 1880) from the Elbe River Estuary (Germany), as well as with eight other European coastal populations. Several important morphological characters clearly separate the North American &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cf.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; from the European clade that include both sexes: a large outside orientated dent on the mandible, and clearly observable seta segmentation in the caudal rami and swimming legs. Unlike &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis,&lt;/i&gt; the newly described species possesses wing-like outgrowths on the genital double-somite and a very small spine near the distal seta insertion point in P5 in females. In males, the specific characters include naked dorsal and ventral sides of the caudal rami, and a cylindrical shape of exopod on the left P5, in contrast to a triangular shape of the segment in &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis.&lt;/i&gt; The new species was also found in Canada (St. Lawrence Estuary) and as an invasive species in the Baltic Sea. &lt;i&gt;Eurytemora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carolleeae&lt;/i&gt; is possibly widely distributed along the North American Atlantic coast, as well as in inland waters from Great Lakes to Mexico.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepod diversity; taxonomy; sibling species; North Atlantic; estuary</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepod diversity</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Victor</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alekseev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anissa</firstname>
          <lastname>Souissi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crassispira (Crassispirella) tuckerana&lt;/i&gt;, a replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Crassispira&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Crassispirella) tuckeri &lt;/i&gt;Bonfitto &amp; Morassi, 2004 (Gastropoda: Turridae: Crassispirinae) not &lt;i&gt;Crassispira tuckeri &lt;/i&gt;Le Renard, 1994</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bonfitto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Morassi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Phasmahyla spectabilis&lt;/i&gt; Cruz, Feio &amp; Nascimento, 2008 (Anura: Phyllomedusinae) with comments on its distribution and reproduction</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Iuri</firstname>
          <middlename>Ribeiro</middlename>
          <lastname>Dias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <lastname>Rödder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <lastname>Weinsheimer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Axel</firstname>
          <lastname>Kwet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mirco</firstname>
          <lastname>Solé</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
