<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2776.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2776</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A second New Zealand species of the stargazer genus &lt;i&gt;Kathetostoma&lt;/i&gt; (Trachinoidei: Uranoscopidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the uranoscopid genus &lt;i&gt;Kathetostoma&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1860, is described from New Zealand waters, where it is broadly sympatric with its sole local congener &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giganteum&lt;/i&gt; Haast, 1873. The new species is readily recognised by its broad, saddle-like dark bands that cross the body dorsally (versus bands absent or only faintly developed), rather robust and short body (vs slender and elongate), and fewer numbers of vertebrae (30–31 versus 33–34), dorsal fin rays (15–17 versus 17–19) and anal fin rays (15–16 versus 17–18). Although both species have extremely broad depth distributions, the new species appears to be restricted to less than about 500 m, with its greatest abundance at 100–300 m, while &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giganteum&lt;/i&gt; reaches over 1000 m, and has its greatest abundance at 200–400 m. A brief redescription of &lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giganteum&lt;/i&gt; is also provided. &lt;i&gt;Kathetostoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fluviatilis&lt;/i&gt; Hutton, 1972, the oldest New Zealand name that applies to this genus, is regarded as a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubium.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Uranoscopidae; stargazer; &lt;i&gt;Kathetostoma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Uranoscopidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gomon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Clive</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Roberts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-12</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and phylogenetic relationships of a remarkable new genus and two new species of Neotropical freshwater stingrays from the Amazon basin (Chondrichthyes: Potamotrygonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology and phylogenetic relationships of a new genus and two new species of Neotropical freshwater stingrays, family Potamotrygonidae, are investigated and described in detail. The new genus, &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon,&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., and its two new species, &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gomesi,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (type-species) and &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosai,&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., are compared to all genera and species of potamotrygonids, based on revisions in progress. Some of the derived features of &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; include its unique disc proportions (disc highly circular, convex anteriorly at snout region, its width and length very similar), extreme subdivision of suborbital canal (forming a complex honeycomb-like pattern anterolaterally on disc), stout and triangular pelvic girdle, extremely reduced caudal sting, basibranchial copula with very slender and acute anterior extension, and precerebral and frontoparietal fontanellae of about equal width, tapering very little posteriorly. Both new species can be distinguished by their unique color patterns: &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gomesi&lt;/i&gt; is uniform gray to light tan or brownish dorsally, without distinct patterns, whereas &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosai&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by numerous white to creamy-white vermiculate markings over a light brown, tan or gray background color. Additional proportional characters that may further distinguish both species are also discussed. Morphological descriptions are provided for dermal denticles, ventral lateral-line canals, skeleton, and cranial, hyoid and mandibular muscles of &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon,&lt;/i&gt; which clearly corroborate it as the sister group of &lt;i&gt;Paratrygon.&lt;/i&gt; Both genera share numerous derived features of the ventral lateral-line canals, neurocranium, scapulocoracoid, pectoral basals, clasper morphology, and specific patterns of the adductor mandibulae and spiracularis medialis muscles. &lt;i&gt;Potamotrygon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Plesiotrygon&lt;/i&gt; are demonstrated to share derived characters of their ventral lateral-line canals, in addition to the presence of angular cartilages. Our morphological phylogeny is further corroborated by a molecular phylogenetic analysis of cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; based on four sequences (637 base pairs in length), representing two distinct haplotypes for &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gomesi.&lt;/i&gt; Parsimony analysis produced a single most parsimonious tree revealing &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paratrygon&lt;/i&gt; as sister taxa (bootstrap proportion of 70%), which together are the sister group to a clade including &lt;i&gt;Plesiotrygon&lt;/i&gt; and species of &lt;i&gt;Potamotrygon.&lt;/i&gt; These unusual stingrays highlight that potamotrygonid diversity, both in terms of species composition and undetected morphological and molecular patterns, is still poorly known.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosai&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gomesi&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; systematics; Myliobatiformes; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heliotrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosai&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nathan</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lovejoy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>13-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Patterns of morphological and genetic variation in the &lt;i&gt;Mentocrex kioloides&lt;/i&gt; complex (Aves: Gruiformes: Rallidae) from Madagascar, with the description of a new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We examine patterns of morphological and molecular genetic differentiation in the endemic &lt;i&gt;Mentocrex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kioloides&lt;/i&gt; complex of Madagascar. This forest-dwelling rail (often placed in &lt;i&gt;Canirallus)&lt;/i&gt; is known from two subspecies: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;k.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kioloides,&lt;/i&gt; which occurs in the island’s humid central and eastern forests; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;k.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;berliozi,&lt;/i&gt; which occurs in the transitional dry deciduoushumid forests of the northwest. Two new specimens (an adult and a downy young) recently became available from limestone karst areas of the lowland central west, the adult of which is notably different in size and plumage coloration, as well as showing considerable genetic divergence, from the two recognized subspecies of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kioloides.&lt;/i&gt; The central west animals are herein named as a species new to science, &lt;i&gt;Mentocrex&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beankaensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Madagascar Wood Rail; Beanka Massif; &lt;i&gt;tsingy&lt;/i&gt; forest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Madagascar Wood Rail</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Goodman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marie</firstname>
          <middlename>Jeanne</middlename>
          <lastname>Raherilalao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nicholas</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Block</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-60</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
