<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2788.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Mar. 2011</title>
    <volume>2788</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-03-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of eastern Asian species of the mysid genus &lt;i&gt;Rhopalophthalmus &lt;/i&gt;Illig, 1906 (Crustacea, Mysida) with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Mysid crustaceans of the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhopalophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; Illig, 1906 (Crustacea: Mysida) are distributed in the eastern Atlantic through the Indo-West Pacific. In this paper, species of &lt;i&gt;Rhopalophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; recorded from eastern Asian waters are reviewed on the basis of materials collected from south-eastern Asia to Japanese water. The taxonomic analysis led to the recognition of six species from the region, including three new species. &lt;i&gt;Rhopalophthalmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phyllodus&lt;/i&gt; Murano, 1988 was regarded as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;egregius&lt;/i&gt; Hansen, 1910. The identity of &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macropsis&lt;/i&gt; Pillai, 1964 has been controversial, and in this study, we recognised it as valid. However, specimens with remarkably stout and few spinose setae on the telson, often reported as either &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macropsis&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes&lt;/i&gt; Ii, 1964 were determined to be a new species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armiger.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, two new species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hastatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;philippinensis,&lt;/i&gt; were reported from south-eastern Asian waters. A key to the 25 currently recognised world species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mysid shrimp; &lt;i&gt;Rhopalophthalmus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species; eastern Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mysid shrimp</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yukio</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanamura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masaaki</firstname>
          <lastname>Murano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alias</firstname>
          <lastname>Man</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-37</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomic status of the Brazilian mouse &lt;i&gt;Calomys anoblepas &lt;/i&gt;Winge, 1887 (Mammalia, Rodentia, Cricetidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We studied the holotype and only known specimen of the rodent &lt;i&gt;Calomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anoblepas&lt;/i&gt; Winge, 1887, an enigmatic and putatively extinct pentalophodont sigmodontine found in the limestone caves of Lagoa Santa, Minas Gerais, Brazil. Comparisons with other sigmodontines suggest that &lt;i&gt;anoblepas&lt;/i&gt; can be allocated under the genus &lt;i&gt;Juliomys&lt;/i&gt; González, 2000 and probably represents an extinct form within it. Cranial characters that support our generic hypothesis include the combination of an interlacrymal depression behind nasals, anterior portion of interfrontal suture with incomplete fusion, zygomatic plate nearly vertical with almost nonexistent upper free border, anterior border of the mesopterygoid fossa located at the level of third molar hypoflexus, and brachyodont molars with crested coronal topography. &lt;i&gt;Juliomys&lt;/i&gt; includes three living species of sylvan and arboreal mice endemic of the Atlantic forests. This genus is absent in contemporaneous rodent assemblage from Lagoa Santa area, suggesting different environmental conditions during Pleistocene deposition times.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sigmodontinae; &lt;i&gt;Juliomys&lt;/i&gt;; Lagoa Santa; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sigmodontinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulyses</firstname>
          <middlename>F. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pardiñas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <lastname>Teta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-44</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The forgotten Narrative of H.M.S. &lt;i&gt;Challenger &lt;/i&gt;and the implications for decapod nomenclature</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Narrative of the &lt;i&gt;Challenger&lt;/i&gt; cruise was published in 1885 and contained valid descriptions of crustacean decapod taxa. While C.S. Bate (Challenger Macrura) mentioned the discovery of new taxa without making them valid, J.R. Henderson (Anomura) and E.J. Miers (Brachyura) provided short descriptions including figures that made several new names available. With a few exceptions, these valid scientific names together with their date of availability have been overlooked by almost all subsequent taxonomic studies. Consequently the decapod taxa named in the &lt;i&gt;Challenger&lt;/i&gt; Narrative are listed and the implications for nomenclature in each case are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Challenger&lt;/i&gt;; Narrative; Crustacea; Decapoda; Anomura; Brachyura; Macrura; nomenclature; C.S. Bate; J.R. Henderson; E.J. Miers</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Challenger&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlo</firstname>
          <lastname>Froglia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Clark</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of hahniid spiders from Far East Asia (Araneae: Hahniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pacifantistea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovtchinnikovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; belonging to Hahniinae is described on the basis of males and females from Moneron Island, Kuril Islands, the southern part of Maritime Province, the southern part of Kamchatka and Hokkaido. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovtchinnikovi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is the largest species among Hahniinae. The new species is compared in detail with other large–sized Hahniinae: &lt;i&gt;Neoantistea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magna&lt;/i&gt; (Nearctic) and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quelpartensis&lt;/i&gt; (SE Palaearctic). The poorly documented affinities of these additional two species are discussed and illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">East Palaearctic; Nearctic; &lt;i&gt;Neoantistea&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Kuril Islands; Moneron; Maritime Province; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">East Palaearctic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marusik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
