<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2804.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Mar. 2011</title>
    <volume>2804</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the genus &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus &lt;/i&gt;Monticelli, 1910 (Polychaeta: Ctenodrilidae) with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harperi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway (GIWW) in Venice, Florida from sediments consisting of coarse sands and shell hash. &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hawaiiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Oahu’s shallow waters and inhabits a successful invasive alga in Waikiki and sandy sediments adjacent to ocean outfalls in Barbers Point and Sand Island, off Honolulu. The genus &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; is emended, the distinctness between the genera &lt;i&gt;Raricirrus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; is confirmed and keys to all recognized genera of Ctenodrilidae and species of &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polychaeta; Ctenodrilidae; &lt;i&gt;Raphidrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nemasoma&lt;/i&gt;; Florida; Hawaii</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polychaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wagner</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Magalhães</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julie</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bailey–Brock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jennifer</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davenport</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological distinction of species of &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia: Echimyidae) through ontogeny of cranial and dental characters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent cytogenetic and molecular studies changed the monotypic status of the genus &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys,&lt;/i&gt; recognizing at least four species. In this study we analyzed cranial and dental characters throughout ontogeny to investigate morphological differences between three species from Brazil: &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laurentius,&lt;/i&gt; from Caruaru, Pernambuco State; &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis,&lt;/i&gt; from Morro do Chapéu, Bahia state; and &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachyurus,&lt;/i&gt; from Barão de Melgaço, Mato Grosso state. The samples were chosen by proximity to type localities and availability in collections. We described age classes for each species, grouped in four categories: juvenile, sub-adult, adult and senile. The unique pattern of wear of cheekteeth described in literature to the genus was made for a population from Bodocó, Pernambuco and was different of the patterns described in this study. The three patterns of tooth wear also differed from each other. In the analysis of the skull, three of the 14 characters observed did not vary during the ontogeny of each species or among the species examined. Four characters observed varied during the ontogeny of the three species examined, but in a similar way. The eight other cranial characters analyzed varied during ontogeny of the species and differently in each species. Among these eight characters, four were useful to distinction of species of &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys.&lt;/i&gt; These characters were stable during the ontogeny of each species but were different among the three species: the shape of the interpremaxilar foramen, the shape of the incisive foramen, the shape of hamular processes, and the shape of the angle of mesopterygoid fossa. The description of the ontogenetic series of these species showed marked differences between them, corroborating morphologically the distinction of three different species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">morphological differentiation; age groups; &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laurentius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thrichomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachyurus&lt;/i&gt;; Neotropic; Brazil; ontogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">morphological differentiation</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>Carlos</middlename>
          <lastname>Da S. A. Neves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leila</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Pessôa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-24</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) of the Langbian Plateau, southern Vietnam, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We sampled two forms of &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; in syntopy at the type locality of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pullum&lt;/i&gt; at upper elevations on the Langbian Plateau, southern Vietnam. The two forms differed in morphology (primarily in coloration), mitochondrial DNA, and male advertisement calls. One form closely agrees with the type series of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pullum&lt;/i&gt; (but not to its original description due to error), and the other is described as new. &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from its congeners by having small body size (males with SVL 38.8–45.2), the upper one-third to one-half of iris white, a blue scleral arc, a dark venter, and sexually active males without spines on the upper lip. &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pullum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mouhoti,&lt;/i&gt; a recently described species from low-elevation slopes of the Langbian Plateau in eastern Cambodia, are morphologically divergent but genetically similar, warranting further investigation into geographic variation in the red-eyed &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; of southern Indochina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Langbian Plateau; &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pullum;&lt;/i&gt; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Langbian Plateau; &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pullum;&lt;/i&gt; Vietnam</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bryan</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stuart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jodi</firstname>
          <middlename>J. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rowley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dao</firstname>
          <middlename>Thi Anh</middlename>
          <lastname>Tran</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Duong</firstname>
          <middlename>Thi Thuy</middlename>
          <lastname>Le</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Huy</firstname>
          <middlename>Duc</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Geoplana multicolor &lt;/i&gt;Graff (Platyhelminthes: Tricladida): new records and taxonomic re-interpretation of morphological characters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Many species of land flatworms have been described based on specimens, or even on a single specimen, from a sole locality. Thus, populational or individual variations are poorly known. The external morphology of &lt;i&gt;Geoplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicolor&lt;/i&gt; Graff, 1899 was first described based on a single specimen from the vicinities of the city of São Paulo, South Brazil. Marcus (1951) analysed specimens from São Paulo with a similar external aspect and considered them as conspecific with &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicolor,&lt;/i&gt; describing their internal anatomy. In the present work, we amplify the known distribution of the species, by registering its occurrence in four localities of southern Brazil (state of Rio Grande do Sul), and comparatively analyse this relatively ample material, which includes different developmental phases. The description of histological aspects, especially those regarding musculature and secretory cells of the copulatory organs, has been enhanced and amplified after the present analysis. Thus, the description of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multicolor&lt;/i&gt; is here complemented, with an improvement on the interpretation of important taxonomical characters. In addition, the paper reports, for the first time, the occurrence of an ejaculate attached to the atrial wall of a species of Geoplaninae which presents a penis papilla, and briefly discusses its significance.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geoplaninae; taxonomy; developmental stages; spermatophore</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geoplaninae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Leal-Zanchet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lisiane</firstname>
          <middlename>Bernardes</middlename>
          <lastname>De Matos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-55</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Distolabrellus magnivulvatus &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Nematoda, Rhabditida, Mesorhabditidae) from Iberian peninsula, the second species of a rare genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Distolabrellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magnivulvatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; collected from green-house soil in central Iberian peninsula, is described and illustrated. It is characterized by having 0.89–1.07 mm long body in females and 0.65–0.99 mm in males, cuticle tesselated, lateral fields with three longitudinal incisures, lip region almost continuous and 10–13 µm wide, lips dimorphic (alternately extremely reduced and ovoid), stoma 22–30 μm long or 2.0–2.8 times lip region diameter, pharyngeal collar shorter than half of total stoma length, distance to pharyngo-intestinal junction 148–190 µm, &lt;i&gt;V&lt;/i&gt; = 82–86, vulva a transverse slit located in a vulval cone and with its anterior lip bearing a flap-like structure, body cuticle surrounding the vulva especially differentiated, female tail conical with acute tip (68–90 μm, &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; = 10.9–14.6, &lt;i&gt;c’&lt;/i&gt; = 2.1–4.5), male tail conical (23–32 μm, &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; = 24.8–34.0; &lt;i&gt;c’&lt;/i&gt; = 1.0–1.4), bursa peloderan and open anteriorly, genital papillae ten pairs (2+1/4+3), spicules 54–64 μ m long and fused two-thirds, and gubernaculum 32–41 μm long. The new taxon is the second species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Distolabrellus&lt;/i&gt; and is compared to type species &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;veechi.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Description; Mesorhabditidae; morphology; rhabditids; Iberian peninsula; new species; SEM; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Description</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joaquín</firstname>
          <lastname>Abolafia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Reyes</firstname>
          <lastname>Peña-Santiago</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
