<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2880.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2880</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological, bioacoustical, and genetic variation in &lt;i&gt;Miniopterus &lt;/i&gt;bats from eastern Madagascar, with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent molecular genetic work, combined with morphological comparisons, of Malagasy members of the bat genus &lt;i&gt;Miniopterus&lt;/i&gt; (Family Miniopteridae), has revealed several cryptic species. Based on new specimens and associated tissues, we examine patterns of variation in the recently described species &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petersoni,&lt;/i&gt; the holotype of which comes from extreme southeastern Madagascar, and for which specimens from more northerly portions of eastern Madagascar were noted to show some morphological divergence from typical &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petersoni.&lt;/i&gt; On the basis of morphological and genetic (cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; characters we described a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;egeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; This taxon also shows bioacoustical differences from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petersoni.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Miniopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;egeri&lt;/i&gt; is widely distributed in the eastern portion of Madagascar across an elevational range from near sea level to 550 m. The specific status of moderately small &lt;i&gt;Miniopterus&lt;/i&gt; from Montagne d’Ambre in the far north remains to be determined.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; morphology; molecular genetics; &lt;i&gt;Miniopterus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; eastern Madagascar; cryptic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Goodman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Beza</firstname>
          <lastname>Ramasindrazana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudette</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Maminirina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Corrie</middlename>
          <lastname>Schoeman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Belinda</firstname>
          <lastname>Appleton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic identity of the patagonian frog &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus jeinimenensis&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Neobatrachia) as revealed by molecular and morphometric evidence</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The frog genus &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; is currently represented by nine species distributed in Argentinean and Chilean Patagonia. It is mainly distributed in Argentina, and there are only three species in Chile (A. &lt;i&gt;ceii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandisonae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis).&lt;/i&gt; Regarding the morphological relationships among &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; species, Meriggio &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (2004) suggest that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis&lt;/i&gt; is more related to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt; than other species. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt; was described from Laguna Los Gendarmes (Argentina), 90 km air line from the type locality of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis.&lt;/i&gt; This paper presents a morphological analysis and a study of population genetics using mtDNA nucleotide data from Argentinean and Chilean localities to assess the genetic distance between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenimenensis.&lt;/i&gt; We obtained 477 bp-long &lt;i&gt;d-loop&lt;/i&gt; sequences from 51 &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; specimens collected in four localities. According to our results, the morphological differences between &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis&lt;/i&gt; populations are limited to size, and there are no distinctive characteristics that would separate two species, in addition to which a simple geographic pattern of genetic diversity suggests a single species of &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus.&lt;/i&gt; Also, the populations from Chile (Cerro Castillo, RN Lago Jeinimeni and Chile Chico) and Argentina (Laguna de Los Gendarmes) have low levels of genetic divergence that may be consistent with glaciations during the Late Pleistocene. We propose &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis&lt;/i&gt; as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt; and that the Chilean populations should be assigned to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">d-loop; haplotypes network; mtDNA; population genetics; taxonomic; morfology; Anura; &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salai&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeinimenensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">d-loop</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Helen</firstname>
          <lastname>Díaz-Páez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcela</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vidal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ortiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carmen</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Úbeda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Néstor</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Basso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-30</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Western boundary of the subfamily Danioninae in Asia (Teleostei, Cyprinidae): derived from the systematic position of &lt;i&gt;Barilius mesopotamicus&lt;/i&gt; based on molecular and morphological data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Analysis of mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; sequences from 198 species confirms the position of &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mesopotamicus&lt;/i&gt; as a species of the Asian genus &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; within the subtribe Chedrina in the subfamily Danioninae. This relationship is supported by a parsimony analysis based on 43 morphological characters, and the morphological examination confirms that &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mesopotamicus&lt;/i&gt; possesses the synapomorphies of the Danioninae and Chedrina, &lt;i&gt;viz.&lt;/i&gt; absence of the Y-shaped ligament and the greatly reduced postcleithrum, respectively. &lt;i&gt;Barilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mesopotamicus&lt;/i&gt; greatly expands the western boundary of the Asian Danioninae into the Tigris-Euphrates basin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b;&lt;/i&gt; Tigris-Euphrates; disjunct distribution; freshwater fish; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b;&lt;/i&gt; Tigris-Euphrates; disjunct distribution; freshwater fish; biogeography</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Te-Yu</firstname>
          <lastname>Liao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Erhan</firstname>
          <lastname>Ünlü</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kullander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys &lt;/i&gt;Miranda-Ribeiro (Amphibia: Anura: Cycloramphidae) from central Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristiceps&lt;/i&gt; group is described from central Brazil based on adult morphology and advertisement call. &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vielliardi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is mainly diagnosed by its medium size, lack of tubercular sagittal crests from eyelids to coccyx and a multi-noted advertisement call. This is the second species of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; described from central Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cerrado; Lissamphibia; Odontophrynini; State of Goiás; taxonomy; vocalization</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cerrado</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lucas</firstname>
          <middlename>Borges</middlename>
          <lastname>Martins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ariovaldo</firstname>
          <middlename>Antonio</middlename>
          <lastname>Giaretta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescriptions of &lt;i&gt;Eunice filamentosa &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;E. denticulata&lt;/i&gt; and description of &lt;i&gt;E. tovarae &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Polychaeta: Eunicidae), highlighted with morphological and molecular data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In a series of studies on eunicids, three Grand Caribbean species &lt;i&gt;Eunice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filamentosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conglomerans&lt;/i&gt; were regarded as synonyms, or part of a species complex with an amphiamerican distribution. The revision of type and additional materials collected in the Grand Caribbean Region (GCR) and along the Mexican Pacific coasts, allowed us to clarify that &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conglomerans&lt;/i&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata.&lt;/i&gt; Thus, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filamentosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt; are valid species in the GCR; while the specimens from the Tropical Eastern Pacific belong to a newly described species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tovarae&lt;/i&gt; n.sp. Herein we describe these three species, and some morphological features described in previous studies are reevaluated. Additionally, we found an important genetic divergence in nucleotide sequence variation of COI, which supported the morphological data. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filamentosa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt; have a genetic divergence of 19.6%; whereas &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tovarae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a genetic divergence of 20.7% from &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata,&lt;/i&gt; and a 12.9% divergence from &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;filamentosa.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; amphiamerican species; COI-Barcoding; cryptic species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carrera-Parra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Salazar-Vallejo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
