<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2889.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2889</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Olivancillaria &lt;/i&gt;(Mollusca: Olividae) from the southwestern Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Olivancillaria&lt;/i&gt; is revised and restricted to eight living species: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;deshayesiana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carcellesi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urceus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contortuplicata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orbignyi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;teaguei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auricularia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vesica.&lt;/i&gt; The last two species were previously considered as subspecies. The name &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uretai&lt;/i&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orbignyi.&lt;/i&gt; The genus &lt;i&gt;Olivancillaria&lt;/i&gt; is endemic to the southwestern Atlantic, ranging from Bahia state, Brazil (~12°S) to Chubut province (42°37’S), Argentina, intertidal to 70 m depth. It is a clear representative of the Argentine Malacological province. Redescriptions and re-illustration of types were done for each species. Shell ultrastructure, radulae, penes, siphon papillae and egg capsules are described and illustrated by SEM images. A geometric morphometric analysis was carried out to confirm shell variation on size and shape among species. The geographic distribution of each species is provided based on field observations as well as on museum records.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Argentina; Gastropoda; geometric morphometric analysis; Neogastropoda; &lt;i&gt;Olivancillaria&lt;/i&gt;; Olividae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Argentina</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Valeria</firstname>
          <lastname>Teso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guido</firstname>
          <lastname>Pastorino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-34</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Labuanium vitatum &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Sesarmidae), a new Indo-West Pacific species of arboreal crab</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Labuanium&lt;/i&gt; Serène &amp; Soh, 1970, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitatum&lt;/i&gt; is described from northeastern Indian Ocean. It belongs to the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotundatum&lt;/i&gt; species-group, but is most closely related to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scandens&lt;/i&gt; Ng &amp; Liu, 2003, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;papuomalesiacum&lt;/i&gt; (Nobili, 1899), the latter being here formally removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotundatum&lt;/i&gt; (Hess, 1865) and raised to full species status. The new species differs from congeners by numerous characters including the structure of the male first pleopod, carapace and third maxillipeds, and by differences in proportions of the male abdominal somites.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; Sesarmidae; &lt;i&gt;Labuanium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitatum&lt;/i&gt; new species; Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>J. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new &lt;i&gt;Byrathis &lt;/i&gt;species (Copepoda: Calanoida) from the deep South Atlantic and Southern Ocean and first description of an adult male</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species, &lt;i&gt;Byrathis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;divae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicillatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from females collected in the deep waters and at abyssal depths above the sea bed, and are the first representatives of the genus recorded from the South Atlantic. Species of &lt;i&gt;Byrathis&lt;/i&gt; Markhaseva &amp; Ferrari, 2005 are divided into 2 groups. The first group, which includes both new species, contains medium sized copepods (from 2.1 to 4.9 mm) with a nude genital double somite, maxillule proximal basal endite with 3 setae, maxillule exopod with 6 or more setae, and maxilla endopod with 3 worm-like and 5 brush-like sensory setae. The second group contains small species (less than 1.4 mm) that share the surface ornamentation of the genital double somite, maxillule proximal basal endite with 2 setae, maxillule exopod with 5 setae or less, and maxilla endopod with 5 worm-like plus 3 brush-like sensory setae. For the first time an adult &lt;i&gt;Byrathis&lt;/i&gt; male is described after &lt;i&gt;Byrathis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arnei&lt;/i&gt; Schulz, 2006 from the Southern Ocean. Among males of Clausocalanoidea that possess sensory setae on maxilla and maxilliped, the &lt;i&gt;Byrathis&lt;/i&gt; male is well defined by symmetric antennules (ancestral segments XXII–XXIII fused on both sides) and poorly expressed P5 coxa and basis asymmetry, with both exopods 3-segmented and the right leg uniramous.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clausocalanoidea; Diaixidae; calanoids; taxonomy; benthopelagic; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clausocalanoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Markhaseva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jasmin</firstname>
          <lastname>Renz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
