<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2890.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2890</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology and Molecular Phylogeny of the East and Southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Meghimatium &lt;/i&gt;slugs (Gastropoda: Pulmonata: Philomycidae) and description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Meghimatium&lt;/i&gt; is a group of terrestrial slugs distributed in Asia. 185 specimens were collected from Taiwan, China, Okinawa (Japan), Thailand and Malaysia. Phylogenetic analyses using concatenated DNA sequences of cytochrome C oxidase subunit I, 16S ribosomal RNA and nuclear 28S ribosomal RNA genes revealed that clades in the resulting molecular phylogeny of &lt;i&gt;Meghimatium&lt;/i&gt; are largely congruent with taxa identified on the basis of their genitalia. Four monophyletic groups, &lt;i&gt;i.e.,&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fruhstorferi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;burchi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uniforme&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striatum&lt;/i&gt; complexes, with moderate to strong statistical supports (86/53/0.98/66, 100/100/1.00/100, 100/100/1.00/100, 100/100/1.00/100) were identified. &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pictum&lt;/i&gt; is paraphyletic and is clustered with &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bilineatum&lt;/i&gt; to constitute an additional monophyletic group (100/100/1.00/100). Body size does not show an evolutionary trend either from small to large or vice versa, based on the phylogenetic tree. A new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baoshanense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is named based on the included specimens constituting a monophyletic group, its medium size (40.1–52.7 mm in body length) and its genitalia with 10–18 papillae at the lower end of the spermathecal duct where it connects to the uterus and vagina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">16S rRNA; 28S rRNA; COI; genitalia; &lt;i&gt;Meghimatium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baoshanense&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">16S rRNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chi-Li</firstname>
          <lastname>Tsai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chung-Cheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Lu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsiao-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Kao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Cycloramphidae) from western Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristiceps&lt;/i&gt; group is described from western Brazil. The new species is characterized by absence of prominent palpebral appendages and postocular swellings, males measuring 44.2 ± 2.1 mm SVL (41.1–47.3 mm) and females 56.4 ± 2.8 mm SVL (52.7–59.8 mm), snout rounded in dorsal ,and obtuse in lateral views, dorsal skin uniformly rugose, with no elevated warts, and tympanum defined as a depression on the skin. The new species was found in Guaporé river drainage, a highly impacted area due to the construction of water dams.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristiceps&lt;/i&gt; group; Amphibia; morphology; Cerrado; Amazon; &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strussmannae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristiceps&lt;/i&gt; group</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robson</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ávila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kawashita-Ribeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Drausio</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morais</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-28</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Fennera holthuisi &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;, a new coral-associated pontoniine shrimp (Decapoda: Palaemonidae: Pontoniinae) from Moorea, French Polynesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The second species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Fennera&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holthuisi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described, based on a female specimen collected at Moorea, French Polynesia. The new species clearly differs from &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951 by &lt;b&gt;carinated&lt;/b&gt; dactylus of major pereiopod II (vs. &lt;b&gt;flattened&lt;/b&gt; in &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei),&lt;/i&gt; more &lt;b&gt;robust&lt;/b&gt; segments and &lt;b&gt;feebly&lt;/b&gt; developed fingers of minor pereiopod II, and proportions of the distal segments of ambulatory pereiopod III. The holotype female of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1951 and specimens from the type series are re-examined and re-described, based on specimens from the Pacific coast of Panama and Columbia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Fennera&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Moorea; French Polynesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-39</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The position of the Hymenosomatidae MacLeay, 1838, within the Brachyura (Crustacea, Decapoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Hymenosomatidae is unique among the Brachyura on the basis of spermatozoal ultrastructure and morphological characters of the adults and larvae. The location of the hymenosomatid male gonopore, always a controversial question, is here shown to be sternal, not coxo-sternal. This disposition, analogous to the arrangement of Thoracotremata, contradicts all morphological characters that indicate a heterotreme affiliation, close to the Majoidea and Dorippoidea. Molecular data also support such an assignment. The multiple hymenosomatid plesiomorphies are reviewed. The exceptional male reproductive system, a new scheme for the Eubrachyura, is assumed, at least in part, to be the result of a strong carcinisation in an ancient, deeply rooted group, at present the most ecologically diverse in Brachyura. The presence of the Hymenosomatidae on the former Gondwanan landmasses and its worldwide pattern of distribution are consistent with the hypothesis of a Gondwanan origin of the family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; Eubrachyura; Thoracotremata; Heterotremata; Hymenosomatidae; Majoidea; Dorippoidea; male reproductive system; male gonopore; spermatozoa; coxo-sternal condition; carcinisation; larval development; megalopa; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danièle</firstname>
          <lastname>Guinot</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-52</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gekko canaensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Squamata: Gekkonidae), a new gecko from Southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; Laurenti 1768 is described from southern Vietnam. The species is distinguished from its congeners by its moderate size: SVL to maximum 108.5 mm, dorsal pattern of five to seven white vertebral blotches between nape and sacrum and six to seven pairs of short white bars on flanks between limb insertions, 1–4 internasals, 30–32 ventral scale rows between weak ventrolateral folds, 14–18 precloacal pores in males, 10–14 longitudinal rows of smooth dorsal tubercles, 14–16 broad lamellae beneath digit I of pes, 17–19 broad lamellae beneath digit IV of pes, and a single transverse row of enlarged tubercles along the posterior portion of dorsum of each tail segment.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cà Ná Cape; description; &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Gekkonidae; granitic outcrop; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cà Ná Cape</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tony</firstname>
          <lastname>Gamble</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">DNA barcoding identifies a third invasive species of &lt;i&gt;Eleutherodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (Anura: Eleutherodactylidae) in Panama City, Panama</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Crawford</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Alonso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>César</firstname>
          <middlename>A. Jaramillo</middlename>
          <lastname>A.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Samuel</firstname>
          <lastname>Sucre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>Ibáñez</middlename>
          <lastname>D.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: OKANISHI, M. &amp; FUJITA, T. (2011) Two new species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Asteroporpa&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Astromoana&lt;/i&gt;) (Ophiuroidea: Euryalida: Gorgonocephalidae) from Japan. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2751, 25–39. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
