<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2899.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2899</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic review of the subfamily &lt;i&gt;Bradyporinae &lt;/i&gt;(Orthoptera: Tettigoniidae; Bradyporini; Ephippigerini) of Turkey, with description of new species and the relationship of the taxa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The members of the subfamily &lt;i&gt;Bradyporinae&lt;/i&gt; including &lt;i&gt;Bradyporini&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ephippigerini&lt;/i&gt; found in Turkey are studied. Two phylogenetic relationships based on morphology for the subgenera, species groups and for the all species of &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.l.&lt;/i&gt; are proposed. A new diagram shows together the relationships and the schematized distributions of the taxa, Geographical Network Relationship, is proposed. A synonymic checklist of the known species of &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.l.&lt;/i&gt; is given. Taxonomical changes, the doubtful and uncertain taxa names are discussed. &lt;i&gt;Callimenus&lt;/i&gt; Fischer von Waldheim, 1830 is proposed as a subgenus of &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; Charpentier, 1825. Four species groups, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oniscus&lt;/i&gt; sp. group, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrogaster&lt;/i&gt; sp. group, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dilatatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. group and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latipes&lt;/i&gt; sp. group, are separated. &lt;i&gt;Callimenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrogaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pancici&lt;/i&gt; Brunner, 1882 is synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrogaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicollis&lt;/i&gt; (Fieber, 1853). Neotypes for &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(s.str.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dasypus&lt;/i&gt; (Illiger, 1800) and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrogaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrogaster&lt;/i&gt; (Lefebvre, 1831) are designated. Five new species, &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;avanos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sureyai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conophallus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toros&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;karabagi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; are described. &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Callimenus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latipes&lt;/i&gt; (Stål, 1875) is recorded from Turkey for the first time. The species &lt;i&gt;Schulmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schulmeisteri&lt;/i&gt; Harz, 1992 is excluded from the subfamily &lt;i&gt;Bradyporinae.&lt;/i&gt; All previous records of &lt;i&gt;Bradyporinae&lt;/i&gt; species in Turkey with full synonymic list of each species are given. The previous misidentifications are determined and then the distribution of each species is adjusted. The characters used the separation of the taxa are briefly discussed. The titillator for Turkish species and the basal projecting of ventral valve of ovipositor are used for the first time. Descriptions and redescriptions of the studied &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; species are given. Keys to tribes, subgenera, species groups and Turkish species of &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt; are provided. In addition 157 original figures including a distributional map are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Orthoptera; Bradyporinae; &lt;i&gt;Bradyporus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Callimenus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; systematic; phylogeny; Geographical Network Relationship; distribution; Europe; Turkey; Caucasia; Iran</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Orthoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mustafa</firstname>
          <lastname>Ünal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">What about intraspecific variation? Reassessment of taxonomic and phylogenetic characters in the genus &lt;i&gt;Synoeca &lt;/i&gt;de Saussure (Hymenoptera: Vespidae: Polistinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Morphological variation within and between species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Synoeca&lt;/i&gt; was studied to test species status and to propose characters that fulfill the principles of communicability, unit delimitation, and conjunction for taxonomic and phylogenetic analyses. Twenty-six morphological characters obtained from the literature were analyzed; 16 of these characters clearly exhibited delimited states but only four of them were unique for each species. The status of every species of the genus was supported by geometric morphometrics of the head (front view, dorsal view and metasomal tergum 1) and by the presence of unique character states for each species. Phylogenetic analyses included nest and genitalia characters. Character reassessment provided a less resolved tree to that previously published. Including polymorphic characters did not improve tree resolution or clade support, while applying the conjunction test offered a more resolved and better supported tree. The study revealed the importance of analyzing variation in taxonomic and phylogenetic studies within and between species. A new key to species and a phylogenetic hypothesis are offered.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Epiponini; geometric morphometrics; polymorphism; conjunction test; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Epiponini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cely</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sarmiento</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-59</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cordulegaster sarracenia, &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Odonata: Cordulegastridae) from east Texas and western Louisiana, with a key to adult Cordulegastridae of the New World</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cordulegaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarracenia&lt;/i&gt; is described from spring seepages in pitcher plant bogs of southeast Texas and western Louisiana. It is most closely related to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sayi&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diastatops&lt;/i&gt; group. It is unique among all North American species of its genus in having the mesepimeral and metepimeral stripes distinctly paler than the mesepisternal stripes in combination with yellow bands on S3–8 that are interrupted middorsally by the carina.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anisoptera; Cordulegastroidea; &lt;i&gt;Zoraena&lt;/i&gt;; new species; pitcher plants</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anisoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Abbott</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Troy</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hibbitts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
