<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2918.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2918</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of cryptic Asian green pitviper (Serpentes: Viperidae: Crotalinae) from southwest China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Asian green pitviper is described from Southwest China based on two female specimens. A new DNA phylogeny recovers the two specimens of the new species as a well-supported clade that is sister group to all sampled representatives of the genera &lt;i&gt;Viridovipera&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Cryptelytrops.&lt;/i&gt; The new genus is distinguished from other pitviper genera by a combination of morphological characters, including the absence of a lateral stripe, large body size, and deep red eye in adult females. Morphologically the new species is superficially most similar to species of &lt;i&gt;Popeia&lt;/i&gt; in body dimension and scalation, but is genetically extremely distinct. The new genus/species is currently known only from south Sichuan, where it was found at about 1000 m above sea level in less disturbed evergreen rainforest.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">southeast Asia; DNA; phylogeny; snakes; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">southeast Asia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peng</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuezhao</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New olenelline trilobites from the Northwest Territories, Canada, and the phylogenetic placement of &lt;i&gt;Judomia absita &lt;/i&gt;Fritz, 1973</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Early Cambrian olenelline trilobites are a diverse clade and have been the subject of several phylogenetic analyses. Here, three new species of &lt;i&gt;Bradyfallotaspis&lt;/i&gt; Fritz, 1972 (B. &lt;i&gt;coriae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nicolascagei,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sekwiensis)&lt;/i&gt; and one new species of &lt;i&gt;Nevadia&lt;/i&gt; Walcott, 1910 (N. &lt;i&gt;saupeae)&lt;/i&gt; are described from the Sekwi Formation of the Mackenzie Mountains, Northwest Territories, Canada. In addition, new specimens potentially referable to &lt;i&gt;Nevadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovalis&lt;/i&gt; McMenamin, 1987 were recovered that may expand that species’ geographic range, which was thought to be restricted to Sonora, Mexico. The results of a phylogenetic analysis incorporating several olenelline taxa, including &lt;i&gt;Judomia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;absita&lt;/i&gt; Fritz, 1973 from the Sekwi Formation, are also presented herein. This species has been assigned to various olenelline genera, including &lt;i&gt;Judomia&lt;/i&gt; Lermontova, 1951 and &lt;i&gt;Paranevadella&lt;/i&gt; Palmer &amp; Repina, 1993. Phylogenetic analysis suggests this species is closely related to &lt;i&gt;Judomia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tera&lt;/i&gt; Lazarenko, 1960 from Siberia. This phylogenetic relationship provides further support for the hypothesis that a close biogeographic relationship existed between Laurentia and Siberia during the Cambrian.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trilobita; Olenellina; Cambrian radiation; phylogenetics; paleobiogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trilobita</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>I.</firstname>
          <middlename>Wesley</middlename>
          <lastname>Gapp</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bruce</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lieberman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pope</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kelly</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dilliard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-28</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Catoptrus iejima&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of cavernicolous swimming crab (Crustacea: Brachyura: Portunidae) from a submarine cave at Ie Island, Ryukyu Islands, Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of swimming crab belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Catoptrus&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1870, is described based on a single female specimen collected from a submarine cave at Ie Island, Ryukyu Islands, Japan. The new species can be easily distinguished from all five congeners by its proportionally longer pereopods as well as by combinations of the characters of the carapace, eyes, and cheliped.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; Portunidae; new species; taxonomy; Ryukyu Islands; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yoshihisa</firstname>
          <lastname>Fujita</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tohru</firstname>
          <lastname>Naruse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of mole-rat (Rodentia, Bathyergidae) from the Horn of Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of mole-rat with a striking colour pattern is described from a single mounted specimen in the historical collection of the ‘Museo Civico di Zoologia’ in Rome, Italy. The lack of skull and original collecting data does not allow the gathering of firm evidences about its taxonomic relationships, geographical range and ecological preferences. This taxon is provisionally allocated to the recently created genus &lt;i&gt;Fukomys&lt;/i&gt; Kock, Ingram, Frabotta, Honeycutt and Burda 2006 on the grounds of pelage colour pattern and geographical origin. All the available evidence, including label and other fragmentary historical data, supports &lt;i&gt;Fukomys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ilariae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; as originating from the Lower Shebelle region near Mogadishu, Somalia, historically known as Benadir. This discovery highlights the relevance for biodiversity conservation of the Horn of Africa and the need of further faunistic research to describe its fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Historical collections; Museo Civico di Zoologia; Mammalia; &lt;i&gt;Fukomys&lt;/i&gt;; Horn of Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Historical collections</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Spartaco</firstname>
          <lastname>Gippoliti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Amori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-46</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new large and colorful skink of the genus &lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus &lt;/i&gt;from Madagascar revealed by morphology and multilocus molecular study</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt; skink from the western edge of the Central Highlands of Madagascar in the Reserve of Makira, and also found in the Réserve Spéciale of Ambohijanahary and in the Réserve Spéciale of Marotandrano. &lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meva&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized and differentiated from other species of the genus by a combination of morphological, chromatic and molecular characters: 1) a relatively large size (SVL of adults from 126 to 150 mm); 2) a characteristic pattern of coloration, &lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meva&lt;/i&gt; being the only skink in Madagascar together with &lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenni&lt;/i&gt; with dark grey dorsum contrasting with orange flanks and ventrum; 3) the absence of a postnasal scale; 4) the presubocular frequently absent, 5) the presence of single elongated tertiary temporal bordering lower secondary temporal and 6) pentadactyl limbs. In addition to the morphological approach, a multi-locus genetic analysis based on eight mitochondrial and nuclear genes clearly supports the distinctiveness of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meva.&lt;/i&gt; This new species was found in areas of rainforest, sometimes containing transitional deciduous forest elements. It was typically observed under large rotten logs associated with dense layers of decomposed wood retaining certain humidity and providing habitat for invertebrate larvae and termites.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt;; conservation; Madagascar; molecular phylogeny; rainforest; Squamata: Scincomorpha: Scincidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amphiglossus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Aurélien</firstname>
          <lastname>Miralles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Achille</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Raselimanana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Domoina</firstname>
          <lastname>Rakotomalala</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vieites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The original spellings of &lt;i&gt;Thryothorus &lt;/i&gt;Vieillot, 1816 (Vertebrata, Aves): a correction</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Normand</firstname>
          <lastname>David</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
