<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2993.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Aug. 2011</title>
    <volume>2993</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-08-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Crepis &lt;/i&gt;Jullien (Bryozoa: Cheilostomata) with description of a new genus and family and notes on Chlidoniidae </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed from original material held in different institutions and transferred to the family Calloporidae. &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes,&lt;/i&gt; the type species, is redescribed and stabilized by typification. The description of &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verticillata&lt;/i&gt; is amplified. Three new species are described, all of them previously identified as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longipes:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmelini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the Strait of Gibraltar, &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sidneyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the Indo-Pacific region, and &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from the South China Sea. A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Mourellina&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., is erected for &lt;i&gt;Crepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decussata,&lt;/i&gt; which is split into two species: &lt;i&gt;Mourellina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decussata&lt;/i&gt; n. comb. and &lt;i&gt;Mourellina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gonzaloi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; This genus is placed in its own family, Mourellinidae n. fam., of uncertain affinities. The diagnosis of the family Chlidoniidae, which up to now included the genera &lt;i&gt;Chlidonia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Crepis,&lt;/i&gt; is modified by excluding the latter genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Calloporidae; new family; new genus; new species; NE Atlantic; Indo-Pacific; Australia; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Calloporidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Reverter-Gil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <lastname>Souto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eugenio</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernández-Pulpeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Salmo tigridis&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of trout from the Tigris River, Turkey (Teleostei: Salmonidae) DAVUT TURAN (Turkey), MAURICE KOTTELAT (Switzerland) &amp; YUSUF BEKTAŞ (Turkey)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Order</middlename>
          <lastname>Pdf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The fossil mite family Archaeorchestidae (Acari, Oribatida) I: redescription of &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus illibatus &lt;/i&gt;and synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus &lt;/i&gt;with &lt;i&gt;Archaeorchestes &lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; is one of several oribatid mite genera proposed by Max Sellnick based on adult specimens preserved in Eocene Baltic amber. The original specimens of its type-species—S. &lt;i&gt;illibatus&lt;/i&gt; Sellnick, 1918—were lost and the genus has received no further empirical study. For many years &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; was included in the family Eremaeidae, but recently this placement was questioned. Herein we redescribe &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illibatus&lt;/i&gt; based on the study of 31 non-type adult specimens from both Baltic and Rovno ambers. Among these are four Baltic specimens identified by Sellnick and currently deposited in the Kaliningrad Museum of Amber (KMA), which we designate as neotype (KMA 197-36) and paraneotypes (KMA 197-34, 197-35, and 197-37). Six immature specimens were associated with this species, of which three—one deutonymph, two tritonymphs—could be studied in detail and their characters are included in the redescription. The type specimens of a second species of &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; proposed by Sellnick—S. &lt;i&gt;cordiformatus&lt;/i&gt; Sellnick, 1918—are also lost and two non-type specimens in the KMA seem to have been misidentified by Sellnick; therefore, we treat &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cordiformatus&lt;/i&gt; as a &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda.&lt;/i&gt; A new diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; is presented, and the Cretaceous fossil genus &lt;i&gt;Archaeorchestes&lt;/i&gt; is considered a junior subjective synonym, based on examination of the holotype of the type-species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minguezae&lt;/i&gt; Arillo &amp; Subías, 2000. As a consequence, &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; is currently the sole genus in Archaeorchestidae. &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minguezae&lt;/i&gt; (n. comb.) is only tentatively maintained as a distinct species, as no certain distinguishing traits could be found. Two families are reported from the fossil record for the first time: Zetomotrichidae from Baltic amber and Zetorchestidae from Rovno amber. In ancillary discussion we note how the specialized tarsal structure of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illibatus&lt;/i&gt; is consistent with its likely arboreal habitat. We also discuss preservation properties and artifacts, note the dimensional discrepancy between cuticular remnants of the mite and its larger imprint in amber, and strongly recommend measuring more than the cuticular remnants themselves. Further, we provide information on different methods to observe amber inclusions, and for the first time report birefringence of fossil cuticular remnants in thin, airless preparations.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oribatida; Archaeorchestidae; Zetorchestidae; Zetomotrichidae; Eremaeidae; &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illibatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Strieremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cordiformatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Archaeorchestes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minguezae&lt;/i&gt;; Eocene; Baltic amber; Rovno amber; fossil; neotype; new combination; new synonymy; cuticular birefringence</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oribatida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ekaterina</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sidorchuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Norton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new &lt;i&gt;Otacilia &lt;/i&gt;species from China, with transfer of two species from the genus &lt;i&gt;Phrurolithus &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae: Corinnidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Otacilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liupan,&lt;/i&gt; is diagnosed, described and illustrated. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Otacilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hengshan&lt;/i&gt; (Song, 1990) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foveata&lt;/i&gt; (Song, 1990) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are transferred from the genus &lt;i&gt;Phrurolithus.&lt;/i&gt; The male of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foveata&lt;/i&gt; is reported for the first time. A distribution map of those three species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Corinnidae; new species; new combination; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dong-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Hu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
