<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3012.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Sep. 2011</title>
    <volume>3012</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A hypothetical evolutionary history of passalid beetles narrated by the comparative anatomy of the hindgut (Coleoptera: Passalidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">When seen as a whole, the hindgut, more than any other section of the digestive tube, provides insights for the taxonomy of higher-level taxa of Passalidae. This comparative cladistics study utilized parsimony analyses, with 57 terminal taxa (including five outgroups) and 18 characters from the ileum of most genera of passalid beetles (Coleoptera: Passalidae), which resulted in a single tree. Based on the results and the topology of the cladogram, the following classification was adopted: (Aulacocyclinae (Solenocyclinae (Proculinae (Passalinae, Macrolininae)))). Three subfamilies (Solenocyclinae, Proculinae, and Macrolininae) are here elevated from the tribal level to the subfamily level. The subfamily Passalinae is redefined and no longer contains any tribes. The family-group name Leptaulacinae is placed in synonym with Solenocyclinae and the family-group name Ceracupedini is placed in synonymy with Aulacocyclinae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cladistic analysis; classification; comparative morphology; ileum; intestines</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cladistic analysis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <middlename>Ruy Vasconcelos</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Fonseca</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Márcio</firstname>
          <middlename>Luís Leitão</middlename>
          <lastname>Barbosa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Fernanda Souza</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology of preimaginal stages of &lt;i&gt;Minettia longipennis &lt;/i&gt;Fabricius (Diptera: Lauxaniidae) MAREK SEMELBAUER &amp; MILAN KOZÁNEK (Slovakia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Order</middlename>
          <lastname>Pdf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-30</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New and obscure species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chilocorus &lt;/i&gt;Mayr in eastern Asia, with the proposal of a "&lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt;-group" concept (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Cydnidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Comments are presented on four East-Asian species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chilocoris&lt;/i&gt; Mayr, of which three are known but have been hardly mentioned―namely &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alienus&lt;/i&gt; Horváth, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birmanus&lt;/i&gt; Lis and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidulus&lt;/i&gt; Lis. One new species is described here as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; New distribution records are provided: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alienus&lt;/i&gt; is new to China (Liaoning), as well as newly representing the genus in northern China; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birmanus&lt;/i&gt; is new to Taiwan; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidulus&lt;/i&gt; is new to Vietnam and Thailand. Until recently, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; found in Japan has been misidentified as &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus&lt;/i&gt; Mayr, and earlier records of the latter from Japan are really this new species. Male genital structures are described and illustrated for all four species, and additionally female genital structures are also described for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birmanus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola.&lt;/i&gt; These East-Asian species are significantly similar to each other in important morphological structures such as the pronotal punctuation, extension of evaporatorium, and the male and female genital organs, yet they can be distinguished from many other congeners by these same structures. It seems plausible, therefore, to group these four species in a species-group named “nitidus-group” because of the species’ definite association with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitidus.&lt;/i&gt; This species-group possibly consists at least ten East-Asian and one North American species and exhibits a relictual, trans-Beringian disjunction, suggesting an association of this group with the Tertiary circum-boreal flora. Its distributional pattern may further differentiate the species-group from other congeners.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cydnidae; &lt;i&gt;Chilocoris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new record; taxonomy; zoogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cydnidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jimpei</firstname>
          <lastname>Imura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-47</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New taxa and records of flat bugs (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Aradidae) from Hainan of China XIAOSHUAN BAI (P.R. China), ERNST HEISS (Austria) &amp; WANZHI CAI (P.R. China)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Preview</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Full</firstname>
          <middlename>Article Order</middlename>
          <lastname>Pdf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Phloeosinopsioides &lt;/i&gt;Schedl (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Scolytinae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The four species included by Wood and Bright (1992) in the Palaeotropical scolytine genus &lt;i&gt;Phloeosinopsioides&lt;/i&gt; Schedl are reviewed. The following new synonymy is proposed: &lt;i&gt;Phloeosinopsioides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosanus&lt;/i&gt; (Schedl) (=Phloeosinopsis &lt;i&gt;triseriata&lt;/i&gt; Schedl). A diagnosis of the genus and a key to the three species now included in the genus are provided. The taxonomy, distribution and biology of the species are briefly reviewed and some new records included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">bark beetles; key; new synonymy; Palaeotropical region; Phloeosinini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">bark beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Beaver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-63</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Oocyclus &lt;/i&gt;Sharp from China with a revised key to the genus for mainland Southeast Asia (Coleoptera: Hydrophilidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of water scavenger beetles, &lt;i&gt;Oocyclus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fikaceki&lt;/i&gt; Short &amp; Jia &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dinghu&lt;/i&gt; Short &amp; Jia &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; are described from Guangdong, Fujian, and Jiangxi Provinces in southeastern China. A revised key to the species of the genus in Indochina and surrounding mainland regions is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aquatic beetles; hygropetric habitats; Oriental Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aquatic beetles</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>Edward Z.</middlename>
          <lastname>Short</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng-Long</firstname>
          <lastname>Jia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
