<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3036.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Sep. 2011</title>
    <volume>3036</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-09-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Peloppiidae) from western North America </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">I present the systematics and distribution of five new species of oribatid mites in the genus &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; (Oribatida: Peloppiidae) from western North America. The species are described on the basis of adult morphology using the following character states: number of hypostomal setae, number, length and expression of posterior notogastral setae, length of lamellae and lamellar cusp, length of interlamellar setae, and the shape and dentition of the rostrum. &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indentata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from forest floor habitats, while &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicuspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tofinoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described from arboreal bryosphere habitats; &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;offarostrata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is associated with bark habitats. &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valerieae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; was collected from both arboreal and forest floor samples. Distributions of all species are provided based on museum and collection records; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indentata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicuspis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tofinoensis&lt;/i&gt; are recorded from coastal temperate coniferous rainforests of the Pacific Northwest of North America, while &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valerieae&lt;/i&gt; was found in coastal temperate rainforests and extending along the southern border of British Columbia into eastern Alberta. &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;offarostrata&lt;/i&gt; is collected only from a small number of locations on the west coast of Canada. Comments on other North American &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; species is given. A morphological key is presented to the described adult species for the genus &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt; in North America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">arboreal habitats; &lt;i&gt;Ceratoppia&lt;/i&gt;; Oribatida; Pacific Northwest; Peloppiidae; temperate rainforest; western North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">arboreal habitats</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zoe</firstname>
          <lastname>Lindo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the deep-sea squat lobster genus &lt;i&gt;Munida &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1820 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Munididae) from Taiwan: morphological and molecular evidence </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1820 is the most diverse group within the squat lobsters, with approximately 250 described species. The extreme morphological similarity among certain species makes very difficult to identify diagnostic characters, and the real diversity of the group is probably underestimated. Here, two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Munida&lt;/i&gt; from Taiwan previously identified as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;distiza&lt;/i&gt; Macpherson, 1994 and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;militaris&lt;/i&gt; Henderson, 1885, respectively, are described and illustrated. The two species are identified by subtle and constant morphological differences, which match clear molecular divergences in the 16S and COI genes. These results confirm the taxonomic value of slight morphological differences, and emphasize the need for more detailed analysis to clarify the phylogenetic relationships within the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; phylogeny; Munididae; morphology; mitochondrial genes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patricia</firstname>
          <lastname>Cabezas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chia-Wei</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Microphilypnus &lt;/i&gt;Myers, 1927 (Teleostei: Gobioidei: Eleotridae) from the lower Amazon basin, with description of one new species </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microphilypnus&lt;/i&gt; Myers, 1927 is a genus with three nominal species (M. &lt;i&gt;amazonicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrostoma&lt;/i&gt; from the lower Amazon basin, and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ternetzi&lt;/i&gt; from Orinoco), and is among the most poorly studied groups of Neotropical fishes. In this paper, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ternetzi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrostoma&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed and validated and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amazonicus&lt;/i&gt; is regarded as synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ternetzi.&lt;/i&gt; Also, a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acangaquara,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the lower Amazon.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microphilypnus&lt;/i&gt;; review; taxonomy; Amazon</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microphilypnus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Caires</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Lima</middlename>
          <lastname>De Figueiredo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-57</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the millipede tribe Tonkinosomatini (Diplopoda: Polydesmida: Paradoxosomatidae) from Vietnam </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The millipede tribe Tonkinosomatini Jeekel, 1968 is reviewed based on literature and fresh material. This tribe comprises two genera: &lt;i&gt;Sellanucheza&lt;/i&gt; Enghoff &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 2004 and &lt;i&gt;Tonkinosoma&lt;/i&gt; Jeekel, 1953, including 6 species distributed in southern China and northern Vietnam. Among them, two new species are described from Vietnam, &lt;i&gt;Sellanucheza&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoffmani,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tonkinosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeekeli,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; A key to all species of Tonkinosomatini and a map of their distribution are also provided for Vietnam fauna</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Vietnam; Polydesmida; Paradoxosomatidae; Tonkinosomatini; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Vietnam</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anh</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-09-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
