<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3085.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Oct. 2011</title>
    <volume>3085</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new sauropod (Macronaria, Titanosauria) from the Adamantina Formation, Bauru Group, Upper Cretaceous of Brazil and the phylogenetic relationships of Aeolosaurini</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Remains of a new titanosaur, &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maximus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Adamantina Formation (Upper Cretaceous), Bauru Group, São Paulo State of Brazil are described. The new species is represented by a single partially articulated skeleton and is characterized by having a well-developed posterior protuberance below the articular area on the anterior and middle haemal arches and a lateral bulge on the distal portion of the articular process of the mid-posterior haemal arches. It shares with other &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; species the presence of prezygapophyses curved downward on anterior caudal vertebrae and haemal arches with double articular facets set in a concave posterodorsal surface. These two characteristics are interpreted here as synapomorphies for the genus &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus.&lt;/i&gt; The new diagnosis for the genus &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; does not support the inclusion of &lt;i&gt;Gondwanatitan&lt;/i&gt; within &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; as previously proposed by some authors. The phylogenetic analysis recovered the two &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; from Argentina as sister groups with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maximus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Gondwanatitan&lt;/i&gt; as progressively more basal taxa (Gondwanatitan (A. &lt;i&gt;maximus&lt;/i&gt; (A. &lt;i&gt;rionegrinus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;colhuehuapensis))).&lt;/i&gt; Additionally, according to the results of the phylogenetic analysis performed in this work, the taxa &lt;i&gt;Panamericansaurus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rinconsaurus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Maxakalisaurus&lt;/i&gt; are also nested within Aeolosaurini, being more basal than &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Gondwanatitan.&lt;/i&gt; On the basis of the stratigraph-ical range of the &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; occurrences in Argentina and the age proposals based on microfossils for the Bauru Group, it is assumed a Campanian–Maastrichtian age for the top of the Adamantina Formation for the Monte Alto region in São Paulo State and the bottom of the Marília Formation in Peirópolis, Minas Gerais State—the places where &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt; remains have been reported in Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dinosauria; Sauropoda; Titanosauriformes; Aeolosaurini; &lt;i&gt;Aeolosaurus&lt;/i&gt;; cladistic analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dinosauria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Santucci</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Arruda-Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Opistognathus albicaudatus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of jawfish (Teleostei: &lt;i&gt;Opistognathidae) &lt;/i&gt;from the Andaman Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of jawfish, &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albicaudatus,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on two specimens, 91.4–94.8 mm SL, from the Andaman Islands. The combination of an elongate upper jaw produced as thin flexible lamina, and a unique colour pattern consisting of an abruptly white caudal fin and gill arches with a series of 8–10 small dark spots, each near the base of a gill raker, distinguishes the new species from other congeners. Based on morphological similarity and general color pattern, the new species seems to be most closely related to &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;variabilis.These&lt;/i&gt; two species appear to have allopatric distributions. A range extension for &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyanospilotus&lt;/i&gt; is also reported.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Jawfish; &lt;i&gt;Opistognathus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Andaman Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Jawfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Smith-Vaniz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Clathria &lt;/i&gt;(Demospongiae, Microcionidae) from Peru occurring on rocky substrates as well as epibiontic on &lt;i&gt;Eucidaris thouarsii &lt;/i&gt;sea urchins</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Southeastern Pacific sponges (Phylum Porifera) range among the world’s least known faunas, with only 13 species reported to date from the entire Peruvian coast. This state of affairs motivated the onset of two large, cooperative, exploratory initiatives, with the aim of mapping sponge richness and distribution in the area: Proyectos ESPER and EsponjAS. Over 800 specimens have been collected in Peru since 2007, with identifications still in progress. Among these, a sponge species originally thought to be an exclusive epibiont on &lt;i&gt;Eucidaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thouarsii&lt;/i&gt; sea urchins, relatively conspicuous on Peru’s Punta Sal region. This sponge, latter found to occur on additional substrates too, is described as a new species of &lt;i&gt;Clathria&lt;/i&gt; (Microciona). Cidarid density ranged between 1.5 and 12/m 2 , and largest diameter of the tests between 3.2 and 5.6 cm. Total number of spines on each sea urchin varied between 68 and 96, and percent sponge coverage of these, between 18.2 and 75.7. There appears to be only a slight tendency for increased sponge coverage on larger sea urchins, so there may be factors, other than sea urchin age, shaping this association. &lt;i&gt;Clathria&lt;/i&gt; (Microciona) &lt;i&gt;aculeofila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be markedly dominant as an epibiont on &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thouarsii,&lt;/i&gt; albeit the great sponge richness in the area. This is in contrast to the allegedly opportunistic, diverse epibiosis by sponges reported previously for Antarctic cidaroids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Porifera; new species; epibiosis; &lt;i&gt;Clathria&lt;/i&gt; (Microciona)</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Porifera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Karem</middlename>
          <lastname>Aguirre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <lastname>Hooker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <lastname>Willenz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajdu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of glass-perch from Belitung Island, Indonesia (Teleostei: Ambassidae: &lt;i&gt;Gymnochanda&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gymnochanda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verae,&lt;/i&gt; new species, a small, colourful and sexually dimorphic freshwater glassperch, is described from the Gantung area of Pulau Belitung, Indonesia. It shares with its congeners a scale-less body, but differs in the males having broad red anal and second dorsal fins, red caudal-fin lobes, and the elongated rays of the second dorsal fin and the anal fin joined throughout their length by an interradial membrane.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; freshwater fish; sexual dimorphism; Southeast Asia; biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hui</middlename>
          <lastname>Tan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kelvin</firstname>
          <middlename>K. P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of eriophyoid mite (Acari: Eriophyoidea: Eriophyidae) on &lt;i&gt;Leucadendron argenteum &lt;/i&gt;(L.) R. Br. from South Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new vagrant eriophyoid mite species, collected from plant material imported into the United Kingdom, is described and illustrated: &lt;i&gt;Aceria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; found on &lt;i&gt;Leucadendron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argenteum&lt;/i&gt; (L.) R. Br. (Proteaceae) from South Africa. A review of the eriophyoid mite species known from plants in the Proteaceae is also provided and recent findings of non-native eriophyoid mites in the United Kingdom are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Eriophyoidea; taxonomy; key; &lt;i&gt;Aceria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuko&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aculops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuchsiae&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>R. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
