<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3104.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3104</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Guernea &lt;/i&gt;Chevreux, 1887 from Korean waters (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Dexaminidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of the dexaminid genus &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; are reported from Korean coastal waters. This is the first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; from Korea. Two of the species are identified as new species; &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jejuensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;namhaensis.&lt;/i&gt; The remaining two Japanese species &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ezoensis&lt;/i&gt; Ishimaru, 1987 and &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nullispina&lt;/i&gt; Hirayama, 1985 are new records for Korean waters. The species are fully illustrated and detailed comparisons are made with related species. A key to north Pacific &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt; species is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Dexaminidae; &lt;i&gt;Guernea&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; Korea; key; north Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Young-Hyo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ed</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hendrycks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kyung-Sook</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Hermit crabs from Brazil: Family Paguridae (Crustacea: Decapoda: Paguroidea), except &lt;i&gt;Pagurus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In a previous paper we presented the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pagurus&lt;/i&gt; recorded from Brazil. Here, we present the other 12 genera of the family Paguridae that occur in Brazil, with diagnoses, synonymies, illustrations and keys to species. These 12 genera include 16 species, some of which were found recently and only in deeper waters. This suggests the need for further studies in areas that have been little studied in Brazil.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hermit crabs; Paguridae; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hermit crabs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>Ricardo</middlename>
          <lastname>Nucci</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>Augusto Schmidt</middlename>
          <lastname>De Melo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-41</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An example of problems associated with DNA barcoding in tardigrades: a novel method for obtaining voucher specimens</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We have in recent papers revealed that an integrative taxonomy approach helps to solve taxonomic problems in tardigrades. However, whole tardigrades are required for DNA work, which leaves no hologenophore voucher specimens with adult morphology. Using a novel methodology for the Tardigrada, we introduce the practice of collecting high quality maximum magnification light microscopy images of recently thawed animals to act as hologenophore voucher specimens of animals later used for DNA barcode sequencing. Within the framework of a DNA barcoding project on tardigrades, we collected a moss sample from the type locality of &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminalis&lt;/i&gt; Bertolani &amp; Rebecchi, 1993 (Castelsantangelo, Central Apennines, Italy), a species of the “Macrobiotus &lt;i&gt;hufelandi&lt;/i&gt; group”. Within the moss sample we found several animals and eggs with a morphology that corresponded to the original description of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminalis,&lt;/i&gt; while others were attributable to &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrocalix&lt;/i&gt; Bertolani &amp; Rebecchi, 1993. In this study, molecular (cox1 mtDNA) analyses demonstrated no intraspecific variability in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminalis&lt;/i&gt; from the type locality but very large interspecific differences when compared with &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrocalix&lt;/i&gt; and GenBank data for other species within the &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; “hufelandi group”. There was also a large difference between our &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminalis&lt;/i&gt; sequences and the GenBank data of a specimen attributed to the same species. The GenBank sequence originated from a population in the Northern Apennines, whose morphology appeared to be like that of the specimens of the &lt;i&gt;locus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typicus.&lt;/i&gt; This confirmed the importance in utilising material from the type locality for linking molecular data to the species’ morphological characters. Our paper underlines the importance of an integrative taxonomy in species diagnoses and demonstrates a scenario where morphological observations alone are not always sufficient. Lastly, this work adds reliable information to the sequence reference library that provides a useful building block for further studies on similar and related tardigrade taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terminalis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;cox1&lt;/i&gt;; integrative taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michele</firstname>
          <lastname>Cesari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ilaria</firstname>
          <lastname>Giovannini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Bertolani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lorena</firstname>
          <lastname>Rebecchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-51</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The spider &lt;i&gt;Micrathena shealsi &lt;/i&gt;Chickering, 1960 (Araneae, Araneidae): description of the male, with new data on its geographic distribution</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male of &lt;i&gt;Micrathena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shealsi&lt;/i&gt; Chickering, 1960 is described and illustrated for the first time. New geographic records of this species are provided, revealing that &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shealsi&lt;/i&gt; inhabits the higher altitudinal belts (1000–3000 m) of the Yungas ecoregion (mountain forests and rainforests from Argentina). Male specimens were observed in the same web of females, in most cases on the upper periphery hanging by a silk line.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Argentina,orb-weaver spider; spider taxonomy; Yungas ecoregion</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Argentina,orb-weaver spider</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carina</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Argañaraz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gonzalo</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rubio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The millipede family Metopidiotrichidae new to the fauna of Taiwan: the description of a new species; a review of and a key to the Chordeumatida occurring in Taiwan (Diplopoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Metopidiotrichidae and the genus &lt;i&gt;Metopidiothrix&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1907 are formally new to the fauna of Taiwan, due to the discovery of &lt;i&gt;Metopidiothrix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taiwanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The fauna of Chordeumatida of Taiwan is reviewed and keyed, at present containing 13 unquestioned species from three genera and three families. Three further species, one genus and one family are dubious either as taxa or as elements of the Taiwanese fauna, or both. Palaearctic elements, such as Diplomaragnidae and Niponiosomatidae, appear to strongly dominate over austral/tropical ones (Metopidiotrichidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Millipede; chordeumatidans; new record; new species; taxonomy; key; distribution; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Millipede</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergei</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Golovatch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsueh-Wen</firstname>
          <lastname>Chang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-63</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new sclerite-free genus and species of Clavulariidae (Coelenterata: Octocorallia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <lastname>Alderslade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Catherine</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcfadden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
