<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3107.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3107</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nematode parasites of invertebrates from Manipur, North East India (Diagnosis, keys and illustration)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present report is based on findings of occasional survey work conducted from the region spanning over six years for the presence of insect parasitic nematodes under the superfamily Thelastomatoidea (Nematoda: Oxyurida), parasitic in invertebrate hosts. Out of five families recognized under the superfamily, the present report discusses the findings of four families from Manipur and its adjoining areas as well. For the first time, out of 15 taxa described in the text, seven species are described from the region, eight species reported. The findings of the study will help in understanding of the biodiversity status of insect parasitic nematodes of the region. Diagnosis of the genus, key to species and illustration with line diagrams and photomicrographs are provided in the manuscript.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Insect; Nematode; Oxyurida; Thelastomatoidea; Manipur; India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Insect</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Manjur</middlename>
          <lastname>Shah</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Mohilal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pramodini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <lastname>Bina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Th.</firstname>
          <lastname>Hemananda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>01-37</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A probably invasive new genus and new species of soft coral (Octocorallia: Alcyonacea: Clavulariidae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stragulum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicolor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Octocorallia: Clavulariidae) is described from Brazil. It was found in shallow waters of the States of Ceará, Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo, Paraná and Santa Catarina, and is probably invasive. The genus forms encrusting sheets on solid objects, such as seaweed basal stems, barnacle shells and artificial substrates. The new taxon has spindles, crosses and radiates in the outer layer of the coenenchyme, fused sclerites in the interior and the polyps are unarmed. The new genus is compared with other taxa that have fused sclerites.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coelenterata; Cnidaria; benthos; &lt;i&gt;Stragulum&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coelenterata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Van Ofwegen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Haddad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-46</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Upeneus &lt;/i&gt;(Perciformes: Mullidae) from southern Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of goatfish, &lt;i&gt;Upeneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itoui,&lt;/i&gt; is described on the basis of 67 specimens collected from southern Japan at depths of less than 40 m. &lt;i&gt;Upeneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itoui&lt;/i&gt; is most similar to the western Indian Ocean species, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pori.&lt;/i&gt; The caudal-fin color pattern in fresh and preserved specimens of the two species is identical. However, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itoui&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pori&lt;/i&gt; in having less head and body depths, wider barbels, and a lower count of gill rakers.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mullidae; &lt;i&gt;Upeneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itoui&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Upeneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pori&lt;/i&gt;; southern Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mullidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masahiro</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamashita</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Golani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Motomura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Polysertularella polyseriata&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and species of hydroid (Hydrozoa; Leptothecata; Sertulariidae) from the Sea of Okhotsk</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Polysertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polyseriata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a hydroid referable to family Sertulariidae, is described from the eastern part of the Sea of Okhotsk. The new taxa is characterized by: multi-serial (5–8 rows) placement of hydrothecae on both stem and branches; a hydrothecal rim with four small cusps; an operculum with four equal flaps similar to but more flattened than that of &lt;i&gt;Sertularella.&lt;/i&gt; Gonothecae are transversely corrugated and resemble those of many species assigned to &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Symplectoscyphus.&lt;/i&gt; They arise from hydrothecae-like tubes on the basal part of the stem and are disposed in opposite pairs, as in species of &lt;i&gt;Synthecium.&lt;/i&gt;Sertulariidae, the largest family in Hydrozoa and with representatives from marine environments worldwide, is relatively well known. Discovery of new genera in the family is relatively infrequent. A diagnosis of a new genus and a description of a new species are given in this paper.&lt;b&gt;Diagnosis.&lt;/b&gt; Sertulariidae with erect, branched colonies, with branches resembling hydrocaulus. Hydrothecae arranged in 5–8 longitudal rows along hydrocaulus and branches; hydrothecal rim with four very low cusps separated by shallow embayments; operculum of four equal triangular valves, flattened rather than pyramidal; hydranth with abcauline caecum. Gonothecae oval with strong transverse corrugations and rings, occurring in opposite pairs on lower part of stem. &lt;b&gt;Type&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polysertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polyseriata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; designated herein. &lt;b&gt;Notes&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;differential&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;diagnosis.&lt;/b&gt; In most genera of Sertulariidae, hydrothecae have an alternate to opposite biserial arrangement on branches, and especially on the stem. A few genera in the family, including &lt;i&gt;Abietinaria&lt;/i&gt; Kirchenpauer, 1884, &lt;i&gt;Thuiaria&lt;/i&gt; Fleming, 1828, &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758, and &lt;i&gt;Staurotheca&lt;/i&gt; Allman, 1888 include some species with multi-serial rows of hydrothecae on branches and very rarely on the stem as well. The nominal genus &lt;i&gt;Selaginopsis&lt;/i&gt; Allman, 1876, originally established for sertulariids having hydrothecae in more than two longitudinal rows, is no longer recognized as valid in some works because of its artificial composition and differences among included species in operculum structure (Peña-Cantero &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 1997). However, no species with a multiserial arrangement of hydrothecae and four-flapped operculum (resembling &lt;i&gt;Sertularella)&lt;/i&gt; has been known in the family until now.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Antsulevich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
