<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3122.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Dec. 2011</title>
    <volume>3122</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-12-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species, new records and redescriptions of Thecate hydroids (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa: Leptothecata) from Southern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A collection of 13 species from southern Australia is described. The collection includes &lt;i&gt;Campanulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cliftonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Campanulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hebella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Antennella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ventromma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellarensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mytila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Obelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spongicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hydranthea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margarica&lt;/i&gt; is a new record of the genus from Australia; five other species previously recorded from Australia are redescribed in detail. The reproductive structure of &lt;i&gt;Macrorhynchia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;whiteleggei&lt;/i&gt; is described for the first time allowing for a new genus species combination. Notes are given on distribution and ecology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; &lt;i&gt;Campanulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cliftonia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Campanulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Hebella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albida&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Antennella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;singulata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ventromma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellarensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mytila&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Obelia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spongicola;&lt;/i&gt; new record; &lt;i&gt;Hydranthea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;margarica&lt;/i&gt;; species redescriptions</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeanette</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Watson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>01-36</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological support for placement of the Wing-banded Antbird &lt;i&gt;Myrmornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquata &lt;/i&gt;in the Thamnophilidae (Passeriformes: Furnariides)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myrmornis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquata&lt;/i&gt; has often been considered an intermediate form between the ground antbirds and the typical antbirds. Although molecular phylogenies have consistently placed &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquata&lt;/i&gt; in the Thamnophilidae (typical antbirds), this species has not been the subject of a thorough anatomical study, and no phylogeny based on morphological characters has been published. We undertook a cladistic morphological analysis of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquata&lt;/i&gt; and representatives of all families in the infraorder Furnariides, to clarify the systematic affinities of this species. In a parsimony analysis of 66 osteological and syringeal characters, &lt;i&gt;Myrmornis&lt;/i&gt; clustered with other thamnophilids with high support values, sharing with them five synapomorphies of unambiguous optimization in all most-parsimonious trees. Two synapomorphies are syringeal features exclusive to the family: (1) the presence of processes on the ventral surface of supporting A-elements of the syrinx cranial to the membrana tracheosyringealis, and (2) the division of the musculus sternotrachealis into two fasciculi near its insertion on the syrinx. A third syringeal synapomorphy (presence of the musculus vocalis ventralis) also occurs in the Dendrocolaptidae and Furnariidae as a homoplasy. Two unambiguous osteological synapomorphies were found: (1) the narrowing of the foramen orbitonasale, and (2) the confluence of the foramen obturatum and the fenestra ischiopubica, a reversal also found in the Furnariidae. Our results provide strong morphological support for the placement of &lt;i&gt;Myrmornis&lt;/i&gt; in the Thamnophilidae. &lt;b&gt;Key-words:&lt;/b&gt; Morphological phylogeny, osteology, syrinx, suboscines, Furnarioidea, Thamnophilidae, Formicariidae, Grallariidae, Neotropics.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <lastname>Galvão</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>Pedreira</middlename>
          <lastname>Gonzaga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
