<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2338.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Jan. 2010</title>
    <volume>2338</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of Afrotropical &lt;i&gt;Thienemanniella &lt;/i&gt;Kieffer (Diptera: Chironomidae: Orthocladiinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species from Ghana, &lt;i&gt;Thienemanniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavata&lt;/i&gt; is described and illustrated as adult male. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antennata&lt;/i&gt; Freeman, 1953, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trivittata&lt;/i&gt; Goetghebuer, 1935 and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineola&lt;/i&gt; Freeman, 1953 are redescribed. Additional measurements and comments are given for &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuga&lt;/i&gt; Lehmann, 1979. Additional records of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antennata&lt;/i&gt; from Ghana and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuga&lt;/i&gt; from South Africa and Tanzania are given. &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;afra&lt;/i&gt; Lehmann, 1981 is tentatively transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Corynoneurella&lt;/i&gt; Brundin. Male and female genital structures are discussed. A large bursa below gonapophysis VIII and the vagina is considered to be an egg-laying chamber. Keys to the known males and females of Afrotropical species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Thienemanniella&lt;/i&gt; are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chironomidae; Orthocladiinae; &lt;i&gt;Thienemanniella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Corynoneurella&lt;/i&gt;; key; new species; new combination; Afrotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chironomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yue</firstname>
          <lastname>Fu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tor</firstname>
          <middlename>Christian</middlename>
          <lastname>Hestenes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ole</firstname>
          <lastname>Sæther</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-22</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Eupholus &lt;/i&gt;Boisduval (Coleoptera, Curculionidae, Entiminae), with observations on coloured cuticular exudates in weevils</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Eupholus&lt;/i&gt; Boisduval from Papua New Guinea are described as new: &lt;i&gt;Eupholus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mimicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedlaceki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n..&lt;/b&gt; A key to the &lt;i&gt;Eupholus&lt;/i&gt; species with yellow colour patterns is provided. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedlaceki&lt;/i&gt; is closely related to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;euphrosyne&lt;/i&gt; Porion but differs in coloration. Male and female terminalia of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;euphrosyne&lt;/i&gt; are illustrated for comparison. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mimicus&lt;/i&gt; is superficially very similar to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;euphrosyne,&lt;/i&gt; but its yellow colour pattern is composed of scales whereas in the latter it is formed by loose particles. These two species belong to different species groups, and the conspicuous colour patterns have evidently evolved convergently. The occurrence and function of extracuticular pigments among species of Eupholini is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">weevils; New Guinea; pigments; mimicry</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">weevils</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Riedel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-34</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An endemic predaceous water beetle from the Murchison River in Western Australia—&lt;i&gt;Antiporus kalbarriensis &lt;/i&gt;sp.n. (Coleoptera: Dytiscidae, Hydroporinae, Hydroporini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Antiporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kalbarriensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Murchison bioregion in Western Australia. The species appears to be restricted to backwater pools and oxbows along the Murchison River. Morphologically it is near &lt;i&gt;Antiporus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bakewellii&lt;/i&gt; (Clark, 1862) (Queensland, New South Wales), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenniferae&lt;/i&gt; Watts, 1997 (Northern Territory, N Queensland, NW Australia) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; Watts, 1978 (Queensland) but differs by the form of the median lobe, size and male proclaw. The habitat and its water beetle coenosis are described in detail. Additional distributional records for &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bakewellii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenniferae&lt;/i&gt; are given. Altogether 15 species of &lt;i&gt;Antiporus&lt;/i&gt; are now reported from Australia. The new species underline the importance of south-western Australia as a hotspot of diversity for Dytiscidae of the tribe Hydroporini Aubé, 1836.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; Hydroporinae; &lt;i&gt;Antiporus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; south-western Australia; hotspot of diversity; Murchison River; backwater pools</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lars</firstname>
          <lastname>Hendrich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chris</firstname>
          <middlename>H. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Watts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-42</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The enigma of the genus &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorura &lt;/i&gt;Absolon, 1900 (Collembola, Tullbergiinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Stenaphorura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japygiformis&lt;/i&gt; Absolon, 1900 was redescribed based on the holotype and on virtually topotypic material from the Moravian Karst, Czech Republic. Lectotype of &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lubbocki&lt;/i&gt; Bagnall, 1935 was redescribed and used for comparison with &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japygiformis.&lt;/i&gt; The postantennal organ, composed of 50–56 simple vesicles, is 3.8 times the length of the frontal pseudocellus in &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japygiformis,&lt;/i&gt; compared to 75 vesicles and 6.3 times in the related &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lubbocki.&lt;/i&gt; Figures and measurements of some structures are given for the first time. As a consequence of my studies &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorurella&lt;/i&gt; Luciáñez &amp; Simón, 1992 is sunk into synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorura&lt;/i&gt; Absolon, 1900. All species transferred into &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorurella&lt;/i&gt; by Luciáñez &amp; Simón (1992) and by Khanislamova &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; (1997) are reintroduced into &lt;i&gt;Stenaphorura&lt;/i&gt; Absolon, 1900.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">type redescriptions; taxonomy; synonym</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">type redescriptions</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Josef</firstname>
          <lastname>Rusek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of five new species of &lt;i&gt;Paduniella &lt;/i&gt;from Madagascar (Trichoptera: Psychomyiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Paduniella&lt;/i&gt; (Trichoptera: Psychomyiidae) are described: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flinti,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nandra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ambra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;madagassa,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sona,&lt;/i&gt; representing the first records of the genus from Madagascar and more than doubling the number of &lt;i&gt;Paduniella&lt;/i&gt; species known from the Afrotropical Region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trichoptera; Psychomyiidae; &lt;i&gt;Paduniella&lt;/i&gt;; Madagascar; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trichoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kjell</firstname>
          <middlename>Arne</middlename>
          <lastname>Johanson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>János</firstname>
          <lastname>Oláh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two newly detected bark and ambrosia beetles from southern Florida (Coleoptera: Curculionidae, Scolytinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Coptoborus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudotenuis&lt;/i&gt; (Schedl) and &lt;i&gt;Cryptocarenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diadematus&lt;/i&gt; Eggers, two species of Neotropical Scolytinae, are reported from Florida and the U.S. for the first time. This is the first report of the genus &lt;i&gt;Coptoborus&lt;/i&gt; from the U.S. We provide descriptions, figures, distribution maps and keys.Specimens collected in southern Florida of &lt;i&gt;Coptoborus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudotenuis&lt;/i&gt; (Schedl) and &lt;i&gt;Cryptocarenus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diadematus&lt;/i&gt; Eggers were recently found in Florida State Collection of Arthropods and via the USDA Forest Service survey for non-native scolytines (Rabaglia &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2008). These widespread Neotropical species of Scolytinae have not been reported previously from the United States. At first glance, these would appear to be two more entries on the growing list of introduced exotic bark and ambrosia beetles detected in the U.S. (Haack 2006, Rabaglia &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2006). While it is possible that they have been introduced, it is also just as plausible that they have been present for much longer or might even occur in southern Florida naturally (i.e., without any human intervention: &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; Atkinson and Peck 1994). Most species of Scolytinae are very small (&lt; 2mm), not attracted to light traps and seldom collected outside their host plants. Consequently, most species are rarely collected and it is possible that these two species have been overlooked until now. As an example, Peck (1989) was the first to use flight intercept traps extensively in southern Florida, resulting in detection of several undescribed species, numerous new records from Florida, as well as the first records in over 100 years of some uncommonly collected species (Atkinson &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 1991, Atkinson and Peck. 1994). Recent USDA Forest Service and APHIS programs to detect non-native bark and ambrosia beetles utilizing funnel traps baited with ethanol or pheromone lures (Rabaglia &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 2008) are accelerating the discovery of new records and range extensions of seldom collected native species (unpublished observations). In summary, whether or not these are recent introductions can probably not be resolved at this time. The following abbreviations are used for museums where specimens are deposited: FSCA (Florida State Collection of Arthropods), MSUC (Michigan State University Collection).&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Coptoborus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;pseudotenuis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(Schedl)&lt;/b&gt; (Figs. 1–4)&lt;i&gt;Xyleborus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudotenuis&lt;/i&gt; Schedl 1936: 109 &lt;i&gt;Xyleborus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuis&lt;/i&gt; Schedl 1948: 269 (Synonomy: Wood 1976a)&lt;b&gt;Diagnosis.&lt;/b&gt; This small xyleborine ambrosia beetle is most easily distinguished from relatives found in the U.S. by the elytra which are tapered posteriorly (Figs. 3, 4). The presence of 2 sutures on the posterior face of the</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Atkinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rabaglia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cognato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
