<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2363.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Feb. 2010</title>
    <volume>2363</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-02-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Thoracic scent efferent system of the Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu lato &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Pentatomoidea) with implication to the phylogeny of the family</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We studied the cuticular structures associated with the opening of the adult metathoracic scent glands in the family Tessaratomidae. The terminology previously used for these structures in the Tessaratomidae and Pentatomoidea is briefly reviewed and most suitable terms are selected (i.e., metathoracic scent apparatus, internal and external scent efferent system, internal orifice, vestibule, ostiole, ostiolar groove, peritreme, auricle, spout, groove, ruga, disc, peritremal lobes, evaporatorium, mycoid surface, mushroom body, bridge, alveole, trabeculae, and peritremal surface). We examined and illustrated external scent efferent system of 40 species from 33 genera belonging to all three subfamilies of Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato,&lt;/i&gt; i.e. Tessaratominae, Natalicolinae, and Oncomerinae. Three basic types were recognized: i) Oncomerinae – ostiole slightly removed laterally from the position between coxal acetabula, oval, ostiolar groove not developed or very short, peritreme in form of spout attached anterolaterally to the ostiole; ii) Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; (= Tessaratominae + Natalicolinae) – ostiole situated between acetabula, strongly incised mesad, thus vestibule distally opened in two planes (ventrally and laterally) as ostiolar groove, peritreme in form of anterior and posterior peritremal lobes surrounding the ostiolar groove; and iii) Platytatina (Platytatus &lt;i&gt;ambiguus&lt;/i&gt; Bergroth, 1892) – ostiole shifted near to lateral metapleural margin, ostiolar groove reduced, situated between two flat, reniform processes (median and lateral lobe). A polarity of these structures is suggested: the type i) of Oncomerinae is regarded as plesiomorphic(shared with Urostylididae, Dinidoridae, etc.); the type iii) of Platytatina is homologized with type ii) of Tessaratominae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto;&lt;/i&gt; the type ii) is unique within Pentatomoidea and considered as an autapomorphy. The information content of the characters of the external scent efferent system and metathoracic spiracle for a phylogenetic hypothesis of relationships within Pentatomoidea is tested by cladistic analyses. We found some apomorphies helping to define Tessaratomidae and Plataspidae, most of the characters, however, seem to be homoplasious at family level. The results of the cladistic analyses further support the monophyly of Dinidoridae + Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; and that of Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto,&lt;/i&gt; while the relationships of Oncomerinae and Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; as well as the relationships among the family-group taxa within Tessaratomidae &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; need further studies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteroptera; Pentatomoidea; Tessaratomidae; Tessaratominae; Natalicolinae; Oncomerinae; morphology; terminology; cuticular structures; metathoracic scent glands; anagenesis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteroptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Petr</firstname>
          <lastname>Kment</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jitka</firstname>
          <lastname>Vilímová</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-59</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Osmylus &lt;/i&gt;Latreille from Henan, China (Neuroptera: Osmylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of &lt;i&gt;Osmylus&lt;/i&gt; Latreille are described from China: &lt;i&gt;Osmylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biangulus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucalatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bipapillatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachycaudatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Parosmylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegantissimus&lt;/i&gt; (Kozhanchikov, 1951) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is transferred is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Osmylus.&lt;/i&gt; A key is given to differentiate species of &lt;i&gt;Osmylus&lt;/i&gt; in China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Osmylidae; &lt;i&gt;Osmylus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Osmylidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yongjie</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhiqi</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
