<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 20KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt; </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Full article (PDF; 40KB) &lt;span style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #1694c9"&gt; open access &lt;/span&gt; </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2372.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Feb. 2010</title>
    <volume>2372</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Contributions to shrimp taxonomy — Editorial</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sammy</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>H. J. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fransen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>5-6</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudopontonides plumosus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new cnidarian-associated pontoniine shrimp (Crustacea, Decapoda, Palaemonidae) from Curaçao</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During a study of the associated fauna of gorgonians and black corals on the reefs of Curaçao (Netherlands Antilles, Caribbean Sea) by the first author, a new species of &lt;i&gt;Pseudopontonides&lt;/i&gt; Heard, 1986: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumosus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. was discovered, which is here described and figured.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudopontonides&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Antipatharia; Curaçao</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nicolette</firstname>
          <lastname>Snijders</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>H. J. M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fransen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>7-14</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and two new species of alvinocaridid shrimps (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea) from a hydrothermal vent field off northeastern Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of alvinocaridid shrimps are described from a hydrothermal vent field off northeastern Taiwan at depths of 252–300 m. &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chelys&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is morphologically very similar to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;williamsi&lt;/i&gt; Shank &amp; Martin, 2003 from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alexander&lt;/i&gt; Ahyong, 2009 from the southern Kermadec Ridge. These three species can be differentiated by the shape of the postrostral ridge, telson, the second segment of the antennular peduncle and the armature of the meri and ischia of the third pereopod. The second new species, although rather similar to &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niwa&lt;/i&gt; Webber, 2004 from the Kermadec-Arc, is assigned to a new genus &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaridinides&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., which appears to be intermediate between &lt;i&gt;Shinkaicaris&lt;/i&gt; Komai &amp; Segonzac, 2005 and other derived genera including &lt;i&gt;Opaepele&lt;/i&gt; Williams &amp; Dobbs, 1995, &lt;i&gt;Chorocaris&lt;/i&gt; Martin &amp; Hessler, 1990 and &lt;i&gt;Rimicaris&lt;/i&gt; Williams &amp; Rona, 1986. &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaridinides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosa&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. differs from &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;niwa&lt;/i&gt; by completely lacking any armature on the ischia of the third to fifth pereopods and by bearing two movable spines at the posterolateral angle of the uropodal exopod. These records constitute the first discovery of the family Alvinocarididae in Taiwanese waters and represent the shallowest occurrence for alvinocaridid shrimps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Alvinocarididae; &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Alvinocaridides&lt;/i&gt;; Taiwan; hydrothermal vents</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Allopontonia alastairi &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a second species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Allopontonia &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, 1972 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae), from the Australian Northwest Shelf</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On two new genera of Asian prawns previously assigned to &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea: Palaemonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera of palaemonid prawns are described from South and Southeast Asia. The new genera are allied to &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; Bate, 1868, but can easily be separated by having a slender and glabrous second pereiopod, a long fifth pereiopod which is distinctly longer than the second pereiopod, a bilobed posterolateral margin of the fifth abdominal pleurite, the presence of one or two pairs of plumose setae at the ventroposterior margin of the telson, the absence of anterior lobes on male thoracic sternite 8 and distinctly larger adult females than males. &lt;i&gt;Arachnochium&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (type species &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mirabilis&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1917), can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Tenuipedium&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. (type species &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palaemonoides&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1950) by having a relatively shorter branchiostegal groove running from the base of the hepatic spine to the antennal carapace margin below the antennal spine, and having plumose setae which are longer than the inner pair of spines on the ventroposterior margin of the telson.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Arachnochium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tenuipedium&lt;/i&gt;; new genera; Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daisy</firstname>
          <lastname>Wowor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On a new species of the shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Athanas &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1814 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Alpheidae) from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Iranian side of the Strait of Hormuz connecting the Persian Gulf with the Gulf of Oman. &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iranicus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is the only species in the genus characterised by the presence of dense setal brushes on the dorsolateral margin of the carpus and on most of the palm of the major and minor chelipeds; the presence of an additional setal brush on the dactylus of the major cheliped; a frontal margin with an untypically short rostrum and short, triangular extra-corneal teeth; and mostly concealed eyestalks.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; Alpheidae; shrimp; &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Iran; Strait of Hormuz; Persian Gulf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Reza</firstname>
          <lastname>Naderloo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A second species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Manipontonia &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, Okuno &amp; Li, 2005 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Manipontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persiana&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., the second species of the genus, is described from the Persian Gulf. The species can be clearly distinguished from the type species &lt;i&gt;Manipontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psamathe&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1902) by a shorter and more robust carpus and a longer propodus of the major second pereiopod. Similarities in other morphological features suggest a similar lifestyle for both species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Palaemonidae; Pontoniinae; &lt;i&gt;Manipontonia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Persian Gulf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new vent shrimp (Crustacea: Decapoda: Alvinocarididae) from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Opaepele&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vavilovi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., family Alvinocarididae, is described from the Broken Spur vent site (26 o 09'N, 44 o 50'W) on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge. An emended diagnosis for &lt;i&gt;Opaepele&lt;/i&gt; is provided, along with characters distinguishing new species from other species of the genus. All known vent species of Alvinocarididae from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge are listed, and key to the genus &lt;i&gt;Opaepele&lt;/i&gt; is provided. Despite intensive sampling of this vent field for several decades, the new species was only discovered in 2005, highlighting our still fragmentary knowledge of hydrothermal vent biodiversity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Alvinocarididae; vent shrimps; Mid-Atlantic Ridge; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anastasia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lunina</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vereshchaka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>69-74</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atydina&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus for &lt;i&gt;Caridina atyoides &lt;/i&gt;Nobili, 1900, from Indonesia (Crustacea: Decapoda: Atyidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atydina,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, is established for &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atyoides&lt;/i&gt; Nobili, 1900, so far known only from two islands in Indonesia. It is characterized by the robust third and fourth pereiopods, and an inflated cylindrical appendix masculina on the male second pleopod. The new genus is compared to the related genera &lt;i&gt;Atyopsis&lt;/i&gt; Chace, 1983 and &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; H Milne Edwards, 1837. The monotypic genus is here described and illustrated in detail.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Atyidae; &lt;i&gt;Atydina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;; freshwater shrimps; new genus; taxonomy; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yixiong</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>75-79</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caridina jeani, &lt;/i&gt;a replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Caridina typus &lt;/i&gt;var. &lt;i&gt;brevirostris &lt;/i&gt;J. Roux, 1911 from Eastern Indonesia (Crustacea: Decapoda: Atyidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typus&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;brevirostris&lt;/i&gt; Roux is shown to be specifically different from &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typus&lt;/i&gt; H. Milne Edwards, 1837. A new name &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeani&lt;/i&gt; is thus proposed for the species as the name &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevirostris&lt;/i&gt; is preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevirostris&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1860. The species is re-described and illustrated in detail based on syntypic specimens. It differs markedly from &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typus&lt;/i&gt; by possessing sexual dimorphism on the third and fourth pereiopods. A lectotype is designated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Atyidae; &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;; freshwater shrimps; taxonomy; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yixiong</firstname>
          <lastname>Cai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>80-84</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Designation of &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov., for the ‘&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes aesopius &lt;/i&gt;species group’ (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae), with the description of a new species and a checklist of congeneric species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of the subfamily Pontoniinae, &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. is established for the ‘Periclimenes &lt;i&gt;aesopius&lt;/i&gt; species group’ of the genus &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; Costa. The new genus is distinguished from other genera of Pontoniinae on account of the strongly produced inferior orbital margin with reflected inner flange, and the basicerite of the antenna armed with an angular dorsal process. Fourteen species have been previously recognized as belonging to the ‘P. &lt;i&gt;aesopius&lt;/i&gt; species group’. One Eastern Pacific species (P. &lt;i&gt;lucasi&lt;/i&gt; Chace), and two Atlantic species (P. &lt;i&gt;anthophilus&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis &amp; EiblEibesfeldt, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pedersoni&lt;/i&gt; Chace) are now also placed in &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. A further new species associated with a cerianthid sea anemone, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luteomaculatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described and illustrated on the basis of specimens from the Ryukyu Islands, southern Japan, and Philippines. A key for their identification, and a checklist of the species of &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <lastname>Okuno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>85-105</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenes laevimanus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. from Vietnam, with a review of the &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulimanus &lt;/i&gt;species group (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae: Pontoniinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new, hydroid-associated representative of the genus &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; from Vietnam is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevimanus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is most similar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulimanus&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1978, but differs from it by the more slender and smooth, not granulated, major second pereiopod and the non-dentate cutting edges of the minor second pereiopod. A new host is reported for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulimanus.&lt;/i&gt; Mouth parts are described and illustrated for &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; Ď uriš, 1990. This species is easily distinguished by its extremely elongate second pereiopods, with the carpus longer than the chela, and the walking legs lacking simple spines proximally from the distoventral series of paired spines. &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tonga&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1990 differs from other members of the species group by having only a single pair of dorsal telson spines. A key for the identification of species of the herein established &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulimanus&lt;/i&gt; species group is provided. Types and/or museum specimens of some other &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; species (P. &lt;i&gt;hongkongensis&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1969, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nomadophila&lt;/i&gt; Berggren, 1994, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ruber&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1982, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toloensis&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1969) were examined to evaluate their relationship with the &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulimanus&lt;/i&gt; species complex.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevimanus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; South China Sea; symbiosis; hydroid-associate</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zdeněk</firstname>
          <lastname>Ďuriš</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>106-125</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two crested and colourful new species of &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Caridea: Hippolytidae) from the continental margin of Western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of hippolytid shrimp are described from the continental margin of Western Australia, &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clarehannah&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from one female specimen collected off Bald Island, WA, at depths of 408–431 m and &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristagalli&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from ten specimens collected off north-western Australia at depths of 397–458 m. Both species belong to the group of &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt; species possessing epipods on only the first two pairs of pereopods. Within this group, they are similar to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yaldwyni&lt;/i&gt; Kensley, Tranter &amp; Griffin, 1987 from NSW, Australia, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compressus&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1947 from Japan in possessing a high crest on the carapace. These crested species of &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt; are reviewed. They can be distinguished from one another by the shape of the carapace crest, the number of spines on maxilliped 3 and by colour pattern. A key to all crested species and colour photos of the Australian species are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Hippolytidae; &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Western Australia; continental margin</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anna</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccallum</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gary</firstname>
          <middlename>C. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Poore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>126-137</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On two small collections of freshwater shrimps (Decapoda: Atyidae: &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;) from Papua New Guinea, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Several species of atyid freshwater shrimp are currently known from Papua New Guinea. Here, two new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;buergersi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elisabethae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. In addition, we provide new records for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;demani&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cognata,&lt;/i&gt; originally described from New Guinea by J. Roux (1911) and De Man (1915).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">freshwater shrimp; new species; endemism; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">freshwater shrimp</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Karge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kristina</firstname>
          <lastname>Von Rintelen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Werner</firstname>
          <lastname>Klotz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>138-150</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Palaemonella dijonesae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae) from Western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>151-156</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The sand shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Philocheras &lt;/i&gt;(Caridea: Crangonidae) from the continental margin of Western Australia including the description of a new species and a key to Australian species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight species of &lt;i&gt;Philocheras&lt;/i&gt; (Crustacea: Caridea: Crangonidae) are reported from the Northwest Shelf of Western Australia. One species is new to science &lt;i&gt;Philocheras&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anthonyi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. Five species are reported for the first time from Australian waters, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angustirostris&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1918), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incisus&lt;/i&gt; (Kemp, 1916), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonicus&lt;/i&gt; (Doflein, 1902), &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;modestus&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1918) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plebs&lt;/i&gt; (Kemp, 1916). A range extension within Australia is reported for &lt;i&gt;Philocheras&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lowisi&lt;/i&gt; (Kemp, 1916) and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;planoculminus&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1994. These records expand the number of &lt;i&gt;Philocheras&lt;/i&gt; species previously recorded from Australian waters from ten to 16. A revised key and illustrated guide to the species from Australia is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Crangonidae; sand shrimp; &lt;i&gt;Philocheras&lt;/i&gt;; new species; key; Western Australia; Australia; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joanne</firstname>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>157-168</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes kuboi &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;A. okunoi &lt;/i&gt;spp. nov. (Decapoda: Pontoniinae), from the Australian Northwest Shelf, Vietnam and the Philippines</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; (Decapoda: Pontoniinae), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuboi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. (Australian northwestern shelf and Vietnam, from 9.2–82 m) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okunoi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., (Australian north-western shelf and the Philippines, from 80–134 m, are described and illustrated. Both are most closely related to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tosaensis&lt;/i&gt; (Kubo, 1951), also found on the Northwest Shelf, and a key for their separation is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuboi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;okunoi&lt;/i&gt; spp. nov.; Decapoda; Pontoniinae; Australian Northwest Shelf; Vietnam; Philippines; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuboi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>169-176</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Salmoneus &lt;/i&gt;Holthuis, 1955 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Alpheidae) in the tropical western Atlantic, with description of five new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present study examines the diversity of the alpheid shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Salmoneus&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1955 in the western Atlantic. Five species are described from the shallow waters of the Caribbean Sea: &lt;i&gt;Salmoneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hispaniolensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., from the southern coast of the Dominican Republic; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camaroncito&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Panama and Honduras; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Panama; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;degravei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Panama, Colombia, Venezuela, and Tobago; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wehrtmanni&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Panama, Honduras, Mexico (Yucatan) and Tobago. In addition, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ortmanni&lt;/i&gt; (Rankin, 1898) is reported from new localities in Panama and Costa Rica; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carvachoi&lt;/i&gt; Anker, 2007 from Mexico (Yucatan) and the Brazilian states of Pernambuco and Paraíba; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavicolus&lt;/i&gt; Felder &amp; Manning, 1986 from Turks and Caicos Islands; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setosus&lt;/i&gt; Manning &amp; Chace, 1990 from Mexico (Yucatan). Most specimens were collected at shallow depths (0.5–2 m), on soft bottoms ranging from mudsilt to coarse sand mixed rubble, under rocks or coral rubble; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;degravei&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. appears to be associated with burrows of the callianassid ghost shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Neocallichirus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandimana&lt;/i&gt; (Gibbes, 1850).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; Alpheidae; &lt;i&gt;Salmoneus&lt;/i&gt;; shrimp; Caribbean; Panama; Dominican Republic; new species; western Atlantic; Callianassidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>177-205</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the “&lt;i&gt;Heterocarpus gibbosus &lt;/i&gt;Bate, 1888” species group (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pandalidae) from the western Pacific and north-western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The widely distributed deep-sea caridean shrimp &lt;i&gt;Heterocarpus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbosus&lt;/i&gt; Bate, 1888 was previously believed to exhibit considerable variations in the development of the basal rostral crest. Based on the comparison of abundant material from the western Pacific, combined with a molecular genetic analysis using partial sequences of the mitochondrial COI and 16S rRNA genes, three distinct species could be recognized. The true &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gibbosus&lt;/i&gt; has a moderately high basal rostral crest and appears to have a more eastern distribution from the South China Sea to the Indian Ocean. Both forms with a very low or very high basal rostral crest are currently undescribed and mainly distributed along the western coast of the Pacific from Japan to Fiji. The low basal rostral crest form, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abulbus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is unique in the genus by lacking a distinct abdominal boss and appears to be restricted to Japan, Taiwan and NE Philippines. The very high basal rostral crest form, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corona&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., occurs in the western Pacific down to NW Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heterocarpus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; West Pacific; COI; 16S rRNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heterocarpus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chien-Hui</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ka</firstname>
          <middlename>Hou</middlename>
          <lastname>Chu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>206-220</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sponge-dwelling snapping shrimps of Curaçao, with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sixteen species of sponge-dwelling snapping shrimp in the genus &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; (gambarelloides group) were collected from sites spanning the south coast of Curaçao, including three new to science. &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoetjesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. belongs to a species complex that includes &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pandionis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dardeaui,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yano,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;goodei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicarpus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ul.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuadramanus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is a distinctive shrimp characterized by a short, square moveable finger on the major first pereopod and by brilliant turquoise embryos in females. &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orapilosus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is a shrimp most morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barahonensis—both&lt;/i&gt; species share the distinctive character of a tuft of setae on the distal end of the third maxilliped, instead of a distal circlet of spines—but can be distinguished from the latter by the number of carpal segments on the second pereopod. Although eusocial &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; species (defined here as species that live in large colonies with strong reproductive skew) are often the most numerically abundant &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; collected from sponges at other sites, only pair-bonding &lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt; species were recorded from our collections in Curaçao.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zuzalpheus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;gambarelloides&lt;/i&gt; group; Alpheidae; sponge; symbiotic; coral reef; eusociality</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synalpheus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kristin</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hultgren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kenneth</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Macdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Emmett</middlename>
          <lastname>Duffy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>221-262</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Engystenopus &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Decapoda: Stenopodidea) &lt;i&gt;Juxtastenopus&lt;/i&gt;, gen. nov. , a new combination for &lt;i&gt;E. spinulatus &lt;/i&gt;Holthuis, 1946, and transfer of &lt;i&gt;E. palmipes &lt;/i&gt;Alcock &amp; Anderson, 1894 to the family Spongicolidae Schram, 1986</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Engystenopus&lt;/i&gt; is presented. A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Juxtastenopus,&lt;/i&gt; is created for the rare deepwater stenopodid shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Engystenopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinulatus&lt;/i&gt; based on a series of specimens from the Red Sea, Gulf of Aden and the Philippines. The genus &lt;i&gt;Engystenopus&lt;/i&gt; is now restricted to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmipes,&lt;/i&gt; its range is extended to Australian, Indonesian, and Madagascan waters, a new diagnosis of the genus is presented, and the genus is transferred to the family Spongicolidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Red Sea; Philippine; Indonesian; Madagascan; Australian deepwater fauna; Stenopodidae; Spongicolidae; &lt;i&gt;Engystenopus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Juxtastenopus&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Red Sea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joseph</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Goy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>263-277</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Palaemon javanicus &lt;/i&gt;Heller, 1862, and &lt;i&gt;Palaemon sundaicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, with description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium &lt;/i&gt;Bate, 1868 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea: Palaemonidae) from Southeast Asia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Re-examination of the type material of &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, shows that the current concept of the species is wrong. This species is in fact a senior subjective synonym of a widespread Southeast Asian species now known as &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trompii&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1898). The species now commonly referred to as “Macrobrachium &lt;i&gt;javanicum”&lt;/i&gt; following De Man (1879) from Southeast Asia is in fact, undescribed, and is here named &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duri&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duri&lt;/i&gt; spec. nov. can easily be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of a small triangular median process on the fourth thoracic sternite, possessing spinulate third to fifth pereiopods, having both second periopods covered with spines and few scattered short stiff setae, and the eggs been small and numerous. To add to the confusion, &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, is also synonymous with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sundaicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, and both were described by Heller (1862) in the same paper, making both names simultaneously available. As first revisors, we hereby choose &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sundaicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, to have priority over &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, when the two names are considered to be synonyms. &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sundaicus&lt;/i&gt; Heller, 1862, is therefore also the senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trompii&lt;/i&gt; (De Man, 1898).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duri&lt;/i&gt;; spec. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sundaicum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Macrobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanicum&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daisy</firstname>
          <lastname>Wowor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>278-297</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lysmata rauli, &lt;/i&gt;a new species of peppermint shrimp, (Decapoda: Hippolytidae) from the southwestern Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new peppermint shrimp species, &lt;i&gt;Lysmata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rauli&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., is described based on a specimen collected in shallow subtidal waters off Salvador, Bahia, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Lysmata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rauli&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. was identified from fresh material collected in tide pools. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rauli&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. appears to be rare in the region with only two specimens collected from Salvador, Brazil. The new species can be readily distinguished from all other species by the absences of a well developed accessory branch, number of carpal segments of the second pereiopod, presence of a well developed pterygostomial tooth and number of teeth on the rostrum, as well as by color pattern.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; Bahia; western Atlantic; &lt;i&gt;Lysmata&lt;/i&gt;; hermaphrodite</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Helio</firstname>
          <lastname>Laubenheimer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rhyne</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>298-304</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caridina &lt;/i&gt;H. Milne Edwards, 1837 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Caridea: Atyoidea: Atyidae) – freshwater shrimps from eastern and southern Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since the study of Richard and Clark (2009), additional material of &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africana&lt;/i&gt; Kingsley, 1882 has been examined and as a consequence &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nilotica&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;paucipara&lt;/i&gt; Weber, 1897 is considered to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africana.&lt;/i&gt; Material of &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratirostris&lt;/i&gt; De Man, 1892, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt; Bouvier, 1905, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla&lt;/i&gt; De Man, 1908 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moeri&lt;/i&gt; Woltereck, 1984 is reported, and redescribed. &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratirostris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time from the African mainland, both species being previously known from Madagascar. The first record of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla&lt;/i&gt; from the African continent is also noted. Furthermore, &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nilotica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;var.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;natalensis&lt;/i&gt; De Man, 1908 and &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nilotica&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;brevidactyla&lt;/i&gt; J. Roux, 1920 are considered to be junior synonyms of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla.&lt;/i&gt; Part of the type series of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla&lt;/i&gt; was examined for the present study and this material together with the description and figures of the rostrum illustrated by De Man (1892) as &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wyckii&lt;/i&gt; appear to be three different species: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla&lt;/i&gt; s. str. and probably two new species. These are not described due to lack of additional material available for study. However, two new African species are described and an identification key is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Atyidae; &lt;i&gt;Caridina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;africana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratirostris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachydactyla&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moeri&lt;/i&gt;; redescriptions; new species; Kenya; Zimbabwe; Tanzania; Mozambique; South Africa; Madagascar</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jasmine</firstname>
          <lastname>Richard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Clark</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>305-337</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the systematic position of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus spinimanus &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, 1969 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae) and the designation of &lt;i&gt;Anisomenaeus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>338-340</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new records of Caridea (Hippolytidae: Pasiphaeidae) from New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New species and new records of caridean shrimps are recorded from New Zealand. The hippolytid genera &lt;i&gt;Leontocaris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Merhippolyte,&lt;/i&gt; and pasiphaeid genus &lt;i&gt;Alainopasiphaea&lt;/i&gt; are reported for the first time from New Zealand waters, exemplified by three species of &lt;i&gt;Leontocaris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Merhippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alainopasiphaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis,&lt;/i&gt; respectively. The three species of &lt;i&gt;Leontocaris,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chacei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;australis&lt;/i&gt; were each previously known only from southern Australia. A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus,&lt;/i&gt; the second to be recorded from New Zealand, is described. &lt;i&gt;Lysmata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time from New Zealand.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; &lt;i&gt;Lebbeus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leontocaris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lysmata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Merhippolyte&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Alainopasiphaea&lt;/i&gt;; New Zealand</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>341-357</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Glyphocrangon &lt;/i&gt;(Decapoda: Caridea: Glyphocrangonidae) from off the coast of western Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Glyphocrangon&lt;/i&gt; has been collected during deep-water sampling off western Mexico, in the east Pacific. The series of specimens, including both males and females, was found between 780 and 1879 m depth. &lt;i&gt;Glyphocrangon&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is close to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sicaria&lt;/i&gt; Faxon, 1893 and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vicaria&lt;/i&gt; Faxon, 1896, both occurring in the east Pacific. It differs from both species, however, by the absence of tubercles between the lateral carinae, the presence of a large tooth at the anterior end of the second anterior lateral carina, the size of the eye (proportionally smaller in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vicaria),&lt;/i&gt; and the presence of two large rostral lateral teeth (one obsolete in &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sicaria).&lt;/i&gt; The new species is, however, strikingly similar to &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriata&lt;/i&gt; Komai &amp; Takeuchi, 1994, from the Mid-Pacific Mountains. It differs from the later species by the shape of the male endopod of first pleopod, the relative size and spination of the appendices interna and masculina, the presence of a large lateral tooth on pleura of abdominal somites 3–5, and the absence of curved setae on distal part of the dactyl of pereiopods 3–5.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Caridea; Glyphocrangonidae; &lt;i&gt;Glyphocrangon&lt;/i&gt;; new species; western Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michel</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hendrickx</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>358-366</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Additions to the genus &lt;i&gt;Phycomenes &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, 2008 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>367-368</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of palaemonid shrimp (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae) to accommodate &lt;i&gt;Leander belindae &lt;/i&gt;Kemp, 1925, with a redescription of the species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A redescription of the little known shrimp &lt;i&gt;Leander&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;belindae&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1925 based on syntypical material as well as some previously unreported museum specimens is provided. In view of its aberrant morphology, a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Rhopalaemon&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov., is erected. The new genus is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; Weber, 1795, but can be easily distinguished from that genus, and all other palaemonine genera, by the following combination of characters: propodus of the ambulatory pereiopods distally expanded; branchiostegal tooth and groove present; basal crest on rostrum absent; appendix interna on the first pleopod of males absent; and mandibular palp present.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Palaemonidae; &lt;i&gt;Rhopalaemon&lt;/i&gt;; new genus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ashelby</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sammy</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>369-378</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus devaneyi &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., from Oahu, Hawai'i (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devaneyi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov, is described from Oahu, Hawai’an Islands. The new species is closely related to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minutus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeancharcoti,&lt;/i&gt; but can be distinguished from both species by the lack of transverse corrugations on the ungui of the ambulatory dactyls, and the absence of minute denticles on the corpus of the dactyli.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devaneyi&lt;/i&gt;; sp. nov.; Crustacea; Decapoda; Pontoniinae; Oahu; Hawai’i; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Periclimenaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devaneyi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>379-388</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new genus and two new species of alpheid shrimps from Guam (Crustacea, Decapoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bruceopsis&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. is established for two species, &lt;i&gt;Bruceopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;projectus&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., n. sp., and &lt;i&gt;Bruceopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guamensis&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., n. sp., both from Guam, Mariana Islands, in the tropical western Pacific. The new genus is characterised by having the eyes at least partly covered dorsally and laterally by orbital hoods, the latter with sharp or blunt teeth; the chelipeds equal or unequal in size, symmetrical or asymmetrical in shape, carried extended, moderately or feebly enlarged, with carpus and merus bearing rows of setae mesially, and with simple chelae, lacking a snapping mechanism on the fingers; the third to fifth pereiopods with dorsally notched dactyli; the first to fourth pereiopods with small dorsolateral coxal lobes; the second pleomere conspicuously enlarged in females; and the posteroventral angle of the sixth pleonite with a welldeveloped, sometimes projecting articulated plate. &lt;i&gt;Bruceopsis&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. resembles &lt;i&gt;Alpheopsis&lt;/i&gt; Coutière, 1896 in general appearance, but may be more closely related to the western Atlantic genera &lt;i&gt;Coutieralpheus&lt;/i&gt; Anker &amp; Felder, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;Harperalpheus&lt;/i&gt; Felder &amp; Anker, 2007.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; Alpheidae; shrimp; new genus; new species; Guam; Micronesia; Pacific; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>389-404</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupontonia oahu &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a second species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Eupontonia &lt;/i&gt;Bruce, 1971, (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae) from Oahu, Hawai’ian Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the pontoniine shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Eupontonia&lt;/i&gt; Bruce, 1971. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oahu&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., from the Hawai’ian island of Oahu, is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Eupontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oahu&lt;/i&gt; is the second species of the genus and was found in association with &lt;i&gt;Pocillopora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meandrina&lt;/i&gt; L., confirming the association of this genus with scleractinian corals.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oahu&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Crustacea; Decapoda; Pontoniinae; Oahu; Hawai’i; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eupontonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oahu&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>405-414</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
