<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2391.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2391</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A study of the subfamily Archoleptonetinae (Araneae, Leptonetidae) with a review of the morphology and relationships for the Leptonetidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Detailed examination of the spinning organs and legs of &lt;i&gt;Archoleptoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schusteri&lt;/i&gt; Gertsch (1974) has revealed a cribellum and calamistrum, which represents the discovery of the first cribellate member of the Leptonetidae. Subsequent examination of all other described &lt;i&gt;Archoleptoneta&lt;/i&gt; species has confirmed the presence of a rectangular colulus similar to other leptonetids. A comparative review of the characters used to support the Leptonetidae is presented, including a discussion of their phylogenetic implications. The distribution of several features of the spinning organs, respiratory system, and genitalia suggests that the phylogenetic position of the Leptonetidae needs to be reevaluated, and makes their position within the Haplogynae uncertain. Illustrations and detailed discussion of characters in the Archoleptonetinae and Leptonetinae are provided. &lt;i&gt;Archoleptoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schusteri&lt;/i&gt; Gertsch is redescribed including detailed images of its spinning organs and genitalia. All ecribellate archoleptonetines are transferred to the new genus &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; gen. nov. based on the loss of the cribellum, giving the following new combinations: &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arganoi&lt;/i&gt; (Brignoli, 1974). comb nov., &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;garza&lt;/i&gt; (Gertsch, 1974) comb nov., &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; (Gertsch, 1974) comb nov., and &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stridulans&lt;/i&gt; (Platnick, 1994) comb nov. Three new species are described: &lt;i&gt;Archoleptoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gertschi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Eastern California, &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reddelli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Puebla, Mexico, and &lt;i&gt;Darkoneta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quetzal&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from San Lorenzo, Guatemala. Dichotomous keys are provided with a discussion of problems with the diagnosis of females. Distribution maps for each species are shown with a discussion of areas that require additional sampling in order to resolve species limits.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spider phylogeny; Haplogynae; cribellum; caves</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spider phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joel</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ledford</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Griswold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic re-assessment of the Australian and New Guinean green-eyed treefrogs &lt;i&gt;Litoria eucnemis&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;L. genimaculata &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;L. serrata &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Hylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The green-eyed treefrogs (Litoria &lt;i&gt;eucnemis&lt;/i&gt; species-group) are found throughout New Guinea and some of its offshore islands, and in two geographically separated regions in north-eastern Queensland, Australia. We examine the genetic relationships among populations of the complex from across its range and find that populations fall into two major lineages: 1) specimens referable to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genimaculata&lt;/i&gt; from New Guinea and its offshore islands, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exophthalmia,&lt;/i&gt; and 2) samples referable to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eucnemis&lt;/i&gt; from New Guinea and northern Cape York, Australia, and two lineages from the Wet Tropics of north-eastern Australia that are currently assigned to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genimaculata.&lt;/i&gt; Based on our molecular genetic analyses, morphological assessment of new collections and re-examination of type material, we retain &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eucnemis&lt;/i&gt; as currently recognised for northern Cape York populations but resurrect the name &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrata&lt;/i&gt; for the Wet Tropics populations. The degree of reproductive isolation between the two Wet Tropics lineages is being studied currently and so at this point we refer both to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrata.&lt;/i&gt; The degree of genetic variation observed in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genimaculata&lt;/i&gt; across New Guinea locations and possible paraphyly with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exophthalmia&lt;/i&gt; suggest the presence of additional undescribed species. Reexamination of type material and collection of new specimens, allow us to reassess the status of several other names currently synonymised with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eucnemis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genimaculata.&lt;/i&gt; Our observations support the present synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhacophorus&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eucnemis&lt;/i&gt; and we remove &lt;i&gt;Nyctimystes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loveridgei&lt;/i&gt; from the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genimaculata&lt;/i&gt; and place it in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eucnemis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Allozyme electrophoresis; advertisement call; Anura; Australia; Hylidae; Indonesia; &lt;i&gt;Litoria&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial DNA; New Guinea; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Allozyme electrophoresis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Richards</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Conrad</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoskin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cunningham</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Keith</firstname>
          <lastname>Mcdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Donnellan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema &lt;/i&gt;Duméril &amp; Bibron (Amphibia: Gymnophiona: Rhinatrematidae) from Guyana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first new species of rhinatrematid caecilian in more than 50 years, &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shiv&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Guyana. The type series of 10 specimens differs from the only other species in the genus, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bivittatum,&lt;/i&gt; in having a longer tail, different colour pattern, more acuminate and relatively shorter head, and in several features of the skull and mandible including dentition. Sequence data for 1572 aligned base pairs of mitochondrial DNA are &gt; 15% different between the two species. &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shiv&lt;/i&gt; is known only from Guyana, and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bivittatum&lt;/i&gt; from French Guiana and far northeastern Brazil. The only reported specimen of the genus from Suriname is not clearly referable to either of the named species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; caecilians; French Guiana; Guiana Shield; herpetology; HRXCT; Kaieteur; South America; Suriname; systematics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gower</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilkinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Emma</firstname>
          <lastname>Sherratt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-08</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Boltenia &lt;/i&gt;(Ascidiacea) from the Red Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Between 2003 and 2008 during surveys and collection of ascidians along the Red Sea coast of Israel several specimens of an undescribed species of &lt;i&gt;Boltenia&lt;/i&gt; were collected by SCUBA from man-made structures at 1–20 m depth. This is the first species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Boltenia&lt;/i&gt; described from the Red Sea. We name the new species &lt;i&gt;Boltenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yossiloya&lt;/i&gt; in honor of Professor Yossi Loya, a world renowned researcher of the coral reefs of Eilat.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; ascidian; coral reef; Red Sea; Gulf of Aqaba; Eilat; &lt;i&gt;Boltenia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Noa</firstname>
          <lastname>Shenkar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gretchen</firstname>
          <lastname>Lambert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
