<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2403.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2403</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new dromaeosaurid (Dinosauria: Theropoda) from the Upper Cretaceous Wulansuhai Formation of Inner Mongolia, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new dromaeosaurid theropod from the Upper Cretaceous Wulansuhai Formation of Bayan Mandahu, Inner Mongolia. The new taxon, &lt;i&gt;Linheraptor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is based on an exceptionally well-preserved, nearly complete skeleton. This specimen represents the fifth dromaeosaurid taxon recovered from the Upper Cretaceous Djadokhta Formation and its laterally equivalent strata, which include the Wulansuhai Formation, and adds to the known diversity of Late Cretaceous dromaeosaurids. &lt;i&gt;Linheraptor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus&lt;/i&gt; closely resembles the recently reported &lt;i&gt;Tsaagan&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mangas.&lt;/i&gt; Uniquely among dromaeosaurids, the two taxa share a large, anteriorly located maxillary fenestra and a contact between the jugal and the squamosal that excludes the postorbital from the infratemporal fenestra. These features suggest a sister-taxon relationship between &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mangas,&lt;/i&gt; which indicates the presence of a unique dromaeosaurid lineage in the Late Cretaceous of Asia. A number of cranial and dental features seen in &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mangas,&lt;/i&gt; and particularly some postcranial features of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus,&lt;/i&gt; suggest that these two taxa are probably intermediate in systematic position between known basal and derived dromaeosaurids. The discovery of &lt;i&gt;Linheraptor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exquisitus&lt;/i&gt; is thus important for understanding the evolution of some salient features seen in the derived dromaeosaurids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dromaeosauridae; Theropoda; Upper Cretaceous; Nei Mongol; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dromaeosauridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonah</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Choiniere</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Pittman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Qingwei</firstname>
          <lastname>Tan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dong</firstname>
          <lastname>Xiao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhiquan</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Tan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Clark</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Norell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>W. E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Corwin</firstname>
          <lastname>Sullivan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-9</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics and ecology of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Peloppiidae) from arboreal habitats in Western North America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We present the systematics and ecology of a new species of arboreal oribatid mite in the family Peloppiidae (Acari: Oribatida), &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jordani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; a dominant arthropod on branch tips and arboreal lichens associated with western hemlock (Tsuga &lt;i&gt;heterophylla&lt;/i&gt; (Pinaceae)) and Pacific silver fir (Abies &lt;i&gt;amabilis&lt;/i&gt; (Pinaceae)) in the coniferous temperate and montane forests of the Pacific Northwest of North America. &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jordani&lt;/i&gt; represents the first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; in North America. The species is described on the basis of morphology of all active instars plus molecular sequence data for the mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase I (COI) gene. &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jordani&lt;/i&gt; is compared with type specimens of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudatus&lt;/i&gt; Aoki from Japan, and a revised diagnosis of the genus &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; is given. &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jordani&lt;/i&gt; has a stable, overlapping population structure through the year, and its association with trees in Pinaceae is an ecological characteristic shared with &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caudatus&lt;/i&gt; from Japan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">oribatid mites; canopy; &lt;i&gt;Dendrozetes&lt;/i&gt;; Pinaceae; Pacific Northwest; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">oribatid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zoe</firstname>
          <lastname>Lindo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marilyn</firstname>
          <lastname>Clayton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Valerie</firstname>
          <lastname>Behan-Pelletier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>10-22</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New findings of rare or little-known alpheid shrimp genera (Crustacea, Decapoda) in Moorea, French Polynesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six rare or little-known genera from the shrimp family Alpheidae are reported from French Polynesia, five of them for the first time. Distribution ranges are significantly extended for the recently described &lt;i&gt;Acanthanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillus&lt;/i&gt; Anker, Poddoubtchenko &amp; Jeng, 2006 and &lt;i&gt;Richalpheus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmeri&lt;/i&gt; Anker &amp; Jeng, 2006, previously known only from two and one type specimens, respectively, from the Philippines. The original description of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillus,&lt;/i&gt; based on two females, is completed with the description and illustration of the male cheliped and pleopod; accordingly, the diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Acanthanas&lt;/i&gt; is slightly emended. The genus &lt;i&gt;Leptalpheus&lt;/i&gt; Williams, 1965 was not known from French Polynesia before, but is represented there by two species: &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulatus&lt;/i&gt; Anker &amp; Marin, 2009, previously known from Vietnam, the Philippines and Fiji; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacificus&lt;/i&gt; Banner &amp; Banner, 1974, previously considered as a Hawaiian endemic. The genus &lt;i&gt;Prionalpheus&lt;/i&gt; Banner &amp; Banner, 1960 is represented in French Polynesia by two species: &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triarticulatus&lt;/i&gt; Banner &amp; Banner, 1960, reported for the first time, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachytomeus&lt;/i&gt; Banner &amp; Banner, 1971, reported with some doubts (P. cf. &lt;i&gt;brachytomeus)&lt;/i&gt; for the first time since the original description. &lt;i&gt;Rugathanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borradailei&lt;/i&gt; (Coutière, 1903), a widespread but rather uncommon and easily overlooked species, is also reported for the first time from French Polynesia. Colour patterns are illustrated for all species, this being for the first time for &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palmeri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacificus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triarticulatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;brachytomeus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caridea; Alpheidae; shrimp; Pacific Ocean; French Polynesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>23-41</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Final-stage phyllosoma of &lt;i&gt;Palinustus &lt;/i&gt;A. Milne-Edwards, 1880 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Achelata: Palinuridae)—The first complete description</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four rare palinurid phyllosoma larvae, one mid-stage and three final stage, were found among the unclassified collections in the Crustacea Section, Natural History Museum, London. Detailed morphological analysis of the larvae indicated that they belong to several &lt;i&gt;Palinustus&lt;/i&gt; species given the presence of incipient blunt-horns, length of antennula, length ratio of segments of antennular peduncle, distribution of pereiopod spines, and shape of uropods and telson. Moreover, the size of the final-stage larvae agrees with that expected given the size of the recently described puerulus stage of &lt;i&gt;Palinustus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mossambicus.&lt;/i&gt; This constitutes the first description of a complete phyllosoma assigned to &lt;i&gt;Palinustus&lt;/i&gt; species. The phyllosoma described in the present study include the largest Palinuridae larva ever found.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Palinura; RRS &lt;i&gt;Discovery&lt;/i&gt;; Scyllaridae; &lt;i&gt;Linuparus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Justitia&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Palinura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ferran</firstname>
          <lastname>Palero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guerao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Clark</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pere</firstname>
          <lastname>Abelló</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">One of a thousand - a new species of &lt;i&gt;Trigonopterus &lt;/i&gt;(Coleoptera, Curculionidae, Cryptorhynchinae) from New Guinea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Trigonopterus&lt;/i&gt; Fauvel, 1862 is described: &lt;i&gt;Trigonopterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vandekampi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n..&lt;/b&gt; It occurs relatively commonly on foliage of lowland rainforests in West New Guinea. The genus &lt;i&gt;Trigonopterus&lt;/i&gt; is hyperdiverse, but the majority of its species are undescribed. This description is the first one including both important morphological and molecular characters and provides a foundation for forthcoming studies on the functional morphology of this species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New Guinea; &lt;i&gt;Trigonopterus&lt;/i&gt;; weevils; hyperdiversity; DNA barcoding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New Guinea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Riedel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
