<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2406.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2406</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The description of a cryptic species related to the pan-Amazonian frog &lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis &lt;/i&gt;(Boulenger 1883) (Anura: Aromobatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of litter frog from western Brazilian Amazon previously referred to as &lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; (Boulenger 1883). The new species is allopatric to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; and its known occurrence is restricted to terra-firme forests on the left bank of the upper Madeira River and southeastern State of Acre. This species is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; and from other species in the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; group by presenting two-note advertisement calls and conspicuous reddish-orange color on ventral surfaces of hind limbs and posterior abdomen. Phylogenetic analyses based on a fragment of the 16S rRNA mitochondrial gene suggest the new species is the sister group to a clade referred to as &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; occurring in southern State of Acre, from which it is distinguished by six unambiguous nucleotide substitutions, in addition to exclusive advertisement calls and color patterns. The new species is more distantly related to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; sensu stricto occurring near the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; type locality in the Peruvian Amazon. Summarizing evidence from molecular phylogenetic analysis, genetic distances and available data on advertisement calls, we identify one possible case of genetic introgression between lineages in this group and highlight the potential for the description of more species within the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt; complex.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amazonia; &lt;i&gt;Allobates&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hodli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; ; Brazil; Dendrobatoidea; &lt;i&gt;femoralis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; species complex; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amazonia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>Ivo</middlename>
          <lastname>Simões</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Albertina</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima1</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Izeni</firstname>
          <middlename>Pires</middlename>
          <lastname>Farias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new &lt;i&gt;Hemienchytraeus &lt;/i&gt;species (Enchytraeidae, Oligochaeta, Annelida) from Korea, with first records of other enchytraeids and terrestrial polychaetes (Annelida)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is the first occasion that the enchytraeid (Enchytraeidae, Oligochaeta) fauna has been investigated in Korea. 18 enchytraeid taxa (7 genera) and two terrestrial polychaetes (Hrabeiella sp. and &lt;i&gt;Parergodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heideri)&lt;/i&gt; were identified. Three species are new to science (Hemienchytraeus &lt;i&gt;koreanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeonjuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadratus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.);&lt;/b&gt; they are described here. Twelve taxa were distinguished at species level, four of them are cosmopolitan widespread species in the Holarctic, and one, &lt;i&gt;Enchytraeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;irregularis&lt;/i&gt; is obviously an introduced species. The two polychaetes were known previously only from Europe.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oligochaeta; Enchytraeidae; &lt;i&gt;Hemienchytraeus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; terrestrial Polychaeta; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oligochaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Klára</firstname>
          <lastname>Dózsa-Farkas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Hong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) from Mizoram, North-eastern India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of megophryid frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Tamdil wetlands of Mizoram State, north-eastern India. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tamdil&lt;/i&gt; new species, is compared with congeners from India and other parts of south-east Asia. The new species is diagnosable in showing the following combination of characters: SVL 32.3 mm in the only male and 31.8 mm in the only female known; dorsum tuberculate; eyelids with tubercles; tympanum and supratympanic fold distinct; supratympanic fold extending to posterior edge of tympanum; macroglands, including preaxillary, pectoral, femoral and ventrolateral glands present; Finger II &gt; I; toe tips not dilated, bearing dermal fringes; relatively long hind limbs, with heels in contact when limbs are held perpendicular to body; dorsum with dark blotches; flanks with small dark blotches; dark tympanic mask present; venter pale; labial bars present and limbs with dark cross-bars.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tamdil&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Megophryidae; Mizoram; north-eastern India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tamdil&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Megophryidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Saibal</firstname>
          <lastname>Sengupta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Saipari</firstname>
          <lastname>Sailo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lalremsanga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Abhijit</firstname>
          <lastname>Das</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Indraneil</firstname>
          <lastname>Das</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
