<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2447.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2447</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The nomenclatural status of the nomina of amphibians and reptiles created by Garsault (1764), with a parsimonious solution to an old nomenclatural problem regarding the genus &lt;i&gt;Bufo &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia, Anura), comments on the taxonomy of this genus, and comments on some nomina created by Laurenti (1768)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The nomenclatural consequences of the recent rediscovery of the works of Garsault (1764, 1765, 1767) in amphibians and reptiles are examined in detail. The 13 new nomina of these two groups created by Garsault (1764) distribute in three categories: (1) three of these nomina (Lacertus, &lt;i&gt;Rana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Testudo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marina)&lt;/i&gt; cause no problem, being just junior synonyms of senior nomina created by Linnaeus (1758); (2) four of them (Bufo, &lt;i&gt;Salamandra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scincus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Vipera)&lt;/i&gt; become the valid nomina of taxa, in replacement of identical nomina created later by Laurenti (1768), thus entailing no change in the nomina of their included species and subspecies but changes in their complete nominal-complexes (including their authors and dates); (3) six of these nomina are here rejected as invalid senior synonyms (Ranetta, &lt;i&gt;Serpens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lacertus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aquatilis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lacertus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrestris)&lt;/i&gt; or homonyms (Lacertus &lt;i&gt;viridis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Testudo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrestris)&lt;/i&gt; of nomina in current use, by virtue of Article 23.9.1 of the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; A very positive result of the rediscovery of these works is that it allows to solve for the best an old nomenclatural problem, concerning the nucleospecies (type-species) of the genus &lt;i&gt;Bufo:&lt;/i&gt; whereas the nucleospecies (type-species) of &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; Laurenti, 1768 is &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; Laurenti, 1768, we hereby designate &lt;i&gt;Rana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bufo&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 as nucleospecies of &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; Garsault, 1764. This case shows that it is sometimes possible, even in complex nomenclatural situations, to solve them through a proper use of the Rules of the &lt;i&gt;Code,&lt;/i&gt; without having to appeal to the ICZN for the use of its Plenary-Powers. From a taxonomic point of view, we think the data published so far do not allow currently to stabilise the generic taxonomy of the &lt;i&gt;BUFONIDAE.&lt;/i&gt; Pending additional data, we support a conservative attitude, maintaining in the genus &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; most species traditionally referred to this genus. In particular, we think all Eurasian species of this family, which include several pairs of species known to be able to produce viable adult hybrids, should be kept in this genus, but in three distinct subgenera: &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; Garsault, 1764 for the group including &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bufo&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1758); &lt;i&gt;Bufotes&lt;/i&gt; Rafinesque, 1815 for the group including &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; (Laurenti, 1768); and &lt;i&gt;Epidalea&lt;/i&gt; Cope, 1864 for the group including &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calamita&lt;/i&gt; (Laurenti, 1768). This survey also allows to discuss the appropriateness of the current Article 11.9.5 dealing with specific trinomina, especially as they appear in Laurenti (1768), and to point again to the need to implement more drastic Rules regarding the conditions required for a nomen being compliant for protection through Article 23.9.1 of the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Garsault (1764); Laurenti (1768); nomenclature; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; Article 11.9.5; Article 23.9.1; synonymy; homonymy; priority; old publications; well-known nomina; subgenus; amphibians; reptiles; &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Garsault (1764)</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <lastname>Bour</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The smallest terrestrial vertebrate of Ecuador: A new frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Strabomantidae) from the Cordillera del Cóndor</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; characterized by its diminutive size (maximum SVL in males 13.7 mm; &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 46), dorsum smooth to slightly shagreen, finger and toe pads expanded, and red iris with thin black reticulation. The species is the smallest terrestrial vertebrate recorded in Ecuador, and the smallest species in the diverse genus &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis.&lt;/i&gt; The osteological traits of the new species are similar to those found in other &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; species, and no elements are lost because of miniaturization. The new species is only known from two close localities in Cordillera del Cóndor, Provincia Zamora Chinchipe, Ecuador.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cordillera del Cóndor; &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt;; osteology; miniaturization; Strabomantidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cordillera del Cóndor</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <lastname>Terán-Valdez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
