<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2458.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2458</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic monograph of the Middle American leaf-litter inhabiting weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Theognete &lt;/i&gt;Champion (Coleoptera: Curculionidae; Molytinae; Lymantini) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The formerly monobasic genus &lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt; Champion is revised. The two syntypes of &lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; Champion are found to represent two species, one of which is described as &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;championi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species. Another 92 new species are also recognized. The 94 known species are grouped into 8 informal species groups, based largely on the structure of the thoracic sterna. These are (numbers of species in group and distribution for each species in parentheses): &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;araneiformis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(6)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;araneiformis&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Puebla); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gracilis&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;azteca&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striatifemur&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Tamaulipas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kovariki&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Tamaulipas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Querétaro, San Luis Potosí); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(4)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis&lt;/i&gt; Champion (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;championi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species Guatemala (Quezaltenango, San Marcos); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janzeni&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species México (Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cozari&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(5)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;denticulata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Puebla); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caviventris&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo, Puebla, Querétaro, San Luis Potosí); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thibodeaui&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulgida&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo, San Luis Potosí); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stefurinoi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;semistriata&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(5)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;semistriata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México,Guerrero); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;akros&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;semiopaca&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humilis&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;bothynometopon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(10)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;bothynometopon&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;giselae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Guerrero); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;genieri&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Guatemala, Quezaltenango); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plumosa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;birdi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ashei&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Santa Barbara); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pragudemi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (El Salvador, Santa Ana; Honduras, Lempira); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeanae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (El Salvador, Santa Ana, Chalatenango; Honduras, Lempira); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chiapaneca&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;tzotzil&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(36)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;tzotzil&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ludvigseni&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;howdenorum&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lutulenta&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;campbelli&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zapatista&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;braunae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Guatemala, Baja Verapaz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lapouimetorum&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Guatemala, Zacapa); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schusteri&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Guatemala, Sacatepequez); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peckorum&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México (Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species México (Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scopulus&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavisetosa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huitepec&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;backorum&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confusa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balli&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalondei&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Guatemala, Totonicapan); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schaubeli&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sylvatica&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hortenseae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaia&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;echinata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Tamaulipas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalannei&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Cortes, Ocotepeque; El Salvador, Santa Ana, Chaltenango); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cavei&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Olancho); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trusterae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Lempira); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coleadesi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Santa Bárbara); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jonesi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maturini&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Santa Bárbara, Yoro); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cortesi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maziaki&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barringerorum&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evelynae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illuviosa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weadockae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galvezi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;distenta&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(18)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;distenta&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kaulbarsi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baranowskii&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;globosa&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fossor&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terrestris&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lalibertei&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dansereaui&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desautelsi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson,6 · &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt; 2458 © 2010 Magnolia Pressnew species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;newtoni&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Puebla); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weiri&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;romanoi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;broadheadae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chauliothorax&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo, San Luis Potosí); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boaseae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Comayagua); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corderoi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (Honduras, Comayagua); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;adarmstrongae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Chiapas); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laurentae,&lt;/i&gt; new species (México, Querétaro); &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Theognete&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;hesmos&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;group&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(10)—T.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;hesmos&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harbini&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Hidalgo); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reprela&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;michaudi&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, México); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lakarms&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Veracruz); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomneyeae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristata&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grimblyae&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Querétaro); &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;draco&lt;/i&gt; Anderson, new species (México, Oaxaca). Species groups are characterized and taxonomic composition and general distribution and ecological correlates summarized. Diagnoses and distributions are given for all species and ecological information is presented where available. Local endemism is remarkable throughout the genus, nearly all species known from one or only a limited number of proximal localities. Individual distribution maps are not presented but .kmz data files for use with GoogleEarth® are presented as hot links under the distribution for each species group. Immature stages, life history and food habits are not known for any of the species, although the larvae are presumed to feed in dead wood, as do other members of Lymantini and related tribes. The species are distributed as follows: México (78), Honduras (10), Guatemala (6), El Salvador (3). This study represents the results of over 20 years of intensive leaf litter collections made in México and northern Middle America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;biodiversity,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;classification,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;taxonomy,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;weevil&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;biodiversity,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;classification,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;taxonomy,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;weevil&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Anderson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-127</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
