<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2481.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2481</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A cladistic revision of &lt;i&gt;Tortopus &lt;/i&gt;Needham &amp; Murphy with description of the new genus &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis &lt;/i&gt;(Ephemeroptera: Polymitarcyidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The 12 species previously placed in &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; together with 3 species newly described here, are revised and included in a phylogenetic analysis. Based on synapomorphic characters on the nymphs and adults of both sexes, &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;igaranus&lt;/i&gt; Needham &amp; Murphy, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;circumfluus&lt;/i&gt; Ulmer, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harrisi&lt;/i&gt; Traver, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zottai&lt;/i&gt; (Navás), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellus&lt;/i&gt; Lugo-Ortiz &amp; McCafferty, and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenales&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and the genus is defined by: female parastyli receptors with long furrows anterior to sockets; penes entirely flattened; male ninth abdominal sternum almost separated in two portions by a median notch; mesosternum with furcasternal protuberances contiguous only on basal corner; and nymphs with two subapical tubercles on mandibular tusks. &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis&lt;/i&gt; is newly described for &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bruchianus&lt;/i&gt; (Navás), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limoncocha&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscuripennis&lt;/i&gt; (Domínguez), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parishi&lt;/i&gt; (Banks), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;primus&lt;/i&gt; (McDunnough), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puella&lt;/i&gt; (Pictet), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarae&lt;/i&gt; (Domínguez), &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spatula&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unguiculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Ulmer). &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by: R sector of female fore wing without additional veins between R 2 and IR; female parastyli receptors C or V-shaped, with sockets opening towards median line; male gonopore associated with a claw-like structure; penes separated from the base; parastyli more than 5 times length of pedestals; parastyli curved in lateral view; nymphs with a single subapical tubercle on mandibular tusks. The study of available type material permitted inclusion of comparative diagnoses, with figures and redescriptions as needed. The male imago of the type species of &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; (T. &lt;i&gt;igaranus&lt;/i&gt; Needham &amp; Murphy) is described for the first time, as are the female adults of &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bellus&lt;/i&gt; Lugo-Ortiz &amp; McCafferty and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harrisi&lt;/i&gt; Traver. Three new Neotropical species based on male and female adults are described: &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arenales&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limoncocha&lt;/i&gt; from Ecuador, and &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spatula&lt;/i&gt; from Colombia. Keys to separate the adults and nymphs of the genera of Polymitarcyidae, and for male and female adults of all the species of &lt;i&gt;Tortopus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tortopsis&lt;/i&gt; are presented, as well as line drawings, pictures and SEM photographs of important structures.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Campsurinae; &lt;i&gt;Campsurus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Asthenopus&lt;/i&gt;; mayfly; coupling apparatus; identification keys</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Campsurinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Molineri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revalidation and redescription of &lt;i&gt;Bungona illiesi &lt;/i&gt;(Lugo-Ortiz &amp; McCafferty) (Ephemeroptera: Baetidae) from Australia, based on mitochondrial and morphological evidence</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bungona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi&lt;/i&gt; (Lugo-Ortiz &amp; McCafferty) n.comb. was described from a single specimen collected in northern Queensland, Australia, as a species of &lt;i&gt;Cloeodes&lt;/i&gt; Traver. The distinguishing characteristics of a minute maxillary palp, the absence of spination on the mandibles between the mola and prostheca, narrow-elongate gills, and medially expanded labial palps were later found to occur in &lt;i&gt;Bungona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narilla&lt;/i&gt; Harker, and the two species were synonymized. Extensive collecting in northern Queensland yielded larvae and adults of &lt;i&gt;Bungona&lt;/i&gt; that differ from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narilla&lt;/i&gt; in all life stages. We believe our specimens are equivalent to &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi&lt;/i&gt; because they were collected only a few kilometres from the type locality, at least one specimen had both minute and normally sized maxillary palps, nearly all specimens had medially expanded labial palps, and the dorsal abdominal colour pattern was similar. Sequences of a 657-bp fragment of the mitochondrial gene cytochrome oxidase I supported the recognition of two species and confirmed the association of larvae and adults of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi.&lt;/i&gt; Interspecific p-distances ranged from 18.8–19.4% and the maximum intraspecific divergence observed was 1.7%. Based on the combination of morphological, mitochondrial, and biogeographical data, we show &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi&lt;/i&gt; should be recognised as a valid species distinct from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narilla.&lt;/i&gt; Larvae of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;illiesi&lt;/i&gt; differ from those of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narilla&lt;/i&gt; by having fewer robust setae on the femora and a small lateral tooth on the outer incisor of both mandibles. Male and female adults differ from those of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;narilla&lt;/i&gt; by having less extensive red colouration on the abdominal terga.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mayfly; Australia; mtDNA; cytochrome oxidase I; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mayfly</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Webb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Suter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-51</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic study of Chinese Empoascini (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae) (I)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of Chinese Empoascini (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Typhlocybinae), &lt;i&gt;Radicafurcus&lt;/i&gt; Qin &amp; Zhang, &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; with one new species, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;breviprocessus&lt;/i&gt; Qin &amp; Zhang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Sichuan Province (S.W. China) is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Baguoidea&lt;/i&gt; Mahmood 1967 is redescribed and a new species, &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yunnanensis&lt;/i&gt; Qin &amp; Zhang, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from Yunnan Province (S.W. China). Two genera (Faiga Dworakowska 1980 and &lt;i&gt;Sikkimasca&lt;/i&gt; Dworakowska 1994) are reported for the first time from China, and the type species of these genera are re-illustrated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homoptera; Auchenorryncha; taxonomy; new taxa; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dao-Zheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Qin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yang</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ya-Lin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of Baetidae (Ephemeroptera) from lakes and reservoirs in eastern North America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Waynokiops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentatogriphus,&lt;/i&gt; new genus and new species (Ephemeroptera: Baetidae), is described from nymphs collected from seven lakes and reservoirs in the eastern United States of America, specifically from the states of Virginia, Kentucky, Ohio, Indiana and Arkansas (type locale), during sampling for the USEPA National Lakes Assessment. The lateral abdominal expansions and the dorsal abdominal armature of the new genus are unique among &lt;i&gt;Cloeon&lt;/i&gt; complex genera. Abdominal tergal projections are unusual for a small minnow mayfly from lentic habitats.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cloeon&lt;/i&gt; complex; identification; systematics; taxonomy; evolutionary novelty</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cloeon&lt;/i&gt; complex</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hill</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <lastname>Pfeiffer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luke</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jacobus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
