<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2482.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2482</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Salfacarus &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Opilioacarida) in Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The opilioacarid genus &lt;i&gt;Salfacarus&lt;/i&gt; in Madagascar is revised, with description of four new species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antsirananensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kirindiensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mahafaliensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ranobensis,&lt;/i&gt; and a new delimitation for the type species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;legendrei.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Salfacarus&lt;/i&gt; is widespread in Madagascar but individual species appear restricted to relatively small areas. A key to the adults of &lt;i&gt;Salfacarus&lt;/i&gt; in Madagascar is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Parasitiformes; Opilioacaridae; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Parasitiformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ma.</firstname>
          <middlename>Magdalena Vázquez</middlename>
          <lastname>G.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <lastname>Klompen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Deep-sea &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Amphipoda: Eusiridae) from New Zealand and the Ross Sea with key to the Pacific, Indian Ocean and Antarctic species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The amphipod genus &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; has a worldwide distribution. Four species new to science are described, increasing the total number of &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; species to 59. Only one species was previously known from New Zealand and none from the Ross Sea. Two species &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chathamensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delicata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; were collected at the same station in 420 m depth off eastern New Zealand; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rossi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; were collected below 3000 m depth in the Ross Sea, Antarctica. Investigation of recently collected material as well as historic material from the NIWA Invertebrate collection revealed several specimens of &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarctica&lt;/i&gt; K.H. Barnard, 1932 sampled in the Ross Sea. Four damaged &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; specimens, recently collected from 5170 m in the Kermadec Trench, north of New Zealand, are reported. Epibionts have been discovered on the mouthparts of several specimens from New Zealand as well as the Ross Sea. Preliminary molecular investigations of the phylogeney of &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; are briefly discussed. A key to Pacific, Indian Ocean and Antarctic species of &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; &lt;i&gt;Rhachotropis&lt;/i&gt;; New Zealand; Antarctica; COI; epibionts</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anne-Nina</firstname>
          <lastname>Lörz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of limestone-forest frog, genus &lt;i&gt;Platymantis &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia: Anura: Ceratobatrachidae) from central Luzon Island, Philippines</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of terrestrial limestone forest frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Platymantis&lt;/i&gt; from Biak Na Bato National Park in central Luzon Island, Philippines. &lt;i&gt;Platymantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biak&lt;/i&gt; is assigned to the primarily arboreal &lt;i&gt;Platymantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guentheri&lt;/i&gt; Species Group, and is distinguished from these and other congeners by features of its external morphology and preferred terrestrial limestone microhabitat. Several distinguishing morphological characters include a moderately large body (32.3–39.9 mm SVL for 23 males and 37.4–42.4 mm SVL for 8 females), moderately expanded finger discs and slightly expanded toe discs, smooth skin, and limb banding pattern. The new species is yet another species in a rapidly growing group of newly discovered Philippine forest frogs with preferences for forested, karst habitats.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Cryptic species; Endemism; Limestone frogs; &lt;i&gt;Platymantis&lt;/i&gt; guentheri Species Group; SW Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Biodiversity; Cryptic species; Endemism; Limestone frogs; &lt;i&gt;Platymantis&lt;/i&gt; guentheri Species Group; SW Pacific</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cameron</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Siler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arvin</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diesmos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Linkem</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mae</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diesmos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafe</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brown</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-63</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of freshwater crab of the genus &lt;i&gt;Neostrengeria &lt;/i&gt;Pretzmann, 1965, from Colombia (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pseudothelphusidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Neostrengeria&lt;/i&gt; Pretzmann, 1965, is described. The genus is endemic to Colombia and is distributed on the slopes and high plains of the Eastern Andes at elevations of 470 to 3000 m. The new species is distinguished from its congeners primarily by the morphology of the first male gonopod: shape of the mesial, lateral and accessory lobes, outline of the apex and the meso-caudal projection of the spermatic channel. The new species raises to 24 the number of species included in &lt;i&gt;Neostrengeria.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Freshwater crabs; Pseudothelphusidae; &lt;i&gt;Neostrengeria&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Colombia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Freshwater crabs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martha</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
