<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2493.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Jun. 2010</title>
    <volume>2493</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Prosaetes rhinodontis &lt;/i&gt;(Wright, 1876) (Crustacea: Copepoda: Siphonostomatoida), an enigmatic parasite of the whale shark, &lt;i&gt;Rhincodon typus&lt;/i&gt; Smith (Elasmobranchii: Orectolobiformes: Rhincodontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The siphonostomatoid copepod &lt;i&gt;Prosaetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinodontis&lt;/i&gt; (Wright, 1876) is redescribed in detail based on adult female specimens recently collected from the sieve-like gill rakers of a whale shark, &lt;i&gt;Rhincodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;typus&lt;/i&gt; Smith, held in captivity off the coast of Motobu-cho, Okinawa-jima Island, Japan. Comparisons with other caligiform copepod species previously identified as &lt;i&gt;Dysgamus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticus&lt;/i&gt; Steenstrup &amp; Lütken, 1861 and described as &lt;i&gt;Echthrogaleus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectinatus&lt;/i&gt; Kirtisinghe, 1964 from a whale shark revealed that these two taxa are conspecific with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinodontis.&lt;/i&gt; The latter is transferred herein from the Pandaridae to the Cecropidae based on the relatively slim shape of its maxilliped corpus, and an amended diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Prosaetes&lt;/i&gt; C. B. Wilson, 1907 is provided. Neotype material of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinodontis&lt;/i&gt; was selected from a previous collection of 173 specimens removed from a whale shark caught alive off the coast of Yonabaru-cho, Okinawa-jima Island, Japan, and subsequently held in captivity, albeit briefly, in the Okinawa Churaumi Aquarium, Motobu-cho, Okinawa-jima Island, Japan. Asymmetrical clusters of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinodontis&lt;/i&gt; females on the host’s gill rakers were observed in this study, which suggest that this aggregative behavior most likely does not facilitate their attachment to the host but rather is a strategy used to augment their reproductive fitness. We also postulate that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rhinodontis&lt;/i&gt; grazes on the epithelium of the host’s gill rakers and is, in contrast to other cecropids, a relatively vagile species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Japan; aquarium; captivity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danny</firstname>
          <lastname>Tang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Makio</firstname>
          <lastname>Yanagisawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kazuya</firstname>
          <lastname>Nagasawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revised taxonomy and redescription of two species of the Peripatidae (Onychophora) from Brazil: a step towards consistent terminology of morphological characters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on the supposed quadrangular shape of the basal pieces of dorsal primary papillae, several species of the “Caribbean group” of the neotropical Peripatidae, including &lt;i&gt;Macroperipatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acacioi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machadoi,&lt;/i&gt; were assigned to &lt;i&gt;Macroperipatus.&lt;/i&gt; So far, the quadrangular shape of dermal papillae was confirmed only for &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquatus,&lt;/i&gt; the type species of the genus. Previous observations revealed that the putatively quadrangular shape reported from other species of the “Caribbean group” might be a fixation artefact. Hence, detailed reinvestigations of all putative &lt;i&gt;Macroperipatus&lt;/i&gt; species are required to clarify their taxonomy. In the present study, two species of the “Caribbean group”, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acacioi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machadoi,&lt;/i&gt; are analyzed and redescribed, based on type material and topotype specimens collected at the corresponding type localities. The original descriptions of both species are complemented with data obtained from scanning electron microscopy, in addition to conventional morphological methods. The quadrangular bases of primary papillae are shown to be absent from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acacioi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machadoi,&lt;/i&gt; thus suggesting that these two species are not closely related to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;torquatus.&lt;/i&gt; The new data instead suggest that these two species are representatives of &lt;i&gt;Epiperipatus:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acacioi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machadoi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov..&lt;/b&gt; The present study highlights the use of scanning electron microscopy for clarifying the taxonomy and phylogeny of the neotropical Peripatidae. It also reveals gaps in taxon sampling and problems regarding the ambiguous terminology of morphological characters used for describing the anatomy of peripatids. An attempt is made towards a consistent terminology for species (re)descriptions and studies of onychophoran anatomy and phylogeny.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; Caribbean group; &lt;i&gt;Epiperipatus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Macroperipatus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivo</firstname>
          <lastname>De Sena Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alfredo</firstname>
          <middlename>Hannemann</middlename>
          <lastname>Wieloch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Georg</firstname>
          <lastname>Mayer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>16-34</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Syllinae (Polychaeta: Syllidae) from Australia. Part 3. Genera &lt;i&gt;Alcyonosyllis&lt;/i&gt;, Genus A, &lt;i&gt;Parahaplosyllis&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Trypanosyllis &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Trypanobia&lt;/i&gt;)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Large collections of Australian Syllidae (Polychaeta) from the Australian Museum (Sydney) have been examined and identified, together with material from the Hamburgische Zoologische Museum der Universität (Hamburg, Germany), as well as some specimens from other museums. All known Australian species of the subfamily Syllinae belonging to the genera &lt;i&gt;Alcyonosyllis&lt;/i&gt; Glasby &amp; Watson, 2001 (1 species), Genus A (1 species), &lt;i&gt;Parahaplosyllis&lt;/i&gt; Hartmann-Schröder, 1990 (1 species), and &lt;i&gt;Trypanosyllis&lt;/i&gt; (Trypanobia) Imajima &amp; Hartman, 1964 (2 species), are fully described and figured, except &lt;i&gt;Alcyonosyllis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;phili&lt;/i&gt; Glasby &amp; Watson, 2001 that recently was described based on Australian material.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Australia; Syllidae; Syllinae; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Australia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>San Martín</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pat</firstname>
          <lastname>Hutchings</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>Teresa</middlename>
          <lastname>Aguado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the &lt;i&gt;Vaejovis eusthenura &lt;/i&gt;group in Oaxaca, Mexico (Scorpiones: Vaejovidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Vaejovis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oaxaca,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of the &lt;i&gt;Vaejovis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eusthenura&lt;/i&gt; group is described from the Mexican state of Oaxaca. It is found in lowlands ranging from the Mitla area in central Oaxaca southeast into the Isthmus of Tehuantepec and the eastern edge of Chiapas.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; Oaxaca; setal counts; systematics.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Santibañez</middlename>
          <lastname>López</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>David</middlename>
          <lastname>Sissom</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sparisoma rocha&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of parrotfish (Actinopterygii: Labridae) from Trindade Island, South-western Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of parrotfish, &lt;i&gt;Sparisoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rocha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Trindade Island off South-eastern Brazil. It differs from its Western Atlantic congeners by the unique colour pattern of live and freshly preserved individuals: initial phase red overall with a brownish shade from lower jaw to over the abdominal cavity, sparse orange blotches on head, and pale circumpeduncular band; terminal phase reddish brown with orange stripe from jaw angle to end of preopercle, sparse orange blotches on head, three pinkish to reddish stripes from about midline to dorsum, from midline to belly pale greyish green to whitish with suffusion of pale reddish brown, a black spot on base of pectoral fins and a bright-yellow blotch below this spot. Additionally, mitochondrial 12S and 16S rRNA loci sequences do not match any known &lt;i&gt;Sparisoma&lt;/i&gt; species. The new parrotfish increases to six the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sparisoma&lt;/i&gt; recorded from South-western Atlantic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sparisoma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Labridae; reef fish; oceanic islands; Western Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sparisoma&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hudson</firstname>
          <middlename>Tercio</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinheiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>João</firstname>
          <middlename>Luiz</middlename>
          <lastname>Gasparini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Sazima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-65</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The nomenclatural status of some generic nomina of Megophryidae (Amphibia, Anura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stéphane</firstname>
          <lastname>Grosjean</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annemarie</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kraig</firstname>
          <lastname>Adler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ermi</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
