<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2504.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jun. 2010</title>
    <volume>2504</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships in the genus &lt;i&gt;Astropecten &lt;/i&gt;Gray (Paxillosida: Astropectinidae) on a global scale: molecular evidence for morphological convergence, species-complexes and possible cryptic speciation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">With over 150 described species, &lt;i&gt;Astropecten&lt;/i&gt; Gray (Paxillosida:Astropectinidae) is one of the most species-rich genera among sea stars. This diversity is remarkable, because most species of &lt;i&gt;Astropecten&lt;/i&gt; have a long-lived planktotrophic larval stage, which would be expected to lead to a low speciation rate. The taxonomy of this genus is complex and not well resolved, and phylogenetic relationships have only been addressed in the beginning of the last century. In order to resolve general taxonomic issues, identify speciation patterns and estimate species diversity within the genus &lt;i&gt;Astropecten,&lt;/i&gt; we inferred a molecular phylogeny of 117 specimens of &lt;i&gt;Astropecten&lt;/i&gt; belonging to 40 species from around the world using mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) sequences of 12S rRNA, 16S rRNA and cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI). We compared the resulting molecular phylogeny to a previously published morphological one by Döderlein and investigated the possibility of morphological convergence in species from different geographic regions. Finally, we also aimed at identifying potentially problematic descriptions and/or signs of cryptic speciation in &lt;i&gt;Astropecten.&lt;/i&gt; The global molecular phylogeny exhibited three main clades, each containing specimens of the same geographic region: 1. the IndoPacific; 2. the Neotropics; and 3. the eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean. Phylogenetic inferences based on mtDNA indicate that morphological and ecological convergence has taken place in &lt;i&gt;Astropecten,&lt;/i&gt; resulting in allopatric non-sister taxa with similar morphologies and habitat preferences. The comparison to Döderlein’s morphological phylogeny reveals congruence on the whole but many discrepancies on a local scale, indicating that meaningful morphological characters are not easily identified and categorized in &lt;i&gt;Astropecten.&lt;/i&gt; Our results also reveal that &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polyacanthus&lt;/i&gt; Müller &amp; Tröschel and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indicus&lt;/i&gt; Döderlein are species-complexes; cryptic speciation may have occurred within each of these morphospecies. Furthermore, several variants, previously presumed to be conspecific, exhibit genetic distances large enough to justify recognizing them as separate species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">global phylogeny; Asteroidea; mitochondrial DNA; echinoderm; marine invertebrates</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">global phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Deborah</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zulliger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lessios</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new nematode species from Saldanha Bay, South Africa: Perepsilonema benguelae sp. nov. and Leptepsilonema saldanhae sp. nov. (Desmodorida, Epsilonematidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Perepsilonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;benguelae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;Leptepsilonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saldanhae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. are described and illustrated from coarse sand sediments in Saldanha Bay, along the west coast of South Africa. &lt;i&gt;Perepsilonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;benguelae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is characterised by a large swollen body in the genital region, the annuli are not clearly orientated into anteriorly and posteriorly directed margins and copulatory thorns are restricted to three pairs in the precloacal region. In &lt;i&gt;Leptepsilonema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saldanhae&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. the somatic setae in the pharyngeal region are very long and the first ambulatory setae of the external subventral row are short. Other distinguishing features include the shape of the amphidial fovea and the copulatory apparatus, and the presence of six ventro-lateral copulatory thorns around the cloaca. These descriptions are the first for the family Epsilonematidae from the west coast of South Africa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Description; morphology; Africa; Benguela Current; marine; Nematoda; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Description</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <middlename>G. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hendricks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gibbons</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-30</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the laomediid genus &lt;i&gt;Naushonia &lt;/i&gt;Kingsley, 1897 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Gebiidea) from the Indo-West Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the rarely collected laomediid genus &lt;i&gt;Naushonia&lt;/i&gt; Kingsley, 1897 are reported from shallow waters of the tropical Indo-West Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Naushonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latimana&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described on the basis of two specimens, a male and a female, collected off Mayotte, Comoro Archipelago, southwestern Indian Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Naushonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratipalma&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. is described based on a single female specimen collected off Moorea, Society Archipelago, French Polynesia, Southwestern Pacific Ocean. Both new species are morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perrieri&lt;/i&gt; (Nobili, 1904) and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Komai, 2004, but can be clearly distinguished from them by several morphological characters. The present report raises the total number of known species in the genus to 10; an identification key to all known species of &lt;i&gt;Naushonia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Laomediidae; Gebiidea; &lt;i&gt;Naushonia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Mayotte; Moorea; French Polynesia; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;Gray, 1826 (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Khanh Hoa province, Southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of bent–toed gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yangbayensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the monsoon evergreen forests of Truong Son Mountain Range, Khanh Hoa province. It differs from all other species of Indo–Chinese &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; by having a mean SVL of 83.5 mm; dark spots and blotches on the head; no continuous nuchal loop; 6–8 precloacal pores in males arranged in a chevron; five or six dark brown, irregular, dorsal bands between limb insertions; 18–20 subdigital lamellae under first toe; 15–17 subdigital lamellae under fourth toe; and a median row of enlarged subcaudal scales.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; taxonomy; new species; southern Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gekkonidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chan</firstname>
          <middlename>Kin</middlename>
          <lastname>Onn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of larval mites (Acari: Prostigmata: Microtrombidiidae) from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Persianthrombium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;farajii&lt;/i&gt; Sedghi, Saboori &amp; Hakimitabar &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Microtrombidiidae) is described and illustrated from larvae ectoparasitic on undetermined &lt;i&gt;Locusta&lt;/i&gt; (Orthoptera: Acrididae) from Jahrom, Fars Province, Iran. A key to larval genera of Microtrombidiidae with three dorsal scuta is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Persianthrombium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;farajii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Acrididae; Jahrom city; larva; ectoparasite; Parasitengona</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Persianthrombium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;farajii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Acrididae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ali</firstname>
          <lastname>Sedghi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alireza</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Ali</middlename>
          <lastname>Akrami</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masoud</firstname>
          <lastname>Hakimitabar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
