<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2534.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jul. 2010</title>
    <volume>2534</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of the spider family Penestomidae (Araneae, Entelegynae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Conflicting character evidence and a scarcity of male specimens has historically made placement of the spider subfamily Penestominae Simon problematic. The Penestominae was recently removed from the family Eresidae and promoted to family rank based on the results of a molecular phylogenetic study; a complementary taxonomic revision of the Penestomidae is presented here. Penestomidae contains a single genus, &lt;i&gt;Penestomus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1902. The genus &lt;i&gt;Wajane&lt;/i&gt; Lehtinen, 1967 was previously included in the Penestominae, and distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Penestomus&lt;/i&gt; based on the lack of a cribellum. &lt;i&gt;Wajane&lt;/i&gt; is, in fact, cribellate, and is here synonymized with &lt;i&gt;Penestomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;New&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonymy.&lt;/b&gt; Nine &lt;i&gt;Penestomus&lt;/i&gt; species are recognized: four species are redescribed (P. &lt;i&gt;planus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1902, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croeseri&lt;/i&gt; Dippenaar-Schoeman, 1989, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stilleri&lt;/i&gt; (Dippenaar-Schoeman, 1989), &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; (Lehtinen, 1967)) &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;combination,&lt;/b&gt; and five species are newly described (P. &lt;i&gt;egazini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kruger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prendinii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zulu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; Male specimens are rare in collections; only &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;egazini,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; are known frommales, and only &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; is unknown from females. A dichotomous key to the species is provided. Data elements in this work have been disseminated across multiple electronic venues, including images on Morphbank, distribution data exposed through GBIF and explorable using Google Earth, new nomenclatural acts registered with ZooBank, and species pages on the Encyclopedia of Life. Where available, species descriptions include links to molecular sequence data on GenBank.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cribellum; cybertaxonomy; Eresidae; &lt;i&gt;Penestomus&lt;/i&gt;; South Africa; &lt;i&gt;Wajane&lt;/i&gt;; Zodariidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cribellum</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeremy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Griswold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Haddad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Petroleuciscus esfahani&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of fish from central Iran (Actinopterygii: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Petroleuciscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;esfahani,&lt;/i&gt; is described from central Iran in the Zayandeh River basin. It is distinguished from other members of the genus by a combination of characters including a mode of 8½ dorsal-fin branched rays, modally 10−11½ anal-fin branched rays, small scales numbering 44−54 in the total pored lateral line, a modal pharyngeal-tooth formula 2.5−4.2, and total vertebrae usually 40−42. It appears to be morphologically closest to &lt;i&gt;Petroleuciscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gaderanus&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1899) that we tentatively consider as a synonym of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulanus&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1899) of the Lake Orumiyeh basin in northwestern Iran.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Petroleuciscus&lt;/i&gt;; Cyprinidae; freshwater fish; new species; Iran</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Petroleuciscus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Brian</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nina</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bogutskaya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Peckoltia compta&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of catfish from the Brazilian Amazon, rio Tapajós basin (Siluriformes: Loricariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The loricariid genus &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; currently encompasses 13 valid species ranging throughout the Amazon basin in Brazil, Venezuela, Colombia, Peru, and Guyanas. &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; is included in the tribe Ancistrini, but its relationships with other taxa within the tribe are not well established. In this paper we describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; from the rio Tapajós drainage, Pará State, Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;compta,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is characterized by a bold color pattern consisting of large dark transversal bars on body and thick longitudinal dark stripes on snout and head. The new species is most similar in color pattern to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; but can be distinguished from all its congeners by the presence of a pale line inside each dark stripe running from the snout tip to anterior margin of eyes (vs. absence of such clear lines and a mottled appearance in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata,&lt;/i&gt; and a mix of vermiculations and spots on the head of the remaining congeners). A brief discussion on the taxonomic status of the nominal species &lt;i&gt;Peckoltia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; is also presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hypostominae; Ancistrini; armored catfishes; taxonomy; Jamanxim River</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hypostominae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renildo</firstname>
          <middlename>Ribeiro</middlename>
          <lastname>De Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jansen</firstname>
          <lastname>Zuanon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lucia</firstname>
          <middlename>Rapp</middlename>
          <lastname>Py-Daniel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>Salles</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A second specimen of &lt;i&gt;Manchurochelys manchoukuoensis &lt;/i&gt;Endo &amp; Shikama, 1942 (Testudines: Eucryptodira) from the Early Cretaceous Yixian Formation of western Liaoning, China </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Within the Early Cretaceous Jehol Biota of China, the turtle &lt;i&gt;Manchurochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; Endo &amp; Shikama, 1942 was one of the first discovered tetrapod fossils, but no additional information on this enigmatic taxon has become available during the past half century since its discovery. Here, a new turtle skeleton from the Yixian Formation of western Liaoning Province is identified as referable to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of an elongate oval shell, long and narrow second to fourth vertebral scutes, and two suprapygals, of which the second is much larger than the first. This specimen therefore represents the second specimen of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis,&lt;/i&gt; the holotype of which was probably lost during World War II. This discovery not only provides essential material that allows the validity of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; to be tested, but also substantially expands understanding of its bony anatomy, especially with regard to cranial morphology. Among other features, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by a postorbital that does not contact the quadrate/squamosal and a deep temporal emargination, which support a close relationship with &lt;i&gt;Sinemys&lt;/i&gt; spp. and distinguish it from the co-existing &lt;i&gt;Ordosemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liaoxiensis.&lt;/i&gt; A cladistic analysis that includes &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; further supports the hypothesis that Sinemydidae is a monophyletic group that includes &lt;i&gt;Sinemys&lt;/i&gt; spp. and &lt;i&gt;Dracochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicuspis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eucryptodira; Sinemydidae; &lt;i&gt;Manchurochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt;; Yixian Formation; western Liaoning; Jehol Biota</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eucryptodira</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chang-Fu</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Priority of &lt;i&gt;Geranoaetus &lt;/i&gt;Kaup, 1844 over &lt;i&gt;Tachytriorchis &lt;/i&gt;Kaup, 1844 (Aves: Accipitridae) based on the first reviser principle</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fábio</firstname>
          <middlename>Raposo Do</middlename>
          <lastname>Amaral</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frederick</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sheldon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anita</firstname>
          <lastname>Gamauf</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elisabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Haring</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Riesing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luís</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anita</firstname>
          <lastname>Wajntal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
