<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2536.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Jul. 2010</title>
    <volume>2536</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-07-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of four new species from the &lt;i&gt;Haploniscus unicornis &lt;/i&gt;Menzies, 1956 complex (Isopoda: Asellota: Haploniscidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on the adult males the four species &lt;i&gt;Haploniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bihastatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monoceros&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machairis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angolensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the deep sea of the Southeast Atlantic. These belong to a species complex, which also includes &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicornis&lt;/i&gt; Menzies from the Puerto Rico Trench and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aduncus&lt;/i&gt; Lincoln from the Iceland Basin and shares several characters with species from the genus &lt;i&gt;Mastigoniscus&lt;/i&gt; Lincoln. While males of the species complex can be reasonably well distinguished by their habitus and pleopods 1 and 2, the discrimination of female specimens is hampered by the pronounced sexual dimorphism. The &lt;i&gt;Haploniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicornis&lt;/i&gt; complex has a wide distribution in the Atlantic Ocean, but appears to be absent from basins south of the Walvis Ridge and also from the southwest Atlantic basins.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">species complex; sexual dimorphism; DIVA; Angola Basin; Guinea Basin; Walvis Ridge</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">species complex</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wiebke</firstname>
          <lastname>Brökeland</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Bryozoa from detritic bottoms in the Menorca Channel (Balearic Islands, western Mediterranean), with notes on the genus &lt;i&gt;Cribellopora&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Samples of Bryozoa were collected during an epibenthic sledge survey (Canal0209) of the Menorca Channel between Menorca and Mallorca in the Balearic Islands in 2009. Twenty-nine species were identified, including a new genus of Calloporidae (Barrosia) and a new species of &lt;i&gt;Fenestrulina,&lt;/i&gt; described herein. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Coronellina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fagei&lt;/i&gt; (Calescharidae). &lt;i&gt;Cribellopora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex,&lt;/i&gt; a species of Lacernidae generally considered to be a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cribellopora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trichotoma,&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed on the basis of the holotype and newly collected material.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cheilostomata; Calloporidae; new genus; &lt;i&gt;Barrosia&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Coronellina&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cribellopora&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Fenestrulina&lt;/i&gt;; Iberian Peninsula; Balearic Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cheilostomata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <lastname>Souto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Reverter-Gil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eugenio</firstname>
          <lastname>Fernández-Pulpeiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Squalius janae&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of fish from the Adriatic Sea basin in Slovenia (Actinopterygii: Cyprinidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Squalius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the upper Dragonja River system in the Adriatic Sea basin in Slovenia. The new species is distinguished from other members of the &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalus&lt;/i&gt; species group by a combination of the following characters: a long head, head length, 29−32% SL, always markedly exceeding body depth; a pointed conical snout; a slightly subterminal mouth, with a clearly projecting upper jaw; a long straight mouth cleft; lower-jaw length 39−45% HL, always greater than caudal-peduncle depth; a large eye, its diameter 19−25% HL; a large triangular 5 th infraorbital; a marked discontinuity between the dorsal profile of the head and body; usually 44−47 total lateral-line scales; usually 9½ branched anal-fin rays; usually 44 total vertebrae (24+20 and 25+19); a strong silvery tint in colouration; scales easily lost; iris, pectoral, pelvic and anal-fin pigmentation with yellow shades; flank scales margined by a few black pigment dots along their free margin and intense pigments on scale pockets, forming vertically elongate black spots.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Adriatic Sea basin; Slovenia; freshwater fishes; taxonomy; morphology; Cyprinidae; &lt;i&gt;Squalius&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Adriatic Sea basin</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nina</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bogutskaya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Primož</firstname>
          <lastname>Zupančič</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
