<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2551.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Jul. 2010</title>
    <volume>2551</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-07-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Patterns of morphological and genetic variation in western Indian Ocean members of the &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon &lt;/i&gt;‘&lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt;’ complex (Chiroptera: Molossidae), with the description of a new species from Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The species delimitations of African, Arabian Peninsula, and western Indian Ocean island members of the Molossidae bat species complex &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; remain largely unresolved. Based on genetic analyses this group is paraphyletic, with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucogaster&lt;/i&gt; nested within &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato, and the latter is composed of several distinct clades. DNA was isolated from a specimen of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; obtained at the type locality (Massawa, Eritrea). Although incomplete, this sequence allowed us to clearly define which clade is referable to nominate &lt;i&gt;pumilus,&lt;/i&gt; a critical step in resolving the systematics of this species complex. Using morphological and molecular genetic (cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and Dloop sequences) characters, we establish that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucogaster&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; ‘pumilus’ on Madagascar represent two different lineages and that the Malagasy population referred to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; ‘pumilus’ is specifically distinct from those on Africa, theArabian Peninsula, the Comoros Archipelago, and the western Seychelles (Aldabra). The Madagascar population is here described as a new species, &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atsinanana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; This taxon is common in the eastern portion of Madagascar, particularly in synanthropic settings, across an elevational range from near sea level to 1100 m, and there are no immediate conservation concerns. Members of the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; species complex from the western Seychelles are referable to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillus,&lt;/i&gt; to which populations from the Comoros (Mayotte, Anjouan, Mohéli, and Grande Comore) are also assigned.Les délimitations du complexe d’espèces &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus,&lt;/i&gt; membre des chauves-souris Molossidae de l’Afrique, de la Péninsule Arabique et de l’Océan Indien occidental, sont largement non résolues. D’après les données génétiques, ce groupe est paraphylétique, avec &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucogaster&lt;/i&gt; inclus dans &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato, ce dernier taxon étant composé de plusieurs clades distincts. L'ADN a été isolé à partir d'un spécimen de &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; obtenu dans la localité type (Massawa, en Erythrée). Bien qu’incomplète, la séquence obtenue nous a permis de définir clairement le clade de référence pour la nomination de &lt;i&gt;pumilus,&lt;/i&gt; une étape cruciale dans la résolution de la systématique de ce complexe d’espèces. L’utilisation des caractères morphologiques et moléculaire (séquences de cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; et de D-loop) nous a permis d’établir que &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leucogaster&lt;/i&gt; et &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; ‘pumilus’ à Madagascar correspondent à deux lignées différentes et que la population malgache désignée comme &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; ‘pumilus’ est spécifiquement distincte de celles de l'Afrique, de la péninsule arabique, de l'Archipel des Comores et des Seychelles occidentales (Aldabra). Nous nommons cette nouvelle espèce, &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atsinanana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Cette dernière est commune dans la partie orientale de Madagascar, en particulier comme espèce synanthropique, et présente une distribution altitudinale allant du niveau de la mer jusqu’à 1100 m d’altitude. A l’heure actuelle, l’espèce ne semble pas nécessiter une attention particulière en termes de conservation. Les membres du complexe &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pumilus&lt;/i&gt; des Seychelles occidentales sont désignés sous le nom de &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pusillus,&lt;/i&gt; ainsi que les populations des Comores (Mayotte, Anjouan, Mohéli et Grande Comore).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; morphology; molecular genetics; &lt;i&gt;Chaerephon&lt;/i&gt;; Madagascar; Africa; Comoros; Aldabra</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Goodman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Waheeda</firstname>
          <lastname>Buccas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Theshnie</firstname>
          <lastname>Naidoo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fanja</firstname>
          <lastname>Ratrimomanarivo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jennifer</firstname>
          <lastname>Lamb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The taxonomic research of Jules Richard on Cladocera (Crustacea: Branchiopoda) and his collection at the National Museum of Natural History, U.S.A.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Jules Richard (1863–1945) contributed significantly to cladoceran taxonomy before he became Director of the Musée Océanographique de Monaco and assistant to Prince Albert I-er de Monaco. His collection, including slides and samples preserved in ethanol, was purchased by E. A. Birge, subsequently incorporated into the collection of David G. Frey, and later gifted to the National Museum of Natural History, Smithsonian Institution. A list of publications of Richard about cladocerans is presented, as well a list of all new taxa described by him (three genera and 37 taxa of species rank), with information about type localities, synonymies and taxonomic comments. Lectotypes and in some cases paralectotypes are selected for &lt;i&gt;Daphnia&lt;/i&gt; (Ctenodaphnia) &lt;i&gt;bolivari&lt;/i&gt; Richard, 1888; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Daphnia)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvirostris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insulana&lt;/i&gt; Moniez in Richard, 1896; &lt;i&gt;Bosmina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Poppe &amp; Richard, 1890; &lt;i&gt;Grimaldina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brazzai&lt;/i&gt; Richard, 1892 and &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sarsi&lt;/i&gt; Richard, 1891. Syntypes exist for &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;moniezi&lt;/i&gt; Richard, 1888 and &lt;i&gt;Pleuroxus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;letourneuxi&lt;/i&gt; (Richard, 1888). The ethanol samples of Richard that may contain species for which there are no types are discussed. In addition, samples in the collection of David G. Frey from type localities of Richard’s species are noted. These samples could be important for future revisions of the Richard’s taxa. A redescription of &lt;i&gt;Pleuroxus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;letourneuxi&lt;/i&gt; (Chydoridae, Chydorinae) is given; &lt;i&gt;Bosmina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; Poppe &amp; Richard, 1890 (Bosminidae), a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longirostris&lt;/i&gt; (O. F. Müller, 1776), also is redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anomopoda; Ctenopoda; systematics; taxonomy; museum collections; lectotype</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anomopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexey</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kotov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ferrari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-64</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Papakula &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Hesydrimorpha&lt;/i&gt;: how two spider genera were described from the same species collected from the same locality (Araneae: Pisauridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Jäger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
