<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2557.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2557</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidocephalichthys &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cobitidae) with distinctive sexual dimorphism and comments on relationships in southern lineages of Cobitidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidocephalichthys&lt;/i&gt; (Telostei:Cobitidae) is diagnosed as being unique among cobitids in having the 7–8th pectoral rays of mature males modified. Recently collected material from Thailand included a new species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidocephalichthys&lt;/i&gt; in which mature males have a large (extending over ~75% of the fin-ray length) dorsally projecting and serrated flange and a ventrally projecting flange. The ventrally projecting structure is unique among cobitids. An expanded phylogenetic analysis of cobitids, including previously published sequences and new material including the new species, reinforces the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Lepidocephalichthys.&lt;/i&gt; Relationships within southern lineages of cobitids, and the unusual habitat of the new species are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cypriniformes; loaches; phylogenetics; dichromatism; Thailand; Vietnam; Mun River; Mekong</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cypriniformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Justin</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Havird</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawrence</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Page</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weerapongse</firstname>
          <lastname>Tangjitjaroen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chavalit</firstname>
          <lastname>Vidthayanon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chaiwut</firstname>
          <lastname>Grudpan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Suriya</firstname>
          <lastname>Udduang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Status and phylogeny of Milyeringidae (Teleostei: Gobiiformes), withhe description of a new blind cave-fish from Australia, &lt;i&gt;Milyeringa brooksi, &lt;/i&gt;n. sp.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A phylogeny of Milyeringidae is reported and a new species, &lt;i&gt;Milyeringa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brooksi,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Cape Range National Park in the North West Cape (Cape Range Peninsula) of Australia. This species is distinguished on the basis of morphological and molecular characters from its only congener &lt;i&gt;Milyeringa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;veritas.&lt;/i&gt; These diagnostic characters are related to a unique pattern of sensory papillae on the body and synapomorphies in three genes (cytochrome c oxidase I, cytochrome b, and NADH dehydrogenase 2). The new species is known only from the southern portion of the North West Cape spanning roughly 50 kilometers of subterranean habitat. This habitat is exceedingly rare and measures to preserve it and its fauna should be taken.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">blind; cave; stygobites; taxonomy; troglodytic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">blind</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Prosanta</firstname>
          <lastname>Chakrabarty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-28</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pollicipes caboverdensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Crustacea: Cirripedia: Scalpelliformes), an intertidal barnacle from the Cape Verde Islands</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recently, genetic evidence supported the existence of a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; from the Cape Verde Islands, previously considered a population of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pollicipes.&lt;/i&gt; However, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; was not sampled at its southern limit of distribution (Dakar, Senegal), which is geographically separated from the Cape Verde Islands by about 500 km. Herein we describe &lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caboverdensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Cape Verde Islands and compare its morphology with the other three species of &lt;i&gt;Pollicipes:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pollicipes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polymerus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; was sampled at both the middle (Portugal) and southern limit (Dakar, Senegal) of its geographical distribution. The genetic divergence among and within these two regions and Cape Verde was calculated through the analysis of partial mtDNA CO1 gene sequences. &lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caboverdensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has a single whorl of capitular plates below the subrostrum, peduncular scales pointing up toward the capitulum and multi-articulate caudal appendages (all characters shared with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pollicipes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans),&lt;/i&gt; reddish-orange capitular plates (large specimens), a single rostral median latus between the median latus and the rostrolatus (both characters shared with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans),&lt;/i&gt; and uniquely possesses peduncular scales that are approximately the same width as height. The genetic distance between the Cape Verde population and the Senegal and Portugal populations is 13–14%, whilst between Senegal and Portugal it is &lt; 1%.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt;; new species; morphology; DNA sequences; Cape Verde; Dakar</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pollicipes&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Joana</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Teresa</firstname>
          <lastname>Cruz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Syoc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nemacheilus marang&lt;/i&gt;, a new loach (Teleostei: Nemacheilidae) from Sangkulirang karst, eastern Borneo</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nemacheilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marang,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from Sungai Marang, Bengalon drainage, in the Sangkulirang peninsula karst formation, Borneo, Indonesia. It is distinguished from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Nemacheilus&lt;/i&gt; of Borneo among others by its unique colour pattern made of 10–18 dark brown bars on the flank, extending from the dorsal midline to just below the lateral line, continuous across back, not or only slightly wider on back and where crossing the midlateral stripe; and having the bars usually regular, straight, and of width less than half that of the interspaces.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Indonesia; Kalimantan; limestone; stone loach</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Indonesia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renny</firstname>
          <middlename>Kurnia</middlename>
          <lastname>Hadiaty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maurice</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The mud-shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Axianassa &lt;/i&gt;Schmitt, 1924 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Axianassidae) in the Indo-West Pacific, with description of a new species from French Polynesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the mud-shrimp genus &lt;i&gt;Axianassa&lt;/i&gt; Schmitt, 1924 is described based on four specimens collected in a muddy near-shore area inside the Moorea lagoon, Society Islands, French Polynesia. &lt;i&gt;Axianassa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ngochoae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; constitutes the first Indo-West Pacific record of this genus, previously known only from the western and eastern coasts of the Americas. A key to all species of &lt;i&gt;Axianassa&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Laomediidae; &lt;i&gt;Axianassa&lt;/i&gt;; new species; mud-shrimp; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Sipunculans and Echiurans of Isla del Coco (Cocos Island), Costa Rica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The sipunculan fauna of Isla del Coco was found to be quite diverse with eleven species reported. Several of the sipunculan species, as well as the echiuran &lt;i&gt;Thalassema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;steinbecki,&lt;/i&gt; have been encountered previously from Pacific Costa Rica. More surprising is the occurrence of several species of sipunculans not previously known from the eastern Pacific region such as &lt;i&gt;Siphonosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cumanense,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Phascolosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scolops,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Aspidosiphon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gosnoldi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;misakiensis,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Paraspidosiphon)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevis.&lt;/i&gt; Possible larval sources for those species previously unknown from this region are discussed. The identity of specimens previously identified as &lt;i&gt;Phascolosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;perlucens&lt;/i&gt; from Pacific Costa Rica are in question and are referred to as &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; sp. The presence of anastomosing longitudinal muscle bands as being characteristic of the genus &lt;i&gt;Siphonosoma&lt;/i&gt; is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sipuncula; Echiura; &lt;i&gt;Siphonosoma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Antillesoma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phascolosoma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aspidosiphon&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thalessema&lt;/i&gt;; Costa Rica; Eastern Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sipuncula</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Harlan</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dean</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sibaja–Cordero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jorge</firstname>
          <lastname>Cortés</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rita</firstname>
          <lastname>Vargas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gisele</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kawauchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
