<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2558.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2558</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A systematic review of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chasmodes &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Perciformes: Blenniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A systematic review of the Atlantic blenniid genus &lt;i&gt;Chasmodes&lt;/i&gt; was conducted. Principal components analysis (PCA) of 18 box-truss measurements revealed little variation in overall body shape among the three recognized &lt;i&gt;Chasmodes&lt;/i&gt; species. In contrast, PCA of six more standard ichthyological measurements and the number of segmented dorsal-fin rays showed significant differences among the three. The species-level classification presented herein agrees with nomenclature in recently published works. Cladistic analysis of partial 12S rRNA gene sequences indicates &lt;i&gt;Chasmodes&lt;/i&gt; is sister to a lineage comprising &lt;i&gt;Hypleurochilus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scartella,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Hypsoblennius.&lt;/i&gt; Based on our conclusions about phylogenetic relationships, we infer that sea-level fluctuations were likely associated with speciation in &lt;i&gt;Chasmodes.&lt;/i&gt; Remarks on the critical habitats of these blennies are given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">morphometric analysis; taxonomy; Blennioidei; mtDNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">morphometric analysis</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Javonillo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antony</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Harold</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The new and the old: littoral tanaidomorph Tanaidacea (Crustacea: Peracarida) from the Andaman Islands, Indian Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent collections of tanaidaceans from intertidal macroalgae on the shores of the Andaman Islands have revealed both new taxa to science and new material of a species which had previously been inadequately described. The present paper gives a redescription of the leptocheliid &lt;i&gt;Konarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassicornis,&lt;/i&gt; discussing its close similarity to the generotype, &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cheirus,&lt;/i&gt; and describes two new species, one of the tanaid genus &lt;i&gt;Zeuxo,&lt;/i&gt; showing similarities to &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Parazeuxo)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kurilensis&lt;/i&gt; and representing the first anatanaid to be recorded from the region, and one paratanaid of a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Triparatanais,&lt;/i&gt; distinguished from other paratanaids in having only three longer articles in the antennule.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Andaman Sea; Bay of Bengal; &lt;i&gt;Konarus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Triparatanais&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zeuxo&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>N</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tapas</firstname>
          <lastname>Chatterjee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zerconella &lt;/i&gt;Willmann, 1953, a forgotten group of Zerconidae (Acari: Mesostigmata)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A short review of the characters used for generic determination in the family Zerconidae is presented. The subgenus &lt;i&gt;Zercon&lt;/i&gt; (Zerconella) Willmann, 1953 is elevated to full generic rank on the basis of the shape of peritreme, peritrematal setae, and epistome, and the presence of post-genital sclerites. The genus &lt;i&gt;Metazercon&lt;/i&gt; Błaszak, 1975 is considered to be a subgenus of &lt;i&gt;Zerconella,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; is divided into the subgenera &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Zerconella) and &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Metazercon). The following new combinations are listed: &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Metazercon) &lt;i&gt;athiasae&lt;/i&gt; (Błaszak, 1975) comb. nov., &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Metazercon) &lt;i&gt;mahunkai&lt;/i&gt; (Halašková, 1979) comb. nov., &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Metazercon) &lt;i&gt;rafalskii&lt;/i&gt; (Błaszak, Kaczmarek &amp; Lee, 1997) comb. nov. A new species, &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; (Metazercon) &lt;i&gt;lobata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from alpine broad-leaved forests in Taiwan. Diagnoses, figures and a key to species of &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt; are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Zerconidae; &lt;i&gt;Zerconella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Metazercon&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Zerconidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zsolt</firstname>
          <lastname>Ujvári</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New insights on the genus &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides &lt;/i&gt;Bagnall 1913 (Scutigerellidae, Symphyla) with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The study of two new species of Symphyla from the Democratic Republic of the Congo, &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;congolensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudocongolensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.sp.,&lt;/b&gt; has led to the detection of &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; Bagnall 1913 species currently misplaced under &lt;i&gt;Hanseniella&lt;/i&gt; Bagnall 1913. Accordingly, it is proposed a new combination for six species originally described under &lt;i&gt;Hanseniella:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angulosa&lt;/i&gt; (Hansen 1903), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenella&lt;/i&gt; (Ribaut 1914), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;producta&lt;/i&gt; (Ribaut 1914), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolosa&lt;/i&gt; (Ribaut 1914), &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graeca&lt;/i&gt; (Remy 1941) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elgolensis&lt;/i&gt; (Scheller 1952). An identification key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; is given. A differential diagnostic for differencing &lt;i&gt;Scolopendrelloides&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Hanseniella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Scutigerella&lt;/i&gt; is also given, as well as a key to the genera of the family Scutigerellidae, mainly intended for observations using SEM.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hanseniella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;congolensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;pseudocongolensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;angulosa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;tenella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;producta&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;dolosa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;graeca&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;elgolensis&lt;/i&gt;; Democratic Republic of the Congo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hanseniella&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>Domínguez</middlename>
          <lastname>Camacho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudolaguvia spicula&lt;/i&gt;, a new sisorid catfish (Teleostei: Sisoridae) from Bangladesh and northeastern India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study describes &lt;i&gt;Pseudolaguvia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spicula,&lt;/i&gt; a new miniature sisorid catfish from the Surma-Meghna River system in India and Bangladesh. &lt;i&gt;Pseudolaguvia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spicula&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from congeners in having a combination of: head width 19.2–22.6% SL, dorsal-fin spine length 11.6–14.3% SL, length of dorsal-fin base 13.2–15.9% SL, pectoral-fin spine length 15.7–17.4% SL, length of adipose-fin base 14.7–17.1% SL, pelvic-fin length 14.6–17.1% SL, body depth at anus 12.8–16.8% SL, caudal peduncle length 15.4–17.9% SL, caudal peduncle depth 7.9–9.6% SL, caudal-fin length 24.2–27.5% SL, snout length 48.6–51.9% HL, eye diameter 10.6–13.9% HL, 30–32 vertebrae, smooth anterior edge of dorsal-fin spine, thoracic adhesive apparatus reaching beyond base of last pectoral-fin ray, absence of pale y-shaped marking on dorsal surface of head and supraoccipital process, and indistinct, pale vertical bands on body.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Siluriformes; Sisoroidea; Mizoram; Barak River; Surma-Meghna River system</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Siluriformes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heok</firstname>
          <middlename>Hee</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lalramliana</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-04</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
