<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2570.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2570</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Additional shallow-water thecate hydroids (Cnidaria: Hydrozoa) from Guadeloupe and Les Saintes, French Lesser Antilles</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This report supplements an earlier account on the hydroids of the Guadeloupe archipelago, and records 31 additional species of thecates. Among them, &lt;i&gt;Halecium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;calderi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Antennella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Antennella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described. &lt;i&gt;Laomedea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tottoni&lt;/i&gt; Leloup, 1935 is redescribed and reassigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Clytia&lt;/i&gt; Lamouroux, 1812. Its synonymy is broadened upon inclusion of &lt;i&gt;Clytia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laxa&lt;/i&gt; Fraser, 1937. &lt;i&gt;Hebella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venusta&lt;/i&gt; (Allman, 1877) is considered valid based on comparison with related species, and its gonotheca is described for the first time. Two sympatric varieties of &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diaphana&lt;/i&gt; (Allman, 1885), easily separable morphologically and by their cnidome composition, are discussed. &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ornata&lt;/i&gt; Fraser, 1937 is recorded for the second time and is fully redescribed. Its name is actually a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fusiformis&lt;/i&gt; (Hincks, 1861) f. &lt;i&gt;ornata&lt;/i&gt; Broch, 1933, and it is here referred to as &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fraseri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thecocarpa&lt;/i&gt; Jarvis, 1922, &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuscula&lt;/i&gt; Billard, 1924, &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parvula&lt;/i&gt; Mammen, 1965, and &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stechowi&lt;/i&gt; Hirohito, 1995 are placed in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Sertularella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongensis&lt;/i&gt; Stechow, 1919, the latter being transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758. &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ephemera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed as a replacement name for &lt;i&gt;Sertularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongensis&lt;/i&gt; Stechow, 1919. &lt;i&gt;Aglaophenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;postdentata&lt;/i&gt; Billard, 1913 is confidently recorded from the Atlantic for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Dentitheca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dendritica&lt;/i&gt; (Nutting, 1900) is redescribed, and additional notes on &lt;i&gt;Macrorhynchia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clarkei&lt;/i&gt; (Nutting, 1900) are provided. All the species discussed herein are new records for the study area. Illustrations are given for each species and data on the nematocyst complement and size of capsules are given when necessary. The number of hydroid species reported from the study area is raised to more than eighty. Hydroids of the Caribbean are moderately well known faunistically, though continuous discovery of new species is likely, the species composition being certainly richer than currently reported.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Hydrozoa; Caribbean Sea; tropical western Atlantic; reef environment</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Horia</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Galea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus dumnuii &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae), a new cave-dwelling gecko from Chiang Mai Province, Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new cave-dwelling species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; is described from Chiang Mai Province in northern Thailand. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumnuii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; may be distinguished from all other congeners by the possession of a series of enlarged femoral scales, disjunct precloacal and femoral pores in males (minute precloacal pores variably present in females), a relatively high number (18–22) of closely spaced, regularly arranged dorsal tubercle rows, well-defined non-denticulate ventrolateral folds, transversely enlarged subcaudal plates, and a color pattern of approximately six pairs of alternating light and dark transverse bands on the trunk. It is the nineteenth member of the genus recorded from Thailand and the eighth Thai &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; known to be a facultative troglophile.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Thailand; Chiang Mai; Reptilia; Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dumnuii&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; cave-dwelling</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Thailand</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kirati</firstname>
          <lastname>Kunya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Montri</firstname>
          <lastname>Sumontha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Piyawan</firstname>
          <lastname>Niyomwan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olivier</firstname>
          <middlename>S. G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pauwels</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lawan</firstname>
          <lastname>Chanhome</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tunyakorn</firstname>
          <lastname>Kunya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-18</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The species of &lt;i&gt;Notonyx &lt;/i&gt;A. Milne-Edwards, 1873, from Lesser Sunda and Maluku Islands, Indonesia, with description of a new species (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Goneplacidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four species of &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1873, are reported from the Lesser Sunda and Muluku islands in Indonesia. &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castroi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterised by its distinctive male first gonopod, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigacarcinicus&lt;/i&gt; Clark &amp; Ng, 2006, originally described from western Thailand, is recorded only for the second time, while Banda and Seram are new Indonesian localities for &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kumi&lt;/i&gt; Naruse &amp; Maenosono, 2009. Taxonomic notes are given for the recently described &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guinotae&lt;/i&gt; Rahayu &amp; Ng, 2010, from Lombok.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Brachyura; Goneplacidae; &lt;i&gt;Notonyx&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new records; Indonesia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dwi</firstname>
          <middlename>Listyo</middlename>
          <lastname>Rahayu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Solenotheres prolixus&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and new species of pinnotherid crab (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura) associated with the razor clam, &lt;i&gt;Solen corneus &lt;/i&gt;Lamarck, 1818 (Solenidae) in Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of pinnotherid crab, &lt;i&gt;Solenotheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prolixus,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the razor clam, &lt;i&gt;Solen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corneus&lt;/i&gt; (Solenidae), in Vietnam. The new genus is characterised by its broad and subquadrate carapace, a spatuliform third maxilliped dactylus that is inserted near the base of the propodus, and asymmetrical third ambulatory legs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Crustacea; Brachyura; Pinnotheridae; new genus; new species; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
