<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2577.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2577</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New fossil mussels (Bivalvia: Mytilidae) from Miocene hydrocarbon seep deposits, North Island, New Zealand, with general remarks on vent and seep mussels</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus&lt;/i&gt; (sensu &lt;i&gt;lato)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heretaunga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Gigantidas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coseli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from Miocene-age hydrocarbon seep carbonates of North Island, New Zealand, adding to only four described fossil hydrocarbon seep mussel species. Both new species are small compared to their modern congeners, and it is suggested that an evolutionary trend toward gigantism occurred in vent and seep mussels since the first known fossil species of the group appeared in the Middle Eocene. &lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heretaunga&lt;/i&gt; is highly variable in morphology, potentially reflecting population variation over a wide geographic area. &lt;i&gt;Gigantidas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coseli&lt;/i&gt; is the first named species, fossil or modern, of its genus known from hydrocarbon seeps, although several closely related species in the same group, the &lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;childressi&lt;/i&gt; clade, have been reported from these environments.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus;&lt;/i&gt; cold seep; Bathymodiolinae; &lt;i&gt;Gigantidas;&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus;&lt;/i&gt; cold seep; Bathymodiolinae; &lt;i&gt;Gigantidas;&lt;/i&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kristian</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Saether</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Crispin</firstname>
          <middlename>T. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Little</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kathleen</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campbell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bruce</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marshall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mike</firstname>
          <lastname>Collins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alfaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of dactyloid anole (SQUAMATA: IGUANIDAE) from the western Andes of Ecuador</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; from the western slopes of the Andes in Ecuador, Provincias Cotopaxi and Pichincha. The new species fits into (1) the &lt;i&gt;aequatorialis&lt;/i&gt; species group by being of moderate to large size with narrow toe lamellae and (2) the &lt;i&gt;eulaemus&lt;/i&gt; subgroup by having a typical &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; digit, in which the distal lamellae of phalanx II distinctly overlap the proximal scales of phalanx I. The new species is most similar to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus&lt;/i&gt; O’Shaughnessy but differs from it by features like the presence of a dark coppery brown stripe on the sides of the head (stripe absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus),&lt;/i&gt; females with dark brown dorsal chevrons extending to the flanks (chevrons absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus),&lt;/i&gt; male dewlap white with green scales (male dewlap greenish-yellow with green scales in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus),&lt;/i&gt; dewlap with wide scale rows of three to six scales per row (narrow scale rows of 2−3 scales per row in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus),&lt;/i&gt; and interparietal scale (if present) surrounded by relatively enlarged flat scales (interparietal surrounded by small swollen scales in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gemmosus).&lt;/i&gt; These two species occur in sympatry in the Reserva de Bosque Integral Otonga, Provincia Cotopaxi, Ecuador.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes of Ecuador; &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt;; lizards; morphology; Otonga; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes of Ecuador</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ayala-Varela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julián</firstname>
          <middlename>Andrés</middlename>
          <lastname>Velasco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia &lt;/i&gt;from the rio Amazonas and rio Orinoco basins (Characiformes: Characidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia&lt;/i&gt; is described from the rio Amazonas and rio Orinoco basins. The new species can be distinguished from congeners mainly by the combination of a conspicuous, relatively small and circular humeral spot, a black spot on the upper caudal-fin lobe, lower caudal-fin lobe without spot or a faint one, and middle caudal-fin rays hyaline or with dark tips. Mature males have a unique combination of two large-sized bony hooks on the anal-fin rays and tiny spines on the distal portion of all fins, which distinguishes the new species from any other species of Characidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Systematics; &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidura&lt;/i&gt; species-group; bony hooks</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Manoela</firstname>
          <middlename>M. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Langeani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
