<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2578.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2578</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New spider mite genus (Prostigmata: Tetranychidae) from Australia &amp; New Zealand, with a discussion of &lt;i&gt;Yezonychus &lt;/i&gt;Ehara</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The concept of &lt;i&gt;Yezonychus&lt;/i&gt; Ehara is revised. A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Neonidulus,&lt;/i&gt; is erected to accommodate four species: &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cornus&lt;/i&gt; (Pritchard &amp; Baker), &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falsicornus&lt;/i&gt; (Zhang &amp; Martin) and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevipilus&lt;/i&gt; (Zhang &amp; Martin) from New Zealand, and a new species described from the central east coast of Australia, &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tereotus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rigiotetranychus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Schizotetranychus&lt;/i&gt;; split empodia; &lt;i&gt;Stigmaeopsis&lt;/i&gt;; Tetranychini; &lt;i&gt;Tribolonychus&lt;/i&gt;; web nest; &lt;i&gt;Yunonyhcus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Rigiotetranychus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jennifer</firstname>
          <lastname>Beard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>Evans</middlename>
          <lastname>Walter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Saltipedis &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Spinosaltipedis&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;puertoricensis&lt;/i&gt;, a new subgenus and species of apseudomorphan (Crustacea: Tanaidacea: Parapseudidae) from coastal waters off Culebra Island, Puerto Rico, with keys and taxonomic observations</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt; (Spinosaltipedis) &lt;i&gt;puertoricensis,&lt;/i&gt; n. subgen, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from eastern Puerto Rico off Culebra Island at a depth of 28 m. The new species is the fourth representative of the genus &lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt; Guţu to be described from the western Atlantic. The new subgenus is distinguished from the currently recognized members of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt; Guţu by the presence of strongly developed accessory setae on the mandible between the base of the palp and the molar process. A combination of other characters that further distinguish &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puertoricensis&lt;/i&gt; from its congeners includes: (1) rostrum having an acute tip and with lateral margins convex; (2) absence of epistomal spine; (3) setation patterns on the first pereopod, inner margin of uropodal basal article, and the pleotelson; and (4) male chela having a distinct tooth on both the fixed and movable fingers. Pending further systematic study, &lt;i&gt;Longipedis&lt;/i&gt; Larsen and Shimomura is resurrected to full generic status. Keys for the separation of the females and known males of &lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt; are presented. Some of the taxonomic problems defining the genus &lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt; and related genera are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tanaidacea; Parapseudidae; &lt;i&gt;Saltipedis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; new subgenus; Caribbean; Puerto Rico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tanaidacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrés</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Morales-Núñez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mónica</firstname>
          <lastname>Alfaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Pygopus &lt;/i&gt;(Pygopodidae; Gekkota; Squamata) from north-eastern Queensland</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on a combination of morphological and genetic data, geographically isolated populations of &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; from northeastern Queensland, formerly referred to &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidopodus&lt;/i&gt; (Lacépède), are herein described as a new species. &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robertsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be diagnosed from its congeners by a suite of scalation characters, including fewer keeled dorsal scales, presence of a single continuous row of supracilaries and a lower number of midbody scale rows. It is also deeply divergent genetically from samples of &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidopodus&lt;/i&gt; from southern Australia. The known distribution of &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;robertsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is similar to that of a number of taxa centred upon relatively dry ecotonal habitats at the western edge of the rainforest blocks of north-eastern Queensland. Additional samples and systematic work will be required to examine the evolutionary divergence of apparently isolated populations of the new species, and the significance of considerable genetic and morphological diversity within remaining populations of &lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidopodus&lt;/i&gt; from south-eastern and southern Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidopodus&lt;/i&gt;; wet tropics; Burdekin Gap; Laura Gap</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pygopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepidopodus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oliver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <lastname>Couper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Amey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-61</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Cydrela &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae, Zodariidae) extending the distribution of the genus into Central Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Cydrela&lt;/i&gt; Thorell (Zodariidae) are described from Burundi: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neptuna&lt;/i&gt; (%&amp;) from miombo woodland and circumguinean forest and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kreagra&lt;/i&gt; (%) from a seminatural area, both at medium altitude. Both species of &lt;i&gt;Cydrela&lt;/i&gt; mentioned from Central Africa previously belong to other genera resulting in the new combinations &lt;i&gt;Systenoplacis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;biunguis&lt;/i&gt; (Strand, 1913) and &lt;i&gt;Capheris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunnea&lt;/i&gt; (Marx, 1893). The find of &lt;i&gt;Cydrela&lt;/i&gt; in Burundi expands the known distribution of the genus considerably.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachystegia&lt;/i&gt; woodland; circumguinean forest; miombo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Brachystegia&lt;/i&gt; woodland</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>B.</firstname>
          <lastname>Nzigidahera</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocqué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-27</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
