<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2579.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2579</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the &lt;i&gt;rugulosus &lt;/i&gt;group of &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus &lt;/i&gt;subgenus &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus &lt;/i&gt;Porat, 1876 (Chilopoda: Scolopendromorpha: Scolopendridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">To facilitate a revision of &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt; (Otostigmus) which currently comprises 61 species, the subgenus is here subdivided into nine species groups based on Attems’ (1930a) monograph. The largest, the &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; group, is the subject of this paper. In most cases, the type material is redescribed and variation discussed. The following species are valid: &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; Porat, 1876, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosus&lt;/i&gt; Porat, 1876, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;astenus&lt;/i&gt; (Kohlrausch, 1881), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiventer&lt;/i&gt; (Tömösváry, 1885) (lectotype designated), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;olivaceus&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1934, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;noduliger&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1937 (lectotype designated), &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angusticeps&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schindleri&lt;/i&gt; Würmli, 1972, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martensi&lt;/i&gt; Lewis, 1992, and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beroni&lt;/i&gt; Lewis, 2001. &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;feae&lt;/i&gt; Pocock, 1891, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fossuliger&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1937 and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striaturatus&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1937 are retained as valid but more data are required to establish their true status. Reasons for previous confusion between &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scaber&lt;/i&gt; Porat, 1876 are discussed as are reasons for specimens of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;astenus&lt;/i&gt; being identified as &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiventer&lt;/i&gt; and some &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;punctiventer&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosus.&lt;/i&gt; A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1958 which is a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multidens&lt;/i&gt; Haase, 1887. &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;owenii&lt;/i&gt; Pocock, 1892, is a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lewisi&lt;/i&gt; Song &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 2005 a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beroni.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rugulosus&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;mertoni&lt;/i&gt; Ribaut, 1912, &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celebensis&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1934, and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dammermani&lt;/i&gt; Chamberlin, 1944, are nomina dubia. A key to the species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;groups&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(Otostigmus)&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;species&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;groups&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;of&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Otostigmus&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(Otostigmus)&lt;/b&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>G. E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lewis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mitochondrial DNA and morphometrical identification of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Hylomyscus &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia: Muridae) from West Africa </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper we describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Hylomyscus&lt;/i&gt; based on molecular (Cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and 16S rDNA gene sequencing) and morphometrical analyses. This new species occurs in Benin and Nigeria, and probably also in Togo. It differs by 8.29 to 10.40 % of sequence divergence (K2P distance for the Cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene) from all other species of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alleni&lt;/i&gt; species complex, and can be distinguished from these species through morphometrical multivariate analyses. It differs significantly from its closest relative, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simus,&lt;/i&gt; by four external and nine cranio-dental measurements. The role of rivers and Pleistocene forest refugia in the diversification of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alleni&lt;/i&gt; species complex is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">16S rDNA; Benin; Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; Nigeria; sibling species; taxonomy; traditional morphometrics; tropical African forests; woodmice</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">16S rDNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Violaine</firstname>
          <lastname>Nicolas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ayodejii</firstname>
          <lastname>Olayemi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wim</firstname>
          <lastname>Wendelen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marc</firstname>
          <lastname>Colyn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>30-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval development of the shrimp &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte sapphica &lt;/i&gt;d’Udekem d’Acoz, 1993 forma A and B (Decapoda: Caridea: Hippolytidae) reared in the laboratory, confirmation of the conspecific status of the two forms</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The complete series of larval staging of &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sapphica&lt;/i&gt; d’Udekem d’Acoz, 1993 forma A and B from Louros estuary was studied in the laboratory and described in detail for the first time. The reared larvae of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sapphica&lt;/i&gt; passed through six zoeal stages and one megalopal stage. The larval monitoring completed when the individuals could be assigned clearly to form A and B &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; rostra formation. Under the experimental conditions, the average durations of the larval stages were as follows: three days for 1 st and 2 nd stages, three to four days for 3 rd , 4 th , 5 th and 6 th stages, four days for the megalopal stage and 19 to 30 days for immature form A and B individuals. Comparison of the larval morphological characters among the described material and the bibliographic data of closely related species was made and discussed. The offspring of females of the forma A includes forma A and B and the same can be said of the offspring of the forma B. This confirms that the formae A and B are indeed conspecific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Hippolyte; shrimp; Decapoda; larval development; Greece</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Hippolyte</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandros</firstname>
          <lastname>Ntakis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chryssa</firstname>
          <lastname>Anastasiadou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roman</firstname>
          <lastname>Liasko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ioannis</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leonardos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphology of the Gas Bladder in Sea Catfishes (Siluriformes: Ariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology of the gas bladder and associated structures in sea catfishes (Siluriformes: Ariidae) is studied. The most simple gas bladder, exclusive to &lt;i&gt;Galeichthys&lt;/i&gt; Valenciennes, is apple-shaped with weakly developed internal trabeculae, has smooth walls externally and a short Müllerian window associated with a broad, short Müllerian ramus that is firmly attached to Baudelot’s ligament and supracleithrum. Most genera of Ariidae have a cordiform bladder with welldeveloped trabeculae, smooth walls externally, an elongate Müllerian window and an elongate Müllerian ramus with an acute tip that is free from the Baudelot’s ligament and supracleithrum. &lt;i&gt;Sciades&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proops&lt;/i&gt; (Valenciennes) and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parkeri&lt;/i&gt; (Traill) have a similar gas bladder but with a well-developed secondary chamber. Other genera of Ariidae also have a cordiform bladder with well-developed trabeculae and elongate Müllerian window, but with lateral diverticula present as shallow rounded bulges or blister-like swellings along the peripheral margins of the bladder. The degree of development of lateral diverticula varies among and within species, with &lt;i&gt;Osteogeneiosus&lt;/i&gt; Bleeker having the most highly-developed diverticula. &lt;i&gt;Bagre&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinnimaculatus&lt;/i&gt; (Steindachner) and &lt;i&gt;Bagre&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bagre&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus) have unusual depressed gas bladders with complex network of internal trabeculae. The implications of gas bladder morphology for the taxonomy and phylogenetic relationships of the family are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">systematics; phylogeny; taxonomy; anatomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">systematics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marceniuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>L. O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Birindelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
