<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2585.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2585</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the European genera of Eviphididae (Acari: Mesostigmata) and the species occurring in Slovakia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The study presents a review of the European fauna of Eviphididae (Acari: Mesostigmata), based on over 4,000 specimens, including type specimens in the Berlese Acaroteca, Florence. The European fauna is shown to include 29 species in 16 genera. These genera are reviewed, and a key provided for their identification. The fauna of Slovakia includes 14 genera and 19 species. These species are reviewed, and keys are provided for their identification. The European fauna includes the genera &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; Halbert 1923, &lt;i&gt;Alloseius&lt;/i&gt; Mašán &amp; Halliday 2009a, &lt;i&gt;Copriphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1910, &lt;i&gt;Crassicheles&lt;/i&gt; Karg 1963, &lt;i&gt;Evimirus&lt;/i&gt; Karg 1963, &lt;i&gt;Eviphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903, &lt;i&gt;Halolaspis&lt;/i&gt; Mašán &amp; Halliday 2009a, &lt;i&gt;Neocrassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pelethiphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1911, &lt;i&gt;Pseudoalliphis&lt;/i&gt; Mašán &amp; Halliday 2009a, &lt;i&gt;Rafaphis&lt;/i&gt; Skorupski &amp; Błaszak 1997, &lt;i&gt;Scamaphis&lt;/i&gt; Karg 1976, &lt;i&gt;Scarabacariphis&lt;/i&gt; Mašán 1994a, &lt;i&gt;Scarabaspis&lt;/i&gt; Womersley 1956, &lt;i&gt;Thinoseius&lt;/i&gt; Halbert 1920 and &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903. All of these genera except &lt;i&gt;Evimirus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Thinoseius&lt;/i&gt; occur in Slovakia. The genus &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903, with type species &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabratus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903 (= &lt;i&gt;Eviphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holsaticus&lt;/i&gt; Willmann 1937), is considered to be a valid genus, and is removed from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Eviphis.&lt;/i&gt; The new taxa described here are &lt;i&gt;Neocrassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; with type species &lt;i&gt;Neocrassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sternomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montivagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The previously unknown adult female of &lt;i&gt;Crassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striatus&lt;/i&gt; (Berlese 1903) and male of &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabratus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903 are described for the first time. The following new synonymies are proposed: &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevisternalis&lt;/i&gt; Ma &amp; Wang 1998 and &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yinchuanensis&lt;/i&gt; Gu &amp; Bai 1997 are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;necrophilus&lt;/i&gt; Christie 1983; &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirschmanni&lt;/i&gt; Arutunian 1991 is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scarabaeorum&lt;/i&gt; Ogandzhanyan 1969; &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montanus&lt;/i&gt; Koroleva 1968, &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rotundianalis&lt;/i&gt; Mašán 1994a and &lt;i&gt;Scarabaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;altaicus&lt;/i&gt; Sklyar 1999 are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Alloseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pratensis&lt;/i&gt; (Karg 1965); &lt;i&gt;Hypoaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evansi&lt;/i&gt; Arutunian 1993 is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Scamaphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;equestris&lt;/i&gt; (Berlese 1911); &lt;i&gt;Iphidoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;concentricus&lt;/i&gt; Oudemans 1904 is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striatus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903; &lt;i&gt;Eviphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;holsaticus&lt;/i&gt; Willmann 1937 and &lt;i&gt;Iphidosoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bennwili&lt;/i&gt; Schweizer 1961 are synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabratus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903; &lt;i&gt;Scarabacariphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandisternalis&lt;/i&gt; Mašán 1994a is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Scarabacariphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ankavani&lt;/i&gt; (Arutunian 1992); &lt;i&gt;Bactriphis&lt;/i&gt; Athias-Henriot 1980 is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; Berlese 1903. The male and deutonymphal paratypes of &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stenosternus&lt;/i&gt; Gu &amp; Liu 1996 are misidentified specimens of &lt;i&gt;Alloseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pratensis&lt;/i&gt; (Karg 1965). One genus and three species are reported from Slovakia for the first time: &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kargi&lt;/i&gt; Arutunian 1991, &lt;i&gt;Rafaphis&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Rafaphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microsternalis&lt;/i&gt; Skorupski &amp; Błaszak 1997, and &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;greeni&lt;/i&gt; (Evans 1980). &lt;i&gt;Alliphis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; are represented in Slovakia by several species each; all other genera in Slovakia are represented by single species. The external morphology and ecology of the European genera and Slovakian species are reviewed. Most of the species are coprophilous and associated with coprophilous insects; a complete list of their phoretic associations is given. The eviphidid species occurring in Slovakia can be classified into three general ecological groups and five subgroups: (A) edaphic detriticoles, with four species; (B) saprophilous detriticoles, with five species, subdivided into (B1) non-specialised coprophiles, with one species, and (B2) specialised coprophiles, with four species; (C) insecticoles, with nine species, subdivided into (C1) non-specialised insecticoles, with three species, and (C2) specialised insecticoles, with six species. &lt;i&gt;Uroiphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montivagus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is not classified ecologically because it is only known from two specimens. Some species that occur in very fresh wet dung or very humid habitats (Alloseius &lt;i&gt;pratensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Crassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;striatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Neocrassicheles&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sternomus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; have a specific morphological adaptation consisting of elongate pointed lateral lobes on pulvilli II–IV in the non-phoretic female. An elongation of some components of the pulvillus also occurs in some strongly hygrophilous Blattisociidae, and the modified pulvillus appears to facilitate the mite's movement in semiaquatic substrates.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Mesostigmata; Eviphididae; taxonomy; dung beetle; Scarabaeidae; phoresy; Slovakia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Mašán</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bruce</firstname>
          <lastname>Halliday</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-122</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
