<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2611.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2611</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A diploid surrounded by polyploids: tadpole description, natural history and cytogenetics of &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus maisuma &lt;/i&gt;Rosset from Uruguay (Anura: Cycloramphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maisuma&lt;/i&gt; is a recently described diploid species of the diploid-tetraploid &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;americanus&lt;/i&gt; complex. It inhabits coastal regions of Uruguay and southern Brazil. Tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maisuma&lt;/i&gt; at stages 33–36 are about 47 mm of total length, and similarly to that of other &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt; are typical pond dwelling anuran larvae; the oral disc is small and laterally emarginated, bearing a single row of marginal papillae interrupted by a large dorsal gap. The labial tooth row formula is 2(2)/3(1); sometimes A2 and P1 are not divided. The advertisement call consists of notes that last 570– 785 ms, composed of 43–57 pulses, and with a dominant frequency between 1124–1211 Hz. The chromosome complement is composed by 11 biarmed chromosome pairs (2n = 2x = 22; NF = 44), with evident positive C-bands in the centromeric regions of all chromosome pairs, in the short arms of pairs 2 and 4, and in the long arms of pair 6 and 9. Nucleolar Organizer Regions (Ag-NORs) are located interstitially in the short arms of both chromosomes of pair 4. Preliminary data suggests that erythrocyte morphology could be used to discriminate between diploid and tetraploid tadpoles of &lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt;; tadpole; advertisement call; Ag-NORs; C-banding; erythrocyte measurements</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Odontophrynus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Borteiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolenc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martín</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pereyra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <lastname>Rosset</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Baldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-15</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new family of trombidioid mites (Acari: Prostigmata) from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Achaemenothrombium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyrusi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari, Prostigmata: Trombidioidea) is described and illustrated from larvae ectoparasitic on &lt;i&gt;Catocala&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) from Tehran, Iran and &lt;i&gt;Achaemenothrombium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;talebii&lt;/i&gt; (Karimi Irvanlou &amp; Kamali, 2001) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is redescribed. A new family, Achaemenothrombiidae is proposed for accommodating this genus. A key to families of larval Trombidioidea and to species of &lt;i&gt;Achaemenothrombium&lt;/i&gt; (larva) is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Parasitengona; new species; new genus; new combination; &lt;i&gt;Catocala&lt;/i&gt; sp.; Noctuidae; larva; ectoparasite; key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Parasitengona</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alireza</firstname>
          <lastname>Saboori</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Wohltmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masoud</firstname>
          <lastname>Hakimitabar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>16-30</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Chironius &lt;/i&gt;Fitzinger, 1826 (Squamata: Colubridae) from the Pantepui region, northeastern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new colubrid snake of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chironius&lt;/i&gt; Fitzinger, 1826 is described from the Pantepui region, Guiana Shield, northern South America. The new species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;challenger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is identified as a member of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chironius&lt;/i&gt; by its low number of dorsal scale rows (&lt; 12), and it differs markedly from all known congeners by the combination of 10 dorsal scale rows at midbody, absence of apical pits and paravertebral keels in females, more than 149 ventrals, less than 105 divided subcaudals, anal scale single, loreal as high as long or only slightly longer than high, adults and juveniles brownish with lighter crossbands, adults with dark mottling on venter, and 39–41 maxillary teeth. A key to the &lt;i&gt;Chironius&lt;/i&gt; species of the Guiana Shield is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auyantepui; Guaiquinima Tepui; Guiana Shield; Guyana; Maringma Tepui; Mount Wokomung; Reptilia; Systematics; Taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auyantepui</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New free-living marine nematode species (Nematoda: Desmodoridae) from the coast of New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pseudochromadora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reathae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from intertidal sand in Otago Harbour (southern New Zealand), and &lt;i&gt;Pseudodesmodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from subtidal sediment in the Firth of Thames (northern New Zealand). &lt;i&gt;Pseudochromadora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reathae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other species of the genus through the combination of the following characters: sexual dimorphism in the shape of the apertura amphidialis, no interdigitation of body annuli at level of lateral alae, presence of eight longitudinal rows of somatic setae, and conspicuous pre-cloacal supplements consisting of star-shaped projections flanked by two cuticularised pieces. &lt;i&gt;Pseudodesmodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterised by the presence of large unispiral amphids on amphidial plates, conspicuous ducts in the head region, low a values, and short cephalic setae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">SEM; taxonomy; Otago coast; Hauraki Gulf; morphology; meiofauna; Desmodorinae; &lt;i&gt;Pseudochromadora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reathae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pseudodesmodora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacrima&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">SEM</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <lastname>Leduc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wharton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-57</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Type material in the National Nematode Collection of New Zealand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An updated list of type material in the National Nematode Collection of New Zealand is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">arthropod collection; nematode collection; New Zealand; holotypes; paratypes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">arthropod collection; nematode collection; New Zealand; holotypes; paratypes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wim</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wouts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zeng</firstname>
          <middlename>Qi</middlename>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
