<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2613.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2613</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the identity of &lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis dentipalpis &lt;/i&gt;Canestrini, 1872 and description of &lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis lithoclasica &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Opiliones: Ischyropsalididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentipalpis&lt;/i&gt; Canestrini, 1872 is re-defined, and a neotype from the type locality in the Aosta Valley, Italy, is assigned. &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helvetica&lt;/i&gt; Roewer, 1916 (sensu Martens 1978) is shown to be conspecific and therefore is synonymised with &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentipalpis.&lt;/i&gt; A population from Bergamo Province, Italy, formerly assigned to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentipalpis&lt;/i&gt; (sensu Martens 1978), is here regarded as a different species and described under the name &lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lithoclasica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; Discrimination of males is possible by genital characters and by the shape of the cheliceral and pedipalpal apophyses. Females are distinguished by peculiarities of cheliceral spination. The distribution of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lithoclasica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is allopatric to that of &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentipalpis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helvetica&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; neotype; synonymy; Aosta Valley; Bergamo; Italy; Switzerland</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Ischyropsalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;helvetica&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Axel</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schönhofer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jochen</firstname>
          <lastname>Martens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-14</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Temnocephala pignalberiae &lt;/i&gt;Dioni, 1967 (Platyhelminthes, Temnocephalida) from two allopatric populations of &lt;i&gt;Dilocarcinus pagei &lt;/i&gt;Stimpson, 1861 (Crustacea, Decapoda) — first record for Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The presence of adult specimens and eggs of &lt;i&gt;Temnocephala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pignalberiae&lt;/i&gt; Dioni, 1967 in &lt;i&gt;Dilocarcinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pagei&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1861, at Poconé, Brazilian ‘Pantanal’, State of Mato Grosso, together with abundant material also collected from &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pagei&lt;/i&gt; at Bebedouro, State of São Paulo, are reported. These two records allowed the extension of the known geographical distribution of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pignalberiae&lt;/i&gt; from Argentina to Central Brazil, and the comparison of the temnocephalan infrapopulations from two allopatric crab populations, living approximately 1,300 km apart from each other. The entire sample from Poconé and part of the sample from Bebedouro were fixed according to our protocols. Juvenile and adult temnocephalans were whitish to light pink and presented the typical red-eye pigmentation. The worms were living in the branchial chambers, where they deposited their eggs, over the tissue covering the inner upper part of the carapace. These eggs were thin-shelled and the most delicate, so far recorded, for any temnocephalan species our group has studied. The most distinctive features of the temnocephalan specimens from the two localities representing different watersheds were the: 1. cirrus with unarmed introvert; 2. prostatic bulb thick-walled; 3. body ellipsoid, with small and more separate tentacles; 4. syncytial plates elongated and with similar shape; and 5. excretory pores in the same position inside the each syncytial plate. Differing minimally by the: 1. contrasting shaft bases – specimens from Poconé, with rims of the shaft base directed inward, while specimens from Bebedouro, with straight and more open shaft base rims, similar to the shaft bases drawn based on specimens found in Argentina; and 2. ratio between cirrus length and prostatic bulb length, resulting in longer prostatic bulbs in the specimens from Bebedouro. Statistical analysis of measurements taken from flattened adult specimens from the infrapopulations of the two localities showed only minimal differences in the length and width of some organs. This is expected to occur when the same species is collected from populations of the same host species living far from each other and representing separate watersheds.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Geographical distribution; Neotropic Region; State of Mato Grosso; State of São Paulo; taxonomy; temnocephalans</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Geographical distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>F. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Amato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Suzana</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Amato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Samantha</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Seixas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mariluce</firstname>
          <lastname>Fonseca</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rodrigo</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ilário</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>15-28</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of worm salamander (Caudata: Plethodontidae: &lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt;) in the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Oeditriton &lt;/i&gt;from the highlands of northern Nicaragua</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt; (subgenus &lt;i&gt;Oeditriton)&lt;/i&gt; from the highlands of north-central Nicaragua. The new species is most closely related to &lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kasios,&lt;/i&gt; a premontane species from north-central Honduras, and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadra,&lt;/i&gt; a lowland species from northern and eastern Honduras. It differs from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kasios&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadra&lt;/i&gt; in molecular characters and by having a more slender habitus and fewer vomerine teeth. We also discuss the status of the additional populations of &lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt; from Nicaragua.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; mtDNA; cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; 16S; Reserva Natural Cerro Datanlí-El Diablo; Reserva Natural Cerro Kilambé; Reserva Natural Macizos de Peñas Blancas</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Oedipina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; mtDNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <lastname>Sunyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wake</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Josiah</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Townsend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Scott</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Travers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sean</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rovito</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Theodore</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Papenfuss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lenin</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Obando</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gunther</firstname>
          <lastname>Köhler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-39</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hersilia &lt;/i&gt;Audouin, 1826 (Araneae: Hersiliidae) from India, with notes on its natural history</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hersilia&lt;/i&gt; Audouin, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orvakalensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Andhra Pradesh, India. The taxonomic affinities of the species are discussed and a brief note on its natural history is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Long-spinnered bark spider; common two-tailed spider; &lt;i&gt;Hersilia&lt;/i&gt;; India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Long-spinnered bark spider</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>M. Maqsood</middlename>
          <lastname>Javed</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Foord</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Farida</firstname>
          <lastname>Tampal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the alpheid shrimp &lt;i&gt;Betaeus levifrons &lt;/i&gt;Vinogradov, 1950 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Alpheidae) from Peter the Great Bay, Russian coast of the Sea of Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The originally poorly described alpheid shrimp &lt;i&gt;Betaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;levifrons&lt;/i&gt; Vinogradov, 1950 is redescribed based on several adult specimens collected in the Vostok Bay (part of Peter the Great Bay) situated near Nakhodka City, about 90 km southwest from the type locality of the species, the Zolotoi Rog Bay, the Sea of Japan. The specimens were collected with the yabby pump from burrows on sandy-gravel bottom and appears to be associated with the burrowing mud-shrimps &lt;i&gt;Upogebia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; (De Haan, 1841) and &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;issaeffi&lt;/i&gt; (Balss, 1914) (Upogebiidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Alpheidae; &lt;i&gt;Betaeus&lt;/i&gt;; shrimp; Sea of Japan; Peter the Great Bay; Russia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new seahorse (Teleostei: Syngnathidae: &lt;i&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/i&gt;) from south-western Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of syngnathid fish, &lt;i&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from mid-continental shelf waters of south-western Australia is described from the only known specimen. It can be distinguished from all congeners, including the very similar &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minotaur&lt;/i&gt; Gomon 1997, by the following features: the lack of a dorsal fin, a series of fleshy, fin-like lobes along the dorsal midline of the trunk and tail and an extremely robust cleithrum and prominent first nuchal plate. In addition to the traditional methods of syngnathid taxonomists, X-ray microtomography (CT scanning) was employed and demonstrated to be a valuable research tool for examining seahorse species that are problematic due to reduced ossification and small size. CT scanning is more capable of imaging poorly ossified and soft tissue regions than traditional radiography and provides a detailed three dimensional view of salient features.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Syngnathidae; X-ray microtomography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paradoxus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralph</firstname>
          <lastname>Foster</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gomon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
