<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2616.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2616</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The most common sponges on the Great Barrier Reef seabed, Australia, include species new to science (Phylum Porifera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new species amongst the most common sponges living on the seabed (inter-reef) of the Great Barrier Reef (GBR) collected during a multi-agency survey (GBR Seabed Biodiversity Project 2003–2006) of the shelf benthic biota using a trawl and dredge at 1254 sites. More than 1,200 sponge morphospecies (operational taxonomic units or OTUs) were recognised, many of which are potentially new species. This paper describes five of the most common sponges, two of which are new to science, &lt;i&gt;Dercitus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xanthus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paracornulum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fistulosum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Taxonomic revisions of the three other most common species (Coscinoderma &lt;i&gt;nardorus&lt;/i&gt; (Lendenfeld, 1886), &lt;i&gt;Spheciospongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vagabunda&lt;/i&gt; (Ridley, 1884) and &lt;i&gt;Xenospongia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patelliformis&lt;/i&gt; Gray, 1858), reveal new characters not previously recorded. Extensive distribution maps are provided for these species within the GBR Marine Park. Analysis of the physical data associated with the biota revealed these species had strong preference for sand and carbonate sediments. As colonisers of the soft seabed these most prevalent species provide important habitat stabilisation, enabling succession communities to more readily establish on the seabed. This wide-scale study along the length and breadth of the GBR provides a concise and encompassing view of the distribution and diversity of the seabed benthos, and has significant implications for the conservation and management of the GBR World Heritage Area.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Demospongiae; &lt;i&gt;Dercitus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Coscinoderma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paracornulum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Spheciospongia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Xenospongia&lt;/i&gt;; inter-reef; new species; predicted distribution; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Demospongiae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patricia</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sutcliffe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>N. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hooper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>C.</firstname>
          <middlename>Roland</middlename>
          <lastname>Pitcher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Psilorhynchus &lt;/i&gt;from the Ayeyarwaddy River drainage, Myanmar (Teleostei: Psilorhynchidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Psilorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachyrhynchus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from the upper Ayeyarwaddy River drainage, northern Myanmar, is distinguished based on a combination of characters, including a short snout (43–48% HL), scale-less ventral surface between paired fins, and features of dorsal and caudal-fin pigmentation. &lt;i&gt;Psilorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piperatus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from the eastern slopes of the Rakhine Yoma mountain range, lower Ayeyarwaddy River drainage, Myanmar, is distinguished based on its unique caudal-fin pigmentation. &lt;i&gt;Psilorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gokkyi,&lt;/i&gt; new species, also from the eastern slopes of the Rakhine Yoma mountain range, lower Ayeyarwaddy River drainage, Myanmar, is distinguished based on unique shape of its snout, which exhibits a deep notch at the level of the ethmoid region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; Ostariophysi; Cypriniformes; Indo-Burma</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conway</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ralf</firstname>
          <lastname>Britz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Thouarella brucei &lt;/i&gt;Thomson and Ritchie, 1906 (Cnidaria: Octocorallia: Primnoidae) and description of two new Antarctic primnoid species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Thouarella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; Thomson and Ritchie, 1906 is redescribed from the type material present in the Museum of Natural History, London, the Zoological Museum of Amsterdam and the National Museum of Scotland. A lectotype and remaining paralectotypes are designated from the material from the latter. We also add a new record from west South Georgia Island. Material collected on Burdwood Bank, during the &lt;i&gt;Brategg&lt;/i&gt; expedition and previously identified as &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brucei&lt;/i&gt; by Broch is here considered as a new species in the recently described genus &lt;i&gt;Digitogorgia&lt;/i&gt; Zapata-Guardiola and López-González, 2010; &lt;i&gt;Digitogorgia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brochi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Finally, a new species is added to the monotypic genus &lt;i&gt;Tokoprymno&lt;/i&gt; Bayer, 1996, &lt;i&gt;Tokoprymno&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; based on material collected north east of Elephant Island, during the &lt;i&gt;Polarstern&lt;/i&gt; cruise ANT XIX/3. The study of these new taxa allows us to describe a wider variation in polyp scale morphology and a wider distribution in Southern Ocean waters, both geographical and bathymetrical. The new species are also compared with their respective congeners.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Coelenterata; Octocorallia; Primnoidae; Antarctica; &lt;i&gt;Tokoprymno&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Thouarella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Digitogorgia&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rebeca</firstname>
          <lastname>Zapata-Guardiola</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pablo</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>López-González</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-17</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
