<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2627.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">27 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2627</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-27</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Empidideicus &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Bombylioidea: Mythicomyiidae) from Iran, with description of six new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Empidideicus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amicus&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ebellicus&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;greatheadi&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;legulicoxa&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;matricarius&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persicus&lt;/i&gt; Gharali &amp; Evenhuis, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described from the northern parts of Iran. A diagnostic key to Iranian species are presented. The subfamily Empidideicinae is recorded from Iran for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Bombylioidea; Mythicomyiidae; &lt;i&gt;Empidideicus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Babak</firstname>
          <lastname>Gharali</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karim</firstname>
          <lastname>Kamali</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Neal</firstname>
          <lastname>Evenhuis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ali</firstname>
          <middlename>Asghar</middlename>
          <lastname>Talebi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jafar</firstname>
          <lastname>Khalgani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Six new species of &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura &lt;/i&gt;(Collembola, Onychiuridae) from southern China, with a key to world species of the genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diagnosis of &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura&lt;/i&gt; Bagnall, 1949 is updated and a key to the world species of the genus is given. &lt;i&gt;Thalassaphorura&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time in the Guangxi province, where it is well diversified and usually dominant in Collembola communities. Eight species were collected, including 6 species new to science that are described in this paper (Thalassaphorura &lt;i&gt;bapen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pomorskii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reducta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tiani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibiotarsalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and two widespread species newly recorded from China (T. &lt;i&gt;petaloides&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;encarpata).&lt;/i&gt; Half of the species (T. &lt;i&gt;encarpata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petaloides&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pomorskii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; were only represented by females and are assumed to be parthenogenetic, the four other ones are bisexual.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">distribution; parthenogenesis; pseudopores; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">distribution</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xin</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jian-Xiu</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <lastname>Deharveng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-38</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of the weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa &lt;/i&gt;Stephens based on adult morphological characters and host plant information (Coleoptera: Curculionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A phylogenetic analysis of the species belonging to the weevil genus &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa&lt;/i&gt; Stephens, 1829 (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Curculioninae: Mecinini) was carried out. &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa&lt;/i&gt; weevils feed on plants of the closely related families Scrophulariaceae and Plantaginaceae. Based on a cladistic analysis of six outgroup and 33 ingroup taxa, and 39 adult morphological and 8 ecological characters, eight well supported species groups and two monobasic groups belonging to three separate and more inclusive assemblages were recognized. The first assemblage (A) includes nine species belonging to two groups (R. &lt;i&gt;bipustulata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tetra&lt;/i&gt; groups), whereas the second and third assemblages (B and C) include a total of 14 species belonging to two groups (R. &lt;i&gt;antirrhini&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linariae&lt;/i&gt; groups) and six groups (R. &lt;i&gt;pilosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;herbarum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neta,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vestita,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mauritii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melas&lt;/i&gt; groups), respectively. Two of the three main assemblages (A and B) are well supported as monophyletic entities, whereas the third assemblage (C) has weak support contingent in part upon the exclusion of host plant associations. Assemblage A includes all species living on species of Scrophulariaceae, with two groups occurring on two closely related plant genera, &lt;i&gt;Scrophularia&lt;/i&gt; (R. &lt;i&gt;bipustulata&lt;/i&gt; group) and &lt;i&gt;Verbascum&lt;/i&gt; (R. &lt;i&gt;tetra&lt;/i&gt; group), respectively. The other two assemblages include species living exclusively on species of the family Plantaginaceae, tribe Antirrhineae. These patterns suggest a well conserved and phylogenetically congruent association among the weevils and their hosts. Optimizing host plant preferences onto the morphological phylogeny indicates that feeding on Plantaginaceae was the plesiomorphic condition for the genus &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa.&lt;/i&gt; In general there are no strict relationships between groups of weevils and their specific feeding habits; however, species of the &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antirrhini&lt;/i&gt; group are all feeding on seed capsules. In contrast, in other groups the larvae of closely related species display significant variations in host plant parasitism. Some species of the &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tetra&lt;/i&gt; group feed on seed capsules whereas others are stem borers. In turn, certain species of the &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neta&lt;/i&gt; group feed on seed capsules yet others are inquilines of gall forming species of &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa.&lt;/i&gt; The latter habit is present in multiple convergent groups such as the &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linariae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilosa&lt;/i&gt; groups.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Curculionidae; host plants; Mecinini; morphology; &lt;i&gt;Rhinusa&lt;/i&gt;; phylogenetics; species groups</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Curculionidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Caldara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Davide</firstname>
          <lastname>Sassi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ivo</firstname>
          <lastname>Toševski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-27</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Isophya sicula &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Orthoptera: Tettigonioidea), a new, morphologically cryptic bush-cricket species from the Eastern Carpathians (Romania) recognized from its peculiar male calling song</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The morphology and pair-forming acoustic signals of &lt;i&gt;Isophya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sicula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; a new phaneropterine bush-cricket species from the Eastern Carpathians (Romania) is described. The species is morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posthumoidalis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camptoxypha,&lt;/i&gt; but the male calling song differs clearly from the songs of those species. The male calling song is a long series of evenly repeated, very short syllables. Syllables are much shorter than in &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camptoxypha,&lt;/i&gt; and the song is composed from only one syllable type differently from &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posthumoidalis,&lt;/i&gt; where the male calling song is composed of two syllable types. Pair formation is achieved during an acoustic duet. The delay of female response (40–70 ms) is shorter than in &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;camptoxypha&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posthumoidalis.&lt;/i&gt; Basic descriptive statistics of sonometric and morphometric characters of the new species as well as SEM photos of the male stridulatory file and female stridulatory bristles are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">acoustic signal; stridulation; oscillogram; spectrogram; male-female duet; Isophya posthumoidalis; Isophya camptoxypha</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">acoustic signal</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kirill</firstname>
          <middlename>Márk</middlename>
          <lastname>Orci</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gergely</firstname>
          <lastname>Szövényi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barnabás</firstname>
          <lastname>Nagy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-27</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
