<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2631.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2631</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and a new record of &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma &lt;/i&gt;Bosc, 1802 (Sphaeromatidae: Isopoda: Crustacea) from intertidal marine habitats of the Persian Gulf</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma&lt;/i&gt; (Sphaeromatidae: Isopoda) from the Iranian coasts of the Persian Gulf were studied and described. &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;khalijfarsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the intertidal zone of the Strait of Hormuz. This species is distinguished by the smooth pereonites; pleon without prominent tubercles and bearing some scattered small tubercles; pleotelson with numerous scattered small tubercles and well upturned posterior margins. &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walkeri&lt;/i&gt; Stebbing, 1905 is reported from Kish and Qeshm Islands and from the southern coasts of Iran. Among the non-Indian Ocean species, &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedium&lt;/i&gt; Baker, 1926 is transferred to genus &lt;i&gt;Lekanesphera&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1943.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Isopoda; Sphaeromatidae; &lt;i&gt;Sphaeroma&lt;/i&gt;; new species; The Persian Gulf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Valiallah</firstname>
          <lastname>Khalaji-Pirbalouty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Johann-Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Wägele</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A redescription of a common euryhaline cumacean from southern Brazil: &lt;i&gt;Diastylis sympterygiae &lt;/i&gt;Băcescu &amp; Queiroz, 1985 (Crustacea: Cumacea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Diastylis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sympterygiae&lt;/i&gt; Băcescu &amp; Queiroz (1985) has been reported in many ecological studies conducted in the Patos Lagoon, southern Brazil. However, the original description of this species is based on damaged specimens from stomach contents of rays, and therefore insufficient for a confident identification. In the present contribution, based on a large number of well-preserved specimens now available from the type locality area, the description of this common euryhaline species is completed and its range of distribution as far north as São Paulo is extended.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diastylidae; Peracarida; taxonomy; South-West Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diastylidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cristales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Roccatagliata</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Natalia</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Alberico</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-35</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the African &lt;i&gt;Chordodes albibarbatus &lt;/i&gt;Montgomery 1898, and description of &lt;i&gt;Chordodes janovyi &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Gordiida, Nematomorpha) and its non-adult stages from Cameroon, Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We redescribe &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albibarbatus&lt;/i&gt; Montgomery 1898 from the original holotype male and the originally described female specimen using Nomarski interference contrast microscopy. Our reinvestigation indicates that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albibarbatus&lt;/i&gt; is sexually dimorphic and contains five types of areoles in the male and six types of areoles in the female. Our reinvestigation of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albibarbatus&lt;/i&gt; indicates that it is a distinct species, and is most similar to the African &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gariazzi&lt;/i&gt; Camerano 1902 and &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heinzei&lt;/i&gt; Sciacchitano 1937, all of which share simple “blackberry”, bulging, tubercles, and thorn areoles. In addition, we describe adult free-living male and female &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janovyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; collected from West Province, Cameroon, Africa using both morphological (light and scanning electron microscopy) and molecular data, and designate types for this species. &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janovyi&lt;/i&gt; belongs to a large group of &lt;i&gt;Chordodes&lt;/i&gt; in which simple areoles are smooth or superficially structured less so than “blackberry” areoles. Present among the simple areoles are clusters of crowned and circumcluster areoles along with thorn and tubercle areoles, whereas bulging areoles are absent. We also describe the egg strings, eggs, larvae, cysts, and oviposition behavior of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;janovyi&lt;/i&gt; and compare these non-adult life stages to other nematomorph genera and species for which such life cycle stages are known, and we discuss the use of non-adult stages and the use of molecular tools in future studies of nematomorph systematics and biodiversity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gordiida; gordiid; hairworm; Gordian worm; Nematomorpha; Africa; scanning electron microscopy; Nomarski interference contrast microscopy; molecular data; oviposition behavior; non-adult life stages</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gordiida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bolek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmidt-Rhaesa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ben</firstname>
          <lastname>Hanelt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Richardson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Hessebius &lt;/i&gt;Verhoeff, 1941 (Chilopoda: Lithobiomorpha: Lithobiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The present paper reviews the centipede species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hessebius&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1941 (Chilopoda: Lithobiomorpha: Lithobiidae) of the Chinese fauna, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jangtseanus&lt;/i&gt; (Verhoeff, 1942), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispinipes&lt;/i&gt; Ma, Pei &amp; Zhu, 2009 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;multiforaminis&lt;/i&gt; Pei, Ma, Zapparoli &amp; Zhu, &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kosswigi&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1941, from Turkey, is selected by subsequent designation as type species of the genus, which was previously unavailable. &lt;i&gt;Schizotergitius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;styliferus&lt;/i&gt; Loksa, 1978, from Mongolia, is transferred in &lt;i&gt;Hessebius&lt;/i&gt; (n. &lt;b&gt;comb.)&lt;/b&gt; and its relationships with &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispinipes&lt;/i&gt; are briefly discussed. A comparative table of the diagnostic characters of the Sino–Mongolian species of the genus is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chilopoda; Lithobiidae; &lt;i&gt;Hessebius&lt;/i&gt;; type species by subsequent designation; China; Mongolia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chilopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sujian</firstname>
          <lastname>Pei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Huiqin</firstname>
          <lastname>Ma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marzio</firstname>
          <lastname>Zapparoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mingsheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-61</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of Ameroidea (Acari: Oribatida) from Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new oribatid mite species, &lt;i&gt;Hymenobelba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exclamationis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pteramerus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clypeatus&lt;/i&gt; spp. nov. (Ameridae), are described and illustrated based on specimens collected from mossy montane rainforest in the Malagasy Republic, Toamasina Province, Maromizaha forest. Both of them show a great variation of peculiar morphological features as having or not the costuliform prodorsal structure, the number and position of the notogastral setae and the abundance or position of aggenital and adanal neotrichy in genus &lt;i&gt;Hymenobelba.&lt;/i&gt; A well observable variation can be observed in the form of pedotecta and in legs segments of the other species (Pteramerus &lt;i&gt;clypeatus),&lt;/i&gt; which is only the second species belonging to this genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Oribatida; new species; new determination keys; Republic of Malagasy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sándor</firstname>
          <lastname>Mahunka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
