<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2636.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2636</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Studies on Pakistan Lizards: &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion baturense &lt;/i&gt;(Khan and Baig 1992) and &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion walli &lt;/i&gt;(Ingoldby 1922) (Sauria: Gekkonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of Eurasian angular or thin-toed geckos has undergone a great deal of revision over the last 30 years. However, it is clear that a desirable level of taxonomic resolution has not yet been attained as their taxonomic assignments are somewhat arbitrary. In this paper, we discuss two lesser-known gecko species, &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baturense&lt;/i&gt; (Khan and Baig 1992) and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; (Ingoldby 1922). One adult specimen of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baturense&lt;/i&gt; (the only known specimen other than the type series) and a series of 53 &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; collected by Walter Auffenberg and the Zoological Survey Department of Pakistan (ZSD) and subsequently deposited in the University of Florida Herpetology collection were compared to the type specimens. Specimens were examined for 46 morphological characters and measurements. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baturense&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; are diagnosable and confirmed to be distinct species. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baturense&lt;/i&gt; is known only from the holotype locality of Pasu and the nearby village of Dih, Hunza District, in the Gilgit Agency, Federally Administered Northern Areas (FANA), Pakistan, at 2,438–3,078 m elevations. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; is known from Ayun, Chitral, Bamburet Valley, Bermoghluscht, Drosh Tehsil, and 7.0 km N Drosh, in the Chitral District, Northwest Frontier, Pakistan, at 1,970–2,120 m elevations. We also conclude that the likely paratype (BMNH 1922.5.22.1) of &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; is not conspecific with the holotype (BMNH 1910.7.12.1) and is most morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tibetanus&lt;/i&gt; (Boulenger 1905). We concur with Khan (1992), based on our own examination of the syntype of &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitralensis&lt;/i&gt; Smith, 1935, that &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chitralensis&lt;/i&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; Ingoldby, 1922. Furthermore, the tail associated with the holotype of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walli&lt;/i&gt; does not belong to that individual.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gekkonidae; gecko; lizard; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Gymnodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mediodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Tenuidactylus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Altigekko&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gekkonidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kurt</firstname>
          <lastname>Auffenberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kenneth</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Krysko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hafizur</firstname>
          <lastname>Rehman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new &lt;i&gt;Mallinella &lt;/i&gt;species from the Sundaland of Indonesia (Araneae, Zodariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new spider species belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Mallinella&lt;/i&gt; Strand, 1906 (Araneae, Zodariidae) are described from the Greater Sunda (Sumatra, Borneo, Java) and adjacent smaller islands (Bali, Palau Belitung). These taxa are &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abdita&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (♂♀, East Kalimantan, Borneo), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bifida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (♂♀, East and South Kalimantan, Borneo), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insulana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (♂, Bali), and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wiputrai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (♂♀, Palau Belitung). Males that were considered by Simon to be conspecific with &lt;i&gt;Storena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanognatha&lt;/i&gt; van Hasselt, 1882 prove to belong to an unknown species and here described as &lt;i&gt;Mallinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (♂, Java and Palau Belitung). New collections from Sundaland confirm that the first species is confined to Sumatra whereas &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is hitherto known from Java and Palau Belitung. The known distribution of &lt;i&gt;Mallinella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albomaculata&lt;/i&gt; Bosmans &amp; Hillyard, 1990, mentioned from Sulawesi, is here extended to the island of Borneo; the internal epigyne structure of this species is described and illustrated for the first time.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Java; Bali; Sumatra; Kalimantan; Borneo; Palau Belitung; biodiversity; new record; &lt;i&gt;Asceua&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Storena&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Java</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pakawin</firstname>
          <lastname>Dankittipakul</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rudy</firstname>
          <lastname>Jocqué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tippawan</firstname>
          <lastname>Singtripop</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pinnotherotonia rumphiusi &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov., a new furry bivalve-associated pontoniine shrimp (Crustacea: Decapoda: Palaemonidae) from Palau</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of a furry, bivalve–associated pontoniine shrimp is described from Palau. This is the second pontoniine shrimp known to be associated with bivalves burrowing into soft bottom, and the first record of a venus clam (Bivalvia, Veneridae) as host for caridean shrimps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Caridea; Pontoniinae; new genus; new species; Bivalvia; Veneridae; &lt;i&gt;Periglypta&lt;/i&gt;; Palau</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustav</firstname>
          <lastname>Paulay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An endemic &lt;i&gt;Taenia &lt;/i&gt;from South America: validation of &lt;i&gt;T. talicei &lt;/i&gt;Dollfus, 1960 (Cestoda: Taeniidae) with characterization of metacestodes and adults</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Taenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;talicei&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed based on new data from polycephalic, fimbriocercus and cysticercus metacestodes found in &lt;i&gt;Ctenomys&lt;/i&gt; spp. (Rodentia: Ctenomyidae) from Argentina. Strobilate adult specimens, derived from experimental infections in domestic dogs, are described for the first time. Identity of the adult and metacestodes stages is based on the number of rostellar hooks (44–50 hooks in 2 rows), their dimensions (large hooks= 232–242; small= 150–187) and shape. &lt;i&gt;Taenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;talicei&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from those species that occur naturally in Neotropical Felidae and from those cosmopolitan species that circulate in synanthropic cycles with rodents (or lagomorphs) and domestic hosts such as cats and dogs in South America based on the structure of the metacestode, dimensions and numbers of rostellar hooks and a suite of specific characters of the genital system in strobilate adults. This species is the first that can be considered endemic to South America. Origins of an endemic &lt;i&gt;Taenia&lt;/i&gt; species or taeniid assemblages in South America would have relationships to either North American or Eurasian placental carnivores. In these instances, the expansion of &lt;i&gt;Taenia&lt;/i&gt; may have resulted from geographic colonization of South America, radiation in both felids (and canids), and host switching by tapeworms to caviomorphs, prior to the emergence of the Panamanian Isthmus. &lt;i&gt;Taenia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;talicei&lt;/i&gt; is capable of development in domestic dogs, and metacestodes in species of &lt;i&gt;Ctenomys&lt;/i&gt; were found in urban or semi-urban environments. These factors may establish a role for synanthropic cycles linked to definitive hosts including dogs and cats as a route for exposure of humans to infection by this taeniid.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">South American rodent; &lt;i&gt;Ctenomys&lt;/i&gt;; cestodes; larval forms; taeniid tapeworms</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">South American rodent</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rossin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Timi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eric</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships of the gecko genus &lt;i&gt;Carinatogecko&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia: Gekkonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The gecko genus &lt;i&gt;Carinatogecko&lt;/i&gt; comprises two species endemic to the foothills of the Zagros Mountains, in Iran and Iraq. Both species are poorly known and to date they are known only from very few records. The phylogenetic affiliation of the genus has been only hypothesized. The aim of this study was to clarify the phylogenetic relationships of the genus by analyzing partial sequences of the mitochondrial 12S rRNA and cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; genes. All phylogenetic analyses performed support placing the genus &lt;i&gt;Carinatogecko&lt;/i&gt; within the genus &lt;i&gt;Mediodactylus.&lt;/i&gt; Taxonomic relevance of both species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Carinatogecko&lt;/i&gt; based on morphological characters is discussed along with nomenclatural implications of our findings.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt;; lizards; &lt;i&gt;Mediodactylus&lt;/i&gt;; mtDNA; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtopodion&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jan</firstname>
          <lastname>Červenka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Frynta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lukáš</firstname>
          <lastname>Kratochvíl</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-64</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
