<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2649.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2649</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Gondwanan relict oribatid genus &lt;i&gt;Crotonia &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Crotoniidae) from rainforests in Queensland and Northern New South Wales: new species show a mixed pattern of short-range and long-range endemism</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twelve new species of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; are described from rainforests in Queensland and Northern New South Wales, Australia. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sterigma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belongs to a new species group, Borbora, to which &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borbora&lt;/i&gt; Luxton, 1987, redescribed here, and for which a lectotype is designated, is re-assigned from the Capistrata group. Six species belong to the Capistrata group (C. &lt;i&gt;brisbanensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monteithi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daviesae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weiri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yeatesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.).&lt;/b&gt; Previously-known Australian members of the Capistrata group, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ardala&lt;/i&gt; Luxton, 1987 and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capistrata&lt;/i&gt; Luxton, 1987, are redescribed and lectotypes are designated. Four species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cameroni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandiae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eungella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seemani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; belong to the Cophinaria species-group and one, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raveni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is morphologically so different from other &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; spp. that it is also assigned to a new species-group. This brings the number of species of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; recorded from Australia to 27, almost half of the global fauna. Mostspecies show localised distribution in rainforest remnants, characteristic of short-range endemics with apparently low dispersal capabilities, are subject to constraints of body water balance and thus confined to wet habitats. They can be divided into those associated with a northern region (ca. 16–18°S) centred around the Wet Tropics from Cape Tribulation to the Walter Hill Range (C. &lt;i&gt;ardala,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borbora,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capistrata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monteithi),&lt;/i&gt; a central region (ca. 20–18°S) from Mount Dryander to Byfield (C. &lt;i&gt;cameroni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eungella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seemani)&lt;/i&gt; and a southern region (ca. 26-28°S) from the Conondale Range to Whian Whian (C. &lt;i&gt;brisbanensis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;daviesae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandiae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raveni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;weiri,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yeatesi).&lt;/i&gt; Other species are long-range endemics. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is found throughout all three regions and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sterigma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is found in both the central and southern regions. Several species show a series of characters that are considered to function in aiding the accumulation and retention of mineral soil and organic debris adhering to the cerotegument. These characters include the elongation of the caudal apophyses, expansion or elongation of the notogastral shield, retention of the elongated, flagelliform nymphal form of the notogastral setae and retention of nymphal exuviae in the caudal region. The layer of detritus covering the cerotegument was dissected off the cuticle of adult female and tritonymphal &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raveni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and was found to constitute more than the mean wet weight of the mites. The acquisition by the mites of the detrital layer after each moult is considered to function as a general anti-predator system and in the reduction of body water loss.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">mite; taxonomy; oribatid; morphology; systematics; biogeography; Australia; cerotegument; predators; water balance</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Colloff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-51</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Anoplodesmus &lt;/i&gt;Pocock, 1895 in Vietnam (Diplopoda: Polydesmida: Paradoxosomatidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Anoplodesmus&lt;/i&gt; are described: &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borealis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from northern Vietnam, and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solenophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from southern Vietnam. Both these species belong to the group showing an extremely long solenomere and strongly reduced paraterga. A key to all three &lt;i&gt;Anoplodesmus&lt;/i&gt; species currently known from Vietnam is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Vietnam; Paradoxosomatidae; &lt;i&gt;Anoplodesmus&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Vietnam</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anh</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Adamystis thailandensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Acari: Prostigmata: Adamystidae), a new species of soil mites from Thailand with a key to world species of Adamystidae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of soil prostigmatic mites, &lt;i&gt;Adamystis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thailandensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Acari: Adamystidae) is described based on adult and immature specimens collected from leaf litter and upper soil layer in a coastal forest in southern Thailand. It differs from its congeners by the presence of a densely striated idiosomal shield and the presence of lens-like structures on the lateral, posterior dorsomedial, and ventral sides of the idiosoma. A diagnostic key to the known species of Adamystidae is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">coastal forest; soil fauna; soil mites; Prostigmata; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">coastal forest</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marut</firstname>
          <lastname>Fuangarworn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chariya</firstname>
          <lastname>Lekprayoon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
