<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2650.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2650</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Crotoniidae) from Lord Howe and Norfolk Islands: further evidence of long-distance dispersal events in the biogeography of a genus of Gondwanan relict oribatid mites</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of oribatid mite belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; are described: one from Lord Howe Island (C. &lt;i&gt;gorgonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and two (C. &lt;i&gt;norfolkensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utricularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; from Norfolk Island, South-west Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gorgonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belongs to the Capistrata species group which reaches its highest diversity in Australia but is absent from New Zealand. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;norfolkensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a member of the Cophinaria group, recorded from Australia, New Zealand and New Caledonia, but with closest morphological similarity to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachyrostrum&lt;/i&gt; (Hammer, 1966) from New Zealand. &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utricularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belongs to the Unguifera group, which reaches its highest diversity in New Zealand, is absent from Australia, and is present on Vanuatu and the Marquesas. The distribution of members of the species-groups of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; in the south-western Pacific indicates that the species from Lord Howe Island has affinities with species from Australia, while the species from Norfolk Island are both most similar to species from New Zealand, and represents further evidence of the capacity of &lt;i&gt;Crotonia&lt;/i&gt; spp. for long-distance dispersal to oceanic islands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mite; oribatid; taxonomy; morphology; long-distance dispersal; biogeography; island faunas; Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Colloff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species in the &lt;i&gt;Tylototriton asperrimus &lt;/i&gt;group (Caudata: Salamandridae) from central Laos</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species in the morphologically conservative &lt;i&gt;Tylototriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asperrimus&lt;/i&gt; group is described from Khammouan Province, Laos. Molecular phylogenetic analysis of mitochondrial DNA confirms its placement in the &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asperrimus&lt;/i&gt; group. &lt;i&gt;Tylototriton&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notialis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is diagnosable in mitochondrial DNA, nuclear DNA, and morphology from its congeners. The new species represents the first record of the genus from Laos, and is the southernmost known member of the &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asperrimus&lt;/i&gt; group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caudata; Laos; Southeast Asia; &lt;i&gt;Tylototriton&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caudata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bryan</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stuart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Somphouthone</firstname>
          <lastname>Phimmachak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Niane</firstname>
          <lastname>Sivongxay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Robichaud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of huntsman spiders from the Neotropical region (Araneae: Sparassidae: Heteropodinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Guadana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is proposed to include six new species: &lt;i&gt;Guadana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manauara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urucu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neblina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quillu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from Ecuador; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;panguana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tambopata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Peru. The genus is distinguished from the remaining Neotropical Sparassidae by the presence of a single row of intermarginal denticles, occupying most of the cheliceral grove, a sickle-shaped dorsal tegular projection in the male palps and epigynal ledges in the female epigynum. It is placed in the subfamily Heteropodinae Thorell due to the presence of intermarginal denticles in the chelicerae, a long toothed female pedipalp claw, a ventral tibial apophysis and a ventral branch in the RTA of the male palps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Guadana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species; Brazil; Ecuador; Peru; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Guadana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Cristina</firstname>
          <middlename>Anne</middlename>
          <lastname>Rheims</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle &lt;/i&gt;(Monogenea: Acanthocotylidae: Myxinidocotylinae) from captive sixgill hagfish, &lt;i&gt;Eptatretus hexatrema&lt;/i&gt; (Chordata: Myxinidae), with amendment of the subfamily diagnosis</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;eptatreti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the skin of the sixgill hagfish, &lt;i&gt;Eptatretus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hexatrema&lt;/i&gt; collected for exhibition at the Two Oceans Aquarium in Cape Town, South Africa. The new species is the first acanthocotylid described from South Africa and differs significantly from the only two known &lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; species by the morphology of the sclerotised male copulatory tube and the presence of a diverticulated intestinal caecum. The subfamily diagnosis is amended to include a single seminal receptacle, found within the anterior concave portion of the ovary and excludes the vaginal &lt;i&gt;seminis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;receptaculum&lt;/i&gt; which is considered the seminal vesicle. The vagina travels ventrally over the seminal vesicle and does not fuse with it bilaterally as originally proposed by Malmberg &amp; Fernholm (1989). &lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle&lt;/i&gt; spp. possess 8 or 9 testes. The proximal male accessory gland reservoirs are connected by an intricate network of fine ducts to the field of extensive male accessory gland cells extending along the length of the body proper. Observations on the locomotion and attachment of live worms &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitro&lt;/i&gt; are discussed and the presence of adhesive secretions is confirmed for the haptoral glands and anterior glands.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle&lt;/i&gt;; Monogenea; Acanthocotylidae; hagfishes; public aquarium</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myxinidocotyle&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vaughan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Christison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Isospora ramphoceli &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Apicomplexa: Eimeriidae) from the Brazilian tanager (Aves: Passeriformes: Thraupidae) &lt;i&gt;Ramphocelus bresilius dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; Sclater, 1855</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In the current study, a new coccidian species (Protozoa: Apicomplexa: Eimeriidae) collected from the Brazilian tanager &lt;i&gt;Ramphocelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bresilius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; Sclater, 1855 is reported from Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Isospora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramphoceli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has oocysts which are spherical to sub-spherical, 23.7 × 22.8 μ m, with smooth, bilayered wall, ~1.2 μ m thick. Micropyle, oocyst residuum and polar granule are absent. Sporocysts are ellipsoidal or slightly ovoidal, 16.0 × 11.4 µm. Stieda body knob-like and prominent and substieda body large and homogeneous. Sporocyst residuum is composed of granules of different sizes. Sporozoites are vermiform with one refractile body and a nucleus. This is the sixth description of an isosporoid coccidium infecting &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;b.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; and the twelfth description from Thraupidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; morphology; coccidia; &lt;i&gt;Isospora&lt;/i&gt;; oocysts; Passeriformes; Thraupidae; Marambaia Island; Rio de Janeiro; Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bruno</firstname>
          <middlename>Pereira</middlename>
          <lastname>Berto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Walter</firstname>
          <lastname>Flausino</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hermes</firstname>
          <middlename>Ribeiro</middlename>
          <lastname>Luz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ildemar</firstname>
          <lastname>Ferreira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Wilson Gomes</middlename>
          <lastname>Lopes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema &lt;/i&gt;Duméril &amp; Bibron (Amphibia: Gymnophiona: Rhinatrematidae) from Amazonas, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of rhinatrematid caecilian, &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ron&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a single specimen from the state of Amazonas in Brazil. The new species differs from other &lt;i&gt;Rhinatrema&lt;/i&gt; in several features, including its larger size, different colouration, and distinctively plicate oral mucosa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; caecilians; French Guiana; Guiana Shield; herpetology; South America; systematics; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilkinson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>J</middlename>
          <lastname>Gower</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
