<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2676.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">15 Nov. 2010</title>
    <volume>2676</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-11-15</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new sacoglossan sea slug species (Opisthobranchia, Gastropoda): &lt;i&gt;Ercolania annelyleorum &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Limapontioidea) and &lt;i&gt;Elysia asbecki &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Plakobranchoidea), with notes on anatomy, histology and biology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new sacoglossan species, belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Ercolania&lt;/i&gt; Trinchese, 1872 (Ercolania &lt;i&gt;annelyleorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and the genus &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; Risso, 1818 (Elysia &lt;i&gt;asbecki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; are described from Lizard Island, Great Barrier Reef, Australia. Anatomy of both species was reconstructed by analyzing histological serial sections. Radula morphology was investigated by using light microscopy and scanning electron microscopy. Sequence analyses (NeighborNet; sequence divergence) and tree reconstructions showed for both species their distinction from con-generic species, but also two distinct mitochondrial lines in the new &lt;i&gt;Ercolania&lt;/i&gt; species. Adults as well as freshly hatched juveniles of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annelyleorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; have been found in clusters of the ulvophycean alga &lt;i&gt;Boodlea&lt;/i&gt; sp., which are sucked out by piercing the cell walls with their radular teeth. This new species differs from other, similar transparent, &lt;i&gt;Ercolania&lt;/i&gt; species by its pattern of the green branches of the digestive gland and the presence of two distinct red patches, one in the anterior and the other in the posterior third of the dorsal body part. This coloration and furthermore the combination of following characters distinguishes the new species from all other described &lt;i&gt;Ercolania&lt;/i&gt; species so far: rhinophores, elliptic in cross section, with one distinct branch of digestive gland running half way up; cerata not inflated; smooth cutting edge of sabot-shaped tooth; two-lobed prostate gland and presence of two allosperm receptacles with no re-opening of the receptaculum seminis to the outside. According to sequence divergence data of CO1, two mitochondrial lines seem to be present in the new species, which are clearly distinct from all other included &lt;i&gt;Ercolania&lt;/i&gt; species. &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asbecki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; species by its whitish coloration with orange and dark brown dots and a distinct lighter spot in the neck region of the head. The rhinophores exhibit a black and yellow ribbon at the tip. The species has distinct reddish patches at the anterior base of the parapodia (at the conjunction with the head), one along the middle part of the parapodial edge on both sides and very distinct lateral patches at the end of the foot. CO1 sequences clearly distinguish this species from all closely related &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; species. The food source of &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asbecki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; could not be verified yet. Measurements of photosynthetic activity within these two new species indicate that &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annelyleorum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; digests chloroplasts immediately after sequestration, whereas &lt;i&gt;Elysia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asbecki&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; shows high maximum quantum yield values, similar to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;timida&lt;/i&gt; (Risso, 1818) and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crispata&lt;/i&gt; (Mørch, 1863), both known as long term retention forms.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sacoglossa; new species; photosynthetic activity; DNA taxonomy; bar coding; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sacoglossa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Heike</firstname>
          <lastname>Wägele</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kristina</firstname>
          <lastname>Stemmer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ingo</firstname>
          <lastname>Burghardt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Katharina</firstname>
          <lastname>Händeler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Aquatic oligochaetes (Annelida: Clitellata) of the Czech Republic: check-list, new records, and ecological remarks</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study contributes to the knowledge of central European clitellates by creating a check-list of Oligochaeta (sensu oligochaetous Clitellata; Erséus 2005) of the Czech Republic, exclusive of taxa in the family Enchytraeidae. In total, 95 aquatic oligochaete species representing 43 genera are reported for the Czech Republic. Rare species are highlighted and associated with the categories for threatened species as outlined by the International Union for the Conservation of Nature. The first records of &lt;i&gt;Trichodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strandi&lt;/i&gt; Hrabě, 1936, &lt;i&gt;Pristina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenkinae&lt;/i&gt; (Stephenson, 1931), &lt;i&gt;Pristina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osborni&lt;/i&gt; (Walton, 1906), &lt;i&gt;Rhyacodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subterraneus&lt;/i&gt; Hrabě, 1963, &lt;i&gt;Aulodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limnobius&lt;/i&gt; Bretscher, 1899, and &lt;i&gt;Aulodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pigueti&lt;/i&gt; Kowalewski, 1914 in the Czech Republic are presented. Their ecology, morphology, and distribution are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oligochaeta; &lt;i&gt;Trichodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strandi&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jenkinae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pristina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;osborni&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Rhyacodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;subterraneus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aulodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;limnobius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Aulodrilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pigueti&lt;/i&gt;; habitat preferences; first records; red list; alien species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oligochaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jana</firstname>
          <lastname>Schenková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petr</firstname>
          <lastname>Pařil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karla</firstname>
          <lastname>Petřivalská</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jindřiška</firstname>
          <lastname>Bojková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new eucryptodiran turtle from the Early Cretaceous Jiufotang Formation of western Liaoning, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new eucryptodiran turtle from the Jiufotang Formation of Lamadong, Jianchang County, represents the third turtle taxon, &lt;i&gt;Liaochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jianchangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; from the Jehol Biota of western Liaoning Province, China. This taxon is diagnosed by a character combination including a midline contact of the prefrontals, vertebrals wider than long, third costals strongly expanded distally, and a medial contact of the eighth costals. A preliminary cladistic analysis places &lt;i&gt;Liaochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jianchangensis&lt;/i&gt; along the phylogenetic stem of Cryptodira in a position more derived than the taxa, &lt;i&gt;Manchurochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manchoukuoensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ordosemys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liaoxiensis,&lt;/i&gt; known from the underlying Yixian Formation. This discovery opens a new window into the osteology and evolution of primitive eucryptodiran turtles.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eucryptodira; "Macrobaenidae"; &lt;i&gt;Liaochelys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jianchangensis&lt;/i&gt;; Jiufotang Formation; western Liaoning; Jehol Biota</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eucryptodira</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chang-Fu</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-15</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new classification of the Galatheoidea (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The high level classification of the Galatheoidea, popularly known as squat lobsters, has been relatively stable for almost a century. Multiple recent studies of their interrelationships, however, have revealed significant incongruities between the traditional classification and phylogeny. The Aeglidae, Chirostylidae and Kiwaidae were recently removed to other superfamilies. On the basis of previous phylogenetic analyses, we herein revise the higher classification of the remaining Galatheoidea to comprise four families: Galatheidae, Munididae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Munidopsidae, and Porcellanidae. The galatheoid families are both morphologically and ecologically distinct. Members of the Munidopsidae are distinguished by the absence or reduction of the maxilliped 1 flagellum and usually occur in outer slope or abyssal habitats. Members of the Munididae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are united by the trifid or trispinous anterior margin of the carapace and usually occur at outer shelf or slope depths. The Galatheidae includes primarily shallow water species, united by a broad, triangular rostrum, and is most closely related to the porcelain crabs, Porcellanidae. The families of the Galatheoidea are diagnosed and a diagnostic key provided. Extant and fossil genera are listed for each galatheoid squat lobster family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Galatheoidea; Galatheidae; Munididae &lt;b&gt;fam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Munidopsidae; Porcellanidae; squat lobsters; phylogeny; classification</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Galatheoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Keiji</firstname>
          <lastname>Baba</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Enrique</firstname>
          <lastname>Macpherson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gary</firstname>
          <middlename>C. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Poore</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-15</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
