<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2332.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Jan. 2010</title>
    <volume>2332</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first sexually dimorphic species of &lt;i&gt;Oribatella &lt;/i&gt;(Acari, Oribatida, Oribatellidae) and a review of sexual dimorphism in the Brachypylina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The oribatid mite genus &lt;i&gt;Oribatella&lt;/i&gt; includes over 100 named species, none of which shows distinct sexual dimorphism in the octotaxic system of dermal glands. We propose a new species of this genus, &lt;i&gt;Oribatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canadensis&lt;/i&gt; sp, nov., collected from dry soil habitats in western Canada, that shows distinct dimorphism in these dermal glands, the first record of this dimorphism in the Oribatelloidea. The posterior pair of glands in males, but not females, is enlarged and associated with a shallow, medial pit-tubercle complex, and is generally similar to convergent dimorphisms in some genera of Mochlozetidae (Oripodoidea), Mycobatidae (Ceratozetoidea) and Galumnidae (Galumnoidea). We describe this species based on adult and nymphal stages, and expand the diagnosis of the genus to accommodate the newly described immatures. We review the expression of sexual dimorphism in brachypyline oribatid mites and discuss its association with periodically dry habitats.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oribatida; &lt;i&gt;Oribatella&lt;/i&gt;; Oribatelloidea; Brachypylina; octotaxic system; sexual dimorphism; Canada</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oribatida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Valerie</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Behan-Pelletier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barbara</firstname>
          <lastname>Eamer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of aquatic oligochaetes (Annelida: Clitellata) from groundwaters in karstic areas of northern Spain, with taxonomic remarks on &lt;i&gt;Lophochaeta ignota&lt;/i&gt; Štolc, 1886</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new species: &lt;i&gt;Gianius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;navarroi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Phallodrilinae) and &lt;i&gt;Isochaetides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gianii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Tubificinae), which were discovered during investigations on the groundwater oligochaete fauna in northern Spain. The present study contributes to the knowledge of the stygobiont oligochaete species in the Iberian Peninsula, which includes 21 species so far. Mature specimens of &lt;i&gt;Lophochaeta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignota&lt;/i&gt; Štolc, 1886 were also collected at some sites, and are used to supplement the limited description of the reproductive organs known for the species to date. Taxonomy of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lophochaeta&lt;/i&gt; Štolc, 1886 is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oligochaeta; &lt;i&gt;Gianius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Isochaetides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Lamadrilus&lt;/i&gt;; stygobiont; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oligochaeta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pilar</firstname>
          <lastname>Rodriguez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ainara</firstname>
          <lastname>Achurra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-39</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of suckermouth armored catfish, &lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus kwinti&lt;/i&gt; (Siluriformes: Loricariidae) from the Coppename River drainage, Central Suriname Nature Reserve, Suriname</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of suckermouth armored catfish, &lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kwinti,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Coppename River, Suriname. It can be diagnosed from all other described &lt;i&gt;Pseudancistrus&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination of characters: dentary papillae absent, mid-dorsal plate row complete, coloration mottled or with bars, hypertrophied odontodes along edge of snout, and weakly evertible cheek plates. It is only known from the Coppename River drainage within the Central Suriname Nature Reserve, a United Nations World Heritage Site, and one of the most pristine environments remaining on the planet. Mining, increased fishing pressure, and tourism threaten to change the region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Guiana Shield; Kwinti; Aquatic Rapid Assessment Program</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Guiana Shield</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Willink</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jan</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mol</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Barry</firstname>
          <lastname>Chernoff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius kadleci &lt;/i&gt;(Cyprinodontiformes: Nothobranchiidae), a new species of annual killifish from central Mozambique</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kadleci,&lt;/i&gt; a new African annual killifish species, is described from the drainages of the Save, Gorongose, Pungwe and Zangue Rivers in the Sofala Province of central Mozambique. &lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kadleci&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furzeri&lt;/i&gt; from which it is distinguished by colouration (red pelvic fins, red lips, more extensive red colouration on body) and morphology (larger distance between pectoral and pelvic fins, shorter anal and dorsal fins, and shorter base of the anal fin). The currently known distribution of these two species is allopatric, with the &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kadleci&lt;/i&gt; range north of the &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furzeri&lt;/i&gt; range. &lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kadleci&lt;/i&gt; occurs sympatrically with &lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orthonotus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Nothobranchius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rachovii,&lt;/i&gt; from which it can clearly be distinguished by different colour patterns of the fins and body, head shape and morphometric characteristics. A total of 12 populations were recorded between the northern bank of the Save River and southern bank of the Zambezi during collection trips in February 2008 and February 2009.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Save River; Beira region; Sofala Province; Zambezi; Limpopo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Save River</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martin</firstname>
          <lastname>Reichard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lithodes formosae&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of king crab from Taiwan (Crustacea: Decapoda: Lithodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of king crab is described from Taiwan, &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The new species resembles &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispina&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1971, from Japan, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacantha&lt;/i&gt; Macpherson, 1991, from French Polynesia, and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi&lt;/i&gt; Macpherson &amp; Chan, 2008, from Guam, in having long dorsal spines in adults, though it is most similar to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosae&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from the aforementioned species primarily by differing branchial spine arrangement and proportional spine length. Comparison of partial cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) gene sequences from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulayi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longispina&lt;/i&gt; supports the specific status of the new species. Six species of Lithodidae are known from Taiwan, of which &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the first to be described as new from Taiwan.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anomura; Lithodidae; &lt;i&gt;Lithodes&lt;/i&gt;; king crabs; new species; western Pacific Ocean; COI</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anomura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shane</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ahyong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
