<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2352.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Feb. 2010</title>
    <volume>2352</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-02-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of Axiidae (Crustacea: Decapoda: Axiidea) from deep-water off Taiwan, with description of a new genus</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">One new genus and five new species of axiid burrowing shrimps are described from deep-waters around Taiwan: &lt;i&gt;Formosaxius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsum&lt;/i&gt; n. gen., n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Ambiaxius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;propinquus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp., &lt;i&gt;Calastacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus&lt;/i&gt; n. sp.; &lt;i&gt;Eiconaxius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubrirostris&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kensleyi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. The new genus, &lt;i&gt;Formosaxius,&lt;/i&gt; appears closest to &lt;i&gt;Bouvieraxius&lt;/i&gt; Sakai &amp; de Saint Laurent, 1989 in the arrangement and armature of the gastric carinae on the carapace and the possession of pleurobranchs, but the presence of appendices internae on the third to fifth pleopods readily separates the new genus from &lt;i&gt;Bouvieraxius.&lt;/i&gt; Affinities of the other four new species are also discussed. This study raises the number of species of Axiidae known from Taiwan to 13.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Axiidea; Axiidae; new genus; new species; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng-Jiau</firstname>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Marphysa &lt;/i&gt;Quatrefages, 1865 (Polychaeta: Eunicida: Eunicidae) from northern Australia and a review of similar taxa from the Indowest Pacific, including the genus &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta &lt;/i&gt;Kinberg, 1865</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic survey of &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; species (Polychaeta: Eunicida: Eunicidae) from coastal regions of northern Australia including recently collected specimens from a fish farm near Darwin, yielded three species: &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mullawa&lt;/i&gt; Hutchings &amp; Karageorgopolous, 2003, a first record from northern Australia; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mossambica&lt;/i&gt; (Peters, 1854; was &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mossambica),&lt;/i&gt; first confirmed record from Australia; and a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fauchaldi.&lt;/i&gt; The new species was recorded from intertidal muddy shores as well as in the sediments of fish farm ponds, where it was extremely abundant. It is characterised by a unique combination of chaetal features. A newly proposed informal subgroup of &lt;i&gt;Marphysa,&lt;/i&gt; the Teretiuscula-group, is erected to contain the new species and other &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; species that share the possession of compound spinigerous chaetae in anterior parapodia only and the peculiar behaviour of encapsulating embryos in jelly cocoons. Morphologically, the new species falls between a group of &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; species having only compound spinigers and the recently resurrected genus &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta,&lt;/i&gt; which completely lacks compound chaetae. The discovery of this new species necessitated a re-evaluation of the morphological features of &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; species lacking falcigers, in particular homology of fan chaetae, the only apparent synapomorphy of &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta.&lt;/i&gt; Fan chaetae appear to be a specialised type of pectinate chaetae, which are found also in species of &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; including the new species. Based on this finding, and an evaluation of other characters, &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta&lt;/i&gt; is returned to synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Marphysa.&lt;/i&gt; Further, an analysis of size-related variation of key morphological characters in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mossambica&lt;/i&gt; and comparison with those in the types of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novaehollandiae&lt;/i&gt; (Kinberg, 1865; formerly &lt;i&gt;Nauphanta)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;simplex&lt;/i&gt; Treadwell, 1922, indicated that both species should be synonymised with &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mossambica.&lt;/i&gt; A key is provided to identify &lt;i&gt;Marphysa&lt;/i&gt; species of the Indo-west Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Annelida; taxonomy; systematics; Barra bloodworm; aquaculture; fish farm</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Annelida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christopher</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Glasby</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pat</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hutchings</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-45</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A colorful new species of insular rock gecko (&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis &lt;/i&gt;Strauch 1887) from southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of endemic, insular &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; is described from Hon Khoai Island, Ca Mau Province, Ngoc Hien District, 18 km off the southern tip of the Ca Mu Peninsula in southern Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psychedelica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the most uniquely colored of all southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in that both sexes and all age classes have bright orange forelimbs, forelegs, hands and feet; a bright orange tail; a dense, yellow reticulum on the neck overlying thick, black, longitudinal lines; and a blue-gray to light purple trunk bearing yellow transverse bars on bright-orange flanks. It also differs from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in aspects of size and squamation. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;psychedelica&lt;/i&gt; is the third insular endemic species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; from Vietnam and brings the total number of species in Vietnam to six. Its occurrence on one of the 92 islands in Rach Gia Bay underscores the necessity for continued surveys of these poorly known islands that are beginning to show a surprising degree of endemism and diversity.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;psychedelica&lt;/i&gt;; Vietnam; Rach Gia Bay; insular endemic; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ngo</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Tri</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jesse</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic Review of the perciform fish genus &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius &lt;/i&gt;from the east coast of southern Africa, with description of a new species and designation of a neotype for &lt;i&gt;Serranus sebastoides &lt;/i&gt;Castelnau, 1861</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; Gill, 1862 comprises ten putative valid species occurring in shallow warm-temperate waters of the Southern Hemisphere: South America (coasts of Ecuador, Peru, Chile, Brazil, and Argentina) southern Africa (Namibia and South Africa), southern Australia, New Zealand, Lord Howe, Norfolk, Kermadec and Easter, and Sala y Gómez islands. Two species: &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sebastoides&lt;/i&gt; (Castelnau, 1861) and &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; sp are known from shallow waters of the east coast of South Africa (Heemstra and Randall, 1986). The latter taxon, previously known from a brief description of a single specimen, is here described from 23 specimens and named &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joanae.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sebastoides&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed from 13 specimens and compared with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joanae&lt;/i&gt; and species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; known from South America and Australia. A neotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Serranus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sebastoides&lt;/i&gt; Castelnau, 1861, as the two syntypes are apparently lost.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">South Africa; &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;joanae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Acanthistius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sebastoides&lt;/i&gt;; new marine fish species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">South Africa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Phillip</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Heemstra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
