<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2354.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Feb. 2010</title>
    <volume>2354</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A revision of the Central American species related to &lt;i&gt;Anolis pentaprion &lt;/i&gt;with the resurrection of &lt;i&gt;A. beckeri &lt;/i&gt;and the description of a new species (Squamata: Polychrotidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Based on differences in coloration, morphometrics, and scalation, I recognize seven species of anoles related to &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; in Central America: &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri&lt;/i&gt; (southeastern Mexico to northern Nicaragua), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristifer&lt;/i&gt; (Pacific lowlands of Chiapas to central Guatemala), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fungosus&lt;/i&gt; (Caribbean premontane zone from central Costa Rica to western Panama), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; (Caribbean lowlands of southern Nicaragua to northwestern Colombia, also on Pacific versant in central and eastern Panama), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;salvini&lt;/i&gt; (Pacific premontane and lower montane zones from central Costa Rica to western Panama), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;utilensis&lt;/i&gt; (restricted to Isla de Utila, Honduras), and a new species (from the Pacific lowlands of Costa Rica and western Panama) described herein. The new species differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; by having a red male dewlap with few large, widely spaced gorgetal scales scattered across the dewlap (pink with purple pigment between rows of gorgetals, and with regular rows of numerous small, narrowly spaced gorgetal scales in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion).&lt;/i&gt; Furthermore, I resurrect the name &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri&lt;/i&gt; Boulenger for the &lt;i&gt;pentaprion-like&lt;/i&gt; populations of anoles distributed from southeastern Mexico to northern Nicaragua. &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; most obviously in the dorsal tail scalation (a serrated caudal crest present in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; versus no such crest in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri)&lt;/i&gt; and dewlap scalation (gorgetal rows with 17–25 narrowly spaced scales in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion&lt;/i&gt; versus gorgetal rows with 4–10 widely spaced scales in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri).&lt;/i&gt; Finally, SMF 83608 is proposed as the neotype for &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion.&lt;/i&gt; I provide standardized descriptions of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beckeri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentaprion,&lt;/i&gt; and the new species described herein.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Reptilia; Squamata; Polychrotidae; &lt;i&gt;Anolis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Neotype Designation; Central America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Reptilia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gunther</firstname>
          <lastname>Köhler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of water mites (Acari: Hydrachnidia) from Malaysia, with descriptions of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New records of water mites (Acari: Hydrachnidia) from Malaysia are presented. Three species new to science, &lt;i&gt;Torrenticola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haliki,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Monatractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cameronensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Atractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cameronensis&lt;/i&gt; are described; first records are given for &lt;i&gt;Monatractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parviventris&lt;/i&gt; (K. Viets, 1935) and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roseus&lt;/i&gt; (Lundblad, 1941).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; new species; new records; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Pesic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Harry</firstname>
          <lastname>Smit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-34</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and subspecies of Ochlesidae Stebbing, 1910 (Amphipoda: Gammaridea) from the Okhotsk Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new amphipod species &lt;i&gt;Antarctodius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;noncarinatus&lt;/i&gt; and new subspecies &lt;i&gt;Odius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cassigerous&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ochoticus&lt;/i&gt; from the Okhotsk Sea are described. The key to the amphipod species of the genera &lt;i&gt;Antarctodius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Odius&lt;/i&gt; is given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphipoda; Ochlesidae; &lt;i&gt;Antarctodius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Odius&lt;/i&gt;; Okhotsk Sea; new species; new subspecies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphipoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vjacheslav</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Labay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the status and relationships of the gecko species &lt;i&gt;Gehyra barea &lt;/i&gt;Kopstein 1926, with description of new specimens and a range extension</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gehyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barea&lt;/i&gt; is a poorly known gecko species from the southern Banda Islands, Maluku Province, Indonesia, that has received scant attention since it was described in 1926. A combination of morphological characters distinguish the types of this species from all other described &lt;i&gt;Gehyra,&lt;/i&gt; and suggest that it is a distinct taxon. These same morphological characters occur in two recently collected specimens from the Raja Ampat Islands, just off the west coast of New Guinea, that we assign to this species, extending the known range of the taxon by over six hundred kilometres. We provide a revised and extended diagnosis and description of the species based on these new specimens. Morphological and genetic data from these specimens indicate &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barea&lt;/i&gt; is closely related to &lt;i&gt;Gehyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baliola&lt;/i&gt; from further east in southern New Guinea, and that these species form a clade with &lt;i&gt;Geyhra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oceanica.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Gehyra&lt;/i&gt; is a taxonomically challenging group, and the status of most species from the Melanesian region is in need of review.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Banda Islands; &lt;i&gt;Gehyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barea&lt;/i&gt;; Gekkonidae; New Guinea; Raja Ampat Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Banda Islands</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Oliver</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <lastname>Sistrom</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Burhan</firstname>
          <lastname>Tjaturadi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Keliopas</firstname>
          <lastname>Krey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <lastname>Richards</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-55</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the Paramo Tapaculo &lt;i&gt;Scytalopus canus &lt;/i&gt;Chapman (Aves: Rhinocryptidae), with description of a new subspecies from Ecuador and Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The nominate subspecies of the Paramo Tapaculo (Scytalopus &lt;i&gt;canus&lt;/i&gt; Chapman), which is restricted to high elevations of the Western Andes of Colombia, differs substantially in song from &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;c.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opacus&lt;/i&gt; from the Central Andes of Colombia, Ecuador, and northern Peru. In accordance with current taxonomy of the genus, which is primarily based on differences in song, we assign species rank to both taxa. Within &lt;i&gt;opacus,&lt;/i&gt; birds from southernmost Ecuador and northernmost Peru sing like northern &lt;i&gt;opacus&lt;/i&gt; but call differently. They are indistinguishable morphologically except for a white patch in the wing present in 10 out of 12 of the adult males of the southern population. We describe this population as a new taxon and rank it as a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opacus.&lt;/i&gt; Genetically, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canus,&lt;/i&gt; nominate &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opacus,&lt;/i&gt; and the new taxon are strongly differentiated (&gt;5% divergence in mtDNA); the first two appear to be sister taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt;; tapaculo; Andes; Colombia; species limits; suboscines</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scytalopus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Niels</firstname>
          <lastname>Krabbe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Daniel</middlename>
          <lastname>Cadena</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-66</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The untold story on the ecological and phylogenetic complexity of the Uruguayan reptile fauna</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Pincheira-Donoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
