<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2375.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Feb. 2010</title>
    <volume>2375</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the family Euryplacidae Stimpson, 1871 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Goneplacoidea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The family Euryplacidae Stimpson, 1871, traditionally included in the Goneplacidae MacLeay, 1838, is revised based on the examination of the type material of many of its species as well as unidentified and previously identified material from around the world. The revised family now consists of 31 species (including five that are described as new) belonging to 13 genera (including four that are described as new): &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; De Haan, 1835, with eight species, of which one is new; &lt;i&gt;Euryplax&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1859, with two species; &lt;i&gt;Frevillea&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards, 1880, with three species; &lt;i&gt;Henicoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; with five species of which three are new; &lt;i&gt;Heteroplax&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, monotypic; &lt;i&gt;Machaerus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1818, with two species; &lt;i&gt;Nancyplax&lt;/i&gt; Lemaitre, García-Gómez, von Sternberg &amp; Campos, 2001, monotypic; &lt;i&gt;Platyozius&lt;/i&gt; Borradaile, 1902, monotypic; &lt;i&gt;Psopheticoides&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1969, monotypic; &lt;i&gt;Systroplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; monotypic; &lt;i&gt;Trissoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; with two species, of which one is new; &lt;i&gt;Trizocarcinus&lt;/i&gt; Rathbun, 1914, with two species; &lt;i&gt;Villoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; monotypic; and &lt;i&gt;Xenocrate&lt;/i&gt; Ng &amp; Castro, 2007, monotypic. The genus &lt;i&gt;Platyozius&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosensis&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1974, are removed from the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alcocki&lt;/i&gt; Serène, in Serène &amp; Lohavanijaya, 1973, respectively. Neotypes are selected for &lt;i&gt;Heteroplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentata&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, and &lt;i&gt;Pilumnoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcatifrons&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, two species described from Hong Kong that have a confusing taxonomic history. A neotype is also selected for &lt;i&gt;Euryplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nitida&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1859, described from the Florida Keys. Seven nominal species described by other authors were found to be junior subjective synonyms for other species: &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;affinis&lt;/i&gt; Haswell, 1882, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costata&lt;/i&gt; Yang &amp; Sun 1979, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haswelli&lt;/i&gt; Campbell 1969, and &lt;i&gt;Pseudorhombila&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcatifrons&lt;/i&gt; var. &lt;i&gt;australiensis&lt;/i&gt; Miers, 1884, of &lt;i&gt;Trissoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dentata&lt;/i&gt; (Stimpson, 1858); &lt;i&gt;Galene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laevimanus&lt;/i&gt; (Lucas, in Jacquinot &amp; Lucas, 1853) of &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dorsalis&lt;/i&gt; (White, 1849); &lt;i&gt;Heteroplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nagasakiensis&lt;/i&gt; Sakai, 1934, of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;transversa&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858; and &lt;i&gt;Pilumnoplax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sulcatifrons&lt;/i&gt; Stimpson, 1858, of &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crenata&lt;/i&gt; (De Haan, 1835). Eight euryplacid genera are exclusively found in the Indo-West Pacific region (except one species introduced in the Mediterranean), one is exclusive to each the Eastern Atlantic and Tropical Eastern Pacific regions, three to the Western Atlantic region, and one genus has both Western Atlantic and Tropical Eastern Pacific species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Crustacea; Brachyura; Goneplacoidea; Euryplacidae; new genera; new species; revision; &lt;i&gt;Eucrate&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euryplax&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Frevillea&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Henicoplax&lt;/i&gt; n. gen.; &lt;i&gt;Heteroplax&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Machaerus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Nancyplax&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Platyozius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Psopheticoides&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Systroplax&lt;/i&gt; n. gen.; &lt;i&gt;Trissoplax&lt;/i&gt; n. gen. &lt;i&gt;Trizocarcinus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Villoplax&lt;/i&gt; n. gen.; &lt;i&gt;Xenocrate&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Castro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-130</pages>
        <date_published>2010-02-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
