<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2390.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2390</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of chydorid cladocerans of subfamily Aloninae (Branchipoda: Anomopoda: Chydoridae) from Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of Aloninae cladocera from Central and South Brazil are described. Two of them, &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tupinamba&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; were previously recorded from the area as European taxa &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harpae&lt;/i&gt; (Baird, 1834) and &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis&lt;/i&gt; (O.F. Müller, 1776), respectively. &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tupinamba&lt;/i&gt; differs from the other species of &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; in smaller size, long posterior setae of the valves, shorter and wider postabdomen, short setules near the base of postabdominal claw, long apical spines of antenna, and peculiar morphology of limb IV exopodite. &lt;i&gt;Alona&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yara&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadrangularis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kolweizii&lt;/i&gt; Van Damme &amp; Dumont, 2008 in the number of ventral setules on ventral face of limb I, from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boliviana&lt;/i&gt; Sinev et Coronel, 2006 in the shape of the body and postabdomen, narrow labral keel, and absence of projections on epipodites IV–V. The third new species, &lt;i&gt;Celsinotum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candango&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.n.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all other species of the genus in proportions of postabdomen. It differs from Australian species (C. &lt;i&gt;hypsophilum&lt;/i&gt; Frey, 1991, &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parooensis&lt;/i&gt; Frey, 1991, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platamoides&lt;/i&gt; Frey, 1991) in a less developed dorsal keel, lateral head pores located close to midline, longer spine on basal segment of antennal exopodite, and in the presence of extremely large projections on exopodites IV–V. &lt;i&gt;Celsinotum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candango&lt;/i&gt; differs from Brazilian &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laticaudatum&lt;/i&gt; Smirnov &amp; Santos-Silva, 1995 in a shorter spine on basal segment of antenna exopodite, in the shape of postabdomen and in morphology of postabdominal denticles. At present, Aloninae fauna of Brazil includes 35 species, and true diversity is undoubtedly higher, with more new species to be expected in the country.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladocera; Brazil; Aloninae; new species; morphology; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladocera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Artem</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lourdes</firstname>
          <middlename>M. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Elmoor-Loureiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New and little known mollusks from ancient chemosynthetic environments</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Twelve mollusk species from late Jurassic to Oligocene cold seep deposits are described and illustrated. Nine of them are new, two have already been named, two new genera are introduced, and one species is described only in open nomenclature. &lt;i&gt;Puncturella&lt;/i&gt; (sensu lato) &lt;i&gt;mcleani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Fissurella&lt;/i&gt; (sensu lato) &lt;i&gt;bipunctata&lt;/i&gt; Stanton, 1895 are the only confirmed fissurellids in fossil cold seeps. The sutilizonid &lt;i&gt;Triassurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;goederti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is similar to the modern ventinhabiting &lt;i&gt;Sutilizona&lt;/i&gt; and the Late Triassic shallow-water reef-inhabitant &lt;i&gt;Triassurella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carnica.&lt;/i&gt; A smooth, late Jurassic neritid is the oldest neritid from fossil seeps and probably represents an independent neritid radiation into the seep environment, without close phylogenetic connection to the modern &lt;i&gt;Bathynerita.&lt;/i&gt; The four new abyssochrysoid caenogastropods &lt;i&gt;Humptulipsia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macsotayi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hokkaidoconcha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novacula,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paskentana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anistratenkorum,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;umbilicata&lt;/i&gt; significantly extend the stratigraphic and geographic ranges of these apparently seep-restricted genera. Four bivalves are described, including the new modiomorphid &lt;i&gt;Caspiconcha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubani&lt;/i&gt; from the early Cretaceous and the new bathymodioline &lt;i&gt;Bathymodiolus&lt;/i&gt; (s.l.) &lt;i&gt;palmarensis&lt;/i&gt; from the Oligocene. Among the lucinids, the oldest seep-inhabiting lucinid (late Jurassic) is described as &lt;i&gt;Beauvoisina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.;&lt;/b&gt; the new genus &lt;i&gt;Cubatea&lt;/i&gt; is introduced for an Oligocene lucinid from Cuba. It is suggested that &lt;i&gt;Caspiconcha,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Paskentana,&lt;/i&gt; and hokkaidoconchids constitute the core of a seeprestricted fauna that inhabited seeps worldwide from (at least) late Jurassic to early Cretaceous time. These taxa are, at the family level, phylogenetically unrelated to the modern vent and seep fauna.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cold seeps; deep-sea; Gastropoda; Bivalvia; Late Jurassic; Early Cretaceous; Oligocene</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cold seeps; deep-sea; Gastropoda; Bivalvia; Late Jurassic; Early Cretaceous; Oligocene</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Steffen</firstname>
          <lastname>Kiel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kathleen</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campbell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <lastname>Gaillard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny-based species delimitation of southern Philippines bent-toed geckos and a new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from western Mindanao and the Sulu Archipelago</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Using a combination of fixed morphological character differences, mitochondrial DNA sequence data, and an estimate of phylogeny as our guide, we describe a new species of bent-toed gekkonid lizard (Genus: &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus)&lt;/i&gt; from southwestern Mindanao Island, and northeastern portions of the Sulu Archipelago, southern Philippines. The new species resembles &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulatus,&lt;/i&gt; but differs from this and all other congeners by characteristics of external morphology, color pattern, and body size. In addition, the new species is distinguished from congeners by marked genetic divergence and reciprocal monophyly of mitochondrial DNA sequences. The new species is common in pristine, low elevation gallery forests throughout Pasonanca Natural Park, Zamboanga Peninsula, southwestern Mindanao Island, and the northeastern portions of the Sulu Archipelago.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New species; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus;&lt;/i&gt; geckos; Mindanao; Pasonanca Natural Park; Philippines; Zamboanga</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New species; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus;&lt;/i&gt; geckos; Mindanao; Pasonanca Natural Park; Philippines; Zamboanga</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luke</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Welton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cameron</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Siler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arvin</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Diesmos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafe</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brown</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
