<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2393.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2393</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus rodickae &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Acari: Oribatida: Cymbaeremaeidae) associated with temporary rock pools in Georgia, with key to &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; species in eastern USA and Canada</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new and apparently endemic oribatid mite—Scapheremaeus &lt;i&gt;rodickae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Cymbaeremaeidae)—is described based on adult specimens collected from mosses (Grimmia &lt;i&gt;laevigata)&lt;/i&gt; growing on shallow soils in weathering depressions (rock pools) on granitic outcrops of the Georgia (USA) Piedmont. &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginalis&lt;/i&gt; (Banks) is considered a senior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marmoratus&lt;/i&gt; (Berlese). A diagnostic key to the five currently recognized species of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; known from the eastern USA and Canada is presented, as are new distribution records. &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palustris&lt;/i&gt; (Sellnick) is the most common and widely distributed species in this region and is the only &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; species known to have a trans-Atlantic distribution; European populations have a slightly different prodorsal microsculpture.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Piedmont; granite outcrops; oribatid mite; soil mite; moss fauna; epilithic fauna; lithotelmata</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Piedmont</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roy</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Norton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Franklin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Crossley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lizards at the end of the world: Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus &lt;/i&gt;of the &lt;i&gt;patagonicus &lt;/i&gt;clade (Squamata, Liolaemidae) revealed in southern Patagonia of Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Liolaemidae radiation has resulted in three genera whose patterns of evolutionary diversification exhibit dramatic differences. Two of these lineages, &lt;i&gt;Ctenoblepharys&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus,&lt;/i&gt; lay at the extremes, being a monotypic genus and one of the most extraordinary adaptive radiations among vertebrates, respectively. In &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus,&lt;/i&gt; in contrast, 22 species are known, all characterized by similar ecological niches and life-history patterns. The &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; genus consists of two major clades, &lt;i&gt;flagellifer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;patagonicus,&lt;/i&gt; restricted to Andean-Patagonian environments in Argentina and Chile. While the former lineage occurs primarily at the northern areas of the genus distribution, the latter mostly occupies central and southern Patagonia. In this study, we report evidence to support the existence of two new species of the genus belonging to the austral clade &lt;i&gt;patagonicus.&lt;/i&gt; These new taxa, &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castillensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;videlai,&lt;/i&gt; occur close to the southernmost distributional limit known for the entire genus. At these austral latitudes, only two other species of the genus, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indistinctus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus,&lt;/i&gt; have been found. Therefore, the two new species reported herein reveal a higher species richness at these cold and harsh South American environments, where the predominant lineage is &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus.&lt;/i&gt; As in the rest of the species of the &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; genus, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castillensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;videlai&lt;/i&gt; are saxicolous, herbivorous, and viviparous, as revealed by our field and lab observations. A number of signals support the idea that these two &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; populations are the result of speciation events. Essentially, both are strongly isolated by hundreds of kilometers from most species of the &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; clade, which precludes dynamic gene exchange among them, while substantial divergence in their patterns of coloration differentiate them from the two geographically closest species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indistinctus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus,&lt;/i&gt; and from each other. The differences in coloration are not, however, strongly accentuated between the sexes, being monochromatic in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;castillensis&lt;/i&gt; and moderately dichromatic in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;videlai.&lt;/i&gt; Interestingly, juveniles &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;videlai&lt;/i&gt; exhibit also these signals of adult sexual dichromatism. Finally, the results reported in this study increase &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt; species richness up to 24 species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt;; Liolaemidae; Patagonia; rock-dwelling lizards; Argentina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Alejandro</middlename>
          <lastname>Scolaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Pincheira-Donoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Morphological and molecular assessment of the &lt;i&gt;Diplodactylus savagei &lt;/i&gt;species complex in the Pilbara region, Western Australia, with a description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The gecko &lt;i&gt;Diplodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;savagei&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to the rocky Pilbara and Ashburton regions of Western Australia. Recent collections have enabled a reappraisal of morphological and genetic diversity within the taxon. Analysis of 1200 base pairs of the mtDNA gene &lt;i&gt;ND2&lt;/i&gt; and surrounding tRNA found strong support for three lineages within &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;savagei:&lt;/i&gt; an eastern clade (which includes the type location of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;savagei&lt;/i&gt; from Marble Bar), a southern clade and a north-central clade. The eastern and southern clades did not differ in morphology or dorsal pattern. Although there are several subtle differences in morphological characters between the eastern and southern clades compared to the north-central form, there were clear differences in dorsal pattern with the north-central forms having finer, widely-scattered spots, a pale dorsal border to the loreal stripe and a gradual transition between the dorsal and ventral colouration. We describe the north-central form as a new species, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galaxias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; based on the distinctiveness of its colour pattern, subtle morphological differences, mtDNA divergence and maintenance of these differences at the edge of the western Hamersley Range where the north-central and southern clades come into contact.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cryptic species; Diplodactylidae; gecko; lizard; &lt;i&gt;ND2&lt;/i&gt;; tRNA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cryptic species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Doughty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mitzy</firstname>
          <lastname>Pepper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Scott</middlename>
          <lastname>Keogh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-45</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius dawkinsi&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of Tardigrada (Eutardigrada: Hypsibiidae) from the Costa Rican highlands, with the key to the genus &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new eutardigrade from Costa Rican highlands, &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dawkinsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described and figured. The new species is most similar to &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zyxiglobus&lt;/i&gt; but differs from it mainly by the presence of gibbosities I c and L IV , and also by the absence of lunules on claws. Apart from the new species description, we propose a unified system of numbering and identifying cuticular gibbosities. Moreover, using two independent traits (the number of placoids and the presence/absence of cuticular gibbosities), we define four groups of species within the genus &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; (doryphorus, &lt;i&gt;evelinae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vietnamensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;zappalai&lt;/i&gt; group) and provide a diagnostic key to all known &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Doryphoribius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dawkinsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;evelinae&lt;/i&gt; group; gibbosities; diagnostic key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Łukasz</firstname>
          <lastname>Michalczyk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Łukasz</firstname>
          <lastname>Kaczmarek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New localities of endangered Chinese turtles from museum specimens and the practical and ethical challenges using and reporting natural history collection data</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ge-Xia</firstname>
          <lastname>Qiao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
