<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2405.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2405</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">North West Pacific deep-sea barnacles (Cirripedia, Thoracica) collected by the TAIWAN expeditions, with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Taiwan is a large island in north western Pacific waters with the sea floor connecting to two major deep-sea basins, the eastern waters facing the Pacific Ocean (to 4000 m depth) and linking to the Philippine Basin, whilst south western waters are associated with the South China Sea Basin (up to 1000 m). Previously, the biodiversity of Taiwanese deep-sea barnacles had not been studied extensively, due to a lack of deep-sea expeditions and sampling. Recently, several TAIWAN deep-sea cruises investigated the biodiversity of the deep-sea fauna of Taiwan and sampling was conducted to depths of 4000 m. The present study reports on the biodiversity of the deep-sea barnacles of Taiwan, a total of 18 species. One species was previously recorded from Taiwanese waters and 17 are new records, including two new species belong to the genera &lt;i&gt;Litoscalpellum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Altiverruca.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Benny</firstname>
          <middlename>K. K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Romanus</firstname>
          <middlename>Edy</middlename>
          <lastname>Prabowo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kwen-Shen</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-22</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Metadynomene tuamotu&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of dynomenid crab from French Polynesia (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A large dynomenid specimen from the Tuamotu Archipelago previously thought to belong to &lt;i&gt;Metadynomene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tanensis&lt;/i&gt; (Yokoya, 1933) is shown to be a new species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuamotu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Metadynomene&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tanensis&lt;/i&gt; is a widespread Western Pacific species occurring from Japan to New Zealand; while &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuamotu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; joins &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;devaneyi&lt;/i&gt; (Takeda, 1977) as the second species of this genus known from French Polynesia. A key to the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Crustacea; Brachyura; Dynomenidae; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Colin</firstname>
          <middlename>L</middlename>
          <lastname>Mclay</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of the male of the spider &lt;i&gt;Dubiaranea difficilis&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae: Linyphiidae), with new records and modeling of its potential geographic distribution</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The male of &lt;i&gt;Dubiaranea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;difficilis&lt;/i&gt; (Mello-Leitão 1944) is described and illustrated for the first time. New geographic records of this species are provided, and its potential distribution is modeled using MAXENT. The actual and potential distribution of &lt;i&gt;Dubiaranea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;difficilis&lt;/i&gt; proved to be much larger than the hitherto known records. This species inhabits at least in three ecoregional sectors in Argentina (northwestern area, central Sierras, and the Pampas), and is also likely that inhabits in Brazil and Bolivia. Possible causes of its wide and environmentally heterogeneous distribution are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Argentina; Dubiaraneinae; Neotropical region; spider taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Argentina; Dubiaraneinae; Neotropical region; spider taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gonzalo</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rubio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Everton</firstname>
          <middlename>N. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Acosta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Polydactylus luparensis, &lt;/i&gt;a new species of threadfin (Perciformes: Polynemidae) from the Batang Lupar River, Sarawak, Borneo, Malaysia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of large-sized brackishwater threadfin, &lt;i&gt;Polydactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luparensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Batang Lupar River in Sarawak, Malaysia, Borneo on the basis of 5 specimens (610–715 mm standard length). The new species can be distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Polydactylus&lt;/i&gt; by having 8 dorsal-fin spines, first spine tiny, second spine very strong (its width more than 5 times the width of remaining spines); 13 second dorsal-fin soft rays; 11 anal-fin soft rays; 12 pectoralfin rays, its length 22–24% (mean 23%) of SL, posterior tip not reaching a vertical through posterior tip of depressed pelvic fin; 6 pectoral filaments, fourth or fifth filament longest, its length 77–85% (mean 81%) of SL, posterior tip extending slightly beyond caudal-fin base; pored lateral-lined scales 67–75 (mean 71); lateral line unbranched, extending onto upper end of lower caudal-fin lobe; 6 scale rows above lateral line, 8 below; 14 gill rakers on upper limb, 18 on lower limb, 32 in total; occipital profile concave; posterior margin of maxilla extending considerably beyond a vertical through posterior margin of adipose eyelid; depth of posterior margin of maxilla 4–5% (mean 5%) of SL, greater than orbit diameter; well-developed swimbladder present; basal half of third to sixth pectoral filament white, becoming black distally. &lt;i&gt;Polydactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luparensis&lt;/i&gt; is currently known only from the mouth of the Batang Lupar River.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Polynemidae; &lt;i&gt;Polydactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luparensis&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Batang Lupar River; Borneo</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Polynemidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pek</firstname>
          <middlename>Khiok Annie</middlename>
          <lastname>Lim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Motomura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Albert</firstname>
          <middlename>Chuan</middlename>
          <lastname>Gambang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
