<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2413.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2413</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A basal parvicursorine (Theropoda: Alvarezsauridae) from the Upper Cretaceous of China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new alvarezsaurid theropod, &lt;i&gt;Xixianykus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhangi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a partial postcranial skeleton collected from the Upper Cretaceous Majiacun Formation of Xixia County, Henan Province. The new taxon can be diagnosed by the following autapomorphies: sacral rib-transverse process complexes and zygapophyses fused to form separate anterior and posterior laminae; distinct fossa dorsal to antitrochanter on lateral surface of ilium; short ridge along posterior surface of pubic shaft near proximal end; distinct depression on lateral surface of ischium near proximal end; sharp groove along posterior surface of ischium; distal end of femur with transversely narrow ectocondylar tuber that extends considerable distance proximally as sharp ridge; transversely narrow tibial cnemial crest with sharp, ridgelike distal half; lateral margin of tibiotarsus forms step near distal end; fibula with substantial extension of proximal articular surface onto posterior face of posteriorly curving shaft; distal tarsals and metatarsals co-ossified to form tarsometatarsus; and sharp flange along anteromedial margin of metatarsal IV near proximal end. Cladistic analysis places this taxon as a basal parvicursorine within the Alvarezsauridae, a position consistent with the presence of several incipiently developed parvicursorine features in this taxon and also with its relatively early geological age. A brief analysis of vertebral functional morphology, together with data from the hindlimb, suggests that parvicursorines represent extreme cursors among non-avian dinosaurs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Late Cretaceous; Majiacun Formation; Parvicursorinae; Theropoda; cursoriality</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Late Cretaceous</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Xing</firstname>
          <lastname>Xu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>De-You</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Corwin</firstname>
          <lastname>Sullivan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>W. E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Feng-Lu</firstname>
          <lastname>Han</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rong-Hao</firstname>
          <lastname>Yan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fu-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Du</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A third new &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Phong Nha-Ke Bang National Park, Truong Son Range, Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a third cryptic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; from Phong Nha – Ke Bang National Park, Quang Binh Province, Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roesleri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from the remaining Indochinese bent-toed geckos by a combination of the following characters: size small, with a maximum SVL of 75.3 mm; dorsal pattern consisting of dark nuchal band and 4–5 sometimes irregularly shaped dark transversal bands between limbs; ventrals in 34–40 longitudinal rows at midbody; continuous series of 20–28 precloacal and femoral pores in males; subcaudal scales transversally enlarged. It is the 15 th new reptilian taxon described as new from the karst forests of Phong Nha – Ke Bang National Park in the past decade. In addition, it is the 19 th species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; known from Vietnam and the third &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; occurring in sympatry in the karst forests of Phong Nha – Ke Bang National Park.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roesleri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Phong Nha – Ke Bang National Park; Quang Binh Province; Vietnam; morphology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roesleri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Phong Nha – Ke Bang National Park</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roman</firstname>
          <lastname>Nazarov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nikolai</firstname>
          <lastname>Orlov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Truong</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thanh</firstname>
          <middlename>Ngoc</middlename>
          <lastname>Vu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kien</firstname>
          <middlename>Ngoc</middlename>
          <lastname>Dang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tri</firstname>
          <middlename>Huy</middlename>
          <lastname>Dinh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmitz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new dendrobatid frog (Anura: Dendrobatidae: &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt;) from the Orinoquian rainforest, southern Venezuela</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Venezuelan Guayana; it is the 21 st described species of &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt; from the Guiana Shield, and the 15 th from Venezuela. This species inhabits rainforest on granitic substrate on the northwestern edge of the Guiana Shield (Estado Amazonas, Venezuela). The new species is distinguished from congeners by sexual dimorphism, its unique male color pattern (including two bright orange parotoid marks and two orange paracloacal spots on dark brown background), call characteristics and other morphological features. Though to the new species is known only from the northwestern edge of the Guiana Shield, its distribution may be more extensive, as there are no significant biogeographic barriers isolating the type locality from the granitic lowlands of Venezuela.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Dendrobatidae; &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt;; Venezuela; Guiana Shield</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>César</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrio-Amorós</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>Carlos</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olga</firstname>
          <lastname>Jovanovic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Second contribution to the knowledge of water mites from the Comoros, with the description of one new species (Acari: Hydrachnidia)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New records of water mites (Acari: Hydrachnidia) from the Comoros are presented. One species new to science, &lt;i&gt;Africasia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;comorosensis&lt;/i&gt; is described; first records are given for &lt;i&gt;Torrenticola&lt;/i&gt; sp. and &lt;i&gt;Atractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thoracatus&lt;/i&gt; Koenike, 1898.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acari; Hydrachnidia; new species; Comoros</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acari</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Harry</firstname>
          <lastname>Smit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Pesic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nathalie</firstname>
          <lastname>Mary-Sasal</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Eulimnadia &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea; Branchiopoda; Diplostraca; Spinicaudata) from North America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eulimnadia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graniticola&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. from Stone Mountain, Georgia, and the Florida Keys, USA, is defined primarily on molecular characters and egg morphology. Ecological, reproductive and life history data are provided. This species is the second species of branchiopod crustacean reported from Stone Mountain more closely related to the South American fauna than to its North American congeners.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clam shrimp; eggs; vernal pools; rock outcrop pools; Georgia; Florida</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clam shrimp</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>Christopher</middlename>
          <lastname>Rogers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Weeks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Walter</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoeh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
