<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2414.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Mar. 2010</title>
    <volume>2414</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Key to the Species of Cosmetidae (Arachnida, Opiliones) of Central America, with Notes on Penis Morphology and Sexual Dimorphisms</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">To facilitate identification of harvestmen of the family Cosmetidae in Central America, we developed dichotomous keys that distinguish the 33 known genera and the 133 described species for this region. Couplets are based upon characters found in the literature and examinations of museum specimens. Important characters include the number of tarsomeres on leg I, armature of the dorsal scutum, free tergites and legs, as well as the coloration and relative length of the body and legs. In addition, we provide a summary of sexually dimorphic features and comment on the potential usefulness of penis morphology and coloration as characters for distinguishing taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arachnida; Central America; Cosmetidae; Laniatores; Opiliones; taxonomic key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arachnida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Victor</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Townsend</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <lastname>Víquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vanzandt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Proud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first pararchaeid spider (Araneae: Pararchaeidae) from New Caledonia, with a discussion on spinneret spigots and egg sac morphology in &lt;i&gt;Ozarchaea&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The first pararchaeid species to be recorded from outside Australia or New Zealand, &lt;i&gt;Flavarchaea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;humboldti&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from female specimens collected near the summit of Mont Humboldt, New Caledonia. Morphological and behavioural data are further described for Western Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Ozarchaea&lt;/i&gt; Rix, with the spinneret spigot morphology of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harveyi&lt;/i&gt; Rix imaged under a scanning electron microscope, and the egg sac of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;westraliensis&lt;/i&gt; Rix described for the first time. Pararchaeid spinnerets possess two major ampullate gland spigots on the anterior lateral spinnerets and no triad on the posterior lateral spinnerets; such a spinneret spigot arrangement does not support the placement of the Pararchaeidae in the superfamily Araneoidea, and further research is needed to test the phylogenetic position of this enigmatic family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Nouvelle Calédonie; Western Australia; spinnerets; spigots; egg sac; Palpimanoidea; Entelegynae; Araneoidea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rix</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Harvey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-40</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First record of &lt;i&gt;Myotis flavus &lt;/i&gt;(Chiroptera: Vespertilionidae) from mainland China and a reassessment of its taxonomic status</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Myotis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus,&lt;/i&gt; a synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus&lt;/i&gt; found in Taiwan, is reported for the first time for mainland China. We captured one bat in Jiangxi province in Southeast China and identified the taxon as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; based upon its external, cranial and baculum morphology. The uncorrected cytb sequence divergence between &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; from Jiangxi and specimen from Taiwan was only 0.61%, indicating intraspecific divergence. Both, morphological and genetic evidence indicated that the specimen from mainland China was a new locality record of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus.&lt;/i&gt; In contrast, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; from Jiangxi and from Taiwan exhibited 15.53–16.67% sequence divergence from samples of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus&lt;/i&gt; obtained from locations outside Taiwan, and they were not sister lineages. Therefore &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flavus&lt;/i&gt; should be recognized as a species from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus.&lt;/i&gt; In addition, the sequence similarity between &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watasei&lt;/i&gt; from Taiwan and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus&lt;/i&gt; from mainland China and their phylogenetic grouping strongly suggests that &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;watasei&lt;/i&gt; is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; Bats; Mainland China; Systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tinglei</firstname>
          <lastname>Jiang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Keping</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chenghan</firstname>
          <lastname>Chou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhenzhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Feng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-51</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of freshwater crab of the genus &lt;i&gt;Odontothelphusa &lt;/i&gt;Rodríguez, 1982, (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pseudothelphusidae) from Chiapas, Mexico</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of freshwater crab of the genus &lt;i&gt;Odontothelphusa&lt;/i&gt; is described. The specimens were collected from one tributary of the Malpaso Dam in northwestern Chiapas state, extending the geographical distribution of the genus to southwestern Mexico. The new species differs from its congeners by the presence of a basal rounded tubercle and a small acute spine near the pointed end of the strong proximomesial spine. The new species represents the seventh species in the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">freshwater crabs; new species Pseudothelphusidae; &lt;i&gt;Odontothelphusa&lt;/i&gt;; Chiapas; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">freshwater crabs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Luis</middlename>
          <lastname>Villalobos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anelli</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>García</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ernesto</firstname>
          <lastname>Velázquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">DNA barcoding of hermit crabs of genus &lt;i&gt;Clibanarius &lt;/i&gt;Dana, 1852 (Anomura: Diogenidae) in the Ryukyu Islands, southwestern Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The diogenid hermit crab genus &lt;i&gt;Clibanarius&lt;/i&gt; Dana, 1852 is a group of decapod crustaceans commonly found in tropical or subtropical shallow waters. The species of the genus are usually characterized by distinct color patterns in life, but the identification of colorless specimens preserved in ethanol is sometimes very difficult. DNA barcoding can facilitate species identification and recognition. In this study, we determined partial sequences of the cytochrome oxidase I (COI) gene of 11 &lt;i&gt;Clibanarius&lt;/i&gt; species commonly found in the intertidal zones of the Ryukyu Archipelago, southwestern Japan. The sequences can be used as nametags to distinguish each of the 11 species, as the data differ for each species. The COI gene sequences of &lt;i&gt;Clibanarius&lt;/i&gt; show an AT bias, especially in the third codon position (A+T = 76.2%), as has been reported for some other anomuran species. Phylogenetic analyses based on the sequences also offer some suggestions on the interspecific relationships of &lt;i&gt;Clibanarius.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Anomura; hermit crabs; COI; barcode; shallow water; Okinawa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mamiko</firstname>
          <lastname>Hirose</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Masayuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Osawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Euichi</firstname>
          <lastname>Hirose</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Honoured by taxon name—Robin John Tillyard</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Trevor</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Crosby</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-03-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
