<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2419.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Apr. 2010</title>
    <volume>2419</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-04-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Checklist of the Acanthocephala in wildlife vertebrates of Mexico </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Fifty four named and twenty three undetermined species of acanthocephalans associated with 213 wildlife vertebrate host species from Mexico are listed; they come from 220 localities, pertaining to 28 of the 33 Mexican states. The checklist contains information on their hosts, habitat, distribution, and records. In addition, three species of acanthocephalans (Polymorphus &lt;i&gt;obtusus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Polymorphus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trochus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Southwellina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimorpha),&lt;/i&gt; are registered for the first time in Mexico, twenty six new locality records, and ten new host records are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">helminths; acanthocephalans; Mexico; vertebrates</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">helminths; acanthocephalans; Mexico; vertebrates</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <lastname>García-Prieto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Martín</firstname>
          <lastname>Garcia-Varela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Berenit</firstname>
          <lastname>Mendoza-Garfias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gerardo</firstname>
          <middlename>Pérez-Ponce</middlename>
          <lastname>De León</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Another new Rock Gecko (genus &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; Strauch 1887) from Pulau Langkawi, Kedah, Peninsular Malaysia </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of forest dwelling Rock Gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roticanai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from the upper elevations of Gunung Raya, Pulau Langkawi, Kedah, Peninsular Malaysia. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roticanai&lt;/i&gt; is the second species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; described from Pulau Langkawi and is differentiated from all other Southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in having a unique combination of color pattern and scale characteristics including keeled subtibials, ventrals, subcaudals, dorsal tubercles, and forearm scales; 25–27 paravertebral tubercles; a median row of enlarged, keeled subcaudals; five or six precloacal, pore-bearing scales in males separated medially by one or two non-pore-bearing scales; 26–29 subdigital lamellae on the fourth toe; no dark, longitudinal gular markings or blotches; no dark shoulder patch enclosing a white to yellow ocellus; and having a yellow to white, prescapular crescent. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;roticanai&lt;/i&gt; is the latest species in a growing list of new taxa being discovered from the Langkawi Archipelago.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;roticanai&lt;/i&gt;; Pulau Langkawi; Malaysia; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Chan</firstname>
          <middlename>Kin</middlename>
          <lastname>Onn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synodus cresseyi&lt;/i&gt; Prokofiev, 2008, an unnecessary replacement for &lt;i&gt;S. macrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; Cressey, 1981, and a description of a new species from the Western Indian Ocean (Teleostei: Synodontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Synodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cresseyi&lt;/i&gt; Prokofiev, 2008 is an unnecessary replacement name for &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; Cressey, 1981 according to Article 23.9.5 of the International Code of Zoological Nomenclature. The material used for the description of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cresseyi&lt;/i&gt; includes two species. One of them represents a new species which differs from its congeners in the following combination of characters: anterior palatine teeth not longer than posterior teeth; preopercle scaled posterior to corner of mouth; membranous posterior flap of anterior nostril slender, with a pointed tip, reaching to above posterior nostril when laid back; pectoral fins reaching a line connecting dorsal and pelvic fin origins; pelvic process broad; color in alcohol without any marking, deep brown on dorsal surface restricted to central two-third of head and body, about two scale rows above lateral line, lateral and ventral surface uniformly silver white without blotches.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">nomenclature; ICZN; &lt;i&gt;Synodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vityazi&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Western Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">nomenclature; ICZN; &lt;i&gt;Synodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vityazi&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hsuan-Ching</firstname>
          <lastname>Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Artém</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Prokofiev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kwang-Tsao</firstname>
          <lastname>Shao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
