<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2422.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Apr. 2010</title>
    <volume>2422</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description and molecular phylogeny of &lt;i&gt;Tethya leysae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Porifera, Demospongiae, Hadromerida) from the Canadian Northeast Pacific with remarks on the use of microtomography in sponge taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The sponge &lt;i&gt;Tethya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leysae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Porifera, Demospongiae, Hadromerida, Tethyidae) is a new species from the Canadian Northeast Pacific. Its type locality is the infralittoral around Ohiat Islet, Barkely Sound, Vancouver Island in Canada. &lt;i&gt;Tethya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leysae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a medium-sized spherical sponge with a verrucose surface, orange-yellow to light red alive and white with a greyish core in ethanol. The highly variable oxyspherasters (25-115 µm in size, R/C 0.34-0.69) are densely scattered almost throughout the entire cortex. The micrasters comprise acanthoxyspherasters, acanthostrongylasters, acanthotylasters and small oxyspherasters, which are present at low densities throughout the sponge and form a dense layer associated with the exopinacoderm. The megascleres and the auxiliary megascleres comprise oxeas and strongyloxeas. The new species is clearly distinguishable from the closely related &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californiana&lt;/i&gt; by the absence of spherules among the micrasters, the lack of an alveolar cortex and the extremely high density of megasters in the cortex. In addition, the R/C values of the megasters differ between the two species and the oxyspherasters of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leysae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; rarely display bent rays. The morphological differences between the species are confirmed by nucleotide and amino acid substitutions within the cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) mtDNA gene. Phylogenetic analyses group &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leysae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; with &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;californiana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;actinia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta,&lt;/i&gt; which together form a sister group to a MediterraneanNorth Atlantic species cluster. Morphological analyses of the skeleton included x-ray microtomography (µCT) and virtual 3D reconstruction, which was used for the first time in conjunction with the description of a new sponge species. Microtomography permitted the visualization and analysis of spicules within the skeletal context or isolated &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silico.&lt;/i&gt; The method represents a valuable extension to the sponge taxonomist’s toolbox since it allows morphometric measurements in 3D. µCT will thus supplement classical morphological methods such as light and scanning electron microscopy.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Sponges; new species; synchrotron radiation based x-ray micro computed tomography; &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;silico&lt;/i&gt; morphometry; COI; maximum likelihood; Bayesian analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Sponges</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Isabel</firstname>
          <lastname>Heim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <lastname>Nickel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-21</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Halichoeres rubrovirens&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of wrasse (Labridae: Perciformes) from the Trindade and Martin Vaz Island group, southeastern Brazil, with a preliminary mtDNA molecular phylogeny of New World &lt;i&gt;Halichoeres&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Here we describe &lt;i&gt;Halichoeres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubrovirens,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; endemic to Trindade and Martin Vaz Islands, off southeastern Brazil. The new species has unique color pattern, morphology and genetics. It can be easily distinguished from its Atlantic congeners by its color pattern consisting of a green body with two broad dotted reddish stripes. A preliminary mtDNA phylogeny indicates that &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubrovirens&lt;/i&gt; closest relative is in the tropical Eastern Pacific. Hence, we hypothesize that &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubrovirens&lt;/i&gt; once had a wide distribution in the western Atlantic but currently consists of a relict species restricted to Trindade and Martin Vaz islands. Little is know about its biology and ecology, but juveniles seem to school with and mimic &lt;i&gt;Thalassoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;noronhanum,&lt;/i&gt; which they resemble in color.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">western Atlantic; taxonomy; endemism; reef fish; oceanic islands.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">western Atlantic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hudson</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinheiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>João</firstname>
          <middlename>Luiz</middlename>
          <lastname>Gasparini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>22-30</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nucleus patterns of zoea I larvae (Crustacea: Decapoda) in the context of taxonomy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Using DAPI as a nucleus marker, we studied zoeas of 6 decapods (Palaemon &lt;i&gt;adspersus&lt;/i&gt; Rathke, 1837; &lt;i&gt;Palaemon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; Rathke, 1837; &lt;i&gt;Porcellana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platycheles&lt;/i&gt; (Pennant, 1777); &lt;i&gt;Pisidia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longicornis&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1767); &lt;i&gt;Xantho&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hydrophilus&lt;/i&gt; (Herbst, 1780) &lt;i&gt;Xantho&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pilipes&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne Edwards, 1867) representing one species pair of Palaemonidae (Caridea), Porcellanidae (Anomura) and Xanthidae (Brachyura) each, with special reference to the telson, and correlated our observations with the general morphological features of the zoeas. The different taxa exhibit specific features with respect to the distribution of nuclei, the patterns they exhibit, their size, density and numbers, thus being sets of characters potentially useful for taxonomic descriptions and diagnoses especially on the “above-species”-level. We discuss how nuclear patterns and classical morphological and/or morphogenetical features normally examined in zoeal larvae are related, and give some ideas on how “nucleus”characters can contribute to taxonomic descriptions.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Zoea; DAPI; pattern; taxonomy; description (Decapoda)</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Zoea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roland</firstname>
          <lastname>Meyer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jana</firstname>
          <lastname>Martin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roland</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Melzer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-42</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Peruvian land planarian species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Gigantea&lt;/i&gt; (Platyhelminthes, Tricladida, Geoplanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Geoplaninae land planarian from south Peru, &lt;i&gt;Gigantea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urubambensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described. The most outstanding features of the new species are the very dorsal location of the testes, between the dorsal diagonal and the supra-intestinal parenchymatic muscle layers; a penis papilla projecting from the roof of the male atrium and acentrally traversed by the ejaculatory duct; and the absence of glandular ridges on the penis papilla.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Flatworm; terrestrial fauna; Continenticola; Neotropical Region; Peru; very dorsal testes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Flatworm</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lisandro</firstname>
          <middlename>H. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Negrete</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Brusa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <lastname>Carbayo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Reef fishes of the Mazunte-Bahías de Huatulco reef track, Oaxaca, Mexican Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Although fish are one of the most abundant, conspicuous and structurally important inhabitants of reef systems, the group has remained largely ignored from biodiversity accounts on the Oaxaca reef track. Reef icthyofauna composition at 10 sites between Mazunte and Isla Montosa was gathered through stationary visual census techniques during 19982008. A total of 112 species belonging to 81 genera, 40 families and 11 orders were recorded. Species richness of the study area is higher than similar reef communities in the Mexican Pacific. Thirty species represent new records for the study area, and some discrepancies were found between local (this study) and regional accounts. Our data suggest that species composition in the area is still incomplete.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">reef icthyofauna; checklist; faunal completeness; Oaxaca; Mexican Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">reef icthyofauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ramón</firstname>
          <middlename>Andrés López</middlename>
          <lastname>Pérez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Imelda</firstname>
          <middlename>López</middlename>
          <lastname>Pérez-Maldonado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ariadna</firstname>
          <middlename>Montserrat López</middlename>
          <lastname>Ortiz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Linda</firstname>
          <middlename>Margarita Barranco</middlename>
          <lastname>Servin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <middlename>Barrientos</middlename>
          <lastname>Villalobos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gerado</firstname>
          <middlename>Esteban Leyte</middlename>
          <lastname>Morales</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of marine fishes illustrate the biogeographic importance of Christmas Island, Indian Ocean</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Christmas Island is situated in the tropical eastern Indian Ocean on a biogeographic border where Indian and Pacific Ocean faunas meet. Detailed field studies in 2004, 2007 and 2008, of the island’s fish fauna revealed 30 new records from 15 families. For six families (Dasyatidae, Chanidae, Bramidae, Mugilidae, Siganidae, Molidae) this is the first time a species has been recorded at Christmas Island. Many of the newly recorded fishes appear to have recently colonised the island, and establishing populations will be dependent on the availability of suitable habitat and conspecific mates. These new records illustrate that Christmas Island is important for range expansion because it serves as a critical stepping-stone in the dispersal of Pacific Ocean species into the Indian Ocean and vice versa. Contact between Indian and Pacific Ocean sister species has also resulted in hybridisation at Christmas Island.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Paul</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hobbs</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ayling</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Howard</middlename>
          <lastname>Choat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Justin</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gilligan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christian</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Joseph</firstname>
          <lastname>Neilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Newman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
