<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2424.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Apr. 2010</title>
    <volume>2424</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-04-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review, cladistic analysis and biogeography of &lt;i&gt;Nezara &lt;/i&gt;Amyot &amp; Serville (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper, the genus &lt;i&gt;Nezara&lt;/i&gt; Amyot &amp; Serville is reviewed and a hypothesis of relationships among its species is proposed. Also, diagnoses for the genus and the 12 included species are provided. A key to separate the species is also provided. Of the seven other species assigned to &lt;i&gt;Nezara&lt;/i&gt; in the literature, four of them are considered &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis,&lt;/i&gt; two are transferred to different genera, and one is considered a junior synonym. The cladistic analysis include 15 taxa and 34 characters. The cladogram was rooted with &lt;i&gt;Carpocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpureipennis&lt;/i&gt; (DeGeer); outgroup comparison also include species of the sister-groups &lt;i&gt;Aethemenes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chloris&lt;/i&gt; (Dallas), and &lt;i&gt;Pseudoacrosternum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cachani&lt;/i&gt; Day. The results showed &lt;i&gt;Nezara&lt;/i&gt; as a monophyletic taxon. Biogeographical scenarios of the evolution of &lt;i&gt;Nezara&lt;/i&gt; were discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nezarini; Pentatominae; key to species; synonymies; Afrotropical region; Oriental region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nezarini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Augusto</firstname>
          <lastname>Ferrari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cristiano</firstname>
          <middlename>Feldens</middlename>
          <lastname>Schwertner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jocelia</firstname>
          <lastname>Grazia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-41</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The Central Asian &lt;i&gt;Herina &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Ulidiidae), with the description of a new species from Afghanistan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Herina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;odnosumi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Afghanistan is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Herina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;odnosumi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from all other Old World species by its predominantly reddish yellow body, acute flagellomere 1 and yellow to brown wing pattern. The other Central Asian species, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monticola&lt;/i&gt; (Stackelberg, 1945), previously known from a Russian brief original description and a short illustrated note on its taxonomic position in is also redescribed. A key to the two species of &lt;i&gt;Herina&lt;/i&gt; Robineau-Desvoidy occurring in Central Asia is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Ulidiidae; &lt;i&gt;Herina&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Afghanistan; Tadjikistan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kameneva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Igor</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pljushtch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eulaema &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Apeulaema&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;felipei &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Hymenoptera: Apidae: Euglossina): a new forest-dependent orchid bee found at the brink of extinction in northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eulaema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Apeulaema)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;felipei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; a species extremely similar to the Amazonian &lt;i&gt;Eulaema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Apeulaema)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mocsaryi&lt;/i&gt; (Friese, 1899), is described from Murici (state of Alagoas, northeastern Brazil). This species seems to be restricted to a single patch of Atlantic Forest at the ‘Estação Ecológica de Murici’. Although this preserve is supposedly protected by law, the small area (less than 3,000 ha) where this bee occurs is entirely surrounded by pastures and sugar cane plantations, and anthropic pressure is strikingly high in the region. Several other endemic animal and plant species are known from the same area. &lt;i&gt;Eulaema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;felipei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is considered as Critically Endangered according to IUCN criteria. An updated identification key for all the species of &lt;i&gt;Eulaema&lt;/i&gt; (Apeulaema) Moure, 1950 is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Atlantic Forest; Centro Pernambuco; conservation; endangered; &lt;i&gt;Eulaema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mocsaryi&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Atlantic Forest</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <lastname>Nemésio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Key to species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hengchunia &lt;/i&gt;Vilbaste (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Deltocephalinae), and with description of a new species from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species &lt;i&gt;Hengchunia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hexaproducta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated from China, representing the first record of the genus from the southeastern Palaearctic Region. A key is given to distinguish all species of the genus. The type specimens of the new species are deposited in the Institute of Entomology, Guizhou University, Guiyang, China (GUGC).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Homoptera; morphology; taxonomy; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Homoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ji-Chun</firstname>
          <lastname>Xing</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ren-Huai</firstname>
          <lastname>Dai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zi-Zhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
