<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2426.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Apr. 2010</title>
    <volume>2426</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-04-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Retroactive changes should be introduced in the &lt;i&gt;Code &lt;/i&gt;only with great care: problems related to the spellings of nomina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Taxonomy is currently facing a major crisis and is likely to have strong difficulties to reduce significantly the taxonomic gap before the biodiversity crisis has wiped out a large proportion of the living species of the earth. In this context, taxonomists should pay great attention to the nomenclatural Rules, and care for them to help them in this urgent task, rather than diverting their time and energy to secondary or useless questions or debates. A major purpose of the &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt; is to promote nomenclatural stability in zoology. This requires stability in the Rules, or at least that a great care be taken, when establishing new Rules, to avoid that they can have unexpected deleterious consequences for stability. In particular, in most cases, it is crucial to deny retroactivity to the new Rules. Several examples of problems created in zoological nomenclature by introduction of changes in Articles dealing with the spellings of nomina are examined in detail. These Articles were modified, with retroactive value, in the 1985 edition (Art. 32, 33, 35 and 39) and in the 1999 edition (Art. 24) of the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; It is shown that these changes, which have no clear “philosophical” or practical justifications and which result in no clear benefits, have in fact had negative impacts on nomenclatural practice. Their implementation requires heavy useless additional work from taxonomists and has negative results in nomenclatural stability that had clearly not been anticipated by the ICZN when promulgating them. In a few sets of nomina tested below, the changes in the 1985 edition resulted in spelling changes for 10.0 to 22.2 % of the nomina, and those in the 1999 edition for 21.7 to 33.3 % of the nomina, roughly a quarter of them on the whole (24.5 %). Among others that are less emblematic, a striking case is that of the fish generic nomen &lt;i&gt;Tetraodon,&lt;/i&gt; widely used especially since the genome of a species of this genus has been sequenced, and which should be changed to &lt;i&gt;Tetrodon&lt;/i&gt; because of the unwarranted introduction of the new Art. 24.2.4 into the &lt;i&gt;Code.&lt;/i&gt; It is suggested that these changes should be cancelled, or at least denied retroactivity from the years of their promulgations. In order to make this discussion easier, a “taxonomy” of the different kinds of spellings of nomina, and a dichotomic key to such situations, are provided. This stresses the fact that detailed discussions on very precise aspects of the functioning of nomenclatural Rules, as well as the computerization of nomenclatural data for online databases, require to use a specialized technical terminology to designate the nomenclatural concepts and tools, not vague “common language” terms like “name” or “type”: “keep &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rules,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;change&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;terms”.&lt;/i&gt; The problems outlined here should be kept in mind by the ICZN before implementing drastic changes in the Rules of nomenclatural availability, as recently suggested.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Nomenclature; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; availability; stability; terminology; nomen; spelling; &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;novum&lt;/i&gt;; First-Reviser; change in Rules; retroactivity; &lt;i&gt;Tetraodon&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Nomenclature</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alain</firstname>
          <lastname>Dubois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new Antarctic species of &lt;i&gt;Aristias &lt;/i&gt;Boeck (Crustacea, Amphipoda, Aristiidae), with remarks on the genus in Antarctica</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of aristiid, &lt;i&gt;Aristias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;excavatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from an Antarctic sponge. The systematics of the genus is discussed. There are now 28 known species in the genus &lt;i&gt;Aristias,&lt;/i&gt; with just three recorded from Antarctic waters. The actual number of Antarctic species is likely to be higher, however, because many of these records were probably incorrectly attributed to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;antarcticus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aristiidae; &lt;i&gt;Aristias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;excavatus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Antarctica; sponge associate</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aristiidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Niamh</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kilgallen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-53</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecules meet macroecology—combining Species Distribution Models and phylogeographic studies</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Combination of various techniques allows the identification of unique genetic lineages and/or taxa new to science via integrative taxonomy approaches. Next to molecular methods such as DNA ‘barcoding’ and phylogeographic analyses, Species Distribution Models may serve as compliment techniques allowing spatially explicit predictions of a species’ potential distribution even across millennia. They may facilitate the identification of possible recent and historical gene flow pathways. Herein, we highlight advantages of the combination of both molecular and macroecological approaches using the African miniature leaf litter frog &lt;i&gt;Arthroleptis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xenodactyloides&lt;/i&gt; as example.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Arthroleptis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xenodactyloides&lt;/i&gt;; fundamental niche; integrative taxonomy; Last Glacial Maximum; realized niche</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Arthroleptis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;xenodactyloides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <lastname>Rödder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <lastname>Weinsheimer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <lastname>Lötters</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>54-60</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: A new species of scaly blenny of the genus &lt;i&gt;Labrisomus &lt;/i&gt;(Actinopterygii: Labrisomidae) from the tropical West Atlantic. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2015, 62–68.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-14</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
