<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2433.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">22 Apr. 2010</title>
    <volume>2433</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-04-22</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics, natural history, and hemipenial morphology of &lt;i&gt;Dendrophidion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunneum &lt;/i&gt;(Günther) (Serpentes: Colubridae), a poorly known snake from the Andes of Ecuador and Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Systematic characters, distribution, natural history, and hemipenial morphology are described for &lt;i&gt;Dendrophidion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunneum&lt;/i&gt; (Günther), a poorly known snake from Ecuador and Peru. It has 17 midbody scale rows; 145–165 ventrals; 135–158 subcaudals; a tail 38–44% of total length; a relatively uniform green to brown dorsum; and a maximum length of 1370 mm (700–800 mm SVL). The species occurs from northern Ecuador to 8° S latitude in Peru, primarily on the Pacific slopes of the Andes but with a few documented lowland localities in Peru. &lt;i&gt;Dendrophidion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brunneum&lt;/i&gt; is diurnal, terrestrial, heliophilic, and oviparous. It occurs in humid montane forests or mixed puna grassland/highland forest. Recorded prey are small terrestrial frogs but a large individual possibly consumed a lizard. Defensive mechanisms include a pseudautotomic tail and behaviors such as striking, biting, and neck inflation. The hemipenis has a short, narrow base, a greatly expanded distal region, and a simple, centrolineal sulcus spermaticus. The expanded region is ornamented with spines, distal to which two flounces completely encircle the organ and another extends partially around one side. The flounces are unusual in being thin, membranous structures and in having mineralized rods (reduced spinules) completely embedded within the membranes. The apex is nude except for a few vestigial calyces. Unusual hemipenial characters are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">South America; hemipenis; taxonomy; reproduction; behavior; snakes; distribution; sexual dimorphism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">South America</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cadle</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On new collections of deep-sea Gadiformes (Actinopterygii: Teleostei) from the Brazilian continental slope, between 11° and 23° S</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">New collections made by the French research vessel &lt;i&gt;Thalassa&lt;/i&gt; and the Brazilian &lt;i&gt;Astro&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Garoupa&lt;/i&gt; on the Brazilian continental slope, between 11° and 23° S revealed a great diversity of deep-sea gadiforms obtained between 200 and 2270 m. Of the 34 species collected, 13 (38%) are being reported for the first time in the western South Atlantic and one may represent a new species. The most species-rich family in the area is Macrouridae (25 species), followed by Moridae (4), Phycidae (2), Merlucciidae (2), and Bregmacerotidae (1). Most of the species collected is also found in the Gulf of Mexico and Caribbean and have their known ranges of distribution extended into the tropical waters of central Brazil. Four species typically occur in temperate waters and were found only in the southernmost stations. A summary comparison of the bathymetric distributions of each species on the slope is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Western South Atlantic; demersal; pelagic; gadiforms; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Western South Atlantic; demersal; pelagic; gadiforms; taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>R. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Melo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Braga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>W. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nunan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>A. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Who’s your mommy? Identifying maternal ancestors of asexual species of &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis &lt;/i&gt;Cuvier, 1829 and the description of a new endemic species of asexual &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis &lt;/i&gt;Cuvier, 1829 from Southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new asexual species of &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis&lt;/i&gt; is described from Binh Chau – Phuoc Buu Nature Reserve, Xuyen Moc district Ba Ria-Vung Tau Province, Vietnam to where it is believed to be endemic. &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ngovantrii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all sexual species of &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis&lt;/i&gt; by lacking males and from all asexual species by having nine rows of enlarged keeled scales across the forearm and 37–40 subdigital lamellae beneath the fourth toe. Phylogenetic inference based on 700 base pairs of the mitochondrial ND2 region, placed &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ngovantrii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; among the currently described asexual species and was used to assess the maternal ancestors of the remaining asexual species. Both maximum parsimony and maximum likelihood analyses recovered &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guttata&lt;/i&gt; as the maternal ancestors of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guentherpetersi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boehmei,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ngovantrii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boehmei&lt;/i&gt; as the maternal ancestor to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;triploida.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">asexual; &lt;i&gt;Leiolepis&lt;/i&gt;; maternal; &lt;i&gt;ngovantrii&lt;/i&gt;; new species; taxonomy; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">asexual</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jesse</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-61</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-22</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Proablepharus &lt;/i&gt;(Scincidae: Lygosominae) from Mt Surprise, north-eastern Queensland, Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Proablepharus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barrylyoni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from a single locality near Mt Surprise, north-eastern Queensland. It is distinguished from its congeners by the following character states: body longitudinally striped, four supraoculars, five supraciliaries, frontoparietals fused to interparietal, upper preocular well-developed, two postsupralabials, lamellae beneath digits of pes smoothly rounded. The species was last collected in 1981 and, using criteria prescribed in the Queensland &lt;i&gt;Nature&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Conservation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Act,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Wildlife&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Regulation&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;1994,&lt;/i&gt; qualifies as Vulnerable.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scincidae; &lt;i&gt;Proablepharus&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Queensland; Australia; conservation status</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scincidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Couper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Colin</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Limpus</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Keith</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Amey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-04-22</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
