<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2442.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2442</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Coelotine spiders from Xishuangbanna Rainforest, Southwestern China (Araneae: Amaurobiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of coelotine species from Xishuangbanna Rainforest, Yunnan, China are described: &lt;i&gt;Coelotes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;forficatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Draconarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bannaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Draconarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;exiguus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Draconarius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turriformis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Morphological descriptions and illustrations of all the four new species are given. The type specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; new species; diagnosis; morphology; tropical forest</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jie</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Transversotrematidae (Platyhelminthes: Trematoda) are rich and abundant on Indo-Pacific fishes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Transversotrematidae, perhaps because of their unique and obscure habitat under the scales of fishes, have been little reported in surveys and studies of trematodes of marine fishes. At present there are just three fully marine species recognized. We have surveyed 2604 individuals, from 359 species and 71 families, of marine fishes from a range of sites mainly from coral reefs in the Indo-Pacific. We found infections on 87 species and 15 families of fishes; one family, Monodactylidae, is new for transversotrematids. Morphological and molecular analyses suggest that, in addition to &lt;i&gt;Crusziella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosa&lt;/i&gt; which parasitizes only mugilids, there are three complexes of species of &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema;&lt;/i&gt; one associated with mullids only, one with haemulids, labrids, lethrinids and scarids, and one associated with at least 13 families of fishes. Molecular evidence suggests that these complexes comprise at least 22 species. Overall we conclude that the richness of this family has been significantly underestimated and that it is rich and abundant on fishes of the Indo-Pacific.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Transversotrematidae; &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt;; Great Barrier Reef; Queensland; Australia; Maldives; Palau; Indo-West Pacific; Chaetodontidae; Haemulidae; Kyphosidae; Labridae; Lethrinidae; Lutjanidae; Monodactylidae; Mugilidae; Mullidae; Nemipteridae; Pomacentridae; Scaridae; Sillaginidae; Sparidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Janet</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hunter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-38</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Four new species of the family Diptilomiopidae (Acari: Eriophyoidea) from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of eriophyoid mites are described and illustrated from China. Three of these species are in the subfamily Rhyncaphytoptinae: &lt;i&gt;Hyborhinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;linderae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; infesting &lt;i&gt;Lindera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obtusiloba&lt;/i&gt; Blume (Lauraceae); &lt;i&gt;Neocatarhinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dendrocalamus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; infesting &lt;i&gt;Dendrocalamus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latiflorus&lt;/i&gt; Munro (Poaceae) and &lt;i&gt;Rhinophytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tremae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; infesting &lt;i&gt;Trema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cannabina&lt;/i&gt; Lour. (Ulmaceae); and one in the subfamily Diptilomiopinae: &lt;i&gt;Vimola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emarginata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; infesting &lt;i&gt;Terminalia&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Combretaceae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new species; taxonomy; Rhyncaphytoptinae; Diptilomiopinae; Oriental China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Guo-Quan</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sui-Gai</firstname>
          <lastname>Wei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ding</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Character evidence for the monophyly of the Microdesminae, with comments on relationships to &lt;i&gt;Schindleria &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Gobioidei: Gobiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The composition of the Microdesminae has been inconsistently reported in recent molecular studies. A monophyletic Microdesminae consisting of both Indo-Pacific and New World/Atlantic genera is diagnosed here by the following synapomorphies: maxilla with elongate projection extending anteriorly over ascending processes of premaxilla; palatine medial process absent; single dorsal process on cleithrum; supracleithrum oriented vertically and closely applied to cleithrum; posttemporal with elongate posteroventral process; body slender and elongate, with associated increase in number of vertebrae and median fin rays (total vertebrae 42–66 with 19 or more precaudal vertebrae, total dorsal-fin rays 42–78, anal-fin rays 27–43), slender pelvis with anterior extensions of the pelvic intercleithral cartilage, and decrease in number of pelvic-fin rays (with a spine and 2–4 segmented rays); single dorsal fin; dorsal-fin spines usually 12 or more; predominantly 1:1 relationship between interneural spaces and anterior dorsal-fin pterygiophores; and first (supernumerary) ray on first anal pterygiophore a bilaterally paired, segmented ray. Several of these characters (particularly single dorsal process on cleithrum, posttemporal with elongate posteroventral process) support a possible relationship between microdesmines and &lt;i&gt;Schindleria,&lt;/i&gt; as does dorsal gill-arch morphology.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Osteology; Indo-Pacific; Atlantic; New World; systematics; elongation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Osteology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anthony</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gill</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Randall</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mooi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Syndesmis patagonica &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Rhabdocoela: Umagillidae) from the sea urchin &lt;i&gt;Arbacia dufresnii &lt;/i&gt;(Echinodermata: Echinoidea) in Patagonia, Argentina</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The umagillid &lt;i&gt;Syndesmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the intestinal tract of the sea urchin &lt;i&gt;Arbacia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dufresnii,&lt;/i&gt; which represents a new host record for the genus. The hosts were collected from the coast of Patagonia (Argentina), and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is the first species of &lt;i&gt;Syndesmis&lt;/i&gt; reported from South America. &lt;i&gt;Syndesmis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from all other species in the genus by the possession of a stylet that is extremely short (less than 50 µm long), and a combination of other characters including the position of the testes, body size, body color and host. An updated overview of the distribution of all species of &lt;i&gt;Syndesmis&lt;/i&gt; is also presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Syndesmis;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; new species; taxonomy; biogeography; endosymbiosis; Puerto Madryn</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Syndesmis;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; new species; taxonomy; biogeography; endosymbiosis; Puerto Madryn</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martín</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brogger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Verónica</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ivanov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
