<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2443.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">3 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2443</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the tarantula spider genus &lt;i&gt;Coremiocnemis&lt;/i&gt; Simon 1892 (Araneae, Theraphosidae), with further notes on the Selenocosmiinae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The selenocosmiine genus &lt;i&gt;Coremiocnemis&lt;/i&gt; Simon 1892 is revised for the first time with six new species included. Five new species are from West Malaysia: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brachyramosa&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Gunung Ledang, Johor; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gnathospina&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoggi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Fraser’s Hill, Selangor; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeremyhuffi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Tapah, Perak, Fraser’s Hill, Selangor to Pahang and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscura&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. from Taiping, Perak to Cameron Highlands, Pahang. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kotacana&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from Aceh Teneggara, Sumatra, being the first record of this genus outside Malaysia or Australia. A lectotype and paralectotype are designated for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunicularia&lt;/i&gt; (Simon 1892). All but two of Abraham’s non-type &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valida&lt;/i&gt; Pocock 1895 (Abraham 1924) specimens held in both the NHM and RMBR are newly transferred to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cunicularia.&lt;/i&gt; Abraham’s two remaining specimens are removed from &lt;i&gt;Coremiocnemis.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valida&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed, its former dubious locality is resolved. Zoogeographic considerations of all species are discussed and resolved. Ontogenetic variation within &lt;i&gt;Coremiocnemis&lt;/i&gt; is discussed. Several new characters are introduced. Subfamilial relationships with proposed sister genera &lt;i&gt;Selenocosmia&lt;/i&gt; Ausserer 1871 and &lt;i&gt;Lyrognathus&lt;/i&gt; Pocock 1895 are discussed. A key to species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mygalomorph; new species; Borneo; Sumatra; Malaysia; Australia; distribution; ontogeny; zoogeography; natural history.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mygalomorph</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rick</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>West</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Steven</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nunn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-64</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-03</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
