<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2475.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2475</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The hyperdiverse oribatid mite genus &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Cymbaeremaeidae) in Australia, with descriptions of new species and consideration of biogeographical affinities</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper contains descriptions of thirteen new Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, 1910, belonging to the species groups Carinatus from New South Wales and Victoria (S. &lt;i&gt;alisonae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;allmani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nivalis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberculosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zephyrus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; Patella from Western Australia and Tasmania (S. &lt;i&gt;baylyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tegulatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; Petrosus from New South Wales, Tasmania, Victoria and Western Australia (S. &lt;i&gt;bulbosensillatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;euthemellus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minjambuta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notoverrucatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.)&lt;/b&gt; and Emarginatus from Queensland (S. &lt;i&gt;walteri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.),&lt;/b&gt; Only members of the predominantly Neotropical and Australasian Carinatus species-group have been described from Australia hitherto, and Australian species constitute a third of this group. The Patella species-group is mostly Afrotropical (four spp.), with one Palaearctic and three Australasian species, including the two new species described herein. The Petrosus species-group, previously known from three Palaearctic, two Oriental and one Neotropical species, is now dominated by five new Australian species described herein. The Emarginatus species-group contains one species each from Australia, New Zealand, Java and Cuba. A key to Australian species is provided. The genus &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; contains some 112 species, and can beconsidered hyperdiverse by oribatid standards. Morphological traits are considered that may relate to the ecological diversification and adaptive radiation of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus,&lt;/i&gt; particularly those related to species living on leaves and stems within rainforest canopies.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Oribatida; biogeography; taxonomy; Australia; hyperdiversity; species-groups.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Oribatida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Colloff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rediscovery, redescription, and illustrations of the milliped, &lt;i&gt;Mitocybe auriportae&lt;/i&gt; Cook and Loomis, 1928 (Colobognatha: Platydesmida: Andrognathidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mitocybe&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auriportae&lt;/i&gt; Cook and Loomis, 1928, is a thread-like, densely pubescent andrognathid milliped that lacks exoskeletal ornamentations and is equivalent in size to the veins in decaying leaves. Its anterior gonopods are dominated by a broad, subtriangular sternum; the falcate ultimate podomere arises subterminally and is directed ventrolaterad. The species is known from a single collection 91 years ago in Marin County, California; I report a new locality in Santa Cruz County and redescribe and illustrate somatic and gonopodal features. &lt;i&gt;Mitocybe&lt;/i&gt; Cook and Loomis, 1928, is monotypic; a new species from Guerrero, Mexico, reported 30 years ago, is still undescribed and, from geographical proximity, probably referrable to &lt;i&gt;Andrognathus&lt;/i&gt; Cope, 1869. Somatic features of these genera are contrasted. The taxonomy of Platydesmida is uncertain because it is based on somatic, rather than gonopodal, features and because &lt;i&gt;Brachycybe&lt;/i&gt; Wood, 1864, bridges the anatomical gap between the two component families. The family-group name, Mitocybeini Hoffman, 1980, is available to accommodate &lt;i&gt;Mitocybe.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;In&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;situ&lt;/i&gt; SEM examinations of colobognath gonopods do not show details of the anterior gonopod sternum, and studies on dissected gonopods are recommended.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mitocybe&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;auriportae&lt;/i&gt;; Platydesmida; Andrognathidae; &lt;i&gt;Andrognathus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Brachycybe&lt;/i&gt;; California; pubescence; gonopods</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mitocybe&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rowland</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Shelley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the striped catfish &lt;i&gt;Mystus carcio &lt;/i&gt;(Hamilton) (Siluriformes: Bagridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Pimelodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carcio,&lt;/i&gt; originally described in 1822 by Francis Hamilton, has long been treated as a junior synonym of either &lt;i&gt;Mystus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tengara&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus.&lt;/i&gt; In this paper we revalidate and redescribe the species and diagnose it from other striped &lt;i&gt;Mystus&lt;/i&gt; by the following combination of characters: small adult size, maturing at 44.0 mm standard length; adipose-fin base shorter than or equal to dorsal-fin base; pelvic fin reaching anal-fin origin; pectoral girdle with coracoid shield exposed ventro-laterally below pectoral fin; eyes rounded and large, dorsally orientated on head; vomerine tooth-patch interrupted at midline. The species is distributed in the Ganga-Brahmaputra drainage of northeast India and Bangladesh.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bagrid catfish; &lt;i&gt;Mystus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tengara&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Mystus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus&lt;/i&gt;; distinctive characters; coracoid shield</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bagrid catfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <lastname>Darshan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Anganthoibi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <lastname>Vishwanath</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis &lt;/i&gt;Strauch (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Laos with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of a presumably karst dwelling Rock Gecko, &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laoensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Dong Phu Vieng National Protected Area, Savannakhet Province, Laos. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laoensis&lt;/i&gt; is differentiated from all other Southeast Asian &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; in having a unique combination of color pattern (in alcohol) and scale characteristics. &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laoensis&lt;/i&gt; is the first record of &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; from Laos and extends the range of this genus approximately 600 km to the northeast. Its presence in Laos underscores the need for continued exploration of karst habitats throughout Indochina were &lt;i&gt;Cnemaspis&lt;/i&gt; commonly occur.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Southeast Asia; taxonomy; karst; Indochina; Rock Gecko</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Southeast Asia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-63</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus solus&lt;/i&gt;, a new species of blenny (Perciformes, Blenniidae) from the Red Sea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described on the basis of 35 specimens collected by J.E. Randall on a shallow rocky shore at the end of a mangrove channel at Ras Mohammed, Red Sea. The new species belongs to the Nigricans Species Group, which is distinguished from all other blennies in having about the medial third of the ventral margin of the upper lip entire and the lateral thirds crenulate. Within the group, now consisting of 11 species, the new species is distinguished by having only single pores at each preopercular pore position, typically three predorsal commissural pores, and small white spots on lips, head and body. &lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;solus&lt;/i&gt; is the only species of the circumtropical genus &lt;i&gt;Entomacrodus&lt;/i&gt; known from the Red Sea.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lonely blenny; fish; Ras Mohammed; Egypt</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lonely blenny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergey</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bogorodsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
