<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2477.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">19 May. 2010</title>
    <volume>2477</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Pill-millipedes (Glomerida, Diplopoda) in Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The order Glomerida is represented in Taiwan by five species in two genera, two subfamilies and one family. All species, as well as one genus and one subfamily, seem to be endemic to Taiwan. Among the species, &lt;i&gt;Mauriesia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;splendida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belongs in a new genus, &lt;i&gt;Mauriesia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; which in its turn represents a new subfamily, Mauriesiinae &lt;b&gt;subfam.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; the latter differing strikingly from the remaining three subfamilies of Glomeridae both in the presence of a caudomedian lobule on the male pygidium and in telopod stoutness and conformation. Four further species belong to the large, basically Asian genus &lt;i&gt;Hyleoglomeris&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1910: &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinuata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;proximata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittata&lt;/i&gt; Verhoeff, 1929. A key is provided to all of the species of Glomerida in Taiwan, and their distributions are mapped and discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">millipede; Glomeridae; taxonomy; new species; new genus; new subfamily; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">millipede</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Golovatch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mikhaljova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsueh-Wen</firstname>
          <lastname>Chang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species and new record of the Amphilochidae (Crustacea: Amphipoda) from Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of the family Amphilochidae were collected from shallow Korean waters. One of the species is new and is described as &lt;i&gt;Hourstonius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;geojeensis.&lt;/i&gt; The morphology of the eyes, lateral cephalic lobe, mandibular palp and molar, antenna 1, gnathopod 2, pereopodal dactyls, epimeron, uropods and telson are the major characteristics which differentiate the new species from its congeners. The other species found, &lt;i&gt;Paramphilochus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parachelatus&lt;/i&gt; Ishimaru &amp; Ikehara, 1986 is a new record for Korean waters, previously known from Japanese waters. Both species are fully illustrated and compared with related species. A key to north Pacific &lt;i&gt;Hourstonius&lt;/i&gt; species is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hourstonius&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;geojeensis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Paramphilochus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;parachelatus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; amphilochid; amphipod; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Hourstonius&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Young-Hyo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ed</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hendrycks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kyung-Sook</firstname>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-36</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eudontomyzon graecus&lt;/i&gt;, a new nonparasitic lamprey species from Greece (Petromyzontiformes: Petromyzontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eudontomyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graecus,&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., a nonparasitic lamprey from Greece, is restricted to the Loúros River drainage, Ionian Sea basin, Epirus Periphery. It is distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Eudontomyzon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hellenicus,&lt;/i&gt; the other nonparasitic Greek brook lamprey, occurring allopatrically in the Strymon River drainage, Aegean Sea basin, Central Macedonia Periphery, by possessing at the adult stage a relatively longer tail and a greater number of bicuspid teeth in both the first row of anterials and posterials, and at the ammocoete stage, by a relatively shorter trunk and longer tail and a less pigmented upper lip, tongue precursor bulb and lateral aspects of the elastic ridge. Taken individually, these three adult and five larval characters, varied in their diagnostic power from 71 to 88% for the adults and from 91 to 97% for the ammocoetes. However, in combination, these characters provide sufficient evidence to justify recognition of this new species, in addition to the wide distance (ca 400 km) separating it from its closest extant relative, as well as its independent origin.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Epirus brook lamprey; morphology; conservation; Critically Endangered; freshwater</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Epirus brook lamprey</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Claude</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Renaud</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Panos</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Economidis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A catalogue of the genus &lt;i&gt;Euscorpiops &lt;/i&gt;Vachon, 1980 (Scorpiones: Euscorpiidae, Scorpiopinae) from China, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A catalogue of Chinese species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Euscorpiops&lt;/i&gt; Vachon, 1980 is provided. There are 10 species in total, none of them was recorded from China in “Catalog of the Scorpions of the World” (Fet &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 2000). A new species, &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puerensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from southern Yunnan is described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puerensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by having 18 external trichobothria (5 &lt;i&gt;eb,&lt;/i&gt; 2 &lt;i&gt;esb,&lt;/i&gt; 2 &lt;i&gt;em,&lt;/i&gt; 4 &lt;i&gt;est,&lt;/i&gt; 5 &lt;i&gt;et),&lt;/i&gt; and 10 or 11 ventral trichobothria in the pedipalp patella; chela with a length/ width ratio average of 2.7 on males and females; pedipalp chela fingers on adult females and males scalloped; pectinal teeth count 7–8; pectinal fulcra present.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">scorpion; catalogue; &lt;i&gt;Euscorpiops&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">scorpion</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Yong</firstname>
          <lastname>Di</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ying-Liang</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Zhi-Jian</firstname>
          <lastname>Cao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Heng</firstname>
          <lastname>Xiao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wen-Xin</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-61</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aoruroides cochinchinensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Oxyurida: Thelastomatidae) from Vietnamese Panesthiinae wood-burrowing cockroaches</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new thelastomatid species, &lt;i&gt;Aoruroides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cochinchinensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n., is described from the hindgut of Vietnamese Panesthiinae cockroaches collected in Bi Doup-Nui Ba National Park. It is the first report of nematodes of the genus &lt;i&gt;Aoruroides&lt;/i&gt; Travassos &amp; Kloss, 1958 from mainland Asia. &lt;i&gt;Aoruroides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cochinchinensis&lt;/i&gt; sp. n. males are characterized by thorn-like cuticular projections on the head end, maximal value of de Man index &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; (19.5) within the genus, and the nerve ring situated on the border of corpus and isthmus. Earlier, only knob-like cervical cuticular projections were described for males of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;queenslandensis&lt;/i&gt; Jex, Cribb &amp; Schneider, 2004.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aoruroides&lt;/i&gt;; cockroach host; hindgut; LSU rDNA sequences; scanning electron microscopy; taxonomy.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aoruroides&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guzeeva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pham</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Luc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sergei</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Spiridonov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-05-19</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
