<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2515.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Jun. 2010</title>
    <volume>2515</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-06-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A reclassification of the weevil subfamily Cyclominae (Coleoptera: Curculionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The structure of mainly the ovipositor is used to better define and constitute the tribes of the weevil subfamily Cyclominae, whose composition and classification are highly confused in existing catalogues. Eight tribes are recognised in the subfamily, Cyclomini, Amycterini, Hipporhinini, Rhythirrinini, Listroderini, Notiomimetini, Dichotrachelini and Aterpini, while Diabathrariini, Gonipterini and Viticiini are excluded from it. Based on unique modifications of the ovipositor for laying eggs into the soil, the reconstituted Cyclomini, Amycterini and Hipporhinini can be regarded as monophyletic groups, while Rhythirrinini may still comprise two separate lineages. Largely due to their unmodified ovipositor and a lack of detailed taxonomic studies, Listroderini and Notiomimetini remain undefined although better constituted, while the position of the monotypic Dichotrachelini in Cyclominae is uncertain and the tribe Aterpini remains in need of comprehensive study to determine whether any of its current genera can be retained in the subfamily. As a result, the concept of the subfamily Cyclominae as a monophyletic taxon remains in doubt. Ovipositor structure further indicates a sister-group relationship between Amycterini and Hipporhinini and is also significant in delineating higher taxa in other terricolous weevils, i.e. Brachycerinae and Microcerinae. A checklist of the genera and species of the tribe Cyclomini is provided. Several taxonomic changes are proposed, as detailed in an appendix: 7 new synonymies, 2 synonymies reinstated, 4 tribes resurrected, 4 tribes transferred and 56 genera transferred.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amycterini; Aterpini; Brachycerini; Byrsopini; Cyclomini; Diabathrariini; Dichotrachelini; Gonipterini; Hipporhinini; Listroderini; Notiomimetini; Rhythirrinini; Viticiini</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amycterini</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rolf</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Oberprieler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-35</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of Collembola: &lt;i&gt;Friesea kariae &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Neanuridae) and &lt;i&gt;Stachia oregonensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Odontellidae) from North America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of genera &lt;i&gt;Friesea&lt;/i&gt; Dalla Torre, 1895 and &lt;i&gt;Stachia&lt;/i&gt; Folsom, 1932 are described and fully illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Friesea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kariae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is easily distinguished by absence of eyes, presence of five anal spines, furcula in state 3 and retinaculum with 2+2 teeth. &lt;i&gt;Stachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oregonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is easily distinguished by its femoral and trochanteral chaetotaxy, presence of three rounded lobes in postantennal organ and setae a 1 on most thoracic and abdominal terga. Keys to the known eyeless members of the genus &lt;i&gt;Friesea&lt;/i&gt; Dalla Torre, 1895 and all the species of &lt;i&gt;Stachia&lt;/i&gt; Folsom, 1932 are also included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; springtails; &lt;i&gt;Friesea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kariae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Stachia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oregonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Oregon; British Columbia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adrian</firstname>
          <lastname>Smolis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>36-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Carrerapyrgota &lt;/i&gt;Aczél (Diptera, Pyrgotidae) with the description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Neotropical genus &lt;i&gt;Carrerapyrgota&lt;/i&gt; Aczél is restricted to the South America (Brazil and Argentina). The genus is composed of two previously described species, which are revised herein: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miliaria&lt;/i&gt; Aczél and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;personata&lt;/i&gt; (Lutz &amp; Lima). Two new Brazilian species are described: &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aczeli&lt;/i&gt; from São Paulo and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bernardii&lt;/i&gt; from Bahia. Illustrations of the external morphology of adults and male and female terminalia are also included. An identification key to the species is presented, as well as a brief discussion of the biology and distribution of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tephritoidea; Pyrgotidae; Pyrgotini; Neotropical</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tephritoidea; Pyrgotidae; Pyrgotini; Neotropical</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ramon</firstname>
          <middlename>Luciano</middlename>
          <lastname>Mello</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>José Einicker</middlename>
          <lastname>Lamas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Albertino</middlename>
          <lastname>Rafael</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-64</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trissolcus radjabii &lt;/i&gt;n.sp. (Hymenoptera: Platygastridae), an egg parasitoid of the shield bug, &lt;i&gt;Apodiphus amygdali &lt;/i&gt;(Heteroptera: Pentatomidae) and the sunn pest, &lt;i&gt;Eurygaster integriceps &lt;/i&gt;(Heteroptera: Scutelleridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Shahzad</firstname>
          <lastname>Iranipour</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Norman</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Johnson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
