<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2519.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Jun. 2010</title>
    <volume>2519</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-06-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella &lt;/i&gt;Johnston, 1929 (Monogenea: Capsalidae), its assignment to Entobdellinae Bychowsky, 1957 and comments on subfamilial composition</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrocolpa&lt;/i&gt; (Lühe, 1906) Yamaguti, 1963 is redescribed from new material collected from ventral skin surfaces of the Australian cownose ray, &lt;i&gt;Rhinoptera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;neglecta&lt;/i&gt; Ogilby (Elasmobranchii: Myliobatidae) from waters in Moreton Bay and from captive rays in a public display aquarium in Townsville, from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;neglecta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Rhinoptera&lt;/i&gt; sp. from Weipa, Queensland, Australia and from &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanica&lt;/i&gt; Müller &amp; Henle caught in the Arabian Gulf north of Dubai, United Arab Emirates. &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posterocolpa&lt;/i&gt; (Hargis, 1955) Yamaguti, 1963 is redescribed from new specimens collected from the cownose ray, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bonasus&lt;/i&gt; (Mitchill) (Myliobatidae) from several localities in the Gulf of Mexico and in the Chesapeake Bay region of the south-eastern and eastern USA, respectively. Detailed anatomical redescriptions demonstrate that each &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; species share several dorsal structures (paired anterior horns, excretory papillae and posterior conical structures at the junction of the body with the haptor), anterolateral grooves on the ventral surface of each anterior attachment organ, a similar route for tendons associated mostly with the accessory sclerites and the anterior hamuli and a long vagina. The different path of the vagina and the position of the vaginal pore are the simplest characters to discriminate the two species. &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unnithani&lt;/i&gt; Gupta &amp; Chanana, 1976 from the gills of a &lt;i&gt;Caranx&lt;/i&gt; sp. (Teleostei: Perciformes: Carangidae) off Kavaratti, Laccadive Islands, Arabian Sea, India is considered a species &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis.&lt;/i&gt; Morphological parallels are identified, in particular concerning the anterior attachment organs of species in &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Branchobdella&lt;/i&gt; Kearn, Whittington &amp; Evans-Gowing, 2007, &lt;i&gt;Entobdella&lt;/i&gt; Blainville in Lamarck, 1818, &lt;i&gt;Neoentobdella&lt;/i&gt; Kearn &amp; Whittington, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;Pseudoentobdella&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguti, 1963. Of these entobdelline genera, species in three of them parasitise principally the skin of elasmobranch rays (Dasyatidae; Myliobatidae; Rhinobatidae); only species in &lt;i&gt;Branchobdella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Entobdella&lt;/i&gt; parasitise flatfish teleosts (Paralichthyidae; Pleuronectidae; Soleidae). On the basis of the redescriptions presented here plus morphological similarities, host associations and recently published molecular genetic data, &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; is moved from the Benedeniinae Johnston, 1931 and the diagnosis for the Entobdellinae Bychowsky, 1957 is amended to unite &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Branchobdella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Entobdella,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Listrocephalos&lt;/i&gt; Bullard, Payne &amp; Braswell, 2004, &lt;i&gt;Neoentobdella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Pseudoentobdella.&lt;/i&gt; The affinities of species in a seventh capsalid genus, &lt;i&gt;Trimusculotrema&lt;/i&gt; Whittington &amp; Barton, 1990 (currently in Benedeniinae), are considered briefly based on morphology and host association and reassigned to the Entobdellinae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes; Monopisthocotylea; Benedeniinae; Entobdellinae; &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;macrocolpa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Benedeniella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;posterocolpa&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Trimusculotrema&lt;/i&gt; species; elasmobranch hosts; Myliobatidae; Australia; United Arab Emirates; United States</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whittington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-30</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Betadevario ramachandrani&lt;/i&gt;, a new danionine genus and species from the Western Ghats of India (Teleostei: Cyprinidae: Danioninae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Betadevario,&lt;/i&gt; new genus, with the single species &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ramachandrani,&lt;/i&gt; new species, from Karnataka, southwestern India, is closely related to &lt;i&gt;Devario&lt;/i&gt; but differs from it in having two pairs of long barbels (vs. two pairs of short or rudimentary barbels, or barbels absent), wider cleithral spot which extends to cover three scales horizontally (vs. covering only one scale in width), long and low laminar preorbital process (vs. absent or a slender pointed spine-like process) along the anterior margin of the orbit, a unique flank colour pattern with a wide dark band along the lower side, bordered dorsally by a wide light stripe (vs. vertical bars, or stripes narrow and usually in greater number).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Karnataka; endemism; &lt;i&gt;Devario&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Danio&lt;/i&gt;; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; rhodopsin; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Karnataka</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>P.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pramod</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fang</firstname>
          <lastname>Fang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>Rema</middlename>
          <lastname>Devi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Te-Yu</firstname>
          <lastname>Liao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Indra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <middlename>S. Jameela</middlename>
          <lastname>Beevi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sven</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kullander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-47</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Macrodon atricauda &lt;/i&gt;(Günther, 1880) (Perciformes: Sciaenidae), a valid species from the southwestern Atlantic, with comments on its conservation</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The American sciaenid genus &lt;i&gt;Macrodon&lt;/i&gt; presently consists of only two species, the Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Macrodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancylodon&lt;/i&gt; (Bloch &amp; Schneider, 1801), and the Pacific &lt;i&gt;Macrodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mordax&lt;/i&gt; (Gilbert &amp; Starks, 1904). The two species are distinguished mainly by the number of pored scales on the lateral line (66–78 in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancylodon&lt;/i&gt; vs. 45–55 in &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mordax).&lt;/i&gt; The present study revalidates a third species, the second from the Atlantic, &lt;i&gt;Macrodon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricauda&lt;/i&gt; (Günther, 1880), which is genetically, morphologically, and geographically distinct from &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ancylodon,&lt;/i&gt; occurring between the Brazilian state of Espírito Santo and northern Argentina. It has significant economic importance in the area and thus considerations about its conservation are also presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">King weakfish; geographic distribution; revalidation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">King weakfish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfredo</firstname>
          <lastname>Carvalho-Filho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Simoni</firstname>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Iracilda</firstname>
          <lastname>Sampaio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An old taxonomic dilemma: the identity of the western south Atlantic lebranche mullet (Teleostei: Perciformes: Mugilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The identification of the lebranche mullet in the western south Atlantic has long been problematical. In most recent works either &lt;i&gt;Mugil&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liza&lt;/i&gt; Valenciennes and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platanus&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1880 or &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liza&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalus&lt;/i&gt; Linnaeus, 1758 were recognized from the region and more rarely the occurrence of only one species has been proposed but without sufficient morphological, biochemical or molecular data to allow the designation of the taxonomically appropriate name. Analysis of meristic and morphometric data taken from samples collected from Venezuela to Argentina, clearly indicates that there is only one species of lebranche mullet in the Caribbean Sea region and the Atlantic coast of South America and that &lt;i&gt;Mugil&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liza&lt;/i&gt; is the appropriate name. The comparison of the combined data from all the samples of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liza&lt;/i&gt; with the data taken from one sample of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalus&lt;/i&gt; that originated in the Mediterranean, the possible locality from which type specimens were collected (Eschmeyer and Fricke, 2009), revealed significant differences indicating that they are different species. It is also suggested that individuals from the western north Atlantic identified as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalus&lt;/i&gt; might represent a population of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liza&lt;/i&gt; in this region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mugilid species; Taxonomy; Misidentification; Caribbean and South American Atlantic waters</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mugilid species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Naércio</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Menezes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cláudio</firstname>
          <lastname>De Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mauro</firstname>
          <lastname>Nirchio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-06-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
