<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2532.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">12 Jul. 2010</title>
    <volume>2532</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-07-12</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A taxonomic revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella &lt;/i&gt;Schminke, 1973, with the description of four new species from southeastern India (Crustacea, Malacostraca, Bathynellacea)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella&lt;/i&gt; Schminke, 1973, presently contains six species. Four new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella,&lt;/i&gt; viz. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krishna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vaitarini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;savitri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vidua&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; are described and illustrated herein and their taxonomic position in the genus &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella&lt;/i&gt; discussed. Inhabiting certain rivers and borewells in the State of Andhra Pradesh, southeastern India, these new species introduce several morphologic features that are unique to either the genus or the family Parabathynellidae. The spine row on the uropodal sympod now displays five character states, and high diversity is also seen in the male thoracopod VIII. The salient morphologic characters and their various states in all the habrobathynellid species are reviewed and the original generic diagnosis revised. The palpless mandible with somewhat pyriform pars molaris, bearing 5–6 teeth, is recognised as a signal synapomorphy of &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella.&lt;/i&gt; Two more synapomorphies based on the male thoracopod VIII and caudal furca are added. Considering its special importance in taxonomy, the male thoracopod VIII of the four already known Indian species, viz. &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nagarjunai&lt;/i&gt; Ranga Reddy, 2002; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schminkei&lt;/i&gt; Ranga Reddy, 2004; &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indica&lt;/i&gt;Ranga Reddy &amp; Schminke, 2005 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plenituda&lt;/i&gt; Ranga Reddy &amp; Schminke, 2009, has been reexamined based on topotypes and freshly illustrated with line drawings and digital images, and errors in the original accounts are corrected. Also, the ecology, biogeography and conservation of &lt;i&gt;Habrobathynella&lt;/i&gt; species are briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">stygofauna; Syncarida; Parabathynellidae; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">stygofauna</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yenumula</firstname>
          <middlename>Ranga</middlename>
          <lastname>Reddy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Venkateswara</firstname>
          <middlename>Rao</middlename>
          <lastname>Totakura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Chimaera notafricana &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Chondrichthyes: Chimaeriformes: Chimaeridae), a new species of chimaera from southern Africa </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of chimaera, &lt;i&gt;Chimaera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;notafricana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from specimens collected off the west and south coasts of southern Africa. The new species is distinguished from its closest congener, the eastern North Atlantic &lt;i&gt;Chimaera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monstrosa,&lt;/i&gt; by a combination of morphometric characters and coloration: pectoral fin when depressed reaches to origin of pelvic fin base; caudal fin ventral margin terminating slightly posterior to caudal fin dorsal margin insertion; distance from anterior base of dorsal-fin spine to center of supratemporal canal short (6.5–14.8% HDL); pelvic claspers externally trifid and short (12.1–12.3% BDL), divided for distal one-third of length, not extending past distal tip of pelvic fins; uniform blackish brown with dark bluish streaking, precaudal tail with longitudinal light and dark stripes. This new species has a restricted distribution from Lüderitz, Namibia to south of Algoa Bay, Eastern Cape Province, South Africa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chimaeridae; &lt;i&gt;Chimaera&lt;/i&gt;; southern Africa; new species; endemic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chimaeridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jenny</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kemper</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ebert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leonard</firstname>
          <middlename>J. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Compagno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dominique</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Didier</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-63</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-12</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The family Izinkalidae fam. nov. (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Lysianassoidea) in Australian waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new lysianassoid amphipod family Izinkalidae is established and the genus &lt;i&gt;Izinkala&lt;/i&gt; is reported from Australian waters for the first time. One new species, &lt;i&gt;Izinkala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griffithsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Lysianassoidea; Izinkalidae; &lt;i&gt;Izinkala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;griffithsi&lt;/i&gt;; Australia; taxonomy; new family; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stoddart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-07-12</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
