<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2574.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2574</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new (extinct?) species of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Bufonidae) from Andean Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We studied populations of frogs of the genus &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; from the Pasto Massif of the Andes in southern Colombia and northern Ecuador, and from the Huancabamba depression in southern Ecuador and northern Perú and conclude that they belong to six species, five of which are described as new to science. &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angelito&lt;/i&gt; is recorded for the first time from Ecuador and its range is extended 183 km (airline) southwest of its type locality in Departamento del Cauca, Colombia. We distinguish the five new species from similar ones using features of coloration, skin texture, and morphometrics. We also include osteological data for four of the new species. A putative hybrid zone at Provincia Imbabura, Ecuador, is proposed to exist between the non-sister taxa &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignescens&lt;/i&gt; and one of the new species. Because recent records of four of the new species and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angelito&lt;/i&gt; are lacking despite search efforts, we hypothesize that they are possibly extinct, as are many other Andean &lt;i&gt;Atelopus.&lt;/i&gt; Thus, we categorize these species, applying IUCN Red List criteria, as Critically Endangered (Possibly Extinct). No search efforts have been carried out for one new species (from La Victoria, Colombia); thus, it is included under the Data Deficient category. The conservation of &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; is briefly discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Anura; Bufonidae; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angelito;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ardila&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigas&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orcesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pastuso&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;podocarpus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Colombia; Conservation; Ecuador; Extinction; Morphology; New species; Osteology; Perú; Systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Anura; Bufonidae; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angelito;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ardila&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigas&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orcesi&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pastuso&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;podocarpus&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Colombia; Conservation; Ecuador; Extinction; Morphology; New species; Osteology; Perú</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coloma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duellman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Almendáriz</middlename>
          <lastname>C.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Santiago</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ron</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrea</firstname>
          <lastname>Terán-Valdez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic differentiation in the nearly extinct harlequin frogs (Bufonidae: &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt;), with emphasis on the Andean &lt;i&gt;Atelopus ignescens &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;A. bomolochos&lt;/i&gt; species complexes</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The evolutionary relationships of Andean harlequin frogs were studied, with emphasis on the &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignescens&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bomolochos&lt;/i&gt; species complexes. Sampling included 53 individuals belonging to eight taxa and several unidentified species, for which a mitochondrial fragment (16S, tRNA-Leu, ND1, and tRNA-Ile; 1294 bp) was amplified. Bayesian and Maximum Likelihood analyses were used to obtain hypotheses of relationships. The resulting phylogeny indicates that the species complexes are non-monophyletic. Additionally, analyses support the presence of four or five undescribed species. Most of these populations and newly discovered lineages have not been recorded in several years and are presumed extinct, the exception being two populations of probably new taxa from mid-elevations in southeastern Ecuador found during recent field surveys. Although sampling is limited, geographic isolation is the most plausible cause of differentiation among populations and taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Andes; &lt;i&gt;Atelopus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ignescens&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;bomolochos&lt;/i&gt;; jambato; phylogeny; phylogeography; genetic differentiation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Andes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Guayasamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elisa</firstname>
          <lastname>Bonaccorso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>William</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Duellman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coloma</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
