<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2592.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">31 Aug. 2010</title>
    <volume>2592</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-08-31</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny and classification of Rhagionidae, with implications for Tabanomorpha (Diptera: Brachycera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper updates current knowledge of Rhagionidae and related taxa within the infraorder Tabanomorpha. An estimate of phylogeny for the group is presented, based on 127 morphological characters for 60 ingroup species and molecular characters consisting of 3200+ bp sequences of 28S rDNA for 38 ingroup species. The morphology and molecular datasets are analyzed separately and in a combined analysis, using parsimony, maximum likelihood, and Bayesian methods. Morphological and molecular data, when analyzed separately and in combination, yield similar hypotheses of the evolution within Tabanomorpha. Arthrocerinae (Rhagionidae), Chrysopilinae (Rhagionidae), Rhagioninae (Rhagionidae), Spaniinae (Rhagionidae), Tabanoidea (Pelecorhynchidae, Oreoleptidae, Athericidae, and Tabanidae), and Vermileonidae are recovered consistently. The relationships among the major tabanomorph clades, including &lt;i&gt;Austroleptis&lt;/i&gt; Hardy and &lt;i&gt;Bolbomyia&lt;/i&gt; Loew, remain weakly supported, however. Rhagionidae are recognized as a monophyletic group of four subfamilies and at least 15 extant genera. The subfamily Spaniinae is defined by a special modification of tergite 9 of the female genitalia, which is shared by members of &lt;i&gt;Omphalophora&lt;/i&gt; Becker, &lt;i&gt;Ptiolina&lt;/i&gt; Zetterstedt, &lt;i&gt;Spania&lt;/i&gt; Meigen, &lt;i&gt;Spaniopsis&lt;/i&gt; White, and &lt;i&gt;Symphoromyia&lt;/i&gt; Frauenfeld. &lt;i&gt;Litoleptis&lt;/i&gt; Chillcott is also placed in this group, however this could not be confirmed because females of this genus were not available. The concept of &lt;i&gt;Omphalophora&lt;/i&gt; is clarified and the genus is resurrected from synonymy with &lt;i&gt;Ptiolina.&lt;/i&gt; On this basis, several species are newly transferred to &lt;i&gt;Omphalophora;&lt;/i&gt; they include &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cinereofasciata&lt;/i&gt; (Schummel 1837) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciata&lt;/i&gt; (Loew 1869b) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;majuscula&lt;/i&gt; (Loew 1869b) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigripilosa&lt;/i&gt; (Hardy &amp; McGuire 1947) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; Chrysopilinae is defined by having scale-like setae on the thorax and femur, as in &lt;i&gt;Chrysopilus&lt;/i&gt; Macquart, &lt;i&gt;Schizella&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi, and &lt;i&gt;Stylospania&lt;/i&gt; Frey. &lt;i&gt;Solomomyia&lt;/i&gt; Nagatomi is recognized as a new junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Chrysopilus.&lt;/i&gt; Seven new names within the genus &lt;i&gt;Chrysopilus&lt;/i&gt; are created for binomials that are preoccupied. These include &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amulus&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latifrons&lt;/i&gt; Williston 1901 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latifrons&lt;/i&gt; Bezzi 1898), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batak&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomentosus&lt;/i&gt; Meijere 1924 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tomentosus&lt;/i&gt; Bigot 1887), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mawambus&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscuripes&lt;/i&gt; Brunetti 1927 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obscuripes&lt;/i&gt; Speiser 1923), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meunieri&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nagatomii&lt;/i&gt; Evenhuis 1994 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nagatomii&lt;/i&gt; Yang &amp; Yang 1991), &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occidentalis&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucifer&lt;/i&gt; Adams 1904 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lucifer&lt;/i&gt; Walker 1852), and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amorimi&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fascipennis&lt;/i&gt; Bromley in Curran 1931 (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fascipennis&lt;/i&gt; (Brunetti 1920)). &lt;i&gt;Chrysopilus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; (Yang &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 1997) &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; is transferred from &lt;i&gt;Spatulina&lt;/i&gt; Szilády, where this species was originally placed. Arthrocerinae contains a single genus, &lt;i&gt;Arthroceras&lt;/i&gt; Williston. Phylogenetic analyses consistently show strong support for a clade consisting of Arthrocerinae, Chrysopilinae, and Spaniinae; most females of these subfamilies have spermathecal duct accessory glands. Spermathecal duct accessory glands are reported here for the first time and are unique in Tabanomorpha. Rhagioninae is the earliest branching subfamily of Rhagionidae. The saw sclerite in the larval mandible may be synapomorphic for this subfamily. Members of Rhagioninae include &lt;i&gt;Atherimorpha&lt;/i&gt; White, &lt;i&gt;Desmomyia&lt;/i&gt; Brunetti, &lt;i&gt;Rhagio&lt;/i&gt; Fabricius, and &lt;i&gt;Sierramyia&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Atherimorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;setosus&lt;/i&gt; (Philippi 1865) is recognized as a &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Atherimorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;praefica&lt;/i&gt; (Philippi 1865) and &lt;i&gt;Neorhagio&lt;/i&gt; Lindner 1924 is recognized as a &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Atherimorpha.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Sierramyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is erected for two species from Mexico that were originally placed in &lt;i&gt;Neorhagio&lt;/i&gt; (type species: &lt;i&gt;Neorhagio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;caligatus&lt;/i&gt; Santos 2006). &lt;i&gt;Rhagina&lt;/i&gt; Malloch is recognized as a &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonym&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;Rhagio.&lt;/i&gt; As a result, &lt;i&gt;Rhagio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yangi&lt;/i&gt; Kerr &lt;b&gt;nom.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is created for &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; Yang &amp; Yang 1993a (preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sinensis&lt;/i&gt; Yang &amp; Nagatomi 1992, &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.).&lt;/b&gt; Two enigmatic genera, &lt;i&gt;Bolbomyia&lt;/i&gt; Loew and &lt;i&gt;Austroleptis&lt;/i&gt; Hardy are retained within their own families, Bolbomyiidae &lt;b&gt;status&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;revised&lt;/b&gt; and Austroleptidae, respectively. &lt;i&gt;Alloleptis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tersus&lt;/i&gt; Nagatomi &amp; Saigusa is &lt;i&gt;incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis&lt;/i&gt; within Rhagionoidea. Comments on larval morphology of Tabanomorpha are given in light of this work. A key is given to all families of Tabanomorpha and genera of Rhagionidae. The genera of Austroleptidae, Bolbomyiidae, and Rhagionidae are diagnosed, re-described, and re-classified based on characters and relationships established by the phylogenetic analyses, with a list of included species for each genus. A history of the recent classification of Rhagionidae and related taxa is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tabanoidea; Rhagionoidea; Austroleptidae; Bolbomyiidae; Arthrocerinae; Rhagioninae; Chrysopilinae; Spaniinae; &lt;i&gt;Sierramyia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Omphalophora&lt;/i&gt;; systematics; new genus; phylogeny; taxonomy; combined analysis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tabanoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kerr</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-133</pages>
        <date_published>2010-08-31</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
