<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2624.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">24 Sep. 2010</title>
    <volume>2624</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-09-24</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A checklist of the water mites of Turkey (Acari: Hydrachnidia) with description of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A review is given of all species of water mites reported from Turkey, based on published records and original data from recent research. In total, 236 species and subspecies in 52 genera and 23 families have been found. Two species, &lt;i&gt;Atractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Atractides)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolicus&lt;/i&gt; Pešić, Erman &amp; Esen &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Atractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Atractides)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;martini&lt;/i&gt; Pešić, Erman &amp; Esen &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are described as new to science. The following species are reported for the first time for Turkey: &lt;i&gt;Atractides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inflatipalpis&lt;/i&gt; K.Viets, 1950, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;remotus&lt;/i&gt; Szalay, 1953 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;orghidani&lt;/i&gt; Motaş &amp; Tanasachi, 1960. The following synonyms are established: &lt;i&gt;Hydrovolzia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persica&lt;/i&gt; Bader &amp; Sepasgozarian, 1979 and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anatolica&lt;/i&gt; Oezkan, 1982 = &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cancellata&lt;/i&gt; Walter, 1906; &lt;i&gt;Arrenurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Rhinophoracarus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hazarensis&lt;/i&gt; Özkan &amp; Erman, 1990 = &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abbreviator&lt;/i&gt; Berlese, 1888. The characteristics of the water mite fauna in the treated area are briefly outlined.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Water mites; new species; biodiversity; Turkey; Asia Minor</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Water mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Orhan</firstname>
          <lastname>Erman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Pešić</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yunus</firstname>
          <lastname>Esen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Muhlis</firstname>
          <lastname>Özkan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-48</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-24</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the larval morphology (Zoea I) of the family Hippolytidae (Decapoda, Caridea), with a description of the first stage of the shrimp &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte obliquimanus &lt;/i&gt;Dana, 1852 </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The aim of this study was to summarize the available data on larval morphology of the first zoea of the family Hippolytidae and describe the first zoeal stage of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; from two geographically distinct populations, Brazilian and Caribbean in order to discuss interand intraspecific variability. Ovigerous females of &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; were collected at Cahuita (Limón, Costa Rica) and at Ubatuba (São Paulo, Brazil). We compiled the published descriptions of all available hippolytid Zoea I (66 spp., 21%), and all zoeae share several characteristics. However, such morphological features cannot be used to distinguish the first zoeae of Hippolytidae from other caridean larvae. Historically, the presence of an exopodal seta at the maxillule and the absence of the anal spine/papilla have been considered as characteristic for the Zoea I of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte.&lt;/i&gt; The results of our revision, however, did not support these conclusions: although &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; showed an exopodal seta at the maxillule, four congeners did not bear such structure; moreover, &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; as well as one other congener have an anal spine/papilla. All morphological characters observed in the first zoeal stage of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; are shared with others species of the family Hippolytidae. Intraspecific variability in &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;obliquimanus&lt;/i&gt; was detected in one morphological aspect: the first zoea had four denticles on the ventral margin of the carapace in the Brazilian population, while specimens from the Costa Rican population had three.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; caridean shrimp; Decapoda; larval development; western Atlantic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mariana</firstname>
          <lastname>Terossi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cuesta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ingo</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Wehrtmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mantelatto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-66</pages>
        <date_published>2010-09-24</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
