<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2634.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2634</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Paramphiascella &lt;/i&gt;Lang (Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Miraciidae) from a brackish water pond in Thailand</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the harpacticoid genus &lt;i&gt;Paramphiascella&lt;/i&gt; Lang, 1944 were collected from a brackish water pond located at the Coastal Fisheries Research Development Center, Department of Fisheries, Samut Sakhon province, Thailand, and are described herein. &lt;i&gt;Paramphiascella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahmsi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrarii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are similar to other species of the genus in having a cylindrical body shape, eight-segmented antennules, and both the baseoendopod and exopod of the female P5 with five setae. However, the two new species can be distinguished from other congeners by having one big ovate-striated knob at the inner edge of the male P1 basis. &lt;i&gt;Paramphiascella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahmsi&lt;/i&gt; bears in addition two ovatestriated knobs on the anterior surface of the proximal rim of the male P1 Enp1 while &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrarii&lt;/i&gt; is without any knobs on the endopod. The Enp2 of male P2 of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahmsi&lt;/i&gt; is distally attenuated, with a medially pointed knob close to Enp1. Adjacent to the knob there are two setae, one spinulose and one pectinate, and one club-like seta bifurcate at its tip. In &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrarii,&lt;/i&gt; the medial knob is rounded, a second long attenuation arises near the base of two unequal spinulose setae and the club-like seta is absent. In addition, the P2 Enp1 bears an inner spinulose seta in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dahmsi,&lt;/i&gt; while in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ferrarii&lt;/i&gt; it bears a pectinate seta. These characters are suggested as autapomorphies of the new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Harpacticoid copepod; species description; taxonomy; brackish water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Harpacticoid copepod</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Supawadee</firstname>
          <lastname>Chullasorn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nematodes from galls on Myrtaceae. I. &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia/Fergusonina &lt;/i&gt;galls on &lt;i&gt;Corymbia &lt;/i&gt;spp., with re-description of &lt;i&gt;F. magna &lt;/i&gt;and notes on its phylogenetic relationships</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Fergusobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;magna&lt;/i&gt; (Neotylenchidae: Fergusobiinae), collected from axial bud (‘stem’) galls on &lt;i&gt;Corymbia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tessellaris&lt;/i&gt; growing in coastal regions of Queensland, Australia, is re-described. It is characterised by having a combination of a relatively large, variably shaped parthenogenetic female with a slender conoid tail; a relatively large arcuate infective female with a long slender tail with a pointed tip and a relatively anterior vulva; and relatively large, arcuate, open C or Jshaped males with angular spicules having manubrium and shaft forming 66% of their length, slender tail and peloderan bursa arising at 30–50% body length. Other known forms of &lt;i&gt;Fergusobia/Fergusonina&lt;/i&gt; galls from &lt;i&gt;Corymbia&lt;/i&gt; are outlined, and the morphology of nematodes from them and the shield morphology of their associated mutualistic fly species from &lt;i&gt;Corymbia&lt;/i&gt; spp. are described where known. The possible phylogenetic relationships of these associations from &lt;i&gt;Corymbia&lt;/i&gt; are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">18S rDNA; 28S rDNA D2/D3; COI; DNA sequencing; Australia; Nematoda; Neotylenchidae; galls; Myrtaceae; Fergusoninidae; flies; molecular phylogeny; morphology; taxonomy; coevolution; cospeciation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">18S rDNA</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kerrie</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Davies</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robin</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Giblin-Davis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Weimin</firstname>
          <lastname>Ye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gary</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Taylor</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>W.</firstname>
          <middlename>Kelley</middlename>
          <lastname>Thomas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-40</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Quaternary records of &lt;i&gt;Conilurus &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia: Muridae) from eastern and northern Australia with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Since European arrival in Australia the murid genus &lt;i&gt;Conilurus&lt;/i&gt; Ogilby has suffered severe decline, the causes of which are still uncertain. Knowledge of the distribution of the genus during the Quaternary may be useful in understanding why &lt;i&gt;Conilurus&lt;/i&gt; has declined and thus inform efforts to conserve remaining populations. The late Quaternary distribution of species of &lt;i&gt;Conilurus&lt;/i&gt; is here revised with the extension of the known ranges of two species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albipes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicilattus,&lt;/i&gt; to the north and east of their previously known ranges, respectively. An additional species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of Pleistocene and Holocene dental remains. &lt;i&gt;Conilurus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; is large for the genus and can be distinguished from &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicillatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albipes&lt;/i&gt; by molar dimensions, a posteriorly narrow anterior palatal foramina, the presence of a T3 and anterior cingulum on M 1 , and small or absent posterior cingula on M 1-2 . The southern-most occurrence of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; overlaps the northern-most record of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albipes.&lt;/i&gt; The temporal ranges of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;penicillatus&lt;/i&gt; overlap, but they have not been found in sympatry. Recently recovered fossil and subfossil specimens from the Broken River area, near Townsville, Queensland and Mount Etna (eastern Queensland) indicate that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; had a temporal range from the late Pleistocene to very recent time. Preservation of some specimens from the Broken River area indicates that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;capricornensis&lt;/i&gt; may still be extant in that area.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Queensland; extinction; Pleistocene; ‘old endemic’ rodents; conservation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Queensland</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <lastname>Cramb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Scott</firstname>
          <lastname>Hocknull</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Vertigo botanicorum &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Gastropoda: Pulmonata: Vertiginidae)—a new whorl-snail from the Russian Altai Mountains</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Vertigo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;botanicorum&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is described from the Russian Altai Mountains. The species was recorded in 8 out of 118 study sites and totally 21 live individuals and 15 empty shells were collected. It is a medium-sized &lt;i&gt;Vertigo&lt;/i&gt; species living in various tall-forb meadows, shrubby and forest habitats; avoiding only dry and strictly open sites. Mostly it was found in rather acidic sites of higher altitudes (above 1300 m a.s.l.).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Vertigo&lt;/i&gt;; terrestrial microgastropods; new species; southern Siberia; distribution; ecology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Vertigo&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michal</firstname>
          <lastname>Horsák</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Beata</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pokryszko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Lepidepecreellidae fam. nov. (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Lysianassoidea) in Australian waters</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new lysianassoid amphipod family Lepidepecreellidae is established and the genus &lt;i&gt;Lepidepecreella&lt;/i&gt; is reported from Australian waters for the first time. The new species &lt;i&gt;Lepidepecreella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nellae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Amphipoda; Lysianassoidea; Lepidepecreellidae; &lt;i&gt;Lepidepecreella&lt;/i&gt;; Australia; taxonomy; new family; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>H.</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stoddart</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-04</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
