<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2646.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2646</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Osteology, natural history notes, and phylogenetic relationships of the poorly known Caribbean frog &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus nesiotus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura, Leptodactylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanonotus&lt;/i&gt; group consists of 15 species, but references to skeletal characters are available for only three species: &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;leptodactyloides,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanonotus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diedrus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotus&lt;/i&gt; is a member of the &lt;i&gt;melanonotus&lt;/i&gt; group known only from the type locality, Bonasse swamp, on the Southwestern peninsula of Trinidad, Trinidad and Tobago. This species has been categorized as vulnerable given its restricted distribution. Herein, we report the adult osteology of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotus,&lt;/i&gt; the skeletal characters are compared with the available data from other &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; species. A phylogenetic analysis recovers a paraphyletic &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanonotus&lt;/i&gt; group relative to the &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;latrans&lt;/i&gt; group. A monophyletic “latrans-melanonotus” clade is supported by five synapomorphies. &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotus&lt;/i&gt; is recovered as the sister species of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;validus,&lt;/i&gt; a relationship supported by two synapomorphies: T-shaped terminal phalanges and a dark-colored stripe on the outer surface of arm. In addition, we report on the ecology of this poorly known species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">skeleton; ecology; phylogenetic relationships; &lt;i&gt;Leptodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">skeleton</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>Laura</middlename>
          <lastname>Ponssa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jowers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rafael</firstname>
          <middlename>O.</middlename>
          <lastname>De Sá</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An assessment of morphometric and molecular variation in &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiata &lt;/i&gt;(Wagner, 1847) (Didelphimorphia: Didelphidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study aims to clarify the taxonomic status of &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorex,&lt;/i&gt; using molecular and morphometric data. Cytochrome-b sequences were obtained from specimens morphologically assignable to those taxa from the vicinity of type localities, but also representing their presumptive area of sympatry and extremes in their known distributions. These sequences were compared to GenBank downloaded sequences of select &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; spp. and also of &lt;i&gt;Marmosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lepida,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Micoureus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;demerarae,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Didelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albiventris,&lt;/i&gt; used as outgroups. Genetic distances and maximum likelihood analyses were performed to recover phylogenetic affinities among taxa. To access morphometric variation, univariate and multivariate statistical methods (Principal Component Analysis and Canonical Variate Analysis) were applied to the covariance matrix of 25 craniometric measurements obtained from a total of 108 specimens sampled across the geographic ranges of the species. The molecular analyses revealed a clade composed by haplotypes assignable to &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorex&lt;/i&gt; (sensu Pine and Handley 2007) as distinct from the remaining &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; species sampled to date, with 100% bootstrap support. Within this clade, one haplotype from Itatiaia was the sister clade to the remaining 11 specimens from Montevideo (Uruguay), Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina states (Brazil), which formed an assemblage without clear geographic arrangement. In the morphometric analyses, the first two principal components of morphometric data separated variables associated with general latent size comparably expressed in all samples, and a group of variables including molars widths, molar toothrow length, and postorbital constriction breadth, which separates the geographic samples in a sequence coincident, to a large extent, with their latitudinal distributions. The sample from Itatiaia, Rio de Janeiro State, was again revealed as clearly distinct from the remaining samples, suggesting that it may represent a peripheral isolated population. With the study of original descriptions and published information on the type material of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorex,&lt;/i&gt; including photographs of syntypes, our analyses point to the recognition of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorex&lt;/i&gt; as a subjective junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiata,&lt;/i&gt; which is then regarded as a widespread taxon ranging from the latitudes of southern Buenos Aires Province and Córdoba in Argentina to at least Minas Gerais State in southeastern Brazil, through the Pampas and the Atlantic Forest domains.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">geographic variation; molecular systematics; multivariate statistics; cranial morphometrics; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sorex&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;henseli&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;itatiayae&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevicaudis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Monodelphis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tricolor&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paulensis&lt;/i&gt;; semelparity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">geographic variation</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Júlio</firstname>
          <middlename>Fernando</middlename>
          <lastname>Vilela</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudia</firstname>
          <middlename>Augusta</middlename>
          <lastname>De Moraes Russo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>João</firstname>
          <middlename>Alves</middlename>
          <lastname>De Oliveira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-42</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of oribatid mites of the superfamily Galumnoidea (Acari: Oribatida) from Ethiopia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of oribatid mites of the superfamily Galumnoidea, &lt;i&gt;Pilizetes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anufrievi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Taeniogalumna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;behanae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Galumnella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;baleensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; are described from Bale Mountains National Park (African region, Ethiopia). Keys to closely related species of these genera are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">oribatid mites; new species; Ethiopia; Bale Mountains National Park</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">oribatid mites</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergey</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ermilov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ekaterina</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sidorchuk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leonid</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rybalov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-62</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The nominal species of rays (Chondrichthyes) described by Stephan (1779)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Stephan's doctoral dissertation (1779) often appears in bibliographies but it does not seem to have been examined in the last 200 years. Ten names are available from it. Six are junior homonyms and three are junior subjective synonyms and do not present major nomenclatural problems. &lt;i&gt;Raia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sloani&lt;/i&gt; Stephan, 1779 is a potential senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ajereba&lt;/i&gt; Walbaum, 1795. Both names are based on several species. A common lectotype is designated and &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ajereba&lt;/i&gt; is declared &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;protectum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sloani&lt;/i&gt; is declared &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oblitum.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">nomenclature; &lt;i&gt;Paratrygon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ajereba&lt;/i&gt;; Artedi; Potamotrygonidae; Marcgrave</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">nomenclature</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maurice</firstname>
          <lastname>Kottelat</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
