<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2652.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2652</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from northern Laos</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the gekkonid genus &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; from northern Laos, based on four specimens from Luang Nam Tha Province. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wayakonei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from the remaining bent-toed-geckos by the combination of the following characters: snout-vent length up to 90 mm; 7–8 supralabials; 9–10 infralabials; rostrum bearing smooth scales; 34–45 scales between fifth supralabials; dorsal tubercles smooth or slightly keeled; 17–19 dorsal tubercle rows; ventrolateral folds slightly developed, with large tubercles; 31–35 ventrals; 85–98 scales around midbody; 151–163 scales between mental and cloacal slit; 6–8 precloacal pores in both sexes; precloacal groove lacking; enlarged femoral scales absent; femoral pores lacking; subcaudals somewhat enlarged, broadened; tail tubercles flat, smooth; head and dorsum with blotched to reticulated pattern.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wayakonei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.;&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Laos</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Truong</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Phouthone</firstname>
          <lastname>Kingsada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Herbert</firstname>
          <lastname>Rösler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Markus</firstname>
          <lastname>Auer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A cryptic complex of &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema &lt;/i&gt;species (Digenea: Transversotrematidae) on labroid, haemulid and lethrinid fishes in the Indo–West Pacific Region, including the description of three new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Sequences of ITS2 rDNA of 36 individuals of 16 host/parasite/location combinations of transversotrematids from labrid, scarid, haemulid and lethrinid fishes from Heron and Lizard Islands on the Great Barrier Reef and Ningaloo Reef Western off Australia comprised four distinct genotypes. One genotype was associated with three species of Labridae at Heron Island, the second with eight species of Scaridae at Heron Island, the third with two species of Scaridae from Ningaloo, and the fourth with two species of Lethrinidae and one of Haemulidae from Lizard Island. All four forms are broadly morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haasi&lt;/i&gt; Witenberg, 1944. The two genotypes from scarids differed at only a single base position and were morphologically indistinguishable; all other combinations of genotypes differed by at least 3 bases. Comparisons between specimens from labrids, scarids, and haemulids and lethrinids revealed consistent differences in the number of vitelline follicles enclosed by the cyclocoel and in the relative sizes of the testes. We conclude that these three forms should be considered distinct species. The species associated with labrids is broadly consistent with and has previously been identified as &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haasi&lt;/i&gt; which was originally reported from an unknown fish from the Red Sea. As no molecular comparison can be made between the original &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;haasi&lt;/i&gt; and the three similar forms from Australia, we propose three new species: &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from labrids, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigantica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from scarids, and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacerta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from haemulids and lethrinids.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Digenea; Transversotrematidae; &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gigantica&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Transversotrema&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lacerta&lt;/i&gt;; cryptic; Great Barrier Reef; Ningaloo Reef; WA</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Digenea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hunter</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>E.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ingram</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Adlard</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cribb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mysids (Crustacea: Peracarida) from the southern Indian Ocean with descriptions of two new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of mysids belonging to two genera from the southern Indian Ocean (Lat. 31–55°S and Long. 45°E) are reported, of these two species - &lt;i&gt;Siriella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevispina&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Euchaetomera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;-&lt;/i&gt; are recorded as new to science. &lt;i&gt;Siriella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;brevispina&lt;/i&gt; shares characters associated with the Brevicaudataand Thompsonii-groups and is distinguished from related species by the presence of a short telson, the anterior margin of the carapace with a triangular rostral plate, the labrum with a long process on the anterior margin, and the inner margin of the uropodal endopod showing an alternating arrangement of long and short spines. &lt;i&gt;Euchaetomera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; is distinguished from the morphologically similar species &lt;i&gt;Euchaetomera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zurstrasseni&lt;/i&gt; by the absence of an ocular papilla, presence of a distal suture in the antennal scale, and the arrangement of spines on the telson.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mysids; &lt;i&gt;Siriella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Euchaetomera&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; systematics; southern Indian Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mysids</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Abraham</firstname>
          <lastname>Biju</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Purushothaman</firstname>
          <lastname>Jasmine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Saramma</firstname>
          <middlename>U.</middlename>
          <lastname>Panampunnayil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and three new species of alpheid shrimps (Crustacea, Decapoda, Caridea) from the tropical American coasts</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new alpheid shrimp genus, &lt;i&gt;Triacanthoneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; is established for three new species from shallow marine waters of Central and South America. &lt;i&gt;Triacanthoneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;toro&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; the type species of the new genus, is described based on four specimens from Bocas del Toro, Caribbean coast of Panama. &lt;i&gt;Triacanthoneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacificus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of a single type specimen from the Pacific coast of Panama and an additional specimen from Bahía Malaga, Pacific coast of Colombia. Finally, &lt;i&gt;Triacanthoneus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alacranes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described based on a single specimen collected near Alacranes Reef, off Yucatán Peninsula in the southern Gulf of Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Triacanthoneus&lt;/i&gt; shares many features with &lt;i&gt;Salmoneus&lt;/i&gt; Holthuis, 1955, but can be easily distinguished by the presence of three very strong and sharp teeth on the carapace, one being in a mediodorsal position posterior to carapace mid-length, and two in a dorsolateral post-hepatic position. This carapace armature is unique within the family Alpheidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Alpheidae; shrimp; new genus; new species; Panama; Mexico; Colombia; Eastern Pacific; Western Atlantic; transisthmian</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-63</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Decapauropus remyi &lt;/i&gt;(Bagnall, 1935) (Myriapoda, Pauropoda), a worm-like pauropod from a sandy beach: first record from Scandinavia, neotype selection and redescription</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A species new to the Scandinavian fauna, &lt;i&gt;Decapauropus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;remyi&lt;/i&gt; (Bagnall), is reported from Norway. The original description is amended and a neotype is designated.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Myriapoda; Pauropoda; &lt;i&gt;Decapauropus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; neotype</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Myriapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ulf</firstname>
          <lastname>Scheller</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arne</firstname>
          <lastname>Fjellberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
