<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2657.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">26 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2657</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Six new species of pyramidellids (Mollusca, Gastropoda, Pyramidelloidea) from West Africa, introducing the new genus &lt;i&gt;Kongsrudia&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During an ongoing project investigating the benthic fauna of the Gulf of Guinea several new species of Pyramidellidae were identified. In spite of several recent investigations of the pyramidellid fauna of the area, a great portion of the fauna is obviously still un-described. This paper introduces five new species of &lt;i&gt;Turbonilla&lt;/i&gt; sensu lato (T. &lt;i&gt;krakstadi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anselmopenasi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iseborae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;korantengi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alvheimi).&lt;/i&gt; A new Chrysallininae genus, &lt;i&gt;Kongsrudia,&lt;/i&gt; is introduced with &lt;i&gt;Actaeopyramis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gruveli&lt;/i&gt; as type species. A new species, &lt;i&gt;K.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rolani&lt;/i&gt; is described, and &lt;i&gt;Pyrgulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;approximans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Chrysallida&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ersei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pyrgulina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mutata&lt;/i&gt; (an existing nom. nov. pro &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lamyi)&lt;/i&gt; are transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Kongsrudia.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Odostomidae; Chrysallidinae; &lt;i&gt;Chrysallida&lt;/i&gt;; Heterostropha; distribution; Pyramidellidae; Turbonillidae; Turbonillinae; &lt;i&gt;Turbonilla&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Odostomidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Frøydis</firstname>
          <lastname>Lygre</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Christoffer</firstname>
          <lastname>Schander</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Acanthochondria cyclopsetta &lt;/i&gt;Pearse, 1952 and &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;alleni &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Copepoda; Cyclopoida; Chondracanthidae) from flatfish hosts of the U.S.A., with comments on the taxonomic position of &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;zebriae &lt;/i&gt;Ho, Kim &amp; Kumar, 2000 and &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;bicornis &lt;/i&gt;Shiino, 1955 and the validity of &lt;i&gt;Pterochondria &lt;/i&gt;Ho, 1973</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A redescription of &lt;i&gt;Acanthochondria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclopsetta&lt;/i&gt; Pearse, 1952 (Copepoda; Chondracanthidae), hitherto reported only from the Mexican flounder, &lt;i&gt;Cyclopsetta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chittendeni&lt;/i&gt; Bean (Pleuronectiformes; Paralichthyidae), from Padre Island in the Gulf of Mexico, is presented based on female specimens from the spotfin flounder, &lt;i&gt;Cyclopsetta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fimbriata&lt;/i&gt; (Goode &amp; Bean), collected off the coast of South Carolina, U.S.A. Furthermore, a description of the male of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cyclopsetta&lt;/i&gt; is provided for the first time. &lt;i&gt;Acanthochondria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alleni&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is also described based on specimens of both sexes collected from the fantail sole, &lt;i&gt;Xystreurys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;liolepis&lt;/i&gt; Jordan &amp; Gilbert (Pleuronectiformes: Paralichthyidae), caught in the Southern California Bight, U.S.A. These two species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthochondria&lt;/i&gt; differ morphologically from their congeners by having a Type B-V antennule and elongate leg 2 rami (Type D), but can be distinguished from each other by differences in head shape, trunk shape, the relative size of the posterolateral processes of the trunk, the relative size of the abdominal somite, the insertion point of the caudal ramus, shape of the antennule tip, ornamentation of the antennal claw, ornamentation of the labrum, number of accessory teeth on the maxilliped claw, and ornamentation of legs 1 and 2 of the adult female. The taxonomic position of &lt;i&gt;Acanthochondria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zebriae&lt;/i&gt; Ho, Kim &amp; Kumar, 2000 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicornis&lt;/i&gt; Shiino, 1955 as well as the validity of the chondracanthid genus &lt;i&gt;Pterochondria&lt;/i&gt; Ho, 1973 are also discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; parasite; Pleuronectiformes; Paralichthyidae; North America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Danny</firstname>
          <lastname>Tang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julianne</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kalman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ju-Shey</firstname>
          <lastname>Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A phylogenetic reassessment of African fossorial skinks in the subfamily Acontinae (Squamata: Scincidae): evidence for parallelism and polyphyly</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Acontinae is a well-supported clade of limbless skinks from sub-Saharan Africa for which three fossorial genera⎯Acontias, &lt;i&gt;Acontophiops,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus⎯have&lt;/i&gt; been traditionally recognized. However, recent phylogenetic analyses demonstrate conflicting support for the monophyly of &lt;i&gt;Acontias&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus,&lt;/i&gt; despite limited taxon sampling for the latter genus. We re-investigate acontine evolutionary relationships, including all currently recognized species of &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus,&lt;/i&gt; in phylogenetic analyses of mitochondrial (Cytb, &lt;i&gt;Co1,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;16s)&lt;/i&gt; and nuclear (Rag1) gene sequences. Our results show that &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus&lt;/i&gt; is polyphyletic and represented in three distinct clades, one of which constitutes the sister lineage to other acontines. The remaining typhlosaurs form strongly-supported clades with either &lt;i&gt;Acontophiops&lt;/i&gt; or the recently-described genus &lt;i&gt;Microacontias&lt;/i&gt; (formerly &lt;i&gt;Acontias&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;litoralis).&lt;/i&gt; We use this new phylogenetic framework to revise acontine taxonomy. &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to five species from southwestern Africa, all characterized by an attenuate body form. &lt;i&gt;Acontias&lt;/i&gt; is expanded to include the former &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantiacus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cregoi,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lineatus&lt;/i&gt; groups as well as &lt;i&gt;Acontophiops&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Microacontias.&lt;/i&gt; Species transfer between acontine genera created two secondary homonyms; thus the affected taxa are assigned replacement names.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">molecular phylogenetics; convergence; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Acontias&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Typhlosaurus&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">molecular phylogenetics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Trip</firstname>
          <lastname>Lamb</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sayantan</firstname>
          <lastname>Biswas</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Aaron</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bauer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of night lizard of the genus &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Xantusiidae) from southern Puebla, México</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Sierra Negra in southern Puebla. This new species is known only from the type locality and is characterized by a combination of several characters (number of dorsal scales, total of femoral pores, number of lateral tubercles, number the dorsal interwhorls separated the whorls, number of the paravertebral rows, number of the toe lamellae and number of gulars). It lives between rocks in remnants of Tropical Evergreen Forest. The description of this new species increases the number of species in the genus to 19.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zongolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species; Xantusiidae; México; Puebla</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Lepidophyma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zongolica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; new species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Uri</firstname>
          <middlename>Omar</middlename>
          <lastname>García-Vázquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luis</firstname>
          <lastname>Canseco-Márquez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>Luis</middlename>
          <lastname>Aguilar-López</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Glyptogidiella omanica &lt;/i&gt;gen. et sp. nov., an inland groundwater bogidiellid from Oman with enlarged coxal plate V (Crustacea, Amphipoda)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of Amphipoda is reported from inland ground waters of the Sultanate of Oman. Although &lt;i&gt;Glyptogidiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;omanica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; exhibits several features typical of the Bogidiellidae (i. e. combined display of distinct carpal lobe on first gnathopod, reduced pleopodal rami, and unsegmented exopodite of third uropod), its exceptionally large fifth coxal plate and short rami of third uropod do not fit in the restricted diagnosis of the family as recently presented elsewhere. In fact, the enlarged coxal plate V is a feature not reported in any other amphipod, whereas no other bogidiellid displays an expanded basis on pereopod VII. The habitus of &lt;i&gt;Glyptogidiella&lt;/i&gt; is not typical for a dweller of a true interstitial niche, with its short antennae, large coxal plate and short and stubby rami on the third uropod. This suggests that the interstitial medium could not be the primary habitat for the species, and that the underground of wadis might contain interstices of large size and could also be in contact with karstic hollows.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gammaridea; Bogidiellidae; stygofauna; subterranean waters; hyporheic; wadi; Arabian Peninsula</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gammaridea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ronald</firstname>
          <lastname>Vonk</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Damià</firstname>
          <lastname>Jaume</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-65</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The advertisement call of the Narrow-mouthed frog &lt;i&gt;Chiasmocleis avilapiresae&lt;/i&gt; Peloso &amp; Sturaro, 2008 (Amphibia, Anura, Microhylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Flávio</firstname>
          <middlename>Bezerra</middlename>
          <lastname>Barros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <middlename>L. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Peloso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luís</firstname>
          <lastname>Vicente</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Henrique</firstname>
          <middlename>Miguel</middlename>
          <lastname>Pereira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>José</middlename>
          <lastname>Sturaro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>66-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-26</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
