<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2660.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Oct. 2010</title>
    <volume>2660</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Oregodasys &lt;/i&gt;(Gastrotricha: Macrodasyida: Thaumastodermatidae) from Carrie Bow Cay, Belize with ultrastructural observations of the epidermal glandular system</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This study represents the first report of Gastrotricha from the coast of Belize. Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Oregodasys&lt;/i&gt; (Macrodasyida: Thaumastodermatidae) are described from sublittoral sediments around the island of Carrie Bow Cay in the Belizean barrier reef complex. &lt;i&gt;Oregodasys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;norenburgi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is unique in the possession of paired red ocelli and in the quantity and distribution of lateral and posterior adhesive tubes. &lt;i&gt;Oregodasys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katharinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is allied with species that possess ventrolateral cirri in the posterior body region, but is distinguished based on the quantity of cirri and adhesive tubes and the bipartite structure of the caudal organ. Ultrastructural analysis of the bodywall of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;katharinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; reveals a highly glandular epithelium covered by a bilayered cuticle consisting of a thin exocuticle and thicker endocuticle containing electron-dense elements. At least three types of papillae are present beneath the cuticle: blunt papillae, triangle-shaped papillae, and sensory papillae. The sensory papillae are two-part structures consisting of a porous epidermal cell and a monociliated epidermal cell. The ultrastructure of blunt papillae was not examined, but triangular papillae are formed from neck-like extensions of underlying glandulocytes and contain a pore to the external environment. Insunk glandulocytes are present between the various papillae and have an elongate neck that extends between epidermal cells. All glandulocytes contain a variety of membrane-bound secretory vesicles with a wide range of staining characteristics, from electron lucent to electron dense.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New species; gastrotrich; meiofauna; Central America; Caribbean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rick</firstname>
          <lastname>Hochberg</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Aromobatidae) from the Pakaraima Mountains of Guyana</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt; from the Pakaraima Mountains of Guyana. &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is currently known from Maringma Tepui at 1060 m elevation and from Mt. Ayanganna at 1490 m elevation. The new species can be distinguished from all known congeners by the following combination of characters: relatively large size (females up to 28.3 mm), head large, Finger I subequal or shorter than II, the tip of Finger IV surpassing the base of the distal tubercle on Finger III when fingers are adpressed, fingers with preaxial keel-like lateral folds, best developed on Fingers II and III, toes moderately webbed with folded flaplike fringing, symmetrical cloacal tubercles present, dorsolateral stripe absent, ventrolateral stripe present, inconspicuous, oblique lateral stripe present, often broken in spots. &lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;megacephalus&lt;/i&gt; has been previously confused with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tepuyensis,&lt;/i&gt; a taxon described from Auyantepui in Venezuela.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt;; endemism; Guiana Shield; Pantepui; taxonomy; tepui</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Anomaloglossus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ross</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Macculloch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Amy</firstname>
          <lastname>Lathrop</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Bert</firstname>
          <lastname>Willaert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franky</firstname>
          <lastname>Bossuyt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>18-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) from Vietnam and further information on &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax tuberosus&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of megophryid frog from central Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croceus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is most similar to &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosus,&lt;/i&gt; but distinguished from this and all other &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; species by its bright orange belly in life and by its unique, complex advertisement call consisting of 4–6 variably pulsed notes with a dominant frequency of 2635–3000 Hz. In contrast, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosus&lt;/i&gt; has an advertisement call consisting of a single, weakly pulsed note lasting 54–78 ms with a dominant frequency of 2584–2756.2 Hz. &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croceus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be further distinguished from its congeners by a combination of an indistinct tympanum, highly tuberculate dorsum, medium body size (22.2–27.3 mm in 16 adult males), head slightly wider than long, rudimentary webbing between toes I–III, no webbing between toes III–V, no lateral fringing on toes, and no ventrolateral glands. The new species is only known from a single locality in evergreen forest at 1316 m elevation. Males were found calling from leaf litter and low vegetation adjacent to a shallow, rocky stream. We suggest the species should be considered Data Deficient following IUCN’s Red List categories.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Acoustics; Anura; &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;croceus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Leptolalax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tuberosus&lt;/i&gt;; Vietnam; Southeast Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Acoustics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jodi</firstname>
          <middlename>J. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rowley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hoang</firstname>
          <middlename>Duc</middlename>
          <lastname>Huy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Le</firstname>
          <middlename>Thi Thuy</middlename>
          <lastname>Duong</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dau</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Vinh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cao</firstname>
          <middlename>Tien</middlename>
          <lastname>Trung</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-45</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships within the &lt;i&gt;cahirinus-dimidiatus &lt;/i&gt;group of the genus &lt;i&gt;Acomys &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia: Muridae): new mitochondrial lineages from Sahara, Iran and the Arabian Peninsula</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Spiny mice belonging to the &lt;i&gt;cahirinus-dimidiatus&lt;/i&gt; group of the genus &lt;i&gt;Acomys&lt;/i&gt; have become a widely used model in physiology and behaviour. To improve current knowledge concerning the phylogeny of this taxon, we analysed 24 samples from Libya, Chad, Egypt, Jordan, Cyprus, Crete, Turkey, Yemen and Iran. We sequenced the whole mitochondrial control region and part of the flanking tRNA genes for a total length of 986 to 996 bp and described 22 haplotypes. Our results confirmed that the Afro-Mediterranean and Asian clades are clearly distinct (p-distance = 68.1%). The former clade corresponds to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cahirinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; (i.e. including also the Cretan &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minous,&lt;/i&gt; Cypriot &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotes&lt;/i&gt; and Turkish &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cilicicus).&lt;/i&gt; Haplotypes of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cahirinus&lt;/i&gt; from the E Sahara (S Egypt, SW Libya, N Chad) grouped with those of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cilicicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minous&lt;/i&gt; (p-distance ≤ 2.2%), while haplotypes of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotes&lt;/i&gt; grouped with one haplotype representing the commensal &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cahirinus&lt;/i&gt; from Cairo (p-distance = 1.2%). Close similarity among haplotypes from mainland Africa and NE Mediterranean (clade &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cahirinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto)&lt;/i&gt; support the hypothesis that ancestors of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nesiotes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cilicicus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minous&lt;/i&gt; dispersed most probably as commensal populations, thus questioning their status of valid species. The most surprising finding was the considerable genetic variation in Asia. In addition to a haplogroup from Sinai and Jordan (corresponding to &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dimidiatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stricto),&lt;/i&gt; we detected two previously unknown haplogroups, from Yemen and Iran + United Arab Emirates. These clades are fairly distinct and separate species/subspecies status of these animals might be further considered.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">spiny mice; mitochondrial DNA; mitochondrial control region; D-loop; phylogeography; commensalism; Yemen; Libya; Cyprus; Persian Gulf</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">spiny mice</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Frynta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Klára</firstname>
          <lastname>Palupčíková</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Erica</firstname>
          <lastname>Bellinvia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Petr</firstname>
          <lastname>Benda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hana</firstname>
          <lastname>Skarlantová</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lucie</firstname>
          <lastname>Schwarzová</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Modrý</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of smooth horned frog, genus &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys &lt;/i&gt;Miranda-Ribeiro (Amphibia: Anura: Cycloramphidae), from the Atlantic Rainforest of eastern Bahia, Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of smooth horned frog related to the &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;appendiculata&lt;/i&gt; complex, constituting the northernmost record of that complex for the Atlantic Forest remnants in eastern Bahia, northeastern Brazil, within a region known as Vale do Jiquiriçá. &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctaritae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is diagnosed from all congeners by the combination of medium size (snout–vent length 38.4–45.5 mm), single and long uni-cuspidate palpebral appendage, rostral appendage longer than upper lip width, presence of preocular crest, frontoparietal crest poorly developed, color of ventral surfaces, and acoustic parameters of the advertisement call.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Alsodinae; &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;appendiculata&lt;/i&gt; species complex; &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sanctaritae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Vale do Jiquiriçá</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Alsodinae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Alberto Gonçalves</middlename>
          <lastname>Cruz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcelo</firstname>
          <middlename>Felgueiras</middlename>
          <lastname>Napoli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-67</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Axonopsis kermanica &lt;/i&gt;nom. n., a new replacement name for the water mite &lt;i&gt;A. iranica &lt;/i&gt;Pešić &amp; Asadi, 2010 (Acari: Hydrachnidia, Aturidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <lastname>Pešić</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mahdieh</firstname>
          <lastname>Asadi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-10-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
