<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2680.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Nov. 2010</title>
    <volume>2680</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sabellaria isumiensis &lt;/i&gt;n. sp. (Annelida: Polychaeta: Sabellariidae) from shallow waters off Onjuku, Boso Peninsula, Japan, and re-descriptions of three Indo-West Pacific sabellariid species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Sabellaria&lt;/i&gt; Lamarck, 1812, is described from shallow waters off Onjuku, the Pacific side of Boso Peninsula, Chiba, Japan. &lt;i&gt;Sabellaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;isumiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is a gregarious species building colonies of tubes made of sand and shell debris over 2 m wide in the intertidal to subtidal zone of the rocky shores. The new species is distinguished by the character combination of having 1 or 2 pairs of nuchal spines, median teeth of outer paleae with 3–5 lateral spines, two kinds (long and short) of opercular paleae in the middle row of the crown, with slender blades of long ones curved outward. Morphological features of the species are described in details and compared to those of congeners from Japan and world-wide. We re-describe three poorly known sabellariid species, &lt;i&gt;Sabellaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;javanica&lt;/i&gt; Augener, 1934 from Java, Indonesia, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chandraae&lt;/i&gt; de Silva, 1961 from Galle Force, Sri Lanka, and &lt;i&gt;Neosabellaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uschakovi&lt;/i&gt; Kirtley, 1994 from the Far Eastern Seas of Russia. The descriptions are based on the type specimens, and we particularly emphasize the head morphology and paleal characters. We provide a summary of diagnostic characters in the genus &lt;i&gt;Sabellaria&lt;/i&gt; and propose new morphological groupings that later will be tested in the framework of a formal phylogenetic analysis.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Indo-West Pacific; &lt;i&gt;Neosabellaria&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sabellaria&lt;/i&gt;; paleae morphology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Indo-West Pacific</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Eijiroh</firstname>
          <lastname>Nishi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julie</firstname>
          <middlename>Helen</middlename>
          <lastname>Bailey-Brock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andre</firstname>
          <middlename>Souza Dos</middlename>
          <lastname>Santos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hiroyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Tachikawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Elena</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kupriyanova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of earthworms belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; (Oligochaeta: Megascolecidae) from Hainan Island, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper describes three new species of earthworms from Hainan Island, China: &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trapezoides&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conchipapillatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dongfangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;trapezoides&lt;/i&gt; has no pigment, and has two pairs of spermathecal pores in 6/7 and 7/8 arranged trapezoidally near the mid-ventral line, a complicated glandular region on ventral side of 1/2XVII–1/4XIX, developed prostates and repeatedly curved prostatic ducts close to ventral midline. &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;conchipapillatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has no pigment, and has a pair of large convex smooth shellfish-like papillae in male pore region, only one pair of spermathecal pores in 5/6 and undeveloped thin prostates which closely adherent to the body wall. &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dongfangensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has a pair of male pores on the centre of a flat-topped conical protuberance surrounded by three to five circular folds, and five pairs of spermathecal pores in 4/5–8/9.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">earthworms; Oligochaeta; Megascolecidae; &lt;i&gt;Amynthas&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Hainan; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">earthworms</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jing</firstname>
          <lastname>Sun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Qi</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jiang-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Qiu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-32</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zullobalanus santamariaensis &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov., a new late Miocene barnacle species of the family Archaeobalanidae (Cirripedia: Thoracica), from the Azores</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Archaeobalanidae barnacle is described from the late Miocene and early Pliocene of Santa Maria Island (Azores). Samples were collected primarily from outcrops at Malbusca and “Pedra-que-Pica”. &lt;i&gt;Zullobalanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santamariaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is endemic to the Azores archipelago and until the discovery of this material, the genus was known only from the Southern Hemisphere. For such a long-range distribution we assume a combination of planktotrophic larval development, sea-surface oceanic currents and transport by cetaceans. This study endorses the elevation of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Zullobalanus&lt;/i&gt; to generic level.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Balanomorpha; Archaeobalanidae; &lt;i&gt;Zullobalanus&lt;/i&gt;; Azores; Miocene</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Balanomorpha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kai</firstname>
          <lastname>Winkelmann</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Buckeridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Cristina</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Ana Manso</middlename>
          <lastname>Dionísio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <lastname>Medeiros</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mário</firstname>
          <lastname>Cachão</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sérgio</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ávila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-44</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Athanas &lt;/i&gt;Leach, 1814 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Alpheidae) from Madagascar and Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of alpheid shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ahyongi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described based on two type specimens from Nosy-Bé, Madagascar, and one additional specimen from Okinawa, Ryukyu Archipelago, Japan. The new species differs from all other species of &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt; by a unique combination of morphological features, mostly on the frontal region and chelipeds, and has a very characteristic colour pattern. The specimens from Nosy-Bé were collected from burrows of unknown hosts, suggesting a commensal life style.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Caridea; shrimp; Alpheidae; &lt;i&gt;Athanas&lt;/i&gt;; new species</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Arthur</firstname>
          <lastname>Anker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>45-54</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Post-larval stages of &lt;i&gt;Ascoschoengastia (Laurentella) lorius &lt;/i&gt;(Gunther) (Acariformes: Trombiculidae) provide evidence for a nest-based life history</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">While certain ecological groups of trombiculid mites are thought to be specialised for nest occupation, supporting evidence is rare. A putatively nest-specialised trombiculid is here described in detail. Larvae, a deutonymph and adults of the trombiculid genus &lt;i&gt;Ascoschoengastia&lt;/i&gt; were collected from three tree hollow nests occupied by Eclectus parrots (Eclectus &lt;i&gt;roratus)&lt;/i&gt; and Sulphur-crested Cockatoos (Cacatua &lt;i&gt;galerita)&lt;/i&gt; at Iron Range, Cape York Peninsula. The larvae are &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Laurentella) &lt;i&gt;lorius&lt;/i&gt; (Gunther), a species originally described from an Eclectus parrot in Papua New Guinea. Deutonymph and adult &lt;i&gt;Ascoschoengastia&lt;/i&gt; are also assigned to this species based on their co-occurrence with larvae in this specific and isolated microhabitat. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;lorius&lt;/i&gt; is inferred to have a nest-based life history. Active stases are described with attention to sensory setae. The previous synonomy of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;daria&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (L.) &lt;i&gt;lorius&lt;/i&gt; is rejected. A key to Australian species of &lt;i&gt;Ascoschoengastia&lt;/i&gt; is presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">nidicole; arboreal; tree hollow nest; yeast; endosymbiosis; Psittaciformes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">nidicole</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <lastname>Shaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-64</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of the hylodid frog &lt;i&gt;Hylodes charadranaetes &lt;/i&gt;Heyer and Cocroft, 1986</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>Nogueira</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <middlename>Costa</middlename>
          <lastname>Siqueira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Davor</firstname>
          <lastname>Vrcibradic</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>Norberto</middlename>
          <lastname>Weber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>Frederico D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
