<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2690.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Nov. 2010</title>
    <volume>2690</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New data on the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Troglohyphantes &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae, Linyphiidae) in the Italian Alps, with the description of a new species and a new synonymy</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper we describe &lt;i&gt;Troglohyphantes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lanai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; from Pennine Alps and the unknown female of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bonzanoi,&lt;/i&gt; from Ligurian Alps. Based on the collection of new material and on the examination of the paratypes, &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;delmastroi&lt;/i&gt; Pesarini, 2001 is proposed as junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iulianae&lt;/i&gt; Brignoli, 1971 (new synonymy). We also provide new faunistic and ecological data on the Italian species of &lt;i&gt;Troglohyphantes,&lt;/i&gt; focusing mainly on Central Italian Alps. Phenetic species groups previously proposed in literature for the Italian species have been updated in view of recent literature and new findings. Pesarini’s complexes of species are used to map the species distribution in the Italian Alps.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cave-dwelling spiders; endemism; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cave-dwelling spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Marco</firstname>
          <lastname>Isaia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paolo</firstname>
          <lastname>Pantini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the sun-spider genus &lt;i&gt;Mummucia &lt;/i&gt;(Arachnida: Solifugae: Mummucidae) from Piauí, northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Brazilian solifuge &lt;i&gt;Mummucia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ibirapemussu&lt;/i&gt; new species (Solifugae, Mummuciidae) from Serra das Confusões National Park, in the semi-arid Caatinga domain, is herein described, with illustrations and SEM pictures of the main taxonomic characters. Geometrical morphometric analyses were also performed and indicated that this new species can be accurately distinguished from &lt;i&gt;Metacleobis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fulvipes&lt;/i&gt; regarding the shape of propeltidium.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; geometric morphometric analysis; solpugid; solifugid; Caatinga</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leonardo</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Candiani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandre</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bonaldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lincoln</firstname>
          <lastname>Suesdek</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>Roberto R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-31</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new hermit crab species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Catapaguroides &lt;/i&gt;A. Milne-Edwards &amp; Bouvier (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura: Paguridae) from the Ryukyu Islands, Japan, and additional record of &lt;i&gt;C. foresti &lt;/i&gt;McLaughlin</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two species of the pagurid genus &lt;i&gt;Catapaguroides&lt;/i&gt; A. Milne-Edwards &amp; Bouvier, 1892, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;longior&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foresti&lt;/i&gt; McLaughlin, 2002, are reported herein. The new species is described on the basis of a single male specimen collected from a submarine cave at Onna Village, Okinawa Island, Ryukyu Islands, at a depth of 30 m. In general morphology, it is most similar to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inermis&lt;/i&gt; de Saint Laurent, 1968, but is readily distinguished from that species by the elongate antennal acicle and the broad carpus of the right cheliped. Examination of newly collected specimens from Japan led us to conclude that &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kasei&lt;/i&gt; Osawa &amp; Takeda, 2004 is a junior subjective synonym of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;foresti&lt;/i&gt; McLaughlin, 2002. An emended key to the presently recognized species of the genus is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Anomura; Paguridae; &lt;i&gt;Catapaguroides&lt;/i&gt;; new species; synonym; submarine cave; Ryukyu Islands</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yusuke</firstname>
          <lastname>Yamada</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Naoki</firstname>
          <lastname>Shirakawa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-42</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Danakilia &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei, Cichlidae) from Lake Abaeded in the Danakil Depression of Eritrea (East Africa)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of cichlid fish is described from a small, endorheic lake (Lake Abaeded), situated some 30 m below sea level in the Danakil Depression of Eritrea (East Africa). &lt;i&gt;Danakilia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dinicolai&lt;/i&gt; is readily distinguished from its congener, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franchettii,&lt;/i&gt; on the basis of body proportions and in the possession of markedly longer pectoral fins at all sizes. Additionally, oral dentition is more robust than that of its congener, and the lower pharyngeal jaw is markedly hypertrophied and covered with considerably finer and more densely implanted teeth on the posterior field of the jaw.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eritrea; East Africa; &lt;i&gt;Danakilia&lt;/i&gt;; Cichlidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eritrea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Melanie</firstname>
          <middlename>L. J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stiassny</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
          <lastname>De Marchi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anton</firstname>
          <lastname>Lamboj</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A third new species of snake of the genus &lt;i&gt;Omoadiphas&lt;/i&gt; (Reptilia, Squamata, Colubridae, Dipsadinae) from Honduras</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Omoadiphas&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Sierra de Agalta, Olancho, Honduras. Three species are now known in the genus. The new species differs from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurula&lt;/i&gt; in number of subcaudal, supralabial, infralabial, and postocular scales, in color and pattern, and in having the posterior nasal scale in contact with the prefrontal scale. It differs from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texiguatensis&lt;/i&gt; (known only from a subadult female) in having fewer subcaudals and the dark brown dorsolateral stripe involving all of scale rows two and three on each side of the body.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Omoadiphas&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Omoadiphas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cannula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Honduras</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Omoadiphas&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>James</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mccranie</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>A. Cruz</middlename>
          <lastname>Díaz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-58</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapercis randalli&lt;/i&gt;, a new sandperch (Pisces: Pinguipedidae) from Southern Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Parapercis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;randalli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of four specimens collected in southern Taiwan by angling at a depth of 5–150 m. It differs from its congeners in having five broad reddish brown saddles on the dorsal surface; both jaws and anterior portion of snout reddish orange; a yellow bar with red margin on cheek; a series of 8 red bars below body axis; configuration of spots on head, dorsal and caudal fins; and a combination of morphological characters: three pairs of canine teeth anteriorly in lower jaw; no palatine teeth; vomerine teeth stout, in a single curved row; lateral-line scales 53; margin of preopercle smooth; 4th dorsal spine longest; caudal fin slightly rounded on ventral half, truncate on dorsal half, with a prolonged upper lobe; appressed pelvic fin extends beyond anus. A total of 21 valid pinguipedid species are now recorded from Taiwanese waters.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Pisces; new species; &lt;i&gt;Parapercis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;randalli&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hsuan-Ching</firstname>
          <lastname>Ho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kwang-Tsao</firstname>
          <lastname>Shao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: BAÑON, R., VILLEGAS-RÍOS, D., SERRANO, A., MUCIENTES, G. &amp; ARRONTE, J.C. (2010) Marine fishes from Galicia (NW Spain): an updated checklist. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2667, 1–27.</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-29</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
