<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2691.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Nov. 2010</title>
    <volume>2691</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2010</year>
    <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">An annotated list of fish parasites (Copepoda, Monogenea, Digenea, Cestoda and Nematoda) collected from Emperors and Emperor Bream (Lethrinidae) in New Caledonia further highlights parasite biodiversity estimates on coral reef fish</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Parasites were collected from 17 species of emperors and emperor bream (Lethrinidae) in the waters off New Caledonia, South Pacific. Host-parasite and parasite-hosts lists are provided, with a total of 188 host-parasite combinations (11 per fish species), including 81 identifications at the species level. A total of 52 parasites were identified at the species level, and 40 new host records were found. Results are presented for larval isopods, copepods (16 species), monogeneans (24), digeneans (27), cestodes (11) and nematodes (10). When results were restricted to the four best-sampled fish species for which more than 30 specimens were examined, the number of host-parasite combinations was 22.25 per fish species, and the number of parasite taxa identified at the species level was 9.5 per fish species. From these data, the total number of metazoan parasite species predicted from all lethrinid species of New Caledonia, based on a classification of fish sizes using length in three categories, is 340, i.e. 13 per fish species. A biogeographical comparison with Heron Island on the Great Barrier Reef (Queensland, Australia) was possible only for a single fish species, &lt;i&gt;Lethrinus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;miniatus:&lt;/i&gt; in a total of 65 host-parasite combinations, only five taxa identified at the species level (three monogeneans and two digeneans) were shared at both localities. Parasite biodiversity in lethrinids was of similar magnitude to that in groupers (Serranidae Epinephelinae) in the same area, and this study confirms a previous prediction of 10 parasite species per coral reef fish species. Although this study required significant sampling and identification, we estimate that only 13% of the parasites of lethrinids are known in New Caledonia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">fish; new host records; new geographical records; inventory; biogeography; South Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jean-Lou</firstname>
          <lastname>Justine</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <lastname>Beveridge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Geoffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Boxshall</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rod</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bray</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>František</firstname>
          <lastname>Moravec</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ian</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Whittington</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogeny of &lt;i&gt;Calyptraeotheres &lt;/i&gt;Campos, 1990 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Brachyura, Pinnotheridae) with the description of &lt;i&gt;C. pepeluisi &lt;/i&gt;new species from the tropical Mexican Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A reassessment of the adult and larval morphology as well as comparison with published molecular information confirms the monophyly of the genus &lt;i&gt;Calyptraeotheres&lt;/i&gt; Campos, 1990, and its relationship with &lt;i&gt;Dissodactylus&lt;/i&gt; Smith, 1870, &lt;i&gt;Clypeasterophilus&lt;/i&gt; Campos &amp; Griffith, 1990 and &lt;i&gt;Tumidotheres&lt;/i&gt; Campos, 1990. &lt;i&gt;Calyptraeotheres&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pepeluisi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;species,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Michoacán, Mexico on the basis of a female specimen. The new species is distinguished from the other nominal species of the genus by having a subarcuate carapace with longer setae on its front and anterolateral margin, the eyes are dorsally visible, and a third maxilliped with a 2-segmented palp and a conical propodus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Decapoda; Crustacea; Brachyura; Pinnotheridae; &lt;i&gt;Calyptraeotheres&lt;/i&gt;; phylogeny; new species; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Decapoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ernesto</firstname>
          <lastname>Campos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Iván</firstname>
          <lastname>Hernández-Ávila</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Discovery of the rare burrowing shrimp &lt;i&gt;Calliapagurops charcoti &lt;/i&gt;de Saint Laurent, 1973 (Decapoda: Axiidea: Callianassidae) in shallow water: first record of the infraorder for Madeira Island</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dworschak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Wirtz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-56</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Dipsas &lt;/i&gt;Laurenti from the Atlantic Forest of Brazil (Serpentes: Dipsadidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Atlantic Forest of Brazil. The new species is distinguished from all congeners by showing anterior portion of body with rounded dorsal blotches wider than interblotches; median and posterior portion of body with blotches higher than long and narrower than interblotches; posterior body blotches lighter than anterior blotches; posterior blotches with conspicuous white edge in paraventral region; tiny and vertically oriented streaks in the interblotches from the posterior half of body; 187–209 ventral scales; 107–129 subcaudal scales; and the first blotch not reaching the rictus. Based on characters of external morphology and color pattern we suggest the new species is related to taxa of the recently proposed &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incerta&lt;/i&gt; species group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; new species; altitudinal variation; &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incerta&lt;/i&gt; species group; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; new species; altitudinal variation; &lt;i&gt;Dipsas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;incerta&lt;/i&gt; species group; taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Otavio</firstname>
          <middlename>A. V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antônio</firstname>
          <middlename>J. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Argôlo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-66</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New records of &lt;i&gt;Diopatra marocensis &lt;/i&gt;(Annelida: Onuphidae) from northern Spain</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrés</firstname>
          <lastname>Arias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nuria</firstname>
          <lastname>Anadón</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hannelore</firstname>
          <lastname>Paxton</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2010-11-30</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
