<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2736.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2736</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heleocoris &lt;/i&gt;(Heteroptera: Naucoridae: Laccocorinae) of Thailand, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Heleocoris&lt;/i&gt; in Indochina has languished for more than a century with no substantial history of taxonomic, biological, or ecological research since the original descriptions of the species, despite its abundance and ubiquity in streams throughout the region. This is largely because of the inability to assign specific identities to these insects and the need for taxonomic revision. Presented here is a comprehensive treatment on the taxonomy and faunistics of the four species now known to occur in Thailand, including the description of &lt;i&gt;Heleocoris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mcphersoni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Diagnostic information, records from Thailand and other Southeast Asian countries, ecological notes, habitus photographs, and a taxonomic key to identify the four species are presented.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heleocoris&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Naucoridae; Laccocorinae; Thailand; Indochina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Heleocoris&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sites</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Akekawat</firstname>
          <lastname>Vitheepradit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-16</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Descriptions of &lt;i&gt;Neboissomina&lt;/i&gt;, new genus and 6 new species of Ecnomidae from Australia (Trichoptera)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Descriptions and keys are provided for males of 7 ecnomid caddisfly species, with 6 species new to science and to Australia. Females of 5 species are also described. These species are placed in the new genus, &lt;i&gt;Neboissomina,&lt;/i&gt; new genus. The following new species are described: &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jardinei,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kuranya,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mida,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persona,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;philsuteri,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;riyala.&lt;/i&gt; A new combination is suggested for &lt;i&gt;N.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;krokale&lt;/i&gt; (Neboiss, 1979). The new genus is erected based on unique characters in the male and female genitalia, wings and setal warts of the head. &lt;i&gt;Neboissomina,&lt;/i&gt; new genus is endemic to northern and eastern Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Caddisflies; ecnomid; taxonomy; keys; Insecta</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Caddisflies</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cartwright</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>17-30</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Seven new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina &lt;/i&gt;Motschulsky from China (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae: Chrysomelinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven new species of Genus &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; Motschulsky are described: &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;markamensis&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Ge, &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hohxilensis&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Ge, &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gyacaensis&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Yang, &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hongyuanensis&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Ge, and &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cuiae&lt;/i&gt; Ge &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi, &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shuyongi&lt;/i&gt; Ge &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi, &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhangi&lt;/i&gt; Daccordi &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; Ge. Illustrations of habitus, male and female antennae, and male protarsi and aedeagus, and a map showing known localities are provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae; Chrysomelinae; &lt;i&gt;Chrysolina&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Chrysomelidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Si-Qin</firstname>
          <lastname>Ge</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mauro</firstname>
          <lastname>Daccordi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wen-Zhu</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xing-Ke</firstname>
          <lastname>Yang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>31-43</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comparative morphology of the male terminalia of the subtribe Rhinotorina (Diptera, Heleomyzidae, Rhinotorini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Rhinotorini (Diptera, Heleomyzidae) are currently divided into three subtribes, which were considered as monophyletic groups. Rhinotorina, the main focus of this study includes &lt;i&gt;Rhinotora&lt;/i&gt; Schiner, &lt;i&gt;Apophoneura&lt;/i&gt; Malloch, &lt;i&gt;Neorhinotora&lt;/i&gt; Lopes, and &lt;i&gt;Rhinotoroides&lt;/i&gt; Lopes. This study is aimed to provide a hypothesis of homology among the structures of the male terminalia of the four genera of Rhinotorina, as well as to reassess the diagnostic features proposed by D. McAlpine for the subtribe, and to furnish new information about the morphology of these structures, particularly of the hypopygium. Species of the four genera of Rhinotorina were studied, as well as species of other subtribes of Rhinotorini. The putative synapomorphies for the Rhinotorina stated by D. McAlpine are considered here to be consistent, being observed in the four genera included in the present study. The hypopygium in Rhinotorina, in contrast, is very variable, and the study of its structures has added only one diagnostic feature to Rhinotorina: the presence of a ventral plate on the hypandrium. The degree of variation is not equivalent among the structures of the hypopygium: the surstyli are the most variable structures in &lt;i&gt;Neorhinotora,&lt;/i&gt; and are very useful to diagnose species, and the shape of the epandrium, bacilliform sclerites, cerci, phallus, ejaculatory apodeme, phallapodeme, and hypandrium are very conservative in this genus. In &lt;i&gt;Rhinotora,&lt;/i&gt; on the other hand, whereas the cerci, surstyli, phallus, phallapodeme, and postgonites vary widely among the species, the shapes of the bacilliform sclerites and the ejaculatory apodeme are relatively constant. The comparisons made among the male terminalia of Rhinotorina suggest that this set of structures is a promising source of informative characters for future phylogenetic studies of Rhinotorini and Heleomyzidae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Heteromyzidae; Acalyptratae; male genitalia; protandrium; &lt;i&gt;Cairnsimyia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Anastomyza&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Heteromyzidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julia</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Almeida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rosaly</firstname>
          <lastname>Ale-Rocha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>44-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caliothrips tongi &lt;/i&gt;sp.n. (Thysanoptera, Thripidae) from China, and a dubious record of North American Bean Thrips</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species, &lt;i&gt;Caliothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tongi,&lt;/i&gt; is described from eastern China, and an old record of the North American bean thrips, &lt;i&gt;Caliothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt; (Pergande), from the same area is considered unreliable. &lt;i&gt;Oneilliella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pallidizonata&lt;/i&gt; Kudo is transferred to &lt;i&gt;Caliothrips&lt;/i&gt; as a new combination.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caliothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt;; bean thrips; &lt;i&gt;Oneilliella&lt;/i&gt;; Thripidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Caliothrips&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fasciatus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Laurence</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mound</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hongrui</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yawei</firstname>
          <lastname>Bei</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus and species of fossil Eodromeinae from the Yixian Formation of Western Liaoning, China (Coleoptera: Adephaga: Trachypachidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and species of fossil trachypachid &lt;i&gt;Fortiseode&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pervalimand&lt;/i&gt; Jia &amp; Ren &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described and illustrated. The new fossil with large and strong mandibles, short and robust legs, and pronotum widest near apical angle differs from other members of Eodromeinae. It is the first record of fossil trachypachid from the Mesozoic Yixian Formation of Huangbanjigou, Liaoning, China.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Trachypachidae; fossil; new genus; new species; Yixian Formation; Late Jurassic-Early Cretaceous; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Trachypachidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ting</firstname>
          <lastname>Jia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hongbing</firstname>
          <lastname>Liang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Huali</firstname>
          <lastname>Chang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dong</firstname>
          <lastname>Ren</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
