<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2742.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">17 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2742</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy and geographic variation of &lt;i&gt;Formicivora serrana &lt;/i&gt;(Hellmayr, 1929) and &lt;i&gt;Formicivora littoralis &lt;/i&gt;Gonzaga and Pacheco, 1990 (Aves: Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Formicivora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrana&lt;/i&gt; was described by Hellmayr in 1929 from specimens collected in Minas Gerais state, and subspecies &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interposita&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; by Gonzaga and Pacheco (1990) from specimens from Minas Gerais and Rio de Janeiro states and Rio de Janeiro state, respectively. According to the latter authors, &lt;i&gt;interposita&lt;/i&gt; is intermediate both geographically and morphologically in relation to &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis.&lt;/i&gt; Two years after its description, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; was elevated to species status (Collar &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.&lt;/i&gt; 1992) and it has subsequently been considered a species of conservation concern because of its restricted geographical range and threatened habitat. &lt;i&gt;Formicivora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interposita,&lt;/i&gt; however, was not elevated and is generally considered a subspecies of &lt;i&gt;serrana.&lt;/i&gt; In this study we review the taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrana,&lt;/i&gt; testing the validity of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; and proposing the best taxonomic treatment for &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interposita.&lt;/i&gt; The results of morphometric, vocal and plumage analyses show that &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;interposita&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; lack diagnostic characters, and are therefore not valid phylogenetic species. Further, our results indicate that &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; is not a valid biological species, but that it and &lt;i&gt;interposita&lt;/i&gt; could be considered subspecies of &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrana&lt;/i&gt; under this species concept. These results stress the need for detailed systematic studies in support of taxonomic decisions.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; geographic variation; &lt;i&gt;Formicivora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serrana&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Formicivora&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt;; Thamnophilidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Firme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marcos</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Raposo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Fishes of the family Sternoptychidae (Stomiiformes) collected on the Brazilian continental slope between 11° and 23°S</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Recent pelagic and benthic trawling activities over the Brazilian continental slope between 11° and 23°S captured nine species representing five genera of the stomiiform family Sternoptychidae. Among these, three species are new records for Brazilian waters: &lt;i&gt;Sternoptyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudodiaphana,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Argyripnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Polyipnus&lt;/i&gt; sp. The known distributions of &lt;i&gt;Argyropelecus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aculeatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Maurolicus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stehmanni&lt;/i&gt; along the Brazilian coast are extended northward to 13°S and 16°S, respectively, while that of &lt;i&gt;Sternoptyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diaphana&lt;/i&gt; is extended southward to 13°S. &lt;i&gt;Argyropelecus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hemigymnus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Argyropelecus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sladeni,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sternoptyx&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudobscura&lt;/i&gt; were rarely caught (n=2–16). A key to the western South Atlantic species of Sternoptychidae is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Western South Atlantic; Brazil; Sternoptychidae; identification key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Western South Atlantic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Adriano</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>A. S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Adriana</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Braga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gustavo</firstname>
          <middlename>W. A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nunan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mincarone</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Gustav Heinrich Kirchenpauer (1808–1887) of the City of Hamburg, and his research on hydroids and bryozoans</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Gustav Heinrich Kirchenpauer was born 2 February 1808 in Hamburg, and he died in that city on 3 March 1887. In 1810 he was taken with his family to St. Petersburg, Russia, to escape economic hardships during the occupation of Hamburg and continental blockade of the United Kingdom by Napoleon. He attended secondary school and university in Dorpat (Tartu), Estonia, and earned a doctorate in law from Universtät Heidelberg in 1831. Kirchenpauer returned to Hamburg in 1832 as a lawyer and journalist, gaining recognition as a specialist in international trade. He later served as senator, federal council representative, and seven-time Bürgermeister (mayor) of the city. One of his avocations was natural history, especially taxonomy of hydroids and bryozoans. While he published only six papers with information on Hydrozoa, Kirchenpauer described and named eight genera and 77 species and subspecies of hydroids. Three familiar genera (Abietinaria, &lt;i&gt;Lytocarpia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Macrorhynchia)&lt;/i&gt; and nearly half of the species he founded are still recognized as valid. In four papers dealing at least in part with Bryozoa, he named and described one new genus and 26 new species-group taxa in that group. Hydroids and bryozoans studied and described by Kirchenpauer came from many parts of the world, especially Australia, the western Pacific and mid-Pacific islands, South Africa, Europe, the Russian Far East, and the eastern South Atlantic. Kirchenpauer was awarded an honorary doctorate from Universtät Kiel in 1876 for his scientific contributions. One family, one genus, and four species have been named in his honour.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">biography; Bryozoa; Hydrozoa; marine biology; natural history; taxonomy; zoology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">biography</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Dale</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Calder</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Anita</firstname>
          <lastname>Brinckmann-Voss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-59</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of anapid spider (Araneae: Araneoidea, Anapidae) in Eocene Baltic amber, imaged using phase contrast X-ray computed micro-tomography</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the extant spider family Anapidae is described from a fossil mature male in Eocene amber from the Baltic region and tentatively assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Balticoroma&lt;/i&gt; Wunderlich, 2004. Phase contrast X-ray computed micro-tomography was used to reveal important features that were impossible to view using traditional microscopy. &lt;i&gt;Balticoroma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wheateri&lt;/i&gt; new species is easily diagnosed from all other anapids by having clypeal extensions that run parallel to the ectal surface of the chelicerae and in having the metatarsus of the first leg highly reduced and modified into what is presumably a y-shaped clasping structure. Although only a single extant anapid species occurs in northern Europe, the family was diverse in the Eocene. The discovery of yet another anapid species in Baltic amber supports the idea that Eocene European forests may have been a hotspot of evolution for this family of spiders.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cenozoic; fossil; new species; palaeontology; spider; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cenozoic</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Penney</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Mcneil</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Green</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Bradley</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marusik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Withers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Preziosi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-66</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomy and the DNA Barcoding Enterprise</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Malte</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ebach</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-17</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
