<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2751.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Jan. 2011</title>
    <volume>2751</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-01-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Six new species of aglajid opisthobranch mollusks from the tropical Indo-Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Six new species of aglajid opisthobranchs are described from various localities in the tropical Indo-Pacific. &lt;i&gt;Philinopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falciphallus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; found from the Marshall Islands to the Red Sea, is distinguished by its reddish body color, a distinct black or maroon longitudinal line on the foot, a posterior projection on the posterior shield and a penis with a chitinous, sickle-shaped spine and numerous smaller spines. &lt;i&gt;Philinopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;coronata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; known only from the Philippines, is similar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;falciphallus&lt;/i&gt; but dominated by yellow body color and a ventral surface of the foot with yellow and maroon spots. It has a trumpet-shaped penis with a crown of rounded tubercles on the apex and anterior and posterior zones of penial spines. &lt;i&gt;Philinopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ctenophoraphaga&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is found from the Philippines, Indonesia and the Red Sea. It feeds on platyctene ctenophores, including &lt;i&gt;Coeloplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;meteroris.&lt;/i&gt; It can be distinguished by its elongate posterior lobe of the headshield, reddish color with white spots, thinly muscularized buccal mass and simple, unarmed penis. &lt;i&gt;Chelidonura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mandroroa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is characterized by its black body with orange patches lined by yellow. It has a simple penis with a cuticularized apical papilla. This species has been found from Japan, Taiwan, the Philippines, Indonesia, Madagascar and Kenya. &lt;i&gt;Chelidonura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alisonae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is apparently restricted to the central and eastern Pacific of the Hawai’ian Islands, Johnston Island, the Marianas Islands and Easter Island. It is similar in coloration to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hirundinina,&lt;/i&gt; but has orange lines on the dorsal and lateral shields and has a broad right posterior lobe rather than an acutely pointed one. The penis is simple and unarmed. &lt;i&gt;Odontoglaja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mosaica&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; found from the Indian Ocean of Madagascar and South Africa, differs from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guamensis&lt;/i&gt; by possessing a reticulate pattern on the notum rather than a pattern of brown spots. It also has a shorter penial papilla that is bifurcate rather than undivided one.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Aglajidae; Indo-Pacific; new species; biodiversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Aglajidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Terrence</firstname>
          <lastname>Gosliner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-24</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-28</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Asteroporpa &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Asteromoana&lt;/i&gt;) (Ophiuroidea: Euryalida: Gorgonocephalidae) from Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Asteroporpa&lt;/i&gt; (Asteromoana) (Echinodermata: Ophiuroidea: Euryalida: Gorgonocephalidae) are described from southwestern and southern Japan. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Asterom.) &lt;i&gt;muricatopatella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has only cone-shaped dermal ossicles with terminal projections on radial shields, only plate-shaped dermal ossicles on oral plates, and coneshaped dermal ossicles with relatively short terminal projections at the lateral interradial disc. &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Asterom.) &lt;i&gt;koyoae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has both cone-shaped dermal ossicles with terminal projections and plate-shaped dermal ossicles on radial shields, cone-shaped dermal ossicles with terminal projections on oral plates, and cone-shaped dermal ossicles with relatively long terminal projections on the lateral interradial disc. A taxonomic key to all four species of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; (Asteromoana) is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; brittle star; &lt;i&gt;Asteroporpa&lt;/i&gt; (Asteromoana) &lt;i&gt;muricatopatella&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Asteroporpa&lt;/i&gt; (Asteromoana) &lt;i&gt;koyoae&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masanori</firstname>
          <lastname>Okanishi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Toshihiko</firstname>
          <lastname>Fujita</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>25-39</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the current status of the &lt;i&gt;Polydora&lt;/i&gt;-complex (Polychaeta: Spionidae) in Australia and a checklist of recorded species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In 1885 Australia’s first recorded marine pest, a mudworm of the &lt;i&gt;Polydora-complex&lt;/i&gt; (Spionidae), was identified on Hunter River, New South Wales, oysters (Saccostrea &lt;i&gt;glomerata&lt;/i&gt; Gould, 1850). Mudworm is still a serious pest of cultured molluscs in Australia but, although of great concern to many, relatively little progress has been made in resolving the problem. One hundred and thirty years later the identity and life history of this pest remains unclear. The longevity of this problem in Australia is largely due to unaddressed issues of basic taxonomy. This review addresses these issues by presenting the information currently available on the &lt;i&gt;Polydora-complex&lt;/i&gt; species in Australia, including taxonomy; history of discovery in the natural environment and in commercial aquaculture facilities; and ecological information. An updated checklist of &lt;i&gt;Polydora-complex&lt;/i&gt; species from Australia is also included. It is hoped that by being explicit about the knowledge gaps and problems they can be addressed, ultimately providing a solid taxonomic background for further research into the &lt;i&gt;Polydora-complex&lt;/i&gt; species and resolution of the mudworm problem in Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mudworm; polydorid; marine pest; oyster disease; estuary; aquaculture; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mudworm</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lexie</firstname>
          <middlename>M</middlename>
          <lastname>Walker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>40-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Designation of the lectotype of &lt;i&gt;Poecilia amazonica &lt;/i&gt;Garman, 1895 (Cyprinodontiformes, Poeciliidae) and discussion of its nomenclatural status</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <middlename>H. F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lucinda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carlos</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Figueiredo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karsten</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hartel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-01-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
