<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2758.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">7 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2758</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-07</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of fungus-inhabiting blattisociid mites (Acari: Mesostigmata: Phytoseioidea) from Middle America, with a key to genera and subgenera of the subfamily Blattisociinae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genus &lt;i&gt;Fungiseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described, based on adults of two newly described species. These rather short-legged mites, with their second pair of legs markedly thickened, have been collected only from bracket fungi. The more generalized form, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavulisetis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is based on female specimens from Chiapas Province, southern Mexico. The more derivative form, &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;armatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;et&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is based on females and males from several samples of bracket fungi in lowland tropical rainforest of Costa Rica, where they coexist with a remarkable variety of other blattisociine mites. Notable morphological attributes peculiar to adults of this genus include the dorsal shield having a delineated lateral rim that bears a row of setae of the lateral or marginal series, legs II greatly thickened, with enlarged, claw-like setae on the dorsolateral face of the tarsus, and deep furrows postgenitally on females and postanally on males and females. Comparisons are made with fungus-inhabiting mites of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hoploseius,&lt;/i&gt; whose adults also have the second pair of legs thickened. A revised key to the world genera and subgenera of the subfamily Blattisociinae is presented; the genus &lt;i&gt;Orthadenella&lt;/i&gt; Athias-Henriot is excluded, and placed in the ascoid family Melicharidae. The subgenera &lt;i&gt;Borinquolaelaps&lt;/i&gt; Fox, &lt;i&gt;Crinidens&lt;/i&gt; Karg, and &lt;i&gt;Cuspiacus&lt;/i&gt; Christian &amp; Karg, sensu Christian &amp; Karg 2006 are treated as &lt;b&gt;new&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;synonyms&lt;/b&gt; of the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Lasioseius&lt;/i&gt; Berlese.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Blattisociidae; Phytoseioidea; fungus mites; &lt;i&gt;Fungiseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hoploseius&lt;/i&gt;; Costa Rica; Mexico</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Blattisociidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Moraza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Evert</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lindquist</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-25</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Diversity and distribution of assemblages of estuarine decapod larvae (Crustacea: Decapoda: Anomura, Brachyura) in tropical southeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Decapod larvae assemblages were studied in the tropical estuaries off southeastern Brazil (Piraquê-açú and Piraquê-mirim rivers estuaries). A total of 32 taxa of decapod larvae were recorded. Brachyuran larvae dominated in Piraquê-açú estuary, with 62% of the relative abundance, and 49% in Piraquê-mirim estuary. Mean larvae concentrations ranged from 17.2 m -3 at Piraquê-mirim (August 2003) to 221.1 m -3 at Piraquê-açú (April 2003). The assemblage of larvae in both estuaries was diverse, especially at Piraquê-mirim, which showed higher ecological stability. The high spatial heterogeneity of the Piraquê-açú and Piraquê-mirim estuarine system resulted in the division of the assemblage into two well-defined groups (truly estuarine and euryhaline). Salinity spatial gradient was a key factor in the structure and distribution of larvae.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">larvae; spatial distribution; seasonal distribution; salinity; southern Brazil estuaries</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">larvae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Magris</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>F. Loureiro</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>26-42</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis &lt;/i&gt;Günther, 1872 (Squamata: Natricidae) from the highlands of Kon Tum Province, Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the snake genus &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; Günther, 1872, &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Kon Tum Plateau in central Vietnam. It is distinguished from any other &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; species by the combination of the following characters: (1) dorsal scales entirely smooth, in 23–19–19 rows; (2) 191 ventrals; (3) 1 loreal, in contact with internasal; (4) 7 supralabials, 5 th entering orbit; (4) dorsum uniformly greyish-brown without bands or crossbars, with an irregular separation between dark dorsum and venter, greyish-yellow speckled with dark grey. An extended comparison with other species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; species is provided together with a key to the known species of the genus. &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is the third new mountain stream snake described from Vietnam in the past decade. The grammatical gender of the genus &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; is discussed; this genus is feminine.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Natricidae; &lt;i&gt;Opisthotropis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cucae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; snake; taxonomy; Vietnam</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Natricidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Patrick</firstname>
          <lastname>David</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cuong</firstname>
          <middlename>The</middlename>
          <lastname>Pham</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Truong</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of snake eel, &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; (Anguilliformes: Ophichthidae) from Korea</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new snake eel, &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis,&lt;/i&gt; is described based on 24 specimens collected from the South Sea of Korea (water depth 5–100 m) between 2005 and 2010. This species is characterized by the following morphological features: fleshy protrusions before and behind the posterior nostril; 1–2 regular rows of conical teeth in both jaws, prevomer and vomer are slightly separated from each other; the origin of the dorsal fin above the middle of the pectoral fin; and the pectoral fin is rounded and not elongated. &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; is most similar to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cancrivorus&lt;/i&gt; in morphology, but the two species differ in their teeth shape (conical in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; granular in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cancrivorus),&lt;/i&gt; and their numbers of vertebrae (143–153 &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; 153–164, respectively). &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boro&lt;/i&gt; in the origin of the dorsal fin (above the middle of the pectoral fin in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; far behind the pectoral fin in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boro),&lt;/i&gt; their numbers of vertebrae (143–153 &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; 170–177, respectively), and their teeth shape (conical in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vs.&lt;/i&gt; granular in &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boro).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; is also easily distinguishable morphologically from the remaining seven &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; spp. worldwide. Molecular analysis using mitochondrial DNA 12S rRNA sequences supported that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt; is a new species because of the considerable genetic distance from what appears to be its most closely related species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cancrivorus&lt;/i&gt; (d=0.068).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ophichthidae; &lt;i&gt;Pisodonophis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sangjuensis&lt;/i&gt;; mitochondrial 12S rRNA; new species; Korea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ophichthidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hwan-Sung</firstname>
          <lastname>Ji</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jin-Koo</firstname>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-07</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
