<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2761.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2761</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Geographic variation, phylogeny and systematic status of &lt;i&gt;Gracilinanus microtarsus &lt;/i&gt;(Mammalia: Didelphimorphia: Didelphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The gracile mouse opossum &lt;i&gt;Gracilinanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtarsus&lt;/i&gt; occurs mainly along the Atlantic forest of eastern and southern Brazil. Earlier studies revealed high levels of genetic divergence among samples across its range. Here, we analyzed the congruence of geographic variation between molecular and morphological characters to evaluate whether the populations that have been segregated by molecular divergence represent more than one species, as previously suggested. We examined 195 specimens of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtarsus,&lt;/i&gt; 94 of &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agilis,&lt;/i&gt; and 12 of &lt;i&gt;Cryptonanus&lt;/i&gt; sp., and inferred a phylogeny based on 25 discrete morphological characters. We compared this result with a phylogeny based on partial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; sequences of 27 specimens. The monophyly of the genus, and of both &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtarsus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;agilis&lt;/i&gt; were corroborated by morphological and molecular analyses. The molecular phylogeny recovered three clades, and the morphological data indicated three distinct lineages, which also segregated in morphometric space, indicating the possibility of occurrence of three cryptic species within what is currently identified as &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtarsus.&lt;/i&gt; However, morphological and molecular phylogenies were not completely congruent, and the morphological classification of the specimens included in the molecular analysis resulted in a paraphyletic group in the molecular phylogeny. Hence, our results suggest that &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microtarsus&lt;/i&gt; represents one species, diagnosable by morphological and molecular characters, showing strong morphological and molecular variation throughout its distributional range.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Atlantic forest; Brazil; cytochrome b; intraspecific variation; mammal; marsupials; neotropics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Atlantic forest</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Simone</firstname>
          <lastname>Lóss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Leonora</firstname>
          <middlename>Pires</middlename>
          <lastname>Costa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yuri</firstname>
          <middlename>L. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leite</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Tenuibiotus, &lt;/i&gt;a new genus of Macrobiotidae (Eutardigrada)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The group of &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt; species having claws of the &lt;i&gt;tenuis-type&lt;/i&gt; is discussed and a new genus, named &lt;i&gt;Tenuibiotus,&lt;/i&gt; is instituted. The &lt;i&gt;tenuis-type&lt;/i&gt; claws are characterised by the fusion of the primary and secondary branches over a long distance so that the common tract is longer than that found in other members of the Macrobiotidae. Distally, the secondary branch is clearly shorter than the primary branch, and forms with it almost a right angle. In all the known species attributable to the new genus, the buccal tube is narrow, the buccal cavity is small with small peribuccal lamellae; the eggs are laid freely and have conical or trunco-conical processes.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tardigrada; &lt;i&gt;Macrobiotus&lt;/i&gt;; claw structure; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tardigrada</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Fejervarya &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Dicroglossidae) from Bangladesh</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new cryptic species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Fejervarya&lt;/i&gt; is described from the Chittagong district of Bangladesh. &lt;i&gt;Fejervarya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asmati&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov. is compared with its morphologically similar and geographically proximate congeners. The species can be readily diagnosed by having the following combination of characters: SVL 29.1– 33.4 mm; butterfly shaped vocal marking present in male; forearm length 70% of hand length; relative length of fingers, shortest to longest: 2 &lt; 4 &lt; 1&lt; 3; nostril much closer to snout tip than eye, nostril–snout length 57% of distance from front of eyes to nostril; nostril–snout length 0.67% of internarial distance; MBE 18% of HL.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Bangladesh; &lt;i&gt;Fejervarya&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;asmati&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; advertisement call; morphometry</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <middlename>Sajid Ali</middlename>
          <lastname>Howlader</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic placement and redescription of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Atelidea &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1895 (Araneae, Tetragnathidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The spider genus &lt;i&gt;Atelidea&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1895 previously included two described species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1895 and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;globosa&lt;/i&gt; Yamaguchi, 1957. In this study we describe for the first time the female of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa,&lt;/i&gt; and provide illustrations and scanning electron microscope images of external and internal features. The phylogenetic placement of this genus was investigated by including &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spinosa&lt;/i&gt; in a recent phylogenetic analysis with 23 tetragnathids. Parsimony analyses under equal and implied weights were performed. Our results suggest that &lt;i&gt;Atelidea&lt;/i&gt; belongs to Tetragnathidae and in particular nests within Leucauginae, this last node is well supported and expected to endure future analysis; however, the relationships of &lt;i&gt;Atelidea&lt;/i&gt; to other leucaugine species and its validity as a genus need to be assessed in future studies with a larger sample of leucaugine taxa. The second species described in the genus, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;globosa,&lt;/i&gt; is only known from its now lost type specimen from Japan and it is proposed as a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubium&lt;/i&gt; leaving &lt;i&gt;Atelidea&lt;/i&gt; monotypic.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladistics; Taxonomy; Sri Lanka; Oriental region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladistics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <lastname>Álvarez-Padilla</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Suresh</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Benjamin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-63</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the identity of Collingwood’s Pill-Making Crab, &lt;i&gt;Sphaerapoeia collingwoodii&lt;/i&gt; Collingwood, 1868 (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Dotillidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The genusand species-group names &lt;i&gt;Sphaerapoeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collingwoodii&lt;/i&gt; were made available in an account of the voyage of the &lt;i&gt;H.M.S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Serpent&lt;/i&gt; by Collingwood (1868) for a species of intertidal ocypodoid crab found in Singapore, Labuan (Borneo) and Johore (Peninsular Malaysia). The names were used in Collingwood (1868) on the basis of a letter to him from Bate, who never published these names himself. Based on the morphological, ecological and locality notes given by Collingwood (1868), we identify &lt;i&gt;Sphaerapoeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collingwoodii&lt;/i&gt; with the dotillid &lt;i&gt;Scopimera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt; Balss, 1934. We enact Article 23.9.2 of the Code to reverse precedence of these names, thereby making &lt;i&gt;Scopimera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt; Balss, 1934, a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;protectum,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Sphaerapoeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collingwoodii&lt;/i&gt; Collingwood, 1868, a &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oblitum.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scopimera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Sphaerapoeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;collingwoodii&lt;/i&gt;; Dotillidae; &lt;i&gt;H.M.S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Serpent&lt;/i&gt;; Cuthbert Collingwood; &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;protectum&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;nomen&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oblitum&lt;/i&gt;; Article 23.9; ICZN; Code</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Scopimera&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;intermedia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Martyn</firstname>
          <middlename>E. Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Low</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-09</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
