<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2768.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2768</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Molecular and morphological description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; (Demospongiae: Halisarcida) from Mediterranean Sea and a redescription of the type species &lt;i&gt;Halisarca dujardini&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmelini&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the northwestern Mediterranean Sea at depths between 15–65 m from coralligenous rocks. The new species occurs as thin sheets only on the bryozoan &lt;i&gt;Smittina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cervicornis.&lt;/i&gt; Morphologically, it is characterized by its thin layer architecture, skin-like, lusterless and smooth surface, a soft, very delicate and easily torn texture, and pale-yellow colour. At the cytological level &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmelini&lt;/i&gt; is characterized by a complex of cells with inclusions: spherulous, vacuolar, granular, microgranular and rhabdiferous cells. The new species is clearly different in cell and endobiotic bacteria content and in external morphology from all previously described species of &lt;i&gt;Halisarca.&lt;/i&gt; In addition to the description of the new species, we have conducted a thorough ultrastructural investigation and re-described the type species &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dujardini&lt;/i&gt; Johnston, 1842 using specimens from different region of the North Atlantic, Arctic and North Pacific. To investigate the relationships between &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmelini&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dujardini&lt;/i&gt; on the molecular level, we determined the complete mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) sequences of the new species of &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; and compared it with that of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dujardini.&lt;/i&gt; The two mitochondrial genomes are identical in gene content and gene arrangement but differ in size by ~1,300 bp (6.8%). The overall genetic distance between coding sequences is 0.1, much greater than what has been previously reported for individual species of non-bilaterian animals. The latter observation supports the new species status of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;harmelini.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; Porifera; Halisarcida; &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt;; new species; mitochondrial genome; &lt;i&gt;Halisarca&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dujardini&lt;/i&gt;; N-W Mediterranean; ultrastructure</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ereskovsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dennis</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lavrov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nicole</firstname>
          <lastname>Boury-Esnault</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jean</firstname>
          <lastname>Vacelet</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>5-31</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the “&lt;i&gt;Hippolyte commensalis &lt;/i&gt;Kemp, 1925” species complex (Decapoda, Caridea, Hippolytidae), with the designation of a new genus and description of two new species from the Indo-West Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Only one species of hippolytid shrimp, namely &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;commensalis&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1925, was previously known to be associated with alcyonacean soft corals (Octocorallia, Alcyonacea) in the Indo-West Pacific. Recent collections revealed that at least three distinct hippolytid species are associated with alcyonacean soft corals. Moreover, these alcyonacean-associated hippolytids differ considerably from all other species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1814 in having a smooth rostrum bearing a single subapical ventral tooth, reduced styliform incisor process of the mandible, the basal antennular segment without ventromedial tooth, and the ambulatory pereiopods lacking or with only relatively small distoventral spines. A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is thus established for &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;commensalis&lt;/i&gt; Kemp, 1925 and two new species. &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dossena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (the type species of the new genus) mainly differs from the congeners in having a humpbacked carapace. &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; closely resembles &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;commensalis&lt;/i&gt; but clearly differs in having a furry carapace and distinct coloration, as well as in association with different alcyonacean host. An identification key is provided as well as information on the live coloration and host for all species of &lt;i&gt;Alcyonohippolyte&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Decapoda; Hippolytidae; &lt;i&gt;Hippolyte&lt;/i&gt;; new genus; new species; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivan</firstname>
          <lastname>Marin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Junji</firstname>
          <lastname>Okuno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tin-Yam</firstname>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>32-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Paretroplus &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Cichlidae: Etroplinae) from northeastern Madagascar, with a phylogeny and revised diagnosis for the &lt;i&gt;P. damii &lt;/i&gt;clade</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Paretroplus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loisellei,&lt;/i&gt; a new species of etropline cichlid from Madagascar, is described from the middle to lower reaches of the Mahanara River, located to the north of the Masoala Peninsula in northeastern Madagascar. The new species is recovered within the “Paretroplus &lt;i&gt;damii&lt;/i&gt; clade” on the basis of several apomorphic anatomical features, including the presence of a triangular, black or dark gray, pectoral-axil patch, chest scales that are greatly reduced in size and highly embedded, and flank scales in which the posterior field is thin and unossified. The new species is distinguished from its sister taxon, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;damii,&lt;/i&gt; by a more or less horizontal profile extending from the anterior margin of the lower jaw to the ventroposterior margin of the suspensorium (vs. strongly rounded and convex), horizontally oriented oral jaws with fleshy lips (vs. oblique and thin), tricuspid symphyseal teeth in the upper jaw with distinct and sharp lateral cusps, a much darker overall pigmentation pattern, and distinctive bright golden breeding coloration (vs. brick red).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">gas bladder; Mahanara; &lt;i&gt;Paretroplus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;loisellei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; “Paretroplus &lt;i&gt;damii&lt;/i&gt; clade”; phylogeny; ventitry</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">gas bladder</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>John</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sparks</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schelly</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
