<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2772.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Feb. 2011</title>
    <volume>2772</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Dusted off—the African &lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus superciliaris&lt;/i&gt;-species complex of giant toads</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; is known to occur in rain forests from West Africa to eastern Democratic Republic of Congo and Gabon. We herein present morphological and molecular data indicating the existence of three distinct taxa. The name &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to toads from the western Lower Guinean Forest (eastern Nigeria, Cameroon, Equatorial Guinea, Gabon). We resurrect &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri&lt;/i&gt; for the Upper Guinean forest (Sierra Leone, Guinea, Liberia, Ivory Coast, Ghana) and describe a new species occurring in the eastern part of the Lower Guinean Forest (eastern Democratic Republic of Congo). &lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;channingi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from eastern Lower Guinean Forest differs from both other taxa by its brownish lateral coloration (reddish-purple in the other taxa). The new species differs morphologically from western Lower Guinean &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; by a less pointed eyelid process, a dark coloured posterior abdominal region and a dark coloured vertebral line (both absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris),&lt;/i&gt; the shape of the parotid glands (bulged and rounded at the posterior tip in the new species, slender drop shaped and pointed at the posterior tip in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris),&lt;/i&gt; and juvenile interorbital markings (V-shaped in the new species, usually interrupted and broken in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris).&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;channingi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from the Upper Guinean &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of an eyelid process (absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri),&lt;/i&gt; presence of a dark vertebral line and a pair of dark spots on the posterior part of the back (both absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri).&lt;/i&gt; The Upper Guinean &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri&lt;/i&gt; differs from western Lower Guinean &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; by the absence of an eyelid process, a dark coloured posterior abdominal region (absent in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris)&lt;/i&gt; and lacking a pair of dark spots in the posterior part of the back (present in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris).&lt;/i&gt; The new species differs from both other taxa by 2.2–2.8% in the investigated 16S rRNA gene. West African and western Central African populations differ by only 0.9–1.1% in 16S rRNA, lacking any intra-taxon variation within each clade, and are cautiously regarded as subspecies although the genetic distinction is mirrored by strong morphological differences and distinct geographic distribution which may support its elevation to species status once that more comprehensive data become available. A key to the taxa of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris-species&lt;/i&gt; complex is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;channingi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;s.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt;; West &amp; Central Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amietophrynus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;channingi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;superciliaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chevalieri&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barej</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andreas</firstname>
          <lastname>Schmitz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michele</firstname>
          <lastname>Menegon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annika</firstname>
          <lastname>Hillers</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Harald</firstname>
          <lastname>Hinkel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Wolfgang</firstname>
          <lastname>Böhme</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mark-Oliver</firstname>
          <lastname>Rödel</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The spider genus &lt;i&gt;Chrysometa &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae, Tetragnathidae) from the Pico da Neblina and Serra do Tapirapecó mountains (Amazonas, Brazil): new species, new records, diversity and distribution along two altitudinal gradients</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Eight new species of the spider genus &lt;i&gt;Chrysometa&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1894 (Araneae, Tetragnathidae) are described and illustrated. &lt;i&gt;Chrysometa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nubigena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waikoxi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrasierwaldae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;santosi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;yanomami&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candianii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lomanhungae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saci&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; Those species were collected in a study on the diversity of spider communities along altitudinal gradients in Brazilian Amazonia. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saci&lt;/i&gt; was captured at the Serra do Tapirapecó (Barcelos), while all the other species are from the Pico da Neblina (São Gabriel da Cachoeira), the highest mountain in Brazil. We provide new records for &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;boraceia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flava,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guttata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;opulenta,&lt;/i&gt; and we describe the male of &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minuta&lt;/i&gt; for the first time. We also present the first results on the diversity and altitudinal distribution of the species of &lt;i&gt;Chrysometa&lt;/i&gt; at the Pico da Neblina and Serra do Tapirapecó. We sampled the first locality at six different elevations, and obtained 336 specimens distributed in 12 species. Richness and abundance, as well as relative importance peaked at the highest sites sampled (2,000 and 2,400 m). The three most abundant species showed a segregated distribution, being dominant or exclusively distributed in different altitudes. At the Serra do Tapirapecó, sampling at four different elevations up to 1200 m, we only obtained 40 individuals divided in four species, and there was no clear relation to altitude. Most of the new species were found at mid and high altitude sites, while species from lower altitude sites represented widespread species. The comparison with other neotropical spiders inventories highlights the high diversity recorded at Pico da Neblina, which could be assigned to the large environmental variation covered in this work and to the sampling of high-altitude environments. Inventories in the Andean region and other information in the literature also seem to support the association of &lt;i&gt;Chrysometa&lt;/i&gt; with high altitude environments.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">spiders; taxonomy; biodiversity; Araneoidea; orbweavers; Neotropical region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">spiders</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>André</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Nogueira</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>João</firstname>
          <middlename>P. P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pena-Barbosa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Eduardo</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Venticinque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Brescovit</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-51</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus &lt;/i&gt;(subgenus &lt;i&gt;Chonomantis&lt;/i&gt;) from Ranomafana National Park, eastern Madagascar (Amphibia, Anura, Mantellidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new frog species of &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; belonging to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Chonomantis&lt;/i&gt; from Ranomafana National Park, in the Southern Central East region of Madagascar, at mid-elevations (about 950 m above sea level). Specimens of &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paidroa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; were observed during the day in cavities under large rocks next to a stream in rainforest. Their advertisement calls are unique in &lt;i&gt;Chonomantis&lt;/i&gt; and consist of a long series of note pairs. The new species shows a high divergence to other &lt;i&gt;Chonomantis&lt;/i&gt; species in DNA sequences of the mitochondrial 16S rRNA gene (5.6–10.8%). &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paidroa&lt;/i&gt; is so far only known from several streams in Ranomafana National Park but may have been overlooked at other rainforest sites in eastern Madagascar. We propose an IUCN threat status of Data Deficient for this new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Anura; Mantellidae; &lt;i&gt;Mantidactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paidroa&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.; Madagascar</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Parfait</firstname>
          <lastname>Bora</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Olga</firstname>
          <lastname>Ramilijaona</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Noromalala</firstname>
          <lastname>Raminosoa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>52-60</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Debating Liolaemidae diversity and classification, and a bit more: A response to Lobo &lt;i&gt;et al.&lt;/i&gt;</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Liolaemidae lizard evolutionary radiation has resulted from active spatial expansions into an extensive territorial area accompanied by active events of cladogenesis that have produced high levels of taxonomic and ecological diversity, especially within the &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; genus. As a result, these lizards have been for decades the subject of intense taxonomic and systematic debates. Here, I provide an analysis of a recent paper where discussions on Liolaemidae diversity and classification involved biased and arbitrary interpretations and observations of two previously published monographs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Liolaemidae; &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Phymaturus&lt;/i&gt;; lizards</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Liolaemidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <lastname>Pincheira-Donoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-66</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">DNA barcoding is useful for taxonomy: a reply to Ebach</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Mitchell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-02-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
