<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2787.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">10 Mar. 2011</title>
    <volume>2787</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cryptic diversity of the semi-terrestrial amphipod &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia japonica&lt;/i&gt; (Tattersall, 1922) (Amphipoda: Talitrida: Talitridae) in Japan and Taiwan, with description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The talitrid amphipod &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt; Bousfield, 1982 is common in sandy beaches, estuarine marshes, shores of lakes and rivers. They are detritivores, and being prey for birds and other animals, they play an important role in the food chain. In the present study, we identified a new &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt; from Guan-du, Taiwan, based on morphological (light microscopy and scanning electron microscopy) and molecular approach (sequence divergence in the mitochondria DNA, COI) and described herein. &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paludosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the Guan-du was morphologically different from all reported &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt; species, but it was very close to &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; (Tattersall, 1922). The distribution pattern of setae in the lateral margin of the telson and sharpness of ramus tip of uropod 3, however, exhibit diagnostic differences between the two species. From sequence divergence in COI, &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paludosus&lt;/i&gt; differed from &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; 13.3% in average, values that are comparable to inter-specific differences in other amphipod taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Marsh; Amphipoda; Talitridae; &lt;i&gt;Platorchestia&lt;/i&gt;; Beach fleas; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Marsh</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yu-Ting</firstname>
          <lastname>Cheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kenji</firstname>
          <lastname>Nakazono</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Y.</firstname>
          <middlename>Kirk</middlename>
          <lastname>Lin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Benny</firstname>
          <middlename>K. K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Chan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cranial anatomy of tadpoles of five species of &lt;i&gt;Scinax &lt;/i&gt;(Hylidae, Hylinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We studied the oral apparatus, buccal cavity and musculoskeletal features in tadpoles of five species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;acuminatus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uruguayus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;pinima,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aromothyella,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;berthae).&lt;/i&gt; Observed variation is mainly related to intrageneric grouping. &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acuminatus&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;ruber&lt;/i&gt; clade, sister taxon of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; group) has a distinctive combination of a mental gap in the margin of oral papillae, straight labial teeth with few or absent cusps, processus muscularis acute and posteriorly directed, and m. subarcualis rectus I with two slips. &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uruguayus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; aff. &lt;i&gt;pinima&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;uruguayus&lt;/i&gt; group) have keratinized sheets ventrolateral to the lower jaw sheath, well-developed infralabial and lateral ridge papillae, robust jaw cartilages, cornua trabeculae with short and widely divergent free portions, processus articularis short and wide, processus muscularis thin and directed anteriorly. &lt;i&gt;Scinax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aromothyella&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;berthae&lt;/i&gt; (S. &lt;i&gt;catharinae&lt;/i&gt; group) have poorly developed, non-colored spurs behind the lower jaw sheath, long and thin processus articularis, wide and rounded processus muscularis, and tripartite cartilago suprarostralis. Anatomical features described are congruent with current phylogenetic arrangements based on molecular, chromosomal, and morphological data, and provide a source of information that can be useful to solve interspecific relationships within &lt;i&gt;Scinax.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">anuran larvae; buccal cavity; chondrocranium; cranial muscles; hyobranchial apparatus</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">anuran larvae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Leandro</firstname>
          <lastname>Alcalde</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Florencia</firstname>
          <middlename>Vera</middlename>
          <lastname>Candioti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolenc</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Claudio</firstname>
          <lastname>Borteiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <lastname>Baldo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-36</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemidophorus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Teiidae) from the Caatinga, Northwest Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two syntopic species of &lt;i&gt;Cnemidophorus&lt;/i&gt; are described from the Caatingas of the Parque Nacional da Serra das Confusões (PNSC), located in the Southwestern region of the state of Piauí in Brazil. Both species are assigned to the ocellifer group, differing from all other members of the group by their distinct color pattern and lepidosis. Besides these differences, both new species share a number of particular features with other members of the group. One of them, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;venetacaudus,&lt;/i&gt; shares with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abaetensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;littoralis&lt;/i&gt; the presence of spurs in the heels of males, six supraciliar scales, a high number of femoral pores (from 21–45), a row of enlarged scales in the dorsal region of the arm, 8–10 rows of ventral scales, and a bright bluish-green tail, while the other species, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confusionibus,&lt;/i&gt; shares with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ocellifer,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mumbuca,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jalapensis&lt;/i&gt; a low number of femoral pores, enlarged scales in the temporal region (posterior to third subocular), 5 supraciliar scales, and 6–8 rows of ventral scales. Based on these comparisons, we suggest that the ocellifer group is more complex than previously admitted, being composed by at least two morphologically recognizable species subgroups.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lizards; &lt;i&gt;Cnemidophorus&lt;/i&gt;; ocellifer group; Serra das Confusões; Caatinga; Northwest of Brazil</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lizards</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Federico</firstname>
          <lastname>Arias</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Celso</firstname>
          <middlename>Morato</middlename>
          <lastname>De Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <middlename>Trefaut</middlename>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hussam</firstname>
          <lastname>Zaher</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The male of &lt;i&gt;Ascorhynchus constrictus &lt;/i&gt;Stock, 1997 (Arthropoda: Pycnogonida), with further new records of deep-sea pycnogonids from New Caledonia, the Solomon Islands and Vanuatu</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Deep-sea pycnogonid material collected during the N/O &lt;i&gt;Alis&lt;/i&gt; Campagnes Norfolk 2 to New Caledonia in 2003 and Salomon 2 to the Solomon Islands in 2004, together with two samples from the BOA0 and BOA1 Campagnes to Vanuatu in 2004–2005, has been analyzed. This includes only the second collection of deep-sea pycnogonids from the Solomon Islands. The material includes 22 specimens from seven species from New Caledonia, taken at depths from 265 to 1150 m, 95 specimens from 14 species from the Solomon islands, at depths from 336 to 1218 m, and two specimens of one species from Vanuatu (864–927 m depth). The first male of &lt;i&gt;Ascorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;constrictus&lt;/i&gt; is described, including the first description of the anterior legs. A new species of &lt;i&gt;Ascorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; is partially described, but not named owing to its incompleteness. Seven of the species are new to the Melanesia region, including a notable range-extension for &lt;i&gt;Colossendeis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tasmanica.&lt;/i&gt; The local zoogeography of these deep-water species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New Caledonia; Solomon Islands; Melanesia; Pycnogonida; &lt;i&gt;Ascorhynchus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Bathypallenopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cilunculus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Colossendeis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Pallenopsis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New Caledonia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>N</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: QIU, L.-H., ZHAO, J.-X., WU, Z.-D., LV, Z.-Y. &amp; PANG, Y. (2011) &lt;i&gt;Steinernema pui &lt;/i&gt;sp. n. (Rhabditida, Steinernematidae), a new entomopathogenic nematode from Yunnan, China. &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2767, 1–13. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-10</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
