<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2800.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">25 Mar. 2011</title>
    <volume>2800</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis &lt;/i&gt;Sars, 1862 and its position within Aloninae (Cladocera: Anomopoda: Chydoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Taxonomic status of the genus &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis&lt;/i&gt; was clarified by the morphological study and cladistic analysis. Morphology of both valid species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elongata&lt;/i&gt; (Sars, 1861) and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aureolata&lt;/i&gt; Doolitle, 1912, was investigated. So far, generic status of the group was questioned, some authors treated &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis&lt;/i&gt; as a part of the genus &lt;i&gt;Acroperus.&lt;/i&gt; Our data confirm independent status of &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis,&lt;/i&gt; and emended diagnosis of the genus is provided. According to our analysis, &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis&lt;/i&gt; are the sister-groups of a monophyletic clade, each having their own autapomorphies. Both genera belong to a well-defined group of Aloninae (named here as Arthrocauda-group), which is characterized by the presence of well-developed abdominal joint and elongated narrow postabdomen. There are two parallel clades within the group, one formed by &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis,&lt;/i&gt; other by &lt;i&gt;Parakozhowia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Kozhowia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus.&lt;/i&gt; According to our analysis, these branches have numerous homoplasies, the most significant of them is the independent appearance of the head keel in two most successful genera, &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladocera; &lt;i&gt;Alonopsis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Acroperus&lt;/i&gt;; Arthrocauda-group; morphology; systematics; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladocera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Artem</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Margarita</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Atroschenko</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-17</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Halacarus socius &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Halacaridae), description of the male and diagnoses of species of the &lt;i&gt;Halacarus actenos &lt;/i&gt;group</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Amongst the about a dozen halacarid species from a shore of Mauritius, the genus &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; was represented by a single species, &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;socius&lt;/i&gt; Bartsch, 1992. The species was once described on the basis of females collected on Moorea, Society Islands, Pacific Ocean, now a description of the male is added and that of the female supplemented. &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;socius&lt;/i&gt; seems to be wide-spread in the Indo-Pacific region. &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tritoni&lt;/i&gt; Otto is a synonym. &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;socius&lt;/i&gt; is a member of the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;actenos&lt;/i&gt; group, a group characterized by the combination: posterior dorsal plate absent in both females and males, ocular plates small or lacking, with or without a cornea, apodemes of anterior and posterior epimeral plates long, female genitoanal plate with rather uniform cerotegumental cover and two pairs of perigenital setae adjacent to the genital opening, one pair (rarely two pairs) of perigenital setae anterior to the genitoanal plate, one or two bipectinate setae on tibia II, no tines on shaft of claws but paired claws often with tines on the accessory process. Species attributed to this group are diagnosed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Halacaroidea; re-description; &lt;i&gt;Halacarus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;actenos&lt;/i&gt; group; species diagnoses; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Halacaroidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ilse</firstname>
          <lastname>Bartsch</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of Syllidae (Annelida: Polychaeta) from the Southern Mexican Pacific</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">As part of a project dealing with soft bottom polychaetes from the western coasts of Acapulco Bay, Southern Mexican Pacific, 1050 specimens of the family Syllidae were collected and identified. Among them, 72 belong to two new species that are herein described. &lt;i&gt;Plakosyllis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;curvispina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (31 specimens) is the fourth known species of the genus, which is newly recorded for the Mexican Pacific. It is characterized by having compound falcigers with elongated blades, very long, fine and curved spines, and three antennae in ventral position, partially or completely covered by the prostomium. &lt;i&gt;Trypanosyllis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microdenticulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (41 specimens) is characterized by having bidentate chaetae, two pairs of eyes, the anterior one in ventral position and the posterior one in dorsal position and a very small trepan with transparent teeth.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; new species; Syllidae; &lt;i&gt;Plakosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Trypanosyllis&lt;/i&gt;; Southern Mexican Pacific; Acapulco Bay</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Diana</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Salcedo</middlename>
          <lastname>Oropeza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guillermo</firstname>
          <lastname>San Martín</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vivianne</firstname>
          <lastname>Solís-Weiss</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-52</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Hemipteroseius &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Otopheidomenidae) parasitic on &lt;i&gt;Dysdercus &lt;/i&gt;(Hemiptera: Pyrrhocoridae) in India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of ectoparasitic mite, &lt;i&gt;Hemipteroseius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vikrami&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Mesostigmata: Otopheidomenidae), collected on &lt;i&gt;Dysdercus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koenigii&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius) in New Delhi and &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulatus&lt;/i&gt; (Fabricius) in Varanasi, India is described. It is distinguished from other species of the genus in having the dorsal shield divided, podonotal shield with nine pairs and opisthonotal shield with four pairs of setae; setae j6, s6 and Z5 with bulbose/spatulate tips; tritosternum with two short slightly barbed lacinae; venter with four pairs of sternal setae, one pair on the sternal shield and three pairs placed posterolaterally; anus terminal; one pair of preanal setae; movable digit of chelicera with two teeth distally; macrosetae on genu I–IV and femur I–II with bulbose/spatulate tip. A list of species of Otopheidomenidae with details of distribution and hosts, key to species of &lt;i&gt;Hemipteroseius&lt;/i&gt; and comparison of morphological characters of species are also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mesostigmata; ectoparasite; Hemiptera; Pyrrhocoridae; checklist; India</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mesostigmata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Pratibha</firstname>
          <lastname>Menon</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Sushila</firstname>
          <lastname>Joshi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Mohammad</firstname>
          <lastname>Hussain</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>V.</firstname>
          <middlename>V.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ramamurthy</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-63</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The tadpole of &lt;i&gt;Hylodes babax &lt;/i&gt;Heyer, 1982 (Amphibia, Anura, Hylodidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renata</firstname>
          <middlename>Magalhães</middlename>
          <lastname>Pirani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tiago</firstname>
          <middlename>Leite</middlename>
          <lastname>Pezzuti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Paula</middlename>
          <lastname>Motta</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Renato</firstname>
          <middlename>Neves</middlename>
          <lastname>Feio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-03-25</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
