<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2809.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">5 Apr. 2011</title>
    <volume>2809</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Proposal of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov., redescription of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina sensillata&lt;/i&gt; comb. nov., and new data on the distribution of &lt;i&gt;Spiniferaphonte&lt;/i&gt; (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Laophontidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomic position and original description of &lt;i&gt;Laophontina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensillata&lt;/i&gt; Wells &amp; Rao, 1987 are reviewed based on specimens collected from the interstitial fauna of littoral coral sands of several islands of the Philippines and New Caledonia, and the species is designated as the type species of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The new genus is proposed based on the total loss of sexual dimorphism in the P3 and P4 exopods, and the sexual dimorphism in P2 exopod. &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; is highly adapted to the littoral interstitial habitat of coral sandy beaches, and is related to &lt;i&gt;Laophontina&lt;/i&gt; Norman &amp; T. Scott, 1905, &lt;i&gt;Wellsiphontina&lt;/i&gt; Fiers, 1991 and &lt;i&gt;Spiniferaphonte&lt;/i&gt; Gheerardyn &amp; Fiers, 2007. The shared characteristics that indicate a strong affinity of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Spiniferaphonte&lt;/i&gt; are the robust, dorsally bent, and strongly sclerotised caudal seta V and the morphology of the genital field. The phylogenetic relationship of &lt;i&gt;Spiniferaphonte&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; is also suggested by the analysis of the last ontogenetic phases of the species of the two genera. We re-describe here the adults of both sexes, describe the last three copepodid stages of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensillata&lt;/i&gt; (Wells &amp; Rao, 1987) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and provide notes on the biogeography of the four related genera, and on the ecology of &lt;i&gt;Fiersiphontina&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Spiniferaphonte.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eastern Pacific; new genus; marine interstitial; coral degradation zone</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eastern Pacific</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maria</firstname>
          <middlename>Cristina</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruno</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vezio</firstname>
          <lastname>Cottarelli</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">On the species identities of a complex &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus &lt;/i&gt;fauna from the Altiplano and Atacama Desert: insights on &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;L. reichei, L. jamesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachecoi, &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;L. poconchilensis &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Liolaemidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The South American lizard genus &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; has undergone a complex adaptive radiation that has resulted in the evolution of more than 200 species widely spread in an extraordinary diversity of environments, and forming a complex array of assemblages. This evolutionary complexity has puzzled systematists and taxonomists since the first species were described more than 150 years ago. Within this lineage, the Andean &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; faunas have proven to be a major challenge for herpetologists. Therefore, intense research is needed in this area to clarify long-standing problems. After more than a century of taxonomic confusion, the identity of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; (Steindachner, 1891) is here restored as the name that must be applied to the lizards widely known as &lt;i&gt;Phrynosaura&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichei&lt;/i&gt; Werner, 1907 from the low to midelevation deserts of Tarapacá, Chile. Since 1966, the name &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; has been erroneously assigned to populations of &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; from the high Andes of the Chile-Bolivia borderlands which, according to observations presented in this study, correspond to &lt;i&gt;Liolaemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachecoi&lt;/i&gt; Laurent, 1995. A lectotype and allotype for &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; are designated and the type locality for &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; (= &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichei)&lt;/i&gt; is emended to “Deserts of Iquique, Tarapacá Region, Chile”. Furthermore, the recognition of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachecoi&lt;/i&gt; as a species distinct from &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jamesi&lt;/i&gt; is supported by mtDNA sequence divergence data despite the inconclusive meristic and morphometric data. In summary, I conclude that (i) the Chilean &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichei&lt;/i&gt; is a synonym of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni,&lt;/i&gt; and hence, that &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; is a species endemic to Chile, not an element of the fauna of present-day Peru and that (ii) the Chilean Altiplano populations currently recognized as &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stolzmanni&lt;/i&gt; are &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pachecoi,&lt;/i&gt; a species hitherto known only from Bolivia. Also, I report the first confirmed specimens of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;poconchilensis&lt;/i&gt; from Peru, a species previously known only from Chile and confused with &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reichei.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lizards; Chile; Peru; Bolivia; Andes; taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Phrynosaura&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Ctenoblepharys&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lizards</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>Langstroth</middlename>
          <lastname>P.</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of small, bathypelagic calanoid copepods from the Arctic Ocean: &lt;i&gt;Brodskius arcticus &lt;/i&gt;sp. nov. (Tharybidae) and three new species of &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. (Discoidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new calanoid copepod species, &lt;i&gt;Brodskius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arcticus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (family Tharybidae Sars, 1902), and three new species of a new genus &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (family Discoidae Gordejeva, 1975) are described from deep waters of the Arctic Canada Basin. The female of &lt;i&gt;Brodskius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arcticus&lt;/i&gt; differs from five of the other six known species of this genus in the absence of rostral filaments, the lack of which it shares with &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; Markhaseva &amp; Schulz, 2007. This new species differs from &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; in having two very short outer proximal spines at the distal segment of the fifth swimming legs (P5). The length of these spines is less than half the width of the segment, whereas in &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abyssalis&lt;/i&gt; they are longer than the width of the segment. The new genus &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius&lt;/i&gt; is created here for a group of seven species within the family Discoidae which have one-segmented endopods of Р 2-Р4. In contrast, the other genera of this family have three-segmented endopods of Р 2-Р4. The three new species of &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius&lt;/i&gt; differ from each other in the appearance of the genital field, and in the number of outer border spines on the distal exopodal segment of P2. In &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tridentatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; this segment bears three external spines on both left and right P2. The left Р 2 of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;heterodentatus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; has three spines, while the right Р 2 bears two spines only. The distal segments of both left and right Р 2 of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serratus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; have two external spines, but the proximal part of the external margin on the left Р 2 bears three relatively large denticles. The distal exopodal segments of Р 2 of the other four species here transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Pertsovius&lt;/i&gt; are smooth with no external spines or denticles, but each bears two outer border spines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Copepoda; Calanoida; taxonomy; diversity; Arctic Canada Basin; deep water</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Copepoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Andronov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ksenia</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kosobokova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-46</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Nomenclature changes in the mite families Neopygmephoridae and Pygmephoridae (Acari: Heterostigmata: Pygmephoroidea) with redescription of two little known species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The type materials of Neopygmephoridae and Pygmephoridae deposited in the Zoological Institute of Russian Academy of Sciences, St. Petersburg, Russia and the Museum of Zoology, I. Mechnikov Odessa National University, Ukraine were examined. Two genera and several species were synonymyzed. In the family Neopygmephoridae, the genus &lt;i&gt;Heteropygmephrus&lt;/i&gt; Kurosa, 2002 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Aegiptophorus&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Abo-Korah, 1984 and &lt;i&gt;Heteropygmephorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;onthophagi&lt;/i&gt; Kurosa, 2002 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Aegiptophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;shibinensis&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and AboKorah, 1984; &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uniseta&lt;/i&gt; Khaustov and Hajiqanbar, 2004 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tenuispina&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov, 1974; &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nouri&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Zahida Al Douri, 1989 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urbanensis&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov, 1974; &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ptilophora&lt;/i&gt; Savulkina, 1978 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt; (Willmann, 1956). In the family Pygmephoridae, the genus &lt;i&gt;Asiapygmephorus&lt;/i&gt; Khaustov and Chydyrov, 2003 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Mesopotamiophorus&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Zahida Al Douri, 1991, and &lt;i&gt;Asiapygmephorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;paucisetosus&lt;/i&gt; (Sevastianov and Chydyrov, 1991) &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Mesopotamiophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;babylonicus&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Zahida Al Douri, 1991; &lt;i&gt;Pygmephorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scrobiculatus&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov, 1975 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pygmephorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;stammeri&lt;/i&gt; Krczal, 1959; &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;petrovanikitinae&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov, Chydyrov and Marroch, 1994 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;athiasae&lt;/i&gt; (Wicht, 1970); &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crassipedis&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Chydyrov, 1994 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amerahae&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianot and Abo-Korah, 1984; &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;monoufiensis&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Abo Korah, 1985 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pediculaster&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kneeboni&lt;/i&gt; (Wicht, 1970); &lt;i&gt;Siteroptes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dionusii&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Abo-Korah, 1984 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Siteroptes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosae&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Abo-Korah, 1984; &lt;i&gt;Siteroptes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tameri&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov and Abo-Korah, 1984 &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Siteroptes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;graminicola&lt;/i&gt; Mitrofanov, Shabanova and Sevastianov, 1984. &lt;i&gt;Bakerdania&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;urbanensis&lt;/i&gt; Sevastianov, 1974 and &lt;i&gt;Neositeroptes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rosae&lt;/i&gt; (Sevastianov and Abo-Korah, 1984) &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (transferred from &lt;i&gt;Siteroptes)&lt;/i&gt; are redescribed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pygmephoridae; Neopygmephoridae; mites; new synonyms; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pygmephoridae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexandr</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Khaustov</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-57</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leelumnus radium&lt;/i&gt;, a new genus and species of pilumnid crab from marine encrusting communities in Singapore (Crustacea: Decapoda: Brachyura: Pilumnidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus and new species of pilumnid crab is described from marine encrusting communities in Singapore. &lt;i&gt;Leelumnus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is morphologically similar to &lt;i&gt;Latopilumnus&lt;/i&gt; Türkay &amp; Schuhmacher, 1985, and &lt;i&gt;Aniptumnus&lt;/i&gt; Ng, 2002, in the general shape of the carapace, chelipeds, ambulatory legs and morphology of the male thoracic sternum, but can be distinguished by the morphologies of the front and anterolateral margin of the carapace, as well as the unique structure of the male first gonopod. Only the type species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;radium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is currently assigned to the new genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pilumnoidea; new genus; new species; taxonomy; Singapore</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pilumnoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jose</firstname>
          <middlename>Christopher E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mendoza</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-66</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Proceratophrys renalis &lt;/i&gt;(Miranda-Ribeiro, 1920) (Amphibia: Anura: Cycloramphidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Diego</firstname>
          <middlename>José</middlename>
          <lastname>Santana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Rodrigues</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ralph</firstname>
          <middlename>Lacerda</middlename>
          <lastname>De Albuquerque</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>Orsi</middlename>
          <lastname>Laranjeiras</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arielson</firstname>
          <middlename>Dos Santos</middlename>
          <lastname>Protázio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frederico</firstname>
          <middlename>Gustavo Rodrigues</middlename>
          <lastname>França</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
          <middlename>Oliveira</middlename>
          <lastname>Mesquita</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-05</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
