<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2814.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">11 Apr. 2011</title>
    <volume>2814</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revalidation of &lt;i&gt;Pterinopelma &lt;/i&gt;Pocock 1901 with description of a new species and the female of &lt;i&gt;Pterinopelma vitiosum &lt;/i&gt;(Keyserling 1891) (Araneae: Theraphosidae: Theraphosinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We revalidate the theraphosid genus &lt;i&gt;Pterinopelma&lt;/i&gt; Pocock 1901, describe the female of &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitiosum&lt;/i&gt; for first time and &lt;i&gt;Pterinopelma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sazimai&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Brazil. These two species were included in a matrix with 35 characters and 32 taxa and were analyzed both with all characters having same weight and with implied weights. Searches considering all characters non-additive or some additive were also carried out. The preferred tree, obtained with implied weights, concavity 6 and all characters non-additive shows that &lt;i&gt;Pterinopelma&lt;/i&gt; is a monophyletic genus sister to the clade &lt;i&gt;Lasiodora&lt;/i&gt; (Vitalius + &lt;i&gt;Nhandu).&lt;/i&gt; The presence of denticles on the prolateral inferior male palpal bulb keel is a synapomorphy of the genus.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brazil; Cladistic analysis; &lt;i&gt;Eurypelma&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Eupalaestrus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; Tarantula</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brazil</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rogério</firstname>
          <lastname>Bertani</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roberto</firstname>
          <middlename>Hiroaki</middlename>
          <lastname>Nagahama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Caroline</firstname>
          <middlename>Sayuri</middlename>
          <lastname>Fukushima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Update to the zodariid spider fauna of the Iberian Peninsula and Madeira (Araneae: Zodariidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This paper describes three new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Zodarion&lt;/i&gt; from the Iberian Peninsula: &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alentejanum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cesari,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costapratae.&lt;/i&gt; One species, &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lusitanicum,&lt;/i&gt; is newly recorded for Spain. In total 46 zodariid species are known from the Iberian Peninsula to date, of which 22 species are recorded from Portugal and 35 species from Spain. New faunistic records and distribution maps are given for another 18 zodariid taxa, either in the Iberian Peninsula or Madeira: &lt;i&gt;Amphiledorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;balnearius,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Selamia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;reticulata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Zodarion&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alacre,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;algarvense,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atlanticum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;costablancae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;duriense,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fuscum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gregua,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jozefienae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;machadoi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculatum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marginiceps,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;merlijni,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pseudoelegans,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;styliferum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;styliferum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;styliferum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;extraneum,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viduum.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amphiledorus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Selamia&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Zodarion&lt;/i&gt;; description; distribution; Madeira; Portugal; Spain</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Amphiledorus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stano</firstname>
          <lastname>Pekár</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Pedro</firstname>
          <lastname>Cardoso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Javier</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barriga</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>José</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvalho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Taxonomic revision of one of the Old World’s smallest frogs, with description of a new Bornean &lt;i&gt;Microhyla &lt;/i&gt;(Amphibia, Microhylidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">An examination of the holotype of &lt;i&gt;Microhyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis&lt;/i&gt; Parker 1928 revealed that this nomen applies to a miniaturized narrow-mouthed frog from Borneo that recently was described as &lt;i&gt;Microhyla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepenthicola&lt;/i&gt; Das &amp; Haas 2010. This is confirmed concordantly by body size of the female holotype of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis,&lt;/i&gt; and by its reduced extent of toe webbing and rather rounded, short snout profile. Consequently, the name &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nepenthicola&lt;/i&gt; is to be considered as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis,&lt;/i&gt; and an old report of nepenthiphilous breeding habits of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis&lt;/i&gt; is therefore justified. A sympatric larger species usually treated as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis&lt;/i&gt; has no scientific name and is described here as &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malang&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The new species and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;borneensis&lt;/i&gt; are sister to each other, and together are closely related to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mantheyi&lt;/i&gt; from Peninsular Malaysia. These three species are morphologically very similar, but can be distinguished by body size, color pattern, and extent of toe webbing. Phylogenetic relationships, miniaturization, and larval oral morphology in the genus &lt;i&gt;Microhyla&lt;/i&gt; are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microhyla&lt;/i&gt;; new species; synonymy; mitochondrial DNA; phylogeny; body size; Borneo; miniaturization</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Microhyla&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Masafumi</firstname>
          <lastname>Matsui</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-49</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comments on new names and nomenclatural acts of amphibians and non-avian sauropsids established by Garsault 1764 and Laurenti 1768 (response to Dubois &amp; Bour 2010)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">This is a response to a recent work published by Dubois &amp; Bour (2010, Zootaxa 2447: 1–52) on the nomenclatural status of some taxa established by Garsault (1764) and Laurenti (1768). We have a substantially deviating interpretation of the ICZN Code concerning the involved names and nomenclatural acts. We see no major problem in regarding most of Laurenti's (1768) species-group names that were published as separate words ("technically trinominal names") as consistent with the Principle of Binominal Nomenclature. Presence or absence of a hyphen in a compound specific name is not a criterion for binominality, instead the grammatical relationships of the separate words have to be analysed for eventually forming a "single entity" as demanded by Art. 11.9.5. Dubois &amp; Bour (2010) proposed a new procedure for the treatment of early genus-group names which were originally established without species included. We do not think this proposal is in accordance with the ICZN Code, and recommend to use the names &lt;i&gt;Bufo,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Salamandra,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Scincus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Vipera&lt;/i&gt; in the widely accepted sense and simply shift authority and date of these four names from Laurenti (1768) to Garsault (1764). In two cases we regard nomenclautural acts published by Dubois &amp; Bour (2010) as risky. The widely used names &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; Laurenti, 1768 (Amphibia) and &lt;i&gt;Natrix&lt;/i&gt; Laurenti, 1768 (Squamata) are threatened because Dubois &amp; Bour (2010) validly and unnecessarily fixed type species for the senior synonyms &lt;i&gt;Ranetta&lt;/i&gt; Garsault, 1764 and &lt;i&gt;Serpens&lt;/i&gt; Garsault, 1764, and at the same occasion missed to protect &lt;i&gt;Hyla&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Natrix&lt;/i&gt; effectively under Art. 23.9.2. They intended to protect the names under Art. 23.9.1.2, but instead of meeting the requirement to "give evidence" that the conditions were met, they gave only indirect references to general bibliographical lists. We regard this as ineffective as would be a general reference to the Zoological Record or any other bibiographical work. These two important generic names should be protected effectively under Art. 23.9.2, by citing 25 publications and not only one, before someone uses the names &lt;i&gt;Ranetta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Serpens&lt;/i&gt; at one occasion deliberately or undeliberately in a current classification, and suppressing them validly under Art. 23.9.2 would not be possible any more. The same applies to &lt;i&gt;Triturus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cristatus&lt;/i&gt; (Laurenti, 1768) (Amphibia: Salamandridae) and &lt;i&gt;Podarcis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muralis&lt;/i&gt; (Laurenti, 1768) (Squamata: Lacertidae).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Garsault (1764); Laurenti (1768); nomenclature; &lt;i&gt;Code&lt;/i&gt;; Article 11.9.5; Article 23.9.2; synonymy; homonymy; priority; old publications; well-known nomina; subgenus; Amphibia; Squamata; &lt;i&gt;Bufo&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Garsault (1764)</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Welter-Schultes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>R.</firstname>
          <lastname>Klug</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of prickleback &lt;i&gt;Ernogrammus zhirmunskii &lt;/i&gt;(Acanthopterygii: Perciformes: Stichaeidae) from the Sea of Japan, Russia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new stichaeid fish, &lt;i&gt;Ernogrammus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zhirmunskii&lt;/i&gt; is described on the basis of the specimens collected in Peter the Great Bay, the Sea of Japan. This new species differs from its congeners &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hexagrammus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;walkeri&lt;/i&gt; in having seven body sensory canals in total number including one short canal in the middle of belly and unique combination in number of the anal fin rays with one short rigid spine posteriormost (I 28-30 I). In coloration the fish has one narrow white stripe between two wide black ones on the base of pelvic fin, and one dark blotch on the dorsal fin anteriorly.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Stichaeidae; new fish species; the Sea of Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Stichaeidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Markevich</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Vladimir</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kharin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-66</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Dossenus &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1898 (Araneae, Trechaleidae) from Northern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Estevam</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Cruz</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Arno</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lise</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>67-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-11</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
