<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2828.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Apr. 2011</title>
    <volume>2828</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The species of &lt;i&gt;Grammostola &lt;/i&gt;(Araneae: Theraphosidae) from Central Argentina: taxonomy, distribution, and surface ultrastructure of coxal setae</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three species of &lt;i&gt;Grammostola&lt;/i&gt; (Araneae, Mygalomorphae, Theraphosidae) from central Argentina are redescribed and illustrated and their geographic distributions are reported. A new synonymy between &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vachoni&lt;/i&gt; Schiapelli &amp; Gerschman 1961 and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schulzei&lt;/i&gt; (Schmidt 1994) &lt;i&gt;n.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;syn.&lt;/i&gt; is proposed. We did not find zones of co-occurrence with the three species but, in several localities, we found two &lt;i&gt;Grammostola&lt;/i&gt; species in sympatry. The surface ultrastructure of three types of coxal setae was studied by scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Two morphological types of spiniform setae were found on the coxae. The first type consisted of short and strong piriform setae, with the surface completely covered by ridges, and the second type consisted of long and thinner spiniform setae, with a piriform basal portion. The basal portion of the setae had ridges, the central portion was smooth and the apical zone had numerous short barbs with curved tips. The different types of setae found in these &lt;i&gt;Grammostola&lt;/i&gt; species are clearly distinguished, and could be new useful character to diagnose at least these species. In combination with other characteristics, these characters could probably help to solve the problems in other species of this difficult genus if not also other genera.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical; Argentina; theraphosids; spider taxonomy; new synonymy; setae morphology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>N.</firstname>
          <lastname>Ferretti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>G.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pompozzi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>F.</firstname>
          <lastname>Pérez-Miles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-18</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus of oribatid mite, &lt;i&gt;Spineremaeus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov. and three new species of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Oribatida: Cymbaeremaeidae) from Norfolk Island,South-west Pacific, and their biogeographical affinities</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus of oribatid mite, &lt;i&gt;Spineremaeus&lt;/i&gt; is erected and its type species, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;smithi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described from Norfolk Island, as well as three new species belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Spineremaeus&lt;/i&gt; is morphologically closest to the Emarginatus species-group of &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus,&lt;/i&gt; found in Australia, Java and New Zealand. &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinguis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is closest morphologically to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;emarginatus&lt;/i&gt; from New Zealand. &lt;i&gt;Scapheremaeus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacificus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tumidus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; members of the Carinatus species-group, are closest morphologically to each other and to &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insularis,&lt;/i&gt; also from New Zealand. Thus all four cymbaeremaeid species from Norfolk Island show strongest biogeographical affinities with the oribatid fauna of New Zealand rather than Australia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Mite; oribatid; taxonomy; morphology; dispersal; biogeography</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Mite</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Colloff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>19-37</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of eriophyoid mites (Acari: Prostigmata: Eriophyoidea) from Montenegro</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of eriophyoid mites from Montenegro are described and illustrated. The first, &lt;i&gt;Phytoptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alchemillae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Phytoptidae), is found on the basic rosette of leaves of &lt;i&gt;Alchemilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoppeana&lt;/i&gt; (Rchb.) D. Torre, &lt;i&gt;aggr.&lt;/i&gt; (Rosaceae). The second species, &lt;i&gt;Leipothrix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;menthae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Eriophyidae), is located on the undersurface of &lt;i&gt;Mentha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;piperita&lt;/i&gt; L. (Lamiaceae) leaves and the third species, &lt;i&gt;Aculus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blagayanae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; (Eriophyidae), inhabits the receptacles of the subendemic plant species, &lt;i&gt;Daphne&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;blagayana&lt;/i&gt; Frey. (Thymelaeaceae). All three species are vagrants, causing no visible damage to their plant host.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Eriophyoidea; Eriophyidae; Phytoptidae; new species; taxonomy; Montenegro</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Eriophyoidea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ivona</firstname>
          <lastname>Jočić</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Radmila</firstname>
          <lastname>Petanović</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Biljana</firstname>
          <lastname>Vidović</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>38-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Polyarthra &lt;/i&gt;Ehrenberg, 1834 belonging to the &lt;i&gt;vulgaris-&lt;/i&gt;group (Rotifera: Monogononta: Synchaetidae) from Argentina, with a key to the identification of species in the Neotropical Region</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of planktonic genus &lt;i&gt;Polyarthra&lt;/i&gt; Ehrenberg, 1834 was found in water bodies of north-eastern Argentina along the Paraná River and Uruguay River systems. This species, which belongs to the group that has a pair of ventral additional paddles, shares several features with other species of the genus particularly with &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dolychoptera&lt;/i&gt; Idelson, 1925, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;luminosa&lt;/i&gt; Kutikova, 1962, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indica&lt;/i&gt; Segers and Babu, 1999. &lt;i&gt;Polyarthra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;platensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; can be distinguished from other species of the genus by at least two autapomorphic traits, 1) the structure of dorsal integument and 2) the unusual heterogeneity in the composition of paddle bundles. Moreover, this species exhibits a specific combination of diagnostic features including the structure of the trophi having bare manubria, unci with a single tooth and absence of teeth before and after the strong major tooth on the rami. The discovery of this new species indicates that a revision of the genus in the Neotropical Region is pressingly needed. This study provides an updated species identification key for this genus in the Neotropical Region.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">morphology; systematics; La Plata basin; South America</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Susana</firstname>
          <middlename>B. José</middlename>
          <lastname>De Paggi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Juan</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Paggi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-57</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Dibamus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Dibamidae) from Phnom Samkos Wildlife Sanctuary, southwestern Cardamom Mountains, Cambodia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of legless lizard, &lt;i&gt;Dibamus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dalaiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; of the family Dibamidae is described from Phnom Dalai in Phnom Samkos Wildlife Sanctuary, southwestern Cardamom Mountains, Cambodia, based on the following unique combination of characters: maximum SVL 127.6 mm; tail 18–22% of SVL; a single postocular scale; three scales bordering the posterior edge of first infralabial; an enlarged, medial, sublabial scale; labial and nasal sutures complete; rostral suture present but incomplete; 20 midbody scale rows; 22 scale rows just posterior to head and 20 scale rows just anterior to vent; 185–209 ventrals; and 48–52 subcaudal scales. The discovery of &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dalaiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; represents a new family, genus and species record for Cambodia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cambodia; Dibamidae; genus; herpetofauna; legless lizard; new species; reptile; systematics</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cambodia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Thy</firstname>
          <lastname>Neang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jeremy</firstname>
          <lastname>Holden</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Toby</firstname>
          <lastname>Eastoe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rathea</firstname>
          <lastname>Seng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Saveng</firstname>
          <lastname>Ith</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>L.</firstname>
          <middlename>Lee</middlename>
          <lastname>Grismer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>58-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
