<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2838.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">29 Apr. 2011</title>
    <volume>2838</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Mata Atlântica enchytraeids (Paraná, Brazil): A new genus, &lt;i&gt;Xetadrilus &lt;/i&gt;gen. nov., with three new species, and four new species of &lt;i&gt;Guaranidrilus &lt;/i&gt;Černosvitov (Enchytraeidae, Oligochaeta)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Seven new species of terrestrial Enchytraeidae (Oligochaeta) are described from soils of the southern Brazilian Atlantic rain forest. They were found in the framework of the German-Brazilian project SOLOBIOMA, which studied rain forest recovery. Specimens were investigated in vivo and as stained whole mounts. Three species belong to a new genus, named &lt;i&gt;Xetadrilus.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Xetadrilus&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;Guaranidrilus&lt;/i&gt; Č ernosvitov, 1937 and &lt;i&gt;Tupidrilus&lt;/i&gt; Righi, 1974; it differs in the absence of lateral chaetae from segment VIII on and in peculiar structures of the prostomium: ganglia, inner papillae, and a frontal epithelial recess. Further peculiarities are small body size, absence of oesophageal appendages, and a variable pattern of pharyngeal glands. The three species are named &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maacki,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aphanus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;X.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fabryi.&lt;/i&gt; Three further nominal species are transferred to &lt;i&gt;Xetadrilus:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Marionina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pituca&lt;/i&gt; Righi, 1974, &lt;i&gt;Marionina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;righiana&lt;/i&gt; Xie &amp; Rota, 2001, and &lt;i&gt;Stercutus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ugandensis&lt;/i&gt; Bell, 1954. The other four new species belong to &lt;i&gt;Guaranidrilus,&lt;/i&gt; the species-richest genus at the sampling sites. They are named &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;andreolii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marquesi,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cingulatus,&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hoeferi.&lt;/i&gt; All species have elongate transverse epidermal gland cells, three pairs of post-pharyngeal ganglia, and a dorsal vesicle in the nephridial postseptale. These traits may be included in the genus diagnosis. In all species described here, most of the species-specific taxonomic traits are found in non-reproductive structures, which means that specimens of all age groups can be identified to the species level, juveniles included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Clitellata; microdriles; South America; soil fauna; succession</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Clitellata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rüdiger</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Schmelz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rut</firstname>
          <lastname>Collado</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jörg</firstname>
          <lastname>Römbke</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-29</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Tardigrada from Santo Antão Island (Archipelago of Cape Verde, West Africa) with the description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three tardigrade species from Santo Antão Island, Archipelago of Cape Verde are firstly reported from Republic of Cape Verde: &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;scabrospinosus&lt;/i&gt; Fontoura, 1982, &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavispinosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Milnesium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tardigradum&lt;/i&gt; Doyère, 1840. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavispinosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; belongs to the ‘viridis group’ of species characterized by the green colour and plate ornamentation comprised of tubercles, fine dots and light spots, by lacking dorsal and lateral trunk appendages (cirrus &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt; excluded) and well developed claws. &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavispinosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all the known species of the ‘viridis group’ in having the area between the paired plate III and the terminal plate unsculptured, in details of the cuticular ornamentation, pointed clavae instead of papillate apices, and stronger spur on internal claws. A dichotomous key to the species of the &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; group and a list of Macaronesian species are also given.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Macaronesia; Tardigrada; first records; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavispinosus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Echiniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;viridis&lt;/i&gt; group; dichotomous key</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Macaronesia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paulo</firstname>
          <lastname>Fontoura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Giovanni</firstname>
          <lastname>Pilato</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Oscar</firstname>
          <lastname>Lisi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>30-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium &lt;/i&gt;van Beneden, 1849 (Cestoda: Tetraphyllidea) in elasmobranchs from the northwest Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico with first records from smooth-hound sharks and guitarfish</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Five new species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; van Beneden, 1849 are described from elasmobranchs from Atlantic coastal waters of the United States and western Gulf of Mexico. &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cairae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; a category 3 species, from the roughtail stingray &lt;i&gt;Dasyatis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;centroura&lt;/i&gt; (Mitchill), from New England coastal waters of Narragansett Bay, Rhode Island is differentiated from congeners by a combination of characteristics including hook lengths, testis number (82–166) and distribution, bilobed ovary and 8 large muscle fascicles symmetrically encircling the reproductive organs. Four new category 1 species of &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; from four new host species from the Gulf of Mexico are &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lentiginosum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the rhinobatid (guitarfish), &lt;i&gt;Rhinobatos&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lentiginosus&lt;/i&gt; Garman; &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;schalli&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from two species of triakid sharks, &lt;i&gt;Mustelus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;canis&lt;/i&gt; Mitchill and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;norrisi&lt;/i&gt; Springer; and &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ulmeri&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;westi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; both from the skate &lt;i&gt;Raja&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texana&lt;/i&gt; Chandler (Rajidae). &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;floridensis&lt;/i&gt; Goldstein, 1964 is reported from a new host, &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;texana&lt;/i&gt; off the Texas coast in the western Gulf of Mexico, a new locality for this species. These species are differentiated by a combination of characters including size, bothridial size, total hook length, ratio of total hook length to bothridium length, ratio of bothridial length to cephalic peduncle length, ovarian shape, position of the genital pore, testis number and distribution. Biogeographically these records from sharks and the guitarfish are new for &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; and add two new host families to the distribution of &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; in coastal waters of the western Atlantic Ocean. &lt;i&gt;Acanthobothrium&lt;/i&gt; is now known to occur in six families of elasmobranchs in the Gulf of Mexico: skates (Rajidae), rays (Dasyatidae, Gymnuridae, Myliobatidae), sharks (Triakidae) and guitarfish (Rhinobatidae) making it the most diverse geographical region for these cestodes in the eastern coastal waters of North America.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Parasites; Onchobothriidae; &lt;i&gt;Dasyatis;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mustelus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Raja;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhinobatos&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Parasites; Onchobothriidae; &lt;i&gt;Dasyatis;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Mustelus;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Raja;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Rhinobatos&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Anne</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Vardo-Zalik</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ronald</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Campbell</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new bent-toed gecko of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;Gray, 1827 (Reptilia, Gekkonidae) from Mount Tompotika, eastern peninsula of Sulawesi, Indonesia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batik&lt;/i&gt; is a new species described on the basis of seven specimens collected from Mount Tompotika, in the Balantak Mountains, eastern peninsula of Central Sulawesi, Indonesia. This large &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; (up to 115 mm snout– vent length), differs from all other congeners by the combination of striking velvety black dorsal coloration with four irregular dark bands and yellow markings, enlarged tubercles not differently colored from other parts of the dorsum except on the flanks, and the absence of precloacal and femoral pores. The new species, together with &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wallacei&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jellesmae&lt;/i&gt; appear to form an exclusive lineage in Sulawesi.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">morphology; systematics; new species; evolution; biogeography; Balantak Mountains; Wallacea</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">morphology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Djoko</firstname>
          <middlename>T.</middlename>
          <lastname>Iskandar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Angga</firstname>
          <lastname>Rachmansah</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Umilaela</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-78</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">First genetic data for species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Haploniscus &lt;/i&gt;Richardson, 1908 (Isopoda: Asellota: Haploniscidae) from neighbouring deep-sea basins in the South Atlantic</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The phylogenetic analysis in this study, based on a fragment of the CO1 mtDNA gene, provides first evidence in favour of Brökeland’s (2010) conclusion of recent or ongoing gene flow in &lt;i&gt;Haploniscus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rostratus&lt;/i&gt; (Menzies, 1962) across the Walvis ridge. It adds the first evidence for the presence of either restricted gene flow or potential cryptic species in the Guinea Basin. The data suggest furthermore that distinct species within the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;unicornis&lt;/i&gt; complex occur sympatrically in the East Atlantic deep-sea basin north of the Walvis Ridge. However, without more specimens (males in particular) and more markers, other processes that may have generated this pattern cannot be excluded.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Isopoda; Haploniscidae; deep sea; CO1; DNA barcoding</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Isopoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Saskia</firstname>
          <lastname>Brix</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Torben</firstname>
          <lastname>Riehl</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Florian</firstname>
          <lastname>Leese</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>79-84</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comment on “Taxonomy and the DNA Barcoding Enterprise” by Ebach (2011)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Mark</firstname>
          <middlename>I.</middlename>
          <lastname>Stevens</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <lastname>Porco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cyrille</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>D’Haese</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <lastname>Deharveng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>85-88</pages>
        <date_published>2011-04-29</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
