<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2862.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2862</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Phylogenetic review of dobsonflies of the subfamily Corydalinae and the genus &lt;i&gt;Corydalus &lt;/i&gt;Latreille (Megaloptera: Corydalidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Phylogenetic relationships of the World genera of dobsonflies, subfamily Corydalinae, are reappraised, as well as those of species of the New World genus &lt;i&gt;Corydalus,&lt;/i&gt; both on the basis of morphological characters. Previous phylogenetic hypotheses of dobsonfly genera by Glorioso, Penny, and Contreras-Ramos, respectively, are re-evaluated, and a fourth revised phylogeny is presented. Ninety-five characters of 10 taxa, one outgroup and nine ingroup taxa, were used in the updated analysis of Corydalinae. It recognizes four lineages, with &lt;i&gt;Chloroniella&lt;/i&gt; as sister to the other three, of which the &lt;i&gt;Nevromus&lt;/i&gt; lineage (Acanthacorydalis + &lt;i&gt;Nevromus&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Neoneuromus)&lt;/i&gt; is sister to the &lt;i&gt;Corydalus&lt;/i&gt; lineage (Chloronia + &lt;i&gt;Platyneuromus&lt;/i&gt; + &lt;i&gt;Corydalus),&lt;/i&gt; and both as a group are sister to the &lt;i&gt;Protohermes&lt;/i&gt; lineage (Protohermes + &lt;i&gt;Neurhermes).&lt;/i&gt; The main changes in the updated Corydalinae phylogeny are the placement of &lt;i&gt;Chloroniella&lt;/i&gt; as sister to all other dobsonfly genera, and the placement of &lt;i&gt;Acanthacorydalis&lt;/i&gt; as a member of the &lt;i&gt;Nevromus&lt;/i&gt; lineage. Previously, Penny had proposed &lt;i&gt;Chloroniella&lt;/i&gt; as sister to all dobsonfly genera except the &lt;i&gt;Protohermes&lt;/i&gt; lineage, and both Glorioso and Penny, respectively, placed &lt;i&gt;Acanthacorydalis&lt;/i&gt; as sister to the &lt;i&gt;Corydalus&lt;/i&gt; lineage. About &lt;i&gt;Corydalus,&lt;/i&gt; its species phylogeny is herein updated, as four species from Venezuela were added to the genus after its taxonomic revision. For the new phylogeny, 120 characters of 35 taxa, two outgroup and 33 ingroup taxa, were used. It produced a strict consensus of two trees, better resolved than the previous one. The &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arpi&lt;/i&gt; species group is moved to sister of all other species except the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cephalotes&lt;/i&gt; species pair, while the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;batesii&lt;/i&gt; species group is conserved, being the only unresolved group within the phylogeny. Two of the species added, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hayashii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mayri,&lt;/i&gt; belong to the well defined &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arpi&lt;/i&gt; species group, of Guayana Shield affinity, whereas &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crossi&lt;/i&gt; is sister to a large and widespread group beginning with the &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nubilus&lt;/i&gt; species group, and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;clavijoi&lt;/i&gt; is sister to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tesselatus&lt;/i&gt; within the latter group.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Phylogeny; dobsonfly; Corydalinae; &lt;i&gt;Corydalus&lt;/i&gt;; classification</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Phylogeny</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Atilano</firstname>
          <lastname>Contreras-Ramos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New Acrididae from Oaxaca State in Mexico (Orthoptera: Caelifera: Acrididae: Ommatolampinae, Melanoplinae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new genera and seven new species, collected in the state of Oaxaca in Mexico, are described. The genera &lt;i&gt;Reyesacris&lt;/i&gt; (R. &lt;i&gt;amedegnatoae)&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Oaxaca&lt;/i&gt; (O. &lt;i&gt;colorata&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinata)&lt;/i&gt; are new to science. &lt;i&gt;Melanoplus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mixes,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oaxacae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ludivinae&lt;/i&gt; are new species for the genus &lt;i&gt;Melanoplus&lt;/i&gt; Stål, 1873 and &lt;i&gt;Cephalotettix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinantecus&lt;/i&gt; is new species for the genus &lt;i&gt;Cephalotettix&lt;/i&gt; Scudder, 1897.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Grasshoppers; Ommatolampinae; Melanoplinae; &lt;i&gt;Reyesacris&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Oaxaca&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Melanoplus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cephalotettix&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Grasshoppers</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paolo</firstname>
          <lastname>Fontana</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Filippo</firstname>
          <middlename>Maria</middlename>
          <lastname>Buzzetti</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ricardo</firstname>
          <lastname>Mariño-Pérez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-55</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new hypogean species of Iberian &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus &lt;/i&gt;and review of the taxonomic position of &lt;i&gt;Speleotyphlus &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Aphaenotyphlus &lt;/i&gt;(Carabidae: Trechinae: Anillini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of cave-dwelling Anillini (Coleoptera: Carabidae) &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;charon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the “Surgencia de l’Orao” Cave (Valencia, East Spain). &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;charon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is close to two troglobiomorphic species, &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;infernalis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alegrei&lt;/i&gt; (new comb.), sharing the same aedeagus morphology. These three species constitute a monophyletic group that is hypothesized as originating in the endogean environment of the southern end of the Iberian Mountain Range, around the Valencia trough. These three species live in caves that were possibly isolated by the Miocene basins. The analysis of key morphological characters in the &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus&lt;/i&gt; phyletic series showed that the slenderness of appendages, that defines taxa as &lt;i&gt;Speleotyphlus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Aphaenotyphlus,&lt;/i&gt; are of little phylogenetic value, as this also happens with other troglobiomorphic features (e.g., depigmentation). However, other morphological characteristics (male aedeagus, chaetotaxy, labial tooth) suggest a close relationship between &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Speleotyphlus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Aphaenotyphlus,&lt;/i&gt; which leads us to propose the last two taxa as synonyms of &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Arthropoda; Hexapoda; Coleoptera; Carabidae; Anillini; &lt;i&gt;Microtyphlus&lt;/i&gt;; Taxonomy; Systematic; cave fauna; troglobiomorphism</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Arthropoda</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vicente</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ortuño</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alberto</firstname>
          <lastname>Sendra</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>56-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
