<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2877.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 May. 2011</title>
    <volume>2877</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-05-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Gill arch and hyoid arch diversity and cypriniform phylogeny: Distributed integration of morphology and web-based tools</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Using the multiple tools available to support an online collaborative environment, we surveyed 62 morphological features from the hyoid arch and gill arches of 53 species of cypriniform fishes that matched those sampled in recent molecularanalyses and two sets of outgroup species (‘Saitoh outgroups’ and ‘Basal outgroups’). This is a skeletal region whose variation is considered historically significant within fishes and Cypriniformes in particular, and we review previous work in light of our own. The clarity of description of characters was enhanced by the use of a community reference ontology, the Teleost Anatomy Ontology. Terms, synonyms, and definitions for skeletal features from this region were contributed to this ontology, and links to these terms and relationships are included in our character descriptions. One thousand two hundred sixty-three images of features from this region were linked to ontology terms and deposited in a community image repository, Morphbank; these are linked to the characters described herein. Character data were analyzed using parsimony and Bayesian methods for two sets of outgroups, one of which matched that used in previous molecular analyses. The parsimony results, using either outgroup set, indicated similar higher-level relationships, including a sister group relationship between cyprinids and loaches. A basal trichotomy among &lt;i&gt;Gyrinocheilus,&lt;/i&gt; catostomids and cyprinids + loaches was the result of Saitoh outgroup analysis in contrast to a sister group relationship between &lt;i&gt;Gyrinocheilus&lt;/i&gt; and catostomids discovered in the Basal outgroup analysis. Interestingly, analyses including basal outgroups recovered a monophyletic Cyprinidae, consistent with all previous studies. Character evolution that supports higher-level nodes of interest in the consensus tree is described. In some respects, it might be a surprise that 62 morphological characters from a small skeletal region for only 53 cypriniform species (out of over 3,200 total species) could provide as much resolution as it does. We expect, however, further phylogenetic resolution as morphological data from across skeleton regions are combined, species sampling is increased, and molecular data are added.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Branchial arches; Hyoid arch; Pharyngeal arches; Ostariophysi; Cypriniformes; Skeleton; Ontology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Branchial arches</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Paula</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mabee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ericka</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Grey</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gloria</firstname>
          <lastname>Arratia</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nina</firstname>
          <lastname>Bogutskaya</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alicja</firstname>
          <lastname>Boron</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>†miles</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Coburn</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Conway</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shunping</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexander</firstname>
          <lastname>Naseka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Nelson</firstname>
          <lastname>Rios</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <lastname>Simons</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jolanta</firstname>
          <lastname>Szlachciak</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xuzhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-40</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Larval development of the freshwater shrimp &lt;i&gt;Atyaephyra desmarestii&lt;/i&gt; (Millet, 1831) &lt;i&gt;sensu lato &lt;/i&gt;(Decapoda: Caridea: Atyidae) and morphological maturation from juveniles to adults</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A complete serial of larval staging of &lt;i&gt;Atyaephyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmarestii&lt;/i&gt; (Millet, 1831) &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; from Louros River (north-western Greece) was obtained in the laboratory and described in detail. Thirty berried females were collected and transferred to an aquarium containing water and vegetation from the sampling site. The newly hatched larvae were transferred into small sterile aquaria and mass cultured. After each moult, several larvae were photographed and preserved with their exuviae. The reared larvae of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmarestii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; passed through six zoeal stages and one megalopal stage. At the experimental conditions, the durations of each larval stage were as follows: three days for the 1 st larval stage; three to four days for 2 nd larval stage; six to eight days for 3 rd ; seven to nine days for 4 th ; nine to ten days for 5 th , 6 th and megalopal stages. All the obtained stages were described in detail. The larval morphological characters of the described material and the larvae specimens collected from natural populations were compared with the literature data on closely related species. Morphological description of the different phases for juveniles, immature, female and male mature individuals of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmarestii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sensu&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lato&lt;/i&gt; are also presented in detail.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">larval development; &lt;i&gt;Atyaephyra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;desmarestii&lt;/i&gt;; Decapoda; Louros River; Greece; morphological maturation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">larval development</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chryssa</firstname>
          <lastname>Anastasiadou</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alexandros</firstname>
          <lastname>Ntakis</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ioannis</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Leonardos</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>41-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new millipede species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Riukiaria &lt;/i&gt;(Diplopoda, Polydesmida, Xystodesmidae) endemic to the Ryukyu Archipelago, Japan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe two new species of the millipede genus &lt;i&gt;Riukiaria&lt;/i&gt; from two islands of the Ryukyu Archipelago: &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Tane-ga-shima, northern Ryukyus, and &lt;i&gt;R.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mundyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; from Yonaguni-jima, the southwesternmost member of the Yaeyama Island Group. Both species show the simple forceps-like male gonopod structure typical for the genus, but they are readily distinguishable from other members by their unique color patterns. We have also compiled a list of species in the genus described up to now.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">species description; Tane-ga-shima; Yonaguni-jima</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">species description</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zoltán</firstname>
          <lastname>Korsós</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yasuyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Nakamura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tsutomu</firstname>
          <lastname>Tanabe</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-05-13</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
