<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2902.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">1 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2902</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-01</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Multi-locus phylogeny and taxonomic revision of &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia &lt;/i&gt;toadlets (Anura: Myobatrachidae) from the western arid zone of Australia, with a description of a new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We generated a multi-locus phylogeny to test monophyly and distributional limits in Australian toadlets of the genus &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia&lt;/i&gt; from the western arid zone of Australia. The molecular data were used in combination with a detailed assessment of morphological variation and some data on call structure to complete a taxonomic revision of the species that occur in this region. Our work reveals the existence of not two but five species in the region. &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;russelli&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to the Carnarvon and Gascoyne Regions south of the Pilbara. &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;micromeles&lt;/i&gt; is distributed from the Tanami Desert through the Great Sandy Desert and along the northern edge of the Pilbara. &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;talpa&lt;/i&gt; was previously believed to be a Fitzroyland region endemic but it is further distributed along Dampierland and into the Roebourne Plain. &lt;i&gt;Uperoleia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glandulosa&lt;/i&gt; is a larger species than previously described as well as a greater habitat generalist, inhabiting the rocky Pilbara region and the sandy region around Port Hedland. We also describe a new species, &lt;i&gt;U.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saxatilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; endemic to the Pilbara craton.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">frog; anuran; Pilbara; Kimberley; geology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">frog</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Renee</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Catullo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Doughty</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Dale</middlename>
          <lastname>Roberts</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Scott</middlename>
          <lastname>Keogh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-43</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-01</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of Telemidae (Araneae) from Western Africa</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three new species of the family Telemidae from Côte d’Ivoire and Cameroon are diagnosed, described, and illustrated: i.e., &lt;i&gt;Cangoderces&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;christae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Seychellia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;jeremyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Côte d’Ivoire; &lt;i&gt;Cangoderces&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;milani&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Cameroon. All types of the new species are deposited in the Nationaal Natuurhistorisch Museum, Leiden, the Netherlands (RMNH).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Taxonomy; &lt;i&gt;Cangoderce&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Seychellia&lt;/i&gt;; forest; diagnosis</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chunxia</firstname>
          <lastname>Wang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>44-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The hydroid and early medusa stages of the deep sea jellyfish &lt;i&gt;Earleria purpurea&lt;/i&gt; (Hydrozoa: Mitrocomidae) from the Monterey Bay Submarine Canyon, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The hydroid and early medusa stages of the deep sea hydrozoan jellyfish &lt;i&gt;Earleria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;purpurea&lt;/i&gt; (Hydrozoa: Mitrocomidae) are described. Mature medusae were collected from the Monterey Bay submarine canyon near Monterey, California, USA utilizing a remotely operated vehicle and returned to the laboratory for culturing. &lt;i&gt;In&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vitro&lt;/i&gt; fertilized eggs developed into free-swimming planulae larvae that settled and metamorphosed into benthic hydroid colonies consisting of feeding hydranths and medusa producing gonangia. Newly released medusae were grown to maturity and placed on educational display at the Monterey Bay Aquarium. The hydranths and gonangia were compared and found to be distinct from those of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;corachloeae&lt;/i&gt; the only other member of the Genus &lt;i&gt;Earleria&lt;/i&gt; with a described life cycle.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">hydromedusae; hydrozoan; life history; Monterey Bay; hydranth; gonangium; &lt;i&gt;Earleria&lt;/i&gt;; Mitrocomidae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">hydromedusae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Chad</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Widmer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-01</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
