<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2903.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">2 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2903</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New &lt;i&gt;Laonice &lt;/i&gt;species (Polychaeta: Spionidae) from western and northern Australia</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Species belonging to the genus &lt;i&gt;Laonice&lt;/i&gt; (Polychaeta: Spionidae) from continental shelf and slope depths off western and northern Australia are described. Three species are new to science (L. &lt;i&gt;lemniscata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;insolita,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pectinata),&lt;/i&gt; two additional species of uncertain identity are recognised from incomplete material and are similar to existing species. A key is provided to allow identification of all six &lt;i&gt;Laonice&lt;/i&gt; species known from Australia. Also, a new standard for the observation of hooded hooks in &lt;i&gt;Laonice&lt;/i&gt; is established. One of the Australian species, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;quadridentata,&lt;/i&gt; belongs to a group of &lt;i&gt;Laonice&lt;/i&gt; species with fused prostomium and peristomium. These species are of great morphological similarity and several are reported to exhibit ontogenetic and individual variability and we discuss the significant taxonomic problems that are a consequence of that variability. The faunas of the continental margin of western and northern Australia were poorly sampled prior to the extensive surveys that generated our study material; this study and other current work suggests that our present estimates of species richness of the Australian marine invertebrate fauna significantly underestimate species richness, perhaps by as much as 50%.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Continental shelf; continental slope; key; ontogenetic variation; hooded hooks</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Continental shelf</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Elizabeth</firstname>
          <lastname>Greaves</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Karin</firstname>
          <lastname>Meißner</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Robin</firstname>
          <lastname>Wilson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-20</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus for a colorful spirostreptid milliped from East Africa (Diplopoda: Spirostreptida: Spirostreptidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The new generic taxon &lt;i&gt;Sagmatostreptus&lt;/i&gt; is proposed for the type species &lt;i&gt;Spirostreptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;strongylopygus&lt;/i&gt; Attems, 1950, endemic to a limited area in northeastern Tanzania and adjacent Kenya.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Spirostreptidae; &lt;i&gt;Sagmatostreptus&lt;/i&gt;; distribution; color pattern; Tanzania</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Spirostreptidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Hoffman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Henrik</firstname>
          <lastname>Enghoff</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>21-28</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Polycladida Acotylea from Patagonia. Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Crassiplana albatrossi&lt;/i&gt; (Pseudostylochidae), lectotype designation and first record of &lt;i&gt;Notocomplana palta &lt;/i&gt;(Notoplanidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Crassiplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albatrossi&lt;/i&gt; is redescribed on the basis of material collected in Patagonia (Argentina) and type material deposited in the USNM. The specimens have specific characters, showing tentacles; tentacular, brain and marginal eyes; genital pores in the posterior portion; male copulatory system with penis papilla; prostatic vesicle free, with strong muscular walls; internal epithelium of prostatic vesicle glandular and with conspicuous projections; seminal vesicle present; vagina very long and extending anteriorly up to pharynx; Lang’s vesicle absent; genito-intestinal duct present. Known geographic range is increased to include Patagonia (Argentina). Identity of &lt;i&gt;Notocomplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palta&lt;/i&gt; is confirmed based on the presence of characters in the original description including: strongly muscular seminal vesicle, long, thin and muscular ejaculatory duct stretching into prostatic vesicle, which has a high and folded epithelium; conical penis papilla. A lectotype is designated from the material studied by Marcus and housed in the SMNH. Known geographic range of &lt;i&gt;Notocomplana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;palta,&lt;/i&gt; known only from the type locality in south Chile, is enlarged to include Patagonia (Argentina), revealing its Magellanic affinities.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes; “Turbellaria”; Magellanic Region; Argentina; Chile</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Platyhelminthes</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Francisco</firstname>
          <lastname>Brusa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Cristina</firstname>
          <lastname>Damborenea</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerephesia &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Sphaerodoridae) from Mamala Bay, south shore of Oahu, Hawaii</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerephesia&lt;/i&gt; is described from Mamala Bay, south shore of Oahu, Hawaii. &lt;i&gt;Sphaerephesia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mamalaensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; differs from its congeners by the absence of microtubercles and number and arrangement of body and parapodial papillae. This species is commonly found in low abundance in shallow (20 m) and deep–waters (500 m) adjacent to ocean outfall diffusers or dredge dump sites and has been resilient to the waste water treatment plume of the outfalls for the last 25 years. A comparative table with morphological characteristics of all seven recognized species of &lt;i&gt;Sphaerephesia&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Annelida; Sphaerodoridae; new species; sewage outfalls; Oahu; Hawaii</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Annelida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Wagner</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Magalhães</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Julie</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bailey–Brock</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Brendan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Barrett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-47</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Elattoma &lt;/i&gt;(Acari: Heterostigmatina: Pygmephoridae) phoretic on &lt;i&gt;Morimus verecundus&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) from Iran</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Elattoma&lt;/i&gt; Mahunka, 1969 (Acari: Heterostigmatina: Pygmephoridae) associated with &lt;i&gt;Morimus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;verecundus&lt;/i&gt; (Faldermann 1836) (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) are described and illustrated from Oak forests in Golestan province, Northern Iran: &lt;i&gt;Elattoma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cerambycidum&lt;/i&gt; Rahiminejad &amp; Hajiqanbar &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;abeskoun&lt;/i&gt; Rahiminejad &amp; Hajiqanbar &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; Both formed large colonies attached on the ventral surface, around coxae I–III of different individuals of the host beetles. This is the first phoretic record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Elattoma&lt;/i&gt; for beetles of the family Cerambycidae. Furthermore, our record of &lt;i&gt;Elattoma&lt;/i&gt; is new for the arthropod fauna of Iran. A key to world species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Elattoma&lt;/i&gt; is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Prostigmata; mite; beetle; phoretic relationship; Scolytidae; Iran</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Prostigmata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vahid</firstname>
          <lastname>Rahiminejad</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hamidreza</firstname>
          <lastname>Hajiqanbar</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yaghoub</firstname>
          <lastname>Fathipour</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>48-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of bonefish, &lt;i&gt;Albula koreana &lt;/i&gt;(Albuliformes: Albulidae) from Korea and Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; of the family Albulidae is described based on five specimens collected from Korea and Taiwan. Its new scientific name, &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is derived from its type locality (Korea). We compared &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; with its similar species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentea&lt;/i&gt; from Fiji (seven specimens), using morphological and molecular methods. &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs morphologically from &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentea&lt;/i&gt; in its tooth patch distributions on the mesopterygoids and parasphenoid. The tooth patches on the mesopterygoids are distributed more anteriorly than those on the parasphenoid in &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; On the other hand, the anterior end of the tooth patches on the mesopterygoids almost corresponds to that of the tooth patches on the parasphenoid in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentea.&lt;/i&gt; The numbers of vertebrae also differ between the two species (77–78 in &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; vs 72–73 in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentea).&lt;/i&gt; We analyzed 546 base pairs of the mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene sequence, and the &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; sequence differed considerably from that of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;argentea.&lt;/i&gt; Kimura’s genetic distances between them were very large (15.9%–16.4%), robustly supporting the new species &lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt;; new bonefish; mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; Korea; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Albula&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;koreana&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hyuck</firstname>
          <middlename>Joon</middlename>
          <lastname>Kwun</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jin</firstname>
          <middlename>Koo</middlename>
          <lastname>Kim</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-63</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Further records of the anchialine shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Periclimenes pholeter &lt;/i&gt;Holthuis, 1973 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Palaemonidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>S.</firstname>
          <lastname>De Grave</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>T.</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sakihara</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-02</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
