<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2910.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2910</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics of the Lower Ordovician pliomerid trilobite &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt;, with species from the Great Basin, western USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The pliomerid trilobite genus &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt; Harrington, 1957, includes only species from the early Tulean (upper Tremadocian) of the Great Basin, USA, and from the Northwest Territories, Canada. Previously assigned species reported from Scandinavia, China, South Korea, and Australia do not appear to be closely related to the western Laurentian species and are excluded from the genus. The monophyly of the group needs to be tested in the context of a broader phylogenetic analysis, but &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt; is rediagnosed with potential synapomorphies including a long, wide anterior border with a large, semicircular median arcuate anterior curve in the posterior margin. &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celsaora&lt;/i&gt; (Ross, 1951) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;firmimarginis&lt;/i&gt; (Hintze, 1953) are redescribed based on large new collections from Utah and Idaho. Ontogenetic material of &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celsaora&lt;/i&gt; includes an articulated silicified M13 meraspid. &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;parafirmimarginis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described on the basis of both abundant disarticulated sclerites and a large articulated individual. Large topotype collections indicate that &lt;i&gt;Hintzeia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;celsaora&lt;/i&gt; (Ross, 1951) is a senior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Protopliomerops&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aemulus&lt;/i&gt; Hintze, 1953; previously claimed differences appear to reflect small original sample sizes, ontogenetic change, and differing photographic orientation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Silicified; Utah; Idaho; Ibexian; Tulean; Pliomeridae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Silicified</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Neo</firstname>
          <middlename>E. B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mcadams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Adrain</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-45</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review on the huntsman spider genus &lt;i&gt;Spariolenus &lt;/i&gt;Simon, 1880 (Araneae: Sparassidae: Heteropodinae) in Iran with description of four new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Four new species of the huntsman spider genus &lt;i&gt;Spariolenus&lt;/i&gt; Simon, 1880 are described from Iran: &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aratta&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (female) from Jebal Barez mountains in Kerman Province, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iranomaximus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female) from Khofash cave in Ilam Province, &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;manesht&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (female) from Manesht mountain in Ilam and &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zagros&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female) from Kenesht cave, Kermanshah Province. We present an extended diagnosis for the genus and information on the natural history of the new species. This is the first record of the subfamily Heteropodinae in Iran. Females of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;iranomaximus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are larger than any spider ever found in the Middle East. All the species occurred in caves and rock crevices of the Zagros mountain range in Iran. According to the geographical distribution of currently known &lt;i&gt;Spariolenus&lt;/i&gt; species, palaeontology perspectives and geological history of the area an evolutionary scenario of speciation associated with Zagros orogeny is proposed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; evolutionary scenario; speciation; biogeography; refugia; Miocene; caves; Zagros orogeny; Middle East</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Majid</firstname>
          <lastname>Moradmand</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <lastname>Jäger</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>46-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new record of &lt;i&gt;Zatypota albicoxa &lt;/i&gt;(Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae) from Indonesia, with description of a new species of its host spider (Araneae: Theridiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Zatypota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albicoxa&lt;/i&gt; (Walker) is newly recorded from Mt. Merapi, Java Is., Indonesia. This is the first record of &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albicoxa&lt;/i&gt; from this part of the Oriental region and from the Southern Hemisphere, and the first record of the genus &lt;i&gt;Zatypota&lt;/i&gt; from Southeast Asia. The Indonesian population of &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albicoxa&lt;/i&gt; attacks a theridiid spider of the genus &lt;i&gt;Parasteatoda,&lt;/i&gt; as do populations of &lt;i&gt;Z.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;albicoxa&lt;/i&gt; in other regions. The spider is a new species, and is described under the name of &lt;i&gt;Parasteatoda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;merapiensis.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">irregular three-dimensional web; host-shift; Java; koinobiont; parasitism; &lt;i&gt;Parasteatoda&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Polysphincta-group&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">irregular three-dimensional web</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Keizo</firstname>
          <lastname>Takasuka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hajime</firstname>
          <lastname>Yoshida</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Putra</firstname>
          <lastname>Nugroho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Rikio</firstname>
          <lastname>Matsumoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
