<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2912.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">9 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2912</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Comb-tailed spiders from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, China (Araneae, Hahniidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Spiders of the family Hahniidae from the rainforest area of Xishuangbanna are examined. Totally 7 species, including 5 new species are reported: &lt;i&gt;Alistra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;hippocampa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female), &lt;i&gt;Hahnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;saccata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female), &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;submaginii&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senaria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (male, female). Two known species, &lt;i&gt;Hahnia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;flagellifera&lt;/i&gt; Zhu, Chen &amp; Sha, 1989 (male, female) and &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;himalayaensis&lt;/i&gt; Hu &amp; Zhang, 1990 (male, female) are firstly recorded from Yunnan Province and redescribed here. The genus &lt;i&gt;Alistra&lt;/i&gt; is firstly recorded from China. Morphological descriptions, illustrations and photos of all species are given. All specimens are deposited in the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing (IZCAS).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">New species; taxonomy; morphology; canopy; Indo-Burma Biodiversity Hotspot</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">New species</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Zhi-Sheng</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shuqiang</firstname>
          <lastname>Li</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Guo</firstname>
          <lastname>Zheng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-27</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A blue-eyed &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Megophryidae) from Arunachal Pradesh, India</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of Megophryidae, &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bompu&lt;/i&gt; is described from Eaglenest Wildlife Sanctuary, Arunachal Pradesh, India. It is a medium sized member of the genus &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium.&lt;/i&gt; In life, the frog is distinguished by the combination of a series of morphological characters from its congeners. Its entirely greyish-blue coloured eyes differentiate the species from all other species in the genus but &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;waysepuntiense.&lt;/i&gt; The morphological comparison is based on a table of 16 characters discriminant in &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bompu&lt;/i&gt;; Megophryidae; Eaglenest; description</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leptobrachium&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sanjay</firstname>
          <lastname>Sondhi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Annemarie</firstname>
          <lastname>Ohler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>28-36</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The highly divergent New World &lt;i&gt;Artemia &lt;/i&gt;species (Branchiopoda, Anostraca), &lt;i&gt;A. franciscana &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;A. persimilis&lt;/i&gt;, show subtle differences in morphological traits involved in mating</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Mate choice significantly impacts upon population divergence and therefore speciation, recognition of equals being critical in cases where species and divergent populations coexist. The New World species of the brine shrimp &lt;i&gt;Artemia,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franciscana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;persimilis,&lt;/i&gt; were compared through Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) for the following traits: shape and ornamentation of spine-like projections on the basal part of the penes; relative size, shape and ornamentation of the frontal knobs; cuticolar cones on the male second antenna, and ovisac (brood pouch) morphology. In particular, frontal knobs, described as playing a role in maintaining riding pairs attached (amplexus), and ovisac morphology, grouped all individuals into the corresponding species, but these differences seem too subtle to prevent inter-specific mating. In other words, mating between both species would be unspecific (not a key-lock type), an expected finding for allopatric species that would not have the chance to reinforce reproductive mechanisms in sympatry, as predicted by the allopatric mode. Additionally, both species inhabit selectively differential habitats that would prevent viability of migrants. At the population level, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franciscana&lt;/i&gt; locations at the southern edge of the species distribution in the Americas (Chile) showed variation to the typical &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;franciscana&lt;/i&gt; pattern, a somewhat expected finding for peripheral populations. The saltworks at Pichilemu (34° S, central Chile) appear to be a special environment where individuals from both species could eventually coexist, as inferred by the hybrid-like appearance of some individuals. This type of environment facilitates the testing of novel morphological variants which may affect the shaping of morphological divergence.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; Chile; New World species; ecological adaptation; genetic divergence; reproductive isolation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Artemia&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Graziella</firstname>
          <lastname>Mura</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Gonzalo</firstname>
          <lastname>Gajardo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new ‘saccamminid’ genus (Rhizaria: Foraminifera), from 4400 m water depth in the Nazaré Canyon (NE Atlantic)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe &lt;i&gt;Bithekammina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;occulta,&lt;/i&gt; a new monothalamous agglutinated foraminiferan (‘saccamminid’) collected in multicore samples at 4400 m on the terrace of the lower Nazaré Canyon on the Portuguese margin. The test is spherical to oval, up to ~400 µm in length, with a simple circular aperture. The wall has a very smooth surface with a distinct sheen in reflected light. It is &lt;10 µm thick and composed of very fine agglutinated plate-like clay particles and a thin inner organic layer. The most distinctive feature of the new species is that the test is contained within an agglutinated case (‘secondary test’) composed mainly of larger (10–50 µm) quartz grains. The case is equipped with a long, narrow tube that originates near the aperture of the inner test and presumably acts as a channel through which pseudopodia are deployed. Secondary agglutinated structures have been described in a number of foraminifera, but never before in a ‘saccamminid’.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">‘Saccamminid’; monothalamous foraminifera; Portuguese margin; Nazaré canyon; cyst; secondary agglutinated structure</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">‘Saccamminid’</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ana</firstname>
          <middlename>Aranda</middlename>
          <lastname>Da Silva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gooday</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Richard</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pearse</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Marina</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cunha</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-58</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus &lt;/i&gt;lacking pelvic fins and pelvic girdle with a very restricted range in Southern Brazil (Siluriformes: Trichomycteridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tropeiro,&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described from the headwaters of the rio das Antas, laguna dos Patos system, Southern Brazil. &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tropeiro&lt;/i&gt; is distinguishable from other species of the genus by the absence of pelvic fins and pelvic girdle, except from &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catamarcensis.&lt;/i&gt; It differs from these two species in several counts and measurements. The apparent endemism of the species is discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Neotropical; Laguna dos Patos system; Endemic fish; &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;candidus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Trichomycterus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;catamarcensis&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Neotropical</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Juliano</firstname>
          <lastname>Ferrer</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Luiz</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Malabarba</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>59-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Dana&lt;/i&gt;, replacement name for the New Zealand talitrid amphipod genus &lt;i&gt;Tara&lt;/i&gt; Duncan, 1994 (Crustacea, Amphipoda, Talitridae), preoccupied by &lt;i&gt;Tara&lt;/i&gt; Peckham &amp; Peckham, 1886 (Araneae, Salticidae, Amycinae, Astiini)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>K.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lowry</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>68-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-09</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
