<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">  </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname></firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2934.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">30 Jun. 2011</title>
    <volume>2934</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new highland species of &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis &lt;/i&gt;Jiménez de la Espada, 1871 (Anura: Strabomantidae) from the Pantepui region, northern South America</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new strabomantid frog of the genus &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; Jiménez de la Espada, 1871 is described from the Eastern Pantepui Region, Guiana Shield, northern South America. The new species, &lt;i&gt;Pristimantis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aureoventris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is known so far from two neighbouring tepuis, namely Wei Assipu Tepui (type locality) at the border between Guyana and Brazil and Mount Roraima in Guyana, and occurs between 2210–2305 m elevation. The new taxon is distinguished from all known congeners by the following combination of characters: Finger I &lt; II; tympanum distinct; basal webbing between Toes IVV; broad lateral fringes on fingers and toes; ventral skin areolate; vocal slits absent in male; two non-spinous whitish nuptial pads and vocal sac present in male; high degree of pattern polymorphism; throat, chest, and belly golden yellow, usually with reddish brown to dark brown mottling; internal organs little or not visible through the ventral skin in life. The call of the new species consists of bouts of a single amplitude-modulated (decreasing to the end) note repeated at a rate of &lt;i&gt;ca.&lt;/i&gt; 18 notes/min with a dominant frequency ranging from 2180 to 2430 Hz.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; Brazil; Guiana Shield; Guyana; Mount Roraima; systematics; taxonomy; Venezuela; Wei Assipu Tepui</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philippe</firstname>
          <middlename>J. R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Kok</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>D.</firstname>
          <middlename>Bruce</middlename>
          <lastname>Means</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Franky</firstname>
          <lastname>Bossuyt</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-19</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus &lt;/i&gt;Marcusen 1854 (Osteoglossomorpha: Mormyridae) from the Sanaga River basin, Cameroon</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the Djerem River, upper Sanaga basin, in Cameroon. It can be distinguished from all other &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; from West and Central Africa by an unique combination of morphological characters including: body without melanin mark, 22–24 branched rays in the dorsal fin and 28 or 29 branched rays in the anal fin, mouth commissure under the posterior half of the eye. &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; mostly resembles &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sullivani.&lt;/i&gt; Yet, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; has proportionally a larger mouth and a wider head, and reaches a longer maximum standard length. The electric organ discharge waveform of this species is not known. Molecular comparisons based on cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; nucleotide sequences are congruent with morphological comparisons in independently supporting the distinctiveness of this species from 17 other species of &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus.&lt;/i&gt; Within the genus &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;similis&lt;/i&gt; belongs to a group that is almost exclusively composed of endemic species of Central Africa, pointing out its likely origin from this region. Additional examinations of museum specimens from the Sanaga River basin demonstrate the occurrence of at least two other species of &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;microphthalmus,&lt;/i&gt; and a second species which is conservatively assigned to &lt;i&gt;Petrocephalus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;cf.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;christyi,&lt;/i&gt; pending additional evidence.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">electric fish; Central Africa; molecular phylogeny; cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; integrative taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">electric fish</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sébastien</firstname>
          <lastname>Lavoué</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>20-28</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new characid fish, &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia aurantia &lt;/i&gt;(Ostariophysi: Characiformes: Characidae), from the upper rio Tocantins basin in Central Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new characid species, &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;aurantia,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the upper portions of rio Tocantins basin, in the Chapada dos Veadeiros, Goiás State, central Brazil. The new species differs from its congeners by the combination of 3 or 4 scale rows below and 5 or 6 scale rows above the lateral line, 21–25 branched anal-fin rays, 33–35 lateral line scales, 2–4 maxillary teeth, one diffuse humeral spot, and caudal spot continuous to the longitudinal line which extends posteriorly over the middle caudal-fin rays. A key to identify &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia&lt;/i&gt; species describe from the Tocantins-Araguaia basin is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Tocantins-Araguaia basin; Chapada dos Veadeiros; Brazilian Cerrado; &lt;i&gt;Moenkhausia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lopesi&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Tocantins-Araguaia basin</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vinicius</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bertaco</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jerep</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fernando</firstname>
          <middlename>R.</middlename>
          <lastname>Carvalh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Clymenura &lt;/i&gt;(Polychaeta: Maldanidae) from the intertidal of Banks Peninsula, New Zealand, with a reassessment of &lt;i&gt;Leiochone &lt;/i&gt;Grube, 1868 and &lt;i&gt;Clymenura &lt;/i&gt;Verrill, 1900</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A maldanid discovered on sand beaches of Banks Peninsula, South Island, New Zealand is newly described. &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;snaiko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is of large size at over 250 mm length, with 18 chaetigers, two achaetous preanal segments with tori, unmodified dentate uncini in anterior chaetigers, a ventral glandular shield on chaetiger eight, a high cephalic rim notched laterally, and a deep anal funnel rimmed with 16 short subequal cirri and one longer ventral cirrus. The confused taxonomy of ventral-shield-bearing maldanids is reassessed and clarified. &lt;i&gt;Leiochone&lt;/i&gt; Grube 1868 and &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; Verrill, 1900 are here treated as the valid members of Arwidsson’s (1906) tribe Leiochonini in Euclymeninae, and given emended diagnoses, while Imajima and Shiraki’s (1982) subfamily Clymenurinae and &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; subgenus &lt;i&gt;Cly.&lt;/i&gt; (Cephalata) are considered invalid. Differentiating character states of the valid Leiochonini species are tabulated. &lt;i&gt;Leiochone&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to six species, including the new combinations &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulata&lt;/i&gt; (Mohammad, 1980) and &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;japonica&lt;/i&gt; (Imajima &amp; Shiraki, 1982). &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; is restricted to nine valid taxa, including &lt;i&gt;Cly.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;snaiko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and the new combination &lt;i&gt;Cly.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;polaris&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lena&lt;/i&gt; (Averincev, 1990). These updated groupings exclude a further eight nominal taxa which mostly may be indeterminable. &lt;i&gt;Leiochone&lt;/i&gt; species occur in inshore temperate to tropical Eastern Hemisphere waters, while &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; mostly occur in high North European latitudes and the northern Pacific region, usually offshore in deep water. The new species is the first record of a &lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt; from Southern Hemisphere waters, and the second member of the genus to be found in the intertidal.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Cephalata&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Leiochone&lt;/i&gt;; Leiochonini; taxonomy; generic emendation; new species; new combinations; sand beach</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Clymenura&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Geoffrey</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Read</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-52</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Redescription of the rheophilous cladocera &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus vietnamensis &lt;/i&gt;Than, 1980 (Cladocera: Anomopoda: Chydoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Little-known Vietnamese chydorid cladocera, &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vetnamensis&lt;/i&gt; Than, 1980 is redescribed on the material from Cat Tien national park, South Vietnam. Detailed morphology of limbs is described for the first time. In some features, &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vietnamensis&lt;/i&gt; is similar to &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;uncinatus&lt;/i&gt; Smirnov, 1971, but can be easily differentiated from it by smaller size, morphology of postabdomen and labrum. &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vietnamensis&lt;/i&gt; is the only species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus&lt;/i&gt; strictly confined to the rheic conditions.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cladocera; &lt;i&gt;Camptocercus&lt;/i&gt;; morphology; systematics; Indochina</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cladocera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Artem</firstname>
          <middlename>Y.</middlename>
          <lastname>Sinev</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-60</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new genus for &lt;i&gt;Psopheticus megalops &lt;/i&gt;Takeda, 1989 (Crustacea: Brachyura: Goneplacidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new genus is established for Psopheticus megalops Takeda, 1989, an unusual and poorly known species of goneplacoid crab known only from Japan. The carapace and male gonopods are very distinctive, and easily distinguish it from all other genera. Although its classification in the Goneplacidae has been questioned, its thoracic sternal and other characters clearly argue for its continued retention in this family.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Brachyura; Goneplacidae; Psopheticus megalops; new genus; Japan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Brachyura</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Peter</firstname>
          <middlename>K. L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Ng</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tomoyuki</firstname>
          <lastname>Komai</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>61-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: Lourenço, A.C.C., Baêta, D., Abreu, A.C.L. &amp; Pombal Jr., J.P. (2010) Tadpole and advertisement call of &lt;i&gt;Rhinella pombali &lt;/i&gt;(Baldissera, Caramaschi &amp; Haddad, 2004) (Amphibia, Anura, Bufonidae). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2370, 65–68. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-06-30</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
