<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2964.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">13 Jul. 2011</title>
    <volume>2964</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-07-13</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A review of the monophyly and composition of the Bengaliinae with the description of a new genus and species, and new evidence for the presence of Melanomyinae in the Afrotropical Region (Diptera, Calliphoridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mafikengia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ciliata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from South Africa and assigned to the subfamily Bengaliinae of the Calliphoridae. It is recognisable by its small size (4 mm), mostly yellow body, and a number of peculiar characteristics. The upper end of the bacilliform sclerite is attached to the medial side of the posterior portion of the surstylus on each side, a very unusual feature among calliphorids. This medial connection in &lt;i&gt;Mafikengia&lt;/i&gt; is found in all genera of Bengaliinae, but is not present in any other calliphorid subfamily. The monophyly of the Bengaliinae is discussed, the subfamily is diagnosed, the component genera are listed, and a key to the world Bengaliinae is presented. The Bengaliinae are a very well circumscribed group within the Oestroidea, and it is suggested that the status of the subfamily might be raised to the rank of family. A cladistic analysis using NONA shows that &lt;i&gt;Mafikengia&lt;/i&gt; is more closely related to the Oriental genus &lt;i&gt;Termitoloemus&lt;/i&gt; Baranov, 1936 than to any other genus, and that the tribes Auchmeromyiini and Bengaliini may still be upheldas separate monophyletic groups, but with very low support. The Afrotropical nominal genus &lt;i&gt;Neocordylobia&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve, 1929 is reduced to a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cordylobia&lt;/i&gt; Grünberg, 1903, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The nominal species &lt;i&gt;Neocordylobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tauffliebi&lt;/i&gt; Zumpt, 1958 is transferred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Tricyclea&lt;/i&gt; Wulp, 1885, as &lt;i&gt;Tricyclea&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tauffliebi&lt;/i&gt; (Zumpt), &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; A new interpretation of the male genitalia of &lt;i&gt;Termitoloemus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;marshalli&lt;/i&gt; Baranov is presented. The male genitalia of the Afrotropical species &lt;i&gt;Tricycleala&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;maculipennis&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve as well as the male and female genitalia of the Afrotropical genera &lt;i&gt;Adichosina&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve, &lt;i&gt;Ochromelinda&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve and &lt;i&gt;Onesihoplisa&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve are figured. The uterine first instar larva of the female of &lt;i&gt;Ochromelinda&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thoracica&lt;/i&gt; Villeneuve is described and illustrated. The genera &lt;i&gt;Adichosina,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ochromelinda,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Onesihoplisa&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Zernyiella&lt;/i&gt; Zumpt are assigned to the calliphorid subfamily Melanomyinae on the basis of the morphology of the female ovipositor, male aedeagus and first instar larva. The occurrence of this subfamily in the Afrotropical Region is established for the first time. A lectotype is designated for &lt;i&gt;Zernyiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dubia&lt;/i&gt; Zumpt, 1956 to fix the interpretation of the name. &lt;i&gt;Auchmeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kurahashi&lt;/i&gt; Lehrer, 2005 is established as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Auchmeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;senegalensis&lt;/i&gt; Macquart, 1851, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Auchmeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pattoniella&lt;/i&gt; Lehrer, 2005 is an unavailable name [no type designation] in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;Auchmeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bequaerti&lt;/i&gt; Roubaud, 1913. &lt;i&gt;Cordylobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ebadiana&lt;/i&gt; Lehrer &amp; Goergen, 2006 is established as a junior synonym of &lt;i&gt;Cordylobia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodhaini&lt;/i&gt; Gedoelst, 1910, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Pachychoeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;kanemia&lt;/i&gt; Lehrer, 2011 is reduced to a synonym of &lt;i&gt;Pachychoeromyia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;praegrandis&lt;/i&gt; Austen, 1910, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; The family-group name Coganomyinae of Peris &amp; González-Mora, 2004 is established as a synonym of Bengaliinae Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889, &lt;b&gt;syn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Diptera; Calliphoridae; Bengaliinae; Melanomyinae; new genus; new species; genitalia; phylogeny</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Diptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Knut</firstname>
          <lastname>Rognes</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-60</pages>
        <date_published>2011-07-13</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
