<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.2978.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">28 Jul. 2011</title>
    <volume>2978</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-07-28</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Cumacea from the continental shelf of Angola and Namibia with descriptions of new species</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">During two sampling campaigns carried out in 2004 and 2008 on the shelf off Angola and northern Namibia (South West Africa), sixteen cumacean species belonging to the families Bodotriidae, Diastylidae and Pseudocumatidae were collected. Two of them are new to science, namely &lt;i&gt;Bodotria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fionae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Heterocuma&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ambrizetensis.&lt;/i&gt; Figures are drawn for the new species and additional for seven species, which are partially described up to date. Additionally, an adapted key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Heterocuma&lt;/i&gt; is provided. Taxonomic and morphological features were analysed and the findings were compared and discussed with earlier investigations from West Africa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bodotriidae; Diastylidae; Pseudocumatidae; Benguela current; West Africa</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bodotriidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Ralf</firstname>
          <lastname>Bochert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Michael</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Zettler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-33</pages>
        <date_published>2011-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new microendemic frog species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Blommersia &lt;/i&gt;(Anura: Mantellidae) from the east coast of Madagascar</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Field surveys in northeastern Madagascar have revealed the existence of a new &lt;i&gt;Blommersia&lt;/i&gt; frog species (Anura: Mantellidae), populations of which were recorded within a 30 km radius of the town of Maroantsetra. We combined morphological, bioacoustic and molecular techniques and show that it is indeed a distinct evolutionary lineage which we describe as &lt;i&gt;Blommersia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;variabilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from the type locality Ambodivoahangy near Maroantsetra. This new species is morphologically most similar to &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;wittei&lt;/i&gt; by the presence of vomerine teeth and relatively small, well-delimited femoral glands, but differs from that species by advertisement call consisting of only 2–6 notes of comparatively longer duration, and a wider separation of femoral glands in males. It is associated with dense secondary vegetation fringing lentic water bodies. Anecdotal evidence suggests its life history is similar to other congeners. The restricted range of this species implies that it is microendemic, being possibly confined to the Antainambalana watershed. Mitochondrial and nuclear DNA variation show that its closest known relatives are &lt;i&gt;Blommersia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dejongi,&lt;/i&gt; both of which also have restricted ranges on the east coast. A putative hybrid between a &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;galani&lt;/i&gt; female and &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dejongi&lt;/i&gt; male with intermediate morphology was identified based on nuclear and mitochondrial DNA variation.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Amphibia; tropical biodiversity; integrative taxonomy; herpetology</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Amphibia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Maciej</firstname>
          <lastname>Pabijan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philip-Sebastian</firstname>
          <lastname>Gehring</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jörn</firstname>
          <lastname>Köhler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <lastname>Glaw</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Miguel</firstname>
          <lastname>Vences</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>34-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Tetilla &lt;/i&gt;Schmidt, 1868 (Tetillidae, Spirophorida, Demospongiae) from Bahia, northeastern Brazil</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">In this paper we describe three new species of &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; from stretches of the coast of Bahia, northeastern Brazil, all collected in shallow waters and soft bottoms. &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pentatriaena&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinct from other species of the genus by the unique possession of five categories of triaenes: two of protriaenes and three of anatriaenes. &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muricyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodriguesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; are the first species in the genus registered exclusively from mangrove ecosystems and are distinct from most species of &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; by their lack of microscleres. &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;muricyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from all species by its spiculation and by having a reticulate skeleton of secondary oxeas. &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rodriguesi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; differs from other species without sigmaspires by the presence of three categories of oxeas, two of trichoidal protriaenes and one of exclusively rhizoidal anatriaenes. In addition to the three new species described here we also provided one identification key to the &lt;i&gt;Tetilla&lt;/i&gt; species occurring in the Atlantic Ocean.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">taxonomy; marine sponges; soft bottom; mangrove; estuary</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">taxonomy</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Julio</firstname>
          <middlename>C. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Fernandez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Solange</firstname>
          <lastname>Peixinho</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulisses</firstname>
          <middlename>S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinheiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carla</firstname>
          <lastname>Menegola</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: El-Banhawy, E.M. &amp; M. Knapp, M. (2011) Mites of the family Phytoseiidae Berlese from Kenya (Acari: Mesostigmata). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2945, 1–176. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-07-28</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
