<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3001.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">23 Aug. 2011</title>
    <volume>3001</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and records of springsnails (Caenogastropoda: Cochliopidae: &lt;i&gt;Tryonia&lt;/i&gt;) from the Chihuahuan Desert (Mexico and United States), an imperiled bio-diversity hotspot </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe 13 new, narrowly localized species of the aquatic gastropod genus &lt;i&gt;Tryonia&lt;/i&gt; from springs in the Chihuahuan Desert (Chihuahua and Texas): &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;allendae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;angosturae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chuviscarae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contrerasi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;julimesensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;metcalfi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minckleyi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;molinae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;oasiensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;ovata&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;peregrina&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;taylori&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zaragozae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp..&lt;/b&gt; These novelties are distinguished by shell and other morphologic characters and are well differentiated genetically from each other and from other congeners (mtCOI sequence divergence &gt;1.9%). We also provide two new records for &lt;i&gt;T.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;seemani&lt;/i&gt; (Frauenfeld, 1863), which is distributed near the southern limit of the Chihuahuan Desert (Durango State) and previously had been thought to be possibly extinct. Bayesian analysis of a mtCOI dataset resolved two clades composed of novelties described herein: one (containing four species) is distributed in several drainages in Chihuahua, the other (containing three species) is a local species flock in the Río Conchos basin (also in Chihuahua) that lives in the warmest waters yet recorded for &lt;i&gt;Tryonia&lt;/i&gt; (41–44°C). (The phylogenetic relationships of the other new species were not well supported.) Both of these clades contain sympatric species pairs; co-occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Tryonia&lt;/i&gt; congeners previously had been reported only in Ash Meadows (southern Nevada). Some of the species described herein are from previously unsurveyed localities and may help delineate new areas of endemism within the Chihuahuan Desert. One of the new species (T. &lt;i&gt;julimesensis)&lt;/i&gt; became extinct between 1991 and 2001 and another (T. &lt;i&gt;oasiensis)&lt;/i&gt; disappeared from its single known locality shortly after it was first discovered in 2009 and also may be extinct. The other species treated herein are at risk of extirpation owing to the declining extent and condition of their unprotected habitats.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">springs; Mexico; Texas; gastropods; mitochondrial DNA; endemism; taxonomy; conservation</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">springs</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Robert</firstname>
          <lastname>Hershler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hsiu-Ping</firstname>
          <lastname>Liu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>J.</firstname>
          <middlename>Jerry</middlename>
          <lastname>Landye</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of pennatulacean octocorals with the ability to attach to rocky substrata (Cnidaria: Anthozoa: Pennatulacea) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">All sea pens have been thought to anchor in soft sediment using a basal, sausage-shaped, muscular peduncle. Based on underwater images and examination of specimens, we report an adaptation of the proximal portion of the peduncle for attachment to solid surfaces. We document four species with this adaptation, three new, &lt;i&gt;Anthoptilum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;lithophilum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (California, 669–700 m), &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;gowlettholmesae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Tasmania, 729–1803 m), and &lt;i&gt;Calibelemnon&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;francei&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (the Bahamas, 1969 m), and one known, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;decipiens&lt;/i&gt; Thomson &amp; Henderson, 1906 (Sri Lanka, 925 m). The peduncle of a colony with this adaptation is greatly expanded by an outgrowth of the coenenchyme that forms a sucker-like structure, beneath which a conical mass of tough tissue surrounds the proximal end of the internal axis. We infer this structure affects suction, increasing or decreasing the strength of adhesion to the substratum, and discuss the systematics and functional morphology of this new ecological phenomenon—pennatulaceans fastened to hard substrata. We alter the definition of the genus &lt;i&gt;Anthoptilum&lt;/i&gt; to accommodate this morphology, reporting on specimens of the type species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grandiflorum;&lt;/i&gt; compare the two sea pen families—Anthoptilidae and Scleroptilidae— and the two genera; and present a key to the known rock-inhabiting species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Octocorallia; Anthoptilidae; Scleroptilidae; new taxa; sea pens; benthic adaptation; rocky substrata</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Octocorallia</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Gary</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Williams</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <lastname>Alderslade</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-48</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Podocinum &lt;/i&gt;Berlese (Acari: Podocinidae) and a key to species of the genus from China </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Mites were collected from leaf litter and the fur of a wild rodent (Niviventer &lt;i&gt;fulvescens&lt;/i&gt; ) in Guizhou Province of China, and described as &lt;i&gt;Podocinum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guizhouense&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; (Podocinidae). This is the first report of Podocinidae from a wild rodent host, but this ecological association may be accidental. A key to the females of &lt;i&gt;Podocinum&lt;/i&gt; from China is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Podocinidae; &lt;i&gt;Podocinum&lt;/i&gt;; new species; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Podocinidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yi</firstname>
          <lastname>Yan</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dao-Chao</firstname>
          <lastname>Jin</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Xian-Guo</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jian-Jun</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>49-56</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Systematics and molecular phylogenetics of Asian snail-eating snakes (Pareatidae) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The taxonomy of the Asian snail-eating snakes (Pareatidae) is an ongoing controversy, partly because morphological characters do not yield consistent results across studies. We infer phylogenetic relationships within Pareatidae using ~ 2 kilobases of DNA sequences including two mitochondrial (cyt &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; and ND4) and one nuclear gene (c-mos). Results reveal four major lineages: &lt;i&gt;Aplopeltura,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Asthenodipsas,&lt;/i&gt; a clade formed by &lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuchalis,&lt;/i&gt; and a clade comprising all other species of &lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; sampled in this study. Our data do not have enough signal to either support or reject a monophyletic &lt;i&gt;Pareas.&lt;/i&gt; However, large molecular divergence (16.5%) is observed between the two major clades of &lt;i&gt;Pareas,&lt;/i&gt; a level that is comparable to that between &lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Aplopeltura.&lt;/i&gt; Scale characters also suggest that &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;carinatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nuchalis&lt;/i&gt; are distinct from congeners, and future morphological and/or molecular studies might assess whether a distinct genus should be recognized. The molecular phylogeny further suggests a distant relationship between &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chinensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;formosensis&lt;/i&gt; and supports the validity of the former species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aplopeltura&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Asthenodipsas&lt;/i&gt;; genetic divergence; mitochondrial genes; nuclear genes; &lt;i&gt;Pareas&lt;/i&gt;; scale patterns</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Aplopeltura&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Yuhong</firstname>
          <lastname>Guo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Yunke</firstname>
          <lastname>Wu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Shunping</firstname>
          <lastname>He</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Haitao</firstname>
          <lastname>Shi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ermi</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>57-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A note on an &lt;i&gt;Ancylomenes &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Decapoda: Pontoniinae) from the Siboga expedition </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>A.</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bruce</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>65-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: JI, D. &lt;i&gt;et al. &lt;/i&gt;(2011) Redescriptions of five species of marine peritrichs, &lt;i&gt;Zoothamnium plumula&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Zoothamnium nii&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Zoothamnium wang&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Pseudovorticella bidulphiae&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Pseudovorticella marina &lt;/i&gt;(Protista, Ciliophora). &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 2930, 47–59. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-08-23</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
