<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3050.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">6 Oct. 2011</title>
    <volume>3050</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-10-06</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Butterflies of the Andaman and Nicobar islands: History of collection and checklist </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The history of butterfly collecting on the islands is detailed, highlighting the contributions of both amateur and professional entomologists. In the light of the recent revival of interest in butterflies in India in general and islands in particular, we present a checklist of the butterflies of these islands. For the first time in many years we take a critical look at the butterflies recorded as occurring on the Andaman and Nicobar islands. We distinguish between species that are known to occur definitely on these islands versus those which are stragglers and those which have been reported on the basis of erroneous identification. We also indicate which species/subspecies are endemics and present an overview of the knowledge of the life histories, larval food plants and natural history that is known of these butterflies. A bibliography of the butterflies of the Andaman and Nicobar islands is included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Endemics; Indian Wildlife Act</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Endemics</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Prashanth</firstname>
          <lastname>Mohanraj</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>K.</firstname>
          <lastname>Veenakumari</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-36</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agabus &lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Acatodes&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;i&gt;puetzi &lt;/i&gt;sp. n., a new species of the &lt;i&gt;confinis&lt;/i&gt;-group from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau (Coleoptera, Dytiscidae, Agabini) </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;puetzi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is described from the eastern part of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau (Sichuan). It is a very distinctive species, males of which can be identified easily even in the field because the inner outline of the protibiae is distinctly curved, a feature which is unknown or considerably less prominent in any other &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1817. The new species undoubtedly belongs to the subgenus &lt;i&gt;Acatodes&lt;/i&gt; Thomson, 1859, although males lack the preapical spine of the median lobe, a character which is also seen in the Nearctic &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;audeni&lt;/i&gt; Wallis, 1933, and the Holarctic &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inexspectatus&lt;/i&gt; Nilsson, 1990. Due to an unusual combination of external characters (e.g., double reticulation, shape of tibiae and of proand metasternal processes) it is not easy to assign the species to one of the known species groups of the subgenus. It seems likely, however, that it belongs to the &lt;i&gt;confinis-group&lt;/i&gt; because several other characters are shared with most members of this group. A few features suggest a closer relationship to &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;thomsoni&lt;/i&gt; (J. Sahlberg, 1871) and &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zetterstedti&lt;/i&gt; Thomson, 1856. The new species raises the number of members of the &lt;i&gt;confinis-group&lt;/i&gt; to 36, seven of which occur in China. A list of all Afrotropical and Palearctic members of this group is given and their median lobes are figured in lateral view. The lectotype of &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;turcmenus&lt;/i&gt; Guignot, 1957 is designated, and its habitus and aedeagus are illustrated for the first time. Some notes on the distribution and external morphology of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inexspectatus&lt;/i&gt; are included.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Dytiscidae; Agabini; &lt;i&gt;Agabus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Acatodes&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;confinis-group&lt;/i&gt;; new species; lectotype; China; Tibet; Kyrgyzstan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Hans</firstname>
          <lastname>Fery</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>37-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Three new species of &lt;i&gt;Loneura &lt;/i&gt;(Psocodea:’Psocoptera’:Ptiloneuridae) from Gorgona Island, Cauca, Colombia, with a new infrageneric classification </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Three related species of &lt;i&gt;Loneura&lt;/i&gt; Navás, from Gorgona Island (Cauca, Colombia), are here described and illustrated. The types are deposited in the Entomological Museum of the Universidad del Valle (MUSENUV). A set of infrageneric groups within &lt;i&gt;Loneura&lt;/i&gt; is proposed based on the structure of the male hypandrium and phallosome. The species of the genus are assigned to the groups recognized in this classification.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Colombian Pacific; neotropics; psocid fauna; Epipsocetae</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Colombian Pacific</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Alfonso</firstname>
          <middlename>N. García</middlename>
          <lastname>Aldrete</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ranulfo</firstname>
          <middlename>González</middlename>
          <lastname>Obando</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <middlename>A. Sarria</middlename>
          <lastname>Sarria</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>55-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-06</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species of Leptohyphidae (Ephemeroptera) from northeastern Brazil </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Two new species of Leptohyphidae are described based on nymphs and adults: &lt;i&gt;Traverhyphes&lt;/i&gt; (Traverhyphes) &lt;i&gt;frevo&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Tricorythopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spongicola&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Traverhyphes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(T.)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;frevo&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from other species, among other characteristics, by the presence of curved penile spines inserted laterally, and posterolateral projections of styliger plate very short and pointed distally in lateral view. &lt;i&gt;Tricorythopsis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spongicola&lt;/i&gt; can be distinguished from the others species, mainly by the presence of spine-like lateral projections present on apical part of penes in the male imago, and by the tarsal claws with four to five marginal denticles, and two rows of 2 + 3 submarginal denticles with apical setae in the nymphs.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">aquatic insects; mayflies; taxonomy; Brazil; Neotropical Region</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">aquatic insects</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Lucas</firstname>
          <middlename>R. C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lima</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Frederico</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Salles</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ulisses</firstname>
          <middlename>Dos S.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pinheiro</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-10-06</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
