<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3091.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">4 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3091</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Freshwater Dalyelliidae from the Nearctic (Platyhelminthes, Rhabdocoela): new taxa and records from Ontario, Canada and Michigan and Alabama, USA</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Nine taxa of Dalyelliidae Graff, 1908 collected from limnic habitats in Ontario, Canada and Michigan and Alabama, USA are discussed. Two taxa are new to science. &lt;i&gt;Pseudodalyellia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;alabamensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; has a unique combination of characters (Microdalyellia-type stylet with two proximal heteromorphic axes of different size and two distal axes with long spines flanking a central spiny plate, uterus without uterine sphincter, glandular protrusion in male atrium) and is therefore placed in a new genus. &lt;i&gt;Gieysztoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;choctaw&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; is strikingly similar to the Amazonian &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;chiqchi&lt;/i&gt; Damborenea &lt;i&gt;et&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;al.,&lt;/i&gt; 2005 but differs by having 13 symmetrically arranged, heteromorphic spines of different size on its fenestrated girdle. &lt;i&gt;Gieysztoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavimentata&lt;/i&gt; (Beklemischew, 1926) Ruebush &amp; Hayes, 1939 and &lt;i&gt;Gieysztoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubra&lt;/i&gt; (Fuhrmann, 1894) Ruebush &amp; Hayes, 1939 discovered in Alabama are the first records for these species in the Nearctic. Remarks on the morphology and distribution of the new North American records of &lt;i&gt;Gieysztoria&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;dodgei&lt;/i&gt; (Graff, 1911) Ruebush &amp; Hayes, 1939, &lt;i&gt;Microdalyellia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fairchildi&lt;/i&gt; (Graff, 1911) Gieysztor, 1938, &lt;i&gt;Microdalyellia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rossi&lt;/i&gt; (Graff, 1911) Gieysztor, 1938, &lt;i&gt;Castrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncata&lt;/i&gt; (Abildgaard, 1789) Hofsten, 1907 and &lt;i&gt;Castrella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pinguis&lt;/i&gt; (Silliman, 1884) Fuhrmann, 1900 are given. For &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pavimentata,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fairchildi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;C.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truncata,&lt;/i&gt; new localities from the Palearctic are also mentioned.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Dalyelliidae; taxonomy; Nearctic; microturbellaria; Rhabdocoela</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Dalyelliidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Niels</firstname>
          <lastname>Van Steenkiste</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stefan</firstname>
          <lastname>Gobert</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Paul</firstname>
          <lastname>Davison</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jurek</firstname>
          <lastname>Kolasa</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Tom</firstname>
          <lastname>Artois</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-32</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The mesostigmatid mite (Acari: Parasitiformes) fauna of Svalbard: a revised inventory of a high Arctic archipelago</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The need for comprehensive studies of the invertebrate fauna in the high Arctic is increasingly acknowledged in order to more fully understand ecosystem functioning, resilience and to project future changes in the biodiversity and species ranges. Information on the mesostigmatid fauna in the high Arctic is scarce and scattered. Large regions of the high Arctic archipelago of Svalbard, including most of the areas in the east of the island group, have never been surveyed for the mesostigmatid fauna. Furthermore, most of the current knowledge on the mesostigmatid fauna of this important region in the European high Arctic originates from studies in the early 20 th century. Much of the associated slide material no longer exists, either being mislaid or deliberately destroyed, resulting in an ambiguous and potentially misleading mesostigmatid fauna checklist in which identifications and potential synonyms cannot be reliably assessed. Determination of fresh material sampled between 2007–2010 may be an ideal procedure to resolve the great number of uncertainties about the mesostigmatid fauna of the Svalbard archipelago. Twelve out of the 27 species recorded from the Svalbard archipelago were found in the new samples collected from a large number of localities and microhabitats. No new species were identified in the current campaign, and most of the non-observed species are considered to be past missidentifications or potential synonyms. Combining this study with recent publications provides a total mesostigmatid mite diversity for Svalbard of 22 species. This represents the most accurate checklist of the mesostigmatid mite fauna of the archipelago to date.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Gamasida; invertebrate; polar; high latitude; diversity</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Gamasida</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>María</firstname>
          <middlename>Luisa</middlename>
          <lastname>Ávila-Jiménez</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Dariusz</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Gwiazdowicz</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Stephen</firstname>
          <middlename>James</middlename>
          <lastname>Coulson</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>33-41</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Validity of &lt;i&gt;Lampetra pacifica &lt;/i&gt;(Petromyzontiformes: Petromyzontidae), a brook lamprey described from the lower Columbia River Basin</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Pacific Brook Lamprey, &lt;i&gt;Lampetra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; Vladykov, 1973 was described from the lower Columbia River Basin near Portland, Oregon. Subsequently, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; has generally been treated as a junior synonym of the Western Brook Lamprey, &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richardsoni&lt;/i&gt; Vladykov and Follett, 1965, a species described from the Fraser River Drainage east of Vancouver, British Columbia. We reexamine the available morphological data used by previous authors (trunk myomere counts), report on recent collections from the Columbia Basin, and reinterpret the trunk myomere data in the context of recent genetic sampling from the same populations. Populations of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; are distinguished from those of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richardsoni&lt;/i&gt; by trunk myomere counts of 53–60 (means &lt;58) versus 57–67 (means &gt;59), respectively, and by genetic sequence divergence (cyt &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; of 2.85 to 3.20%. We find no support for placing &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; in the synonymy of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;richardsoni&lt;/i&gt; and recognize &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; as a valid species. However, we recognize that there is considerable unresolved diversity in the western North American lampreys and recommend restriction of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;pacifica&lt;/i&gt; to the Columbia Basin, suggesting that unresolved populations of &lt;i&gt;Lampetra&lt;/i&gt; brook (non-parasitic) lampreys outside the basin with mean trunk myomere counts below 59 be referred to as &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;pacifica,&lt;/i&gt; until further systematic information is available.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Pacific Brook Lamprey; Western Brook Lamprey; myomeres</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Pacific Brook Lamprey</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Stewart</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Reid</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Boguski</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Damon</firstname>
          <middlename>H.</middlename>
          <lastname>Goodman</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Margaret</firstname>
          <middlename>F.</middlename>
          <lastname>Docker</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>42-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Nebalia &lt;/i&gt;(Crustacea: Phyllocarida: Leptostraca) from the Cape d’Aguilar Marine Reserve, Hong Kong</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of leptostracan, &lt;i&gt;Nebalia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mortoni,&lt;/i&gt; is described from the waters of the Cape d’Aguilar Marine Reserve, Hong Kong. It is distinguished from previously described species in particular owing to the squared denticles on the posterior dorsal margins of the pleonites. The species has been collected using baited traps, and has been the subject of previous study of its behaviour and demography. Laboratory culture of immature males has revealed that passage to maturity involved a sudden and dramatic lengthening of the antennae within the space of a single moult. This is only the second description of nebaliacean species from Asia.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Leptostraca; Nebaliacea; &lt;i&gt;Nebalia&lt;/i&gt;; southeast Asia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Leptostraca</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Christine</firstname>
          <middlename>N. W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Lee</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Roger</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Bamber</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-59</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Iiella &lt;/i&gt;Băcescu, 1968 (Crustacea: Mysida: Mysidae) from Malaysia, with notes on &lt;i&gt;I. elegans &lt;/i&gt;(Tattersall, 1960)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Iiella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;malayensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; from Malaysian waters is described here. This species is distinguished from related species by the shape of the rostral plate, the number and length of the subsegments of the first exopodal segment of the third male pleopod, the number of spines on the labrum, the number of spiniform setae on the lateral margin of the telson, and the position of the anterior end of the apical cleft of the telson. Supplemental taxonomic notes on &lt;i&gt;I.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;elegans&lt;/i&gt; (Tattersall, 1960) based on type specimens are provided. A key to the species of &lt;i&gt;Iiella&lt;/i&gt; is provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Crustacea; Mysida; &lt;i&gt;Iiella&lt;/i&gt;; new species; Malaysia</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Crustacea</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kouki</firstname>
          <lastname>Fukuoka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>60-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-04</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
