<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3093.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3093</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New species and new collection records of aquatic beetles in the genus &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; Leach from southern Africa (Coleoptera: Hydraenidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The southern African species of the water beetle genus &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; Leach, 1815, are reviewed. Eight new species are described, and new collection records are given for eight previously described species, based on the examination and databasing of 8,919 specimens from 253 localities/events. Male genitalia of the new species are illustrated, and high resolution habitus images of the holotypes of new species are provided. Distribution maps are given for the 18 species of &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; now known from southern Africa, including Namibia, South Africa, Lesotho, Zimbabwe, the extreme southern part of Angola, and the southern part of Mozambique. New species of &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; are: &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;anchorus&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, KwaZulu-Natal Province, Oribi Gorge); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bicomicus&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, Western Cape Province, 22 mi. N. Nelspoort); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bupunctus&lt;/i&gt; (Namibia, Kaokoveld, Kunene River, Swartbooisdrift); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;endroedyi&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, North West Province, Barberspan); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;granulinus&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, Western Cape Province, Elandsdrift); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;involatus&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, Western Cape Province, near Kommetje); &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sitiensis&lt;/i&gt; (Namibia, Okau Fountain, 12.5 km inland); and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;zulu&lt;/i&gt; (South Africa, KwaZulu-Natal Province, Nqutu).</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Coleoptera; Hydraenidae; &lt;i&gt;Ochthebius&lt;/i&gt; Leach; new species; southern Africa; aquatic insects; aquatic microhabitats; holotype digital images</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Coleoptera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Philip</firstname>
          <middlename>D.</middlename>
          <lastname>Perkins</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-34</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Mortonagrion indraneil &lt;/i&gt;spec. nov. from Borneo, and a redescription of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri &lt;/i&gt;Fraser (Odonata: Zygoptera: Coenagrionidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indraneil&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;spec.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is described from locations in Sarawak, Malaysian Borneo. Both sexes of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;arthuri&lt;/i&gt; Fraser are re-described based on recent material. Records of &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoena&lt;/i&gt; Ris from Borneo in fact refer to &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;indraneil;&lt;/i&gt; there is no evidence that &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;amoena&lt;/i&gt; occurs on Borneo. Relationships between &lt;i&gt;Argiocnemis,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Agriocnemis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mortonagrion&lt;/i&gt; are discussed.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Odonata; Zygoptera; Coenagrionidae; Malaysia; Borneo; Singapore; Thailand; &lt;i&gt;Mortonagrion&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;indraneil&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;arthuri&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Odonata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Rory</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Dow</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-46</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Review of the leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Dryodurgades &lt;/i&gt;Zachvatkin (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae: Megophthalminae) with description of a new species from China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The megophthalmine leafhopper genus &lt;i&gt;Dryodurgades&lt;/i&gt; Zachvatkin is reviewed. One species is described as new, &lt;i&gt;D.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;tortilis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; and three known species are recognized and illustrated. A key to Chinese species of &lt;i&gt;Dryodurgades&lt;/i&gt; based on males is given and a checklist of all known species of &lt;i&gt;Dryodurgades&lt;/i&gt; is also provided.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha; Agalliini; morphology; taxonomy; distribution</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Auchenorrhyncha</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Bin</firstname>
          <lastname>Zhang</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>47-54</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa..1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">PublishDate</title>
    <volume></volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year></year>
    <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">with unusual gall morphology</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Australia has a diverse array of gall-inducing scale insects (Hemiptera: Sternorrhyncha: Coccoidea), most of which feed on eucalypts. Here we describe a recently discovered and previously unrecognised species of &lt;i&gt;Apiomorpha&lt;/i&gt; Rübsaamen that induces an unusual gall. Galls of the adult females were first found in bushland in South West Rocks, in northern New South Wales (Australia), but the original location has been cleared for housing development. Additional specimens have been discovered in nearby bushland and near the Arakoon Conservation Park, NSW. All specimens observed to date occur on &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;racemosa&lt;/i&gt; Cav. The morphology of the adult female and COII mtDNA sequences suggest affinities with the &lt;i&gt;Apiomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; (Froggatt) species-group of Gullan (1984), but the gall of the adult female is quite distinct from those of other members of that species-group in that it has two chambers instead of one. In addition, the newly recognised species, &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nookara&lt;/i&gt; Mills, MacDonald, Rigby &amp; Cook &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; has a diploid chromosome complement of 2n = 6, a count not yet noted for members of the &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt; species-group. The description of the species was partly prepared by undergraduates at The University of Queensland, who were helping to overcome the so-called "taxonomic impediment" by describing and naming previously undescribed taxa.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Scale insects; New South Wales; &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Apiomorpha&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomic impediment</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Scale insects</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Penelope</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Mills</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Melanie</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Macdonald</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lisa</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Rigby</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Lyn</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Cook</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages></pages>
        <date_published><![CDATA[]]></date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3093.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">8 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3093</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A second species of &lt;i&gt;Bittacus &lt;/i&gt;Latreille, 1805 (Mecoptera: Bittacidae) from Hainan Island, China</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Bittacus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;diaoluoshanus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; the second species of Bittacidae (Mecoptera) from Hainan Island, China is described from Diaoluoshan National Forest Park. The new species is separated from other hangingflies of &lt;i&gt;Bittacus&lt;/i&gt; by two crossveins below pterostigma; four tawny brown spots each at ORs, FRs, OM, and the distal end of CuP; one tawny stripe along apical margin from pterostigma to beyond apex; absence of Av; and male epandrial appendages subquadrangular at lateral aspect.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Insecta; Mecoptera; Bittacidae; &lt;i&gt;Bittacus&lt;/i&gt;; Hainan Island; China</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Insecta</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jing</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Baozhen</firstname>
          <lastname>Hua</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>64-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-08</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
