<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3102.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">18 Nov. 2011</title>
    <volume>3102</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-11-18</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Rove beetles (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae) associated with &lt;i&gt;Aenictus laeviceps&lt;/i&gt; (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) in Sarawak, Malaysia: Strict host specificity, and first myrmecoid Aleocharini</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Munetoshi</firstname>
          <lastname>Maruyama</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Takashi</firstname>
          <lastname>Matsumoto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Takao</firstname>
          <lastname>Itioka</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-26</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-18</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A redefinition of the Curculionini of the world, with a key to subtribes and genera, and two new genera: &lt;i&gt;Pseudoculio &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Megaoculis&lt;/i&gt; (Coleoptera: Curculionidae: Curculioninae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A key to the subtribes and genera of the Curculionini is presented, and two new genera are described: &lt;i&gt;Pseudoculio&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Curculio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Balaninus)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;discreticoxis&lt;/i&gt; Marshall, as its type species (new combination); and &lt;i&gt;Megaoculis&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;i&gt;Megaoculis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;egeri,&lt;/i&gt; new species, as its type species. Keys to the species of the new genera are provided. Photos of habitus are included for most taxa and of genitalia of the new species. The following taxa are described as new in this paper: subtribes Archariina, new subtribe, Erganiina, new subtribe, and Labaninina, new subtribe; and new species: &lt;i&gt;Pseudoculio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;barclayi,&lt;/i&gt; new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;confusicoxis&lt;/i&gt; , new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;crinitus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;promissus,&lt;/i&gt; new species, &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;spiesi,&lt;/i&gt; new species, and &lt;i&gt;P.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;vittatus,&lt;/i&gt; new species. &lt;i&gt;Curculio&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;guyanensis&lt;/i&gt; Rheinheimer is reassigned to the new genus &lt;i&gt;Megaoculis,&lt;/i&gt; new combination. The following genera placed in &lt;i&gt;Incertae&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;sedis&lt;/i&gt; in Alonso-Zarazaga and Lyal are removed from the tribe: &lt;i&gt;Allocionus&lt;/i&gt; Hustache, &lt;i&gt;Balaninorhynchus&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire, &lt;i&gt;Bradyninus&lt;/i&gt; Fairmaire, &lt;i&gt;Semicardius&lt;/i&gt; Hustache and &lt;i&gt;Trichanthonomus&lt;/i&gt; Hustache.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">new genera; new species; new subtribes; taxonomy; weevils</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">new genera</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Frank</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Pelsue</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Jr.</firstname>
          <lastname></lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Charles</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>O’Brien</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>27-49</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Biology of the Afrotropical &lt;i&gt;Sepedonella nana &lt;/i&gt;(Diptera: Sciomyzidae), whose larvae feed only on freshwater &lt;i&gt;Aulophorus furcatus &lt;/i&gt;(Oligochaeta: Naididae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">All studies during the last six decades have stated that sciomyzid larvae are strictly malacophagous. However, the Afrotropical sciomyzid &lt;i&gt;Sepedonella&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nana&lt;/i&gt; species was found in this study to feed only on the small freshwater oligochaete, &lt;i&gt;Aulophorus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;furcatus.&lt;/i&gt; The divergent oligophagous feeding behaviour of this species was investigated. The physical attributes of the egg, first-, secondand third-instar larvae, and the puparium are described. Four types of sensilla—coeloconicum, trichodeum, chaeticum, and styloconicum—are present with a characteristic distribution on each tagma. Each thoracic segment is distinguished by presence of a pair of Keilin’s organ on ventral surface. Each abdominal segment has eleven pairs of the same sensilla types; their variable locations are presented. Population dynamics of the adults are shown from our field investigations in permanent and temporary freshwater biotopes during 1996–2008. The life cycle of the species is presented from our field observations and laboratory experiments. Among the 62 species of Afrotropical Sciomyzidae, this is the eighth species for which life-cycle is entirely resolved.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Immature stages; larval feeding behaviour; larval biology; life-cycle; sensilla; population dynamic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Immature stages</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Jeanclaude</firstname>
          <lastname>Vala</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Louis</firstname>
          <middlename>Ghélus</middlename>
          <lastname>Gbedjissi</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>50-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-11-18</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
