<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3129.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">14 Dec. 2011</title>
    <volume>3129</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Filellum &lt;/i&gt;Hincks, 1868 (Lafoeidae, Leptothecata, Hydrozoa)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A taxonomic review of the cosmopolitan genus &lt;i&gt;Filellum&lt;/i&gt; was performed considering morphology, morphometry and cnidome. Species for which we had access to materials were redescribed and morphologically characterized based on optical and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The materials examined belong to museum collections, including type specimens. All records found in the literature were checked. Our analyses confirmed the validity of 10 out of the 18 nominal species referred to the genus, and established four others (F. &lt;i&gt;adnatum,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bouvieri,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;contortum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;F.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;plicatum)&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda.&lt;/i&gt; A new species, &lt;i&gt;Filellum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bouvetensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; is described. The species &lt;i&gt;Reticularia&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulata&lt;/i&gt; Watson, 1973, type species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Corystolona&lt;/i&gt; Watson, 2002, has its type specimen referred to the genus &lt;i&gt;Filellum,&lt;/i&gt; composing &lt;i&gt;Filellum&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;annulatum&lt;/i&gt; (Watson, 1973). We provide a key for the identification of the valid species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Filellum.&lt;/i&gt;</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Lafoeidae; &lt;i&gt;Filellum&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomy; morphology; &lt;i&gt;species&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;inquirenda&lt;/i&gt;</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Lafoeidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Antonio</firstname>
          <middlename>C.</middlename>
          <lastname>Marques</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Álvaro</firstname>
          <middlename>L. Peña</middlename>
          <lastname>Cantero</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thaís</firstname>
          <middlename>P.</middlename>
          <lastname>Miranda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Alvaro</firstname>
          <middlename>E.</middlename>
          <lastname>Migotto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-28</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Description of &lt;i&gt;Sarsilatona &lt;/i&gt;cf. &lt;i&gt;fernandoi &lt;/i&gt;(Rane, 1983) (Crustacea: Cladocera: Sididae) found in the south of Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The representatives of the rare genus &lt;i&gt;Sarsilatona&lt;/i&gt; close to originally poorly described &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; (Rane, 1983) from Central India (Madhya Pradesh State) are studied on the basis of female specimens from two localities in the south of Vietnam. Their exact species assignment remains to be vague due to inability to investigate the type material. The studied specimens differ from all other species of the genus in presence of only small denticles, not setules, on the sensory seta of antennules. &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; cf. &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; resembles &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;serricauda&lt;/i&gt; (Sars, 1901) in presence of large dorsal postabdominal outgrowths but differs from the latter in shorter antennules, lack of a large prominence on the posterior side of antennal basipodite, presence of setules, not small denticles, on the ventral valve margins, more numerous anal teeth in each cluster, and less numerous and thicker clusters of spinules near postero-ventral valve margins. The representatives of &lt;i&gt;S.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;fernandoi&lt;/i&gt; s.l. seem to be widely distributed in tropical Asia, from India to Vietnam, preferring small water bodies. Superficially similar representatives of the genus from Africa probably belong to a yet undescribed new species.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sarsilatona&lt;/i&gt;; tropical Asia; detailed morphological description; geographical distribution; types of water bodies</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Sarsilatona&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Nikolai</firstname>
          <middlename>M.</middlename>
          <lastname>Korovchinsky</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>29-38</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus &lt;/i&gt;(Squamata: Gekkonidae) from Huong Son limestone forest, Hanoi, northern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; based on two adult specimens from Huong Son limestone forest, Hanoi, Vietnam. &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huongsonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from the remaining Indochinese bent-toed geckos by a combination of the following characters: medium-sized, with a maximum SVL of 89.8 mm; dorsal pattern consisting of dark nuchal loop, neck band and five in part irregular transverse body bands between limbs; two enlarged lateral chinshields in contact with first postmental pair; dorsal tubercles present on occiput, body, forearms, hind limbs and tail base; 14–16 irregularly running dorsal tubercle rows; ventrals in 41–48 longitudinal rows at midbody; lateral skin folds present, without interspersed tubercles; six precloacal pores plus in total 17 femoral pores in males, which are separated by 8–12 poreless scales; enlarged femoral scales and precloacal scales present; three postcloacal spurs in males; subcaudal scales transversely enlarged. This is the 24 th species of &lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; known from Vietnam.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huongsonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Hanoi; Vietnam; morphology; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Cyrtodactylus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;huongsonensis&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;nov.,&lt;/b&gt; Hanoi</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Vinh</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Luu</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Truong</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Nguyen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Huy</firstname>
          <middlename>Quang</middlename>
          <lastname>Do</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>39-50</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Another new &lt;i&gt;Gekko &lt;/i&gt;species (Squamata: Gekkonidae) from southern Vietnam</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">We describe a new species of the gekkonid genus &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; from southern Vietnam on the basis of three adult specimens from Cuc Dong Cape, Ninh Hoa District, Khanh Hoa Province. &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truongi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; is distinguished from congeners by the combination of the following characters: medium-sized species with a maximum 95.9 mm SVL; supralabials 13–15; postmentals enlarged; interorbitals 45–58; dorsal tubercles absent; well developed lateral folds; scales between mental and cloaca 160–172; ventrals 35 or 36; subdigital lamellae below first toe 11–13, below fourth toe 15–17; faint basal webbing between fingers and toes; precloacal pores in males 10 or 11; postcloacal tubercles in males 1/1; number of transverse dorsal scale rows in the middle of the third caudal whorl 11; a prominent light postocular stripe is lacking; dorsum grey with dark pattern and light blotches and lines.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Squamata; Gekkonidae; &lt;i&gt;Gekko&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;truongi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;sp.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.,&lt;/b&gt; taxonomy; Khanh Hoa Province; southern Vietnam.</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Squamata</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Trung</firstname>
          <middlename>My</middlename>
          <lastname>Phung</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Thomas</firstname>
          <lastname>Ziegler</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-61</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">The aquatic and littoral forms of the Patagonian frog &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; (Batrachylinae): new molecular evidence</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; is one of the eight species included in the Patagonian genus &lt;i&gt;Atelognathus,&lt;/i&gt; an endemic frog occurring in the system of endorheic basaltic lagoons of the Laguna Blanca National Park (PNLB), Neuquén, Argentina. Based on morphological data, Cei &amp; Roig (1968) described two forms of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus,&lt;/i&gt; which they called “aquatic” and “littoral”. These morphotypes were first suggested to belong to different species, but later, Cei (1972) proposed that both forms represent a balanced polymorphism within &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus.&lt;/i&gt; More recently, an ecomorphological study showed that aquatic and littoral are reversible forms of the same individual (phenotypic plasticity). In this paper we compare the morphotypes of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; using nucleotide sequences of the mtDNA (cytochrome b and control region) in order to test the existence of genetic differentiation between the aquatic and littoral forms. In addition, we present data of genetic variability of &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; from the Laguna Blanca system. We did not detect genetic differentiation between littoral and aquatic morphotypes for both genes studied. This observation is consistent with the hypothesis of phenotypic plasticity. In contrast with the expected results for low vagility organisms, the diversity index observed in &lt;i&gt;A.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt; revealed a low genetic variability.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt;; phenotypic plasticity; mtDNA; morphotypes</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Atelognathus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;patagonicus&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Liza</firstname>
          <middlename>B.</middlename>
          <lastname>Martinazzo</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Néstor</firstname>
          <middlename>G.</middlename>
          <lastname>Basso</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Carmen</firstname>
          <middlename>A.</middlename>
          <lastname>Úbeda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>62-68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-14</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
