<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3134.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">16 Dec. 2011</title>
    <volume>3134</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Monographic revision of the endemic &lt;i&gt;Helix mazzullii &lt;/i&gt;De Cristofori &amp; Jan, 1832 complex from Sicily and re-introduction of the genus &lt;i&gt;Erctella &lt;/i&gt;Monterosato, 1894 (Pulmonata, Stylommatophora, Helicidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Helix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mazzullii&lt;/i&gt; De Cristofori &amp; Jan, 1832 &lt;i&gt;s.l.(Pulmonata,&lt;/i&gt; Stylommatophora, Helicidae) is an endemic, rupicolous, saxicavous taxon of northwestern Sicily. Its populations are vulnerable and it is of great ecological significance. However, its taxonomy, phylogeny and biogeography are still uncertain. The present paper reports on a comprehensive analysis of morphological diagnostic characters (shell and genitalia) joined by the molecular study of two mitochondrial (16S rRNA and 12S rRNA) and one nuclear (ITS-2) partial gene sequences, investigated by individual segment analyses or combining the three gene fragments with a concatenate analysis. Our results corroborated the hypothesis that this species is rather a group (i.e., the &lt;i&gt;mazzullii&lt;/i&gt; group) including three different taxa (mazzullii, &lt;i&gt;cephalaeditana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;insolida)&lt;/i&gt; recognized as species. Moreover, molecular dating of lineages suggests that this complex might have occurred long before the Messinian salinity crisis. Finally, peculiar morphological and ecological features along with molecular data strongly support the proposal to re-introduce the genus &lt;i&gt;Erctella&lt;/i&gt; Monterosato, 1894 for the &lt;i&gt;H.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mazzullii&lt;/i&gt; complex. Synonyms and bibliographic references are reported in the systematic part; collection records are listed in Appendix 1.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Land snails; &lt;i&gt;mazzullii&lt;/i&gt; group; &lt;i&gt;Erctella&lt;/i&gt;; Helicidae; Sicilian endemism; molecular taxonomy; molecular phylogeny; biodiversity; biogeography; Mio-pliocene events</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Land snails</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>M.</firstname>
          <middlename>Stella</middlename>
          <lastname>Colomba</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Armando</firstname>
          <lastname>Gregorini</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Fabio</firstname>
          <lastname>Liberto</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Agatino</firstname>
          <lastname>Reitano</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Salvatore</firstname>
          <lastname>Giglio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Ignazio</firstname>
          <lastname>Sparacio</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>1-42</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gymnothorax melanosomatus&lt;/i&gt;, a new moray eel (Teleostei: Anguilliformes: Muraenidae) from southeastern Taiwan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Gymnothorax&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;melanosomatus&lt;/i&gt; new species, is described here on the basis of eight specimens collected from eastern coastal Taiwan at a depth 50–180 m. This new moray eel is distinguished from a closely similar species, &lt;i&gt;G.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;prolatus,&lt;/i&gt; by a combination of the following characters: a uniformly black body when fresh (vs. brown), a relatively long preanal length 58.5 % of TL (vs. 48.9), shorter snout length 17.8 % of HL (vs. 20.0), interobital width 12.2 % of HL (vs. 14.3); more preanal vertebrae 105–109 (vs. 74–86) and total vertebrae 201–211 (vs. 174–190). The male and female are not different in body color and pattern, but the numbers of median intermaxillary teeth are different between the sexes, 0 in male and 2–3 in female.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Muraenidae; &lt;i&gt;Gymnothorax&lt;/i&gt;; moray eel; new species; Taiwan</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Muraenidae</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kar-Hoe</firstname>
          <lastname>Loh</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Kwang-Tsao</firstname>
          <lastname>Shao</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Hong-Ming</firstname>
          <lastname>Chen</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>43-52</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
        <open_access/>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Eviota rubriceps&lt;/i&gt;, a new goby from the Southwestern Pacific Ocean, with comments on &lt;i&gt;E. mikiae &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;E. raja &lt;/i&gt;(Teleostei: Gobiidae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">A new species of goby, &lt;i&gt;Eviota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubriceps,&lt;/i&gt; most similar to &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrispina,&lt;/i&gt; is described from Indonesia, Papua New Guinea, and the Philippine Islands. Both species have the lower two thirds of the body dark in preserved specimens, belong to the cephalic sensory-pore pattern group 2 of Lachner and Karnella (1980), have an 8/7 dorsal/anal formula, and unbranched pectoral-fin rays. &lt;i&gt;Eviota&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;rubriceps&lt;/i&gt; differs from &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;nigrispina&lt;/i&gt; in live and preserved coloration and in caudal-peduncle depth. The descriptions of &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;mikiae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;E.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;raja&lt;/i&gt; are expanded based on additional materials.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Ichthyology; systematics; Gobiidae; &lt;i&gt;Eviota&lt;/i&gt;; new species; pygmygoby; dwarfgoby; S.W. Pacific Ocean</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Ichthyology</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>David</firstname>
          <middlename>W.</middlename>
          <lastname>Greenfield</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Susan</firstname>
          <middlename>L.</middlename>
          <lastname>Jewett</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>53-62</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">New genus for a unique species of Indo-West Pacific bryozoan</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">Larval type, larval morphology, ancestrular morphology and colony astogeny have great systematic value in the cheilostomate bryozoans, but for most species these characters are undocumented. Whilst most cheilostomate bryozoan species produce lecithotrophic coronate larvae; a minority of species produce planktotrophic cyphonautes larvae, all belonging to genera within the superfamily Membraniporoidea. &lt;i&gt;Biflustra&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laboriosa&lt;/i&gt; Tilbrook, 2006 nominally belongs to a membraniporid genus whose species are otherwise characterised by having a twinned ancestrula. The production of a single ancestrula from a cyphonautes larva and overall zooidal morphology excludes &lt;i&gt;B.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laboriosa&lt;/i&gt; from the Membraniporidae and its zooidal characters are alien to any other membraniporoidean genus. Accordingly, &lt;i&gt;Tarsocryptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;gen.&lt;/b&gt; is erected to accommodate it, resulting in the new combination &lt;i&gt;Tarsocryptus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;laboriosa&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;n.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;comb.&lt;/b&gt; Its reassignment here to the membraniporoidean Electridae is tentative.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Bryozoa; new genus; Indo-West Pacific</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Bryozoa</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Kevin</firstname>
          <middlename>J.</middlename>
          <lastname>Tilbrook</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>63-67</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Erratum: YOUNG-HYO KIM, ED A. HENDRYCKS &amp; KYUNG-SOOK LEE (2011) The genus &lt;i&gt;Guernea &lt;/i&gt;Chevreux, 1887 from Korean waters (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Dexaminidae) &lt;i&gt;Zootaxa&lt;/i&gt;, 3104, 1–25. </title>
        <abstract locale="en_US"/>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <pages>68</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-16</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
