<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "native.dtd">
<issues>
  <issue current="false" identification="title" public_id="" published="true">
    <id type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.3138.1</id>
    <title locale="en_US">21 Dec. 2011</title>
    <volume>3138</volume>
    <number>1</number>
    <year>2011</year>
    <date_published>2011-12-21</date_published>
    <section>
      <title locale="en_US">Articles</title>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">Genetic evaluation of the Baja California rock squirrel &lt;i&gt;Otospermophilus atricapillus &lt;/i&gt;(Rodentia: Sciuridae)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">The Baja California rock squirrel (Otospermophilus &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; Bryant) is endemic to the Baja California Peninsula, Mexico and known from only five localities. &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; is considered as the sister species of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi&lt;/i&gt; (Richardson) and both have been considered different species mainly by its colorations. In an attempt to better understand the relationship within &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; and with its sister species &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi,&lt;/i&gt; we used genetic information gathered from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus,&lt;/i&gt; aiming to investigate the phylogenetic and phylogeography of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi.&lt;/i&gt; We analyzed two sets of mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt; gene (Cyt &lt;i&gt;b)&lt;/i&gt; data: One 800 (bp) fragments of 118 individuals and a second one of 1140 (bp) for the 32 haplotypes found. Our own hypothesis is that specific characteristics used to distinguish &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;artricapillus&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi&lt;/i&gt; are at the same level than the differences among the recognized subspecies of &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi.&lt;/i&gt; Under that condition, a genetic analysis will show that &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; are within the genetic variation of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi,&lt;/i&gt; and the current diagnostic characters of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; could be considered only at subspecific level. The analysis of molecular variance revealed that &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; is not significantly different from &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi,&lt;/i&gt; and that, apart from highland populations in the Sierra Nevada, the sampled populations of &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;beecheyi&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;O.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;atricapillus&lt;/i&gt; are not significantly different among all of them.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;; México; genetic variation; &lt;i&gt;Otospermophilus&lt;/i&gt;; Rodentia; &lt;i&gt;Spermophilus&lt;/i&gt;; taxonomic</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">cytochrome &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Sergio</firstname>
          <middlename>Ticul</middlename>
          <lastname>Álvarez-Castañeda</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <author primary_contact="false">
          <firstname>Patricia</firstname>
          <lastname>Cortés-Calva</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>35-51</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-21</date_published>
      </article>
      <article language="en">
        <title locale="en_US">A new species of &lt;i&gt;Leiopathes &lt;/i&gt;(Anthozoa: Antipatharia) from the Great Meteor seamount (North Atlantic)</title>
        <abstract locale="en_US">&lt;i&gt;Leiopathes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana,&lt;/i&gt; a new species previously reported as &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glaberrima&lt;/i&gt; (Esper), is described from the plateau of the Great Meteor seamount (North Atlantic) at depth 300–335 m. The new species can be easily distinguished from all other species of the genus by very thin at tips, slightly bended terminal branchlets 0.15–0.2 mm in diameter above the base, rather long in comparison to the size of the colony, small compressed triangular spines 0.02–0.03 mm long and 0.22–0.5 mm apart, and small densely-set polyps (6–9 per centimeter). Eight species assigned to the genus &lt;i&gt;Leiopathes&lt;/i&gt; represent two distinct groups: (1) sparsely branched forms with longer terminal branchlets (L. &lt;i&gt;glaberrima,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valdiviae,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;acanthophora,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;bullosa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana),&lt;/i&gt; and (2) forms with sinusoidal stem and branches, and very short branchlets forming flabellate fronds (L. &lt;i&gt;expansa,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grimaldii,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;secunda).&lt;/i&gt; The largest in size syntype of &lt;i&gt;L.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;grimaldii&lt;/i&gt; Roule, 1902 collected off the Azores is proposed here as the lectotype, since it is the only full grown and complete specimen and also the only specimen illustrated and described in detail by Roule.</abstract>
        <indexing>
          <discipline locale="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></discipline>
          <subject locale="en_US">Cnidaria; Leiopathidae; &lt;i&gt;Leiopathes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;montana&lt;/i&gt;; new species; &lt;i&gt;Leiopathes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;valdiviae&lt;/i&gt;; new combination; taxonomy</subject>
          <subject_class locale="en_US">Cnidaria</subject_class>
        </indexing>
        <author primary_contact="true">
          <firstname>Tina</firstname>
          <middlename>N.</middlename>
          <lastname>Molodtsova</lastname>
          <email>user@example.com</email>
        </author>
        <pages>51-64</pages>
        <date_published>2011-12-21</date_published>
      </article>
    </section>
  </issue>
</issues>
